<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sex Kittens Go to College</original_title><imdb_rating>2.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Albert Zugsmith</director><producer>Albert Zugsmith Productions</producer><producer>Photoplay Associates</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
Collins College needs a new department head for their science department. Doctors Carter and Zorch consult Thinko...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Mamie Van Doren</actor><actor>Tuesday Weld</actor><actor>Mijanou Bardot</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1163639/comments</url><from>from mission, ks</from><name>eminges</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

There are no actual decapitations, cattle mutilation, desecration of houses
of worship, or spurting arteries in Sex Kittens Go To College.  Within those
limits, this is ghastly beyond anything you can imagine. Imagine Mamie van Doren as an ex-stripper with an IQ of 268 and twelve
college degrees - no, thirteen, hired as a college professor.  Imagine
Jackie Coogan as a blustering oilman doing a 45-minute W.C. Fields
impression.  Imagine Martin Milner out-geeking Eddie Deezen, a twelve-foot
robot named Thinko that handicaps horse races, a chimp in golf pants. 
Imagine the most credible and disciplined performance in the film being
turned in by Louis Nye.  Imagine Vampira so hagged out you'd flee to the
arms of Nancy Kulp...Brigitte Bardot's little sister as an exchange
student...Conway Twitty...fire engine...funny gangsters...
Are your sides aching with laughter yet? Terrifyingly awful.  The only saving grace is that neither Woody Woodbury
nor Paul Anka makes a guest appearance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3932421/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>joeshoe89</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
It's really sad that there is only one comment on this fun classic in
six years. Written and directed by Albert Zugsmith who worked with
Orson Welles on one of his greatest films Touch of Evil, Sex Kittens Go
To College is a great Psychotronic film that really should be out on
DVD hopefully with a Joe Bob Briggs commentary. The cast is nothing
short of amazing! Mamie Van Doren is a "genius" with 13 degrees and a
body that drives men wild and women to fume with jealousy. Tuesday Weld
is a bit young for college at 17 but looks fantastic. Mijanou Bardot is
more like the right age at 21 and her frerrranch accent like the great
one done by John Cleese in Holy Grail can't help but make you laugh.
There's John Carradine doing the Charleston with Mamie. The great
horror movie host Vampira (who dated James Dean and at 39 isn't the hag
the other reviewer says she is)is Louis Nye's lab assistant taking care
of Thinko the robot a computer (!) that is a big metal robot with a lot
of phony machines all around him. Hopefully if they put this on DVD
they'll get the European cut which includes four strippers who do their
"acts" for Thinko and Voltaire the chimp who's dressed like a beatnik
most of the time. The strippers get down to some pretty skimpy panties
(one is a thong so young people who think those were invented in the
nineties are wrong)and pasties on their nipples. This was really hot
stuff in 1960. Today it would get a PG on ABC family channel. MST3K did
a great job with one of Mamie's other classics Girl's Town but
unfortunately never got to do this film. Here's hoping if the show ever
comes back or Joe Bob gets a shot at it this is the film they do. Like
Plan Nine From Outer Space this is a classic!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0328150/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL, United States</from><name>GJValent</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I caught this in the mid 1960s as a late Sunday night, (intended for
adults), telecast here in Chicago. It was presented under the 'Beauty
and the Robot' title. I thought it was pretty good. You had Mamie as a
super intelligent, HOT, babe, taking on an entire college and trying to
win the smart guy, Todd, from Route 66. She gets to hypnotize John
Carradine into dancing. She gets to drive a fire engine. Bridget
Bardot's sister wears the frat pin of her boyfriend on her bra strap,
which sticks out of the over-sized, FlashDance', neck of her
sweatshirt. Super hot rodder Norman 'Woo Woo' Grabowski is a major
character. Louis Nye plays an old man. What more do you need ? Also,
the full name of the computer/robot is SAM Thinko. The SAM stands for
System Analog Modulator. It means nothing, but, sounds technical. Would
be great to watch with friends and a few beers. Oh, yeah, we had a
color TV, and, I swear this was in color. Maybe not.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19744164/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jadedalex</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
This movie, along with "High School Confidential" and an even worse
"College Confidential" (with Steve Allen) are among the most witless
and unfunny productions, geared towards "teenagers", coming out of
Hollywood in this era of late fifties and early sixties .... how may of
these films was Albert Zugsmith involved in? I just checked....all
three!You'd think that there would be some nostalgic appeal in seeing Mamie
Van Doren, in her prime. Or the very young and nubile Tuesday Weld, a
pretty Mijanou Bardot (Brigitte Bardot's sister). But the plot is so
lame, it's real work to get through this film. It hardly utilizes the
talents of Maila Nurmi ("Vampyra"). She is reduced to a short unfunny
bit as a school secretary, her beauty hidden by dorky glasses.Jackie Coogan must have looked like he was pounding the last nails in
his coffin, I mean career. Fortunately, his classic turn as "Uncle
Fester" on "The Addams Family" left us with some pleasant memories of
the former child actor.Seeing officer Pete Malloy (Martin Milner) as a big part of this sleazy
production is a side of Martin we never saw in his stiff portrayal of
the LAPD officer in "Adam-12".This movie is not easily obtained, but I got my DVD copy relatively
cheap via the internet. I couldn't quite understand why "Sex Kittens"
was never shown on the late, late show, along with "High School
Confidential".I was about falling to sleep through this unfunny romp. (Really sad to
see a talent like Louis Nye wasted here.) Then I perked up, as after
all of the movie's unfunny situations, we finally get to look at real
Hollywood mammary glands. Some brunette does a topless striptease and
had I not already been so bored by the movie's asinine antics, I might
have livened up a bit for her.So, essentially, for it's time, "Sex Kittens Go To College" is a
soft-core porn film. That's why it never turned up on the late, late
show. This film reminds me of "Orgy of the Dead", where the director
does for me what no other director besides "Sex Kitten's" auteur has
done -- by the end of the movie, I'm kind of tired of watching cleavage
and mammary glands. Don't get me wrong. Movie is worth it for the early footage of Tuesday
Weld. Too much footage of the goofy robot, and not enough Mijanou!But the movie, well....if it looks like a zugsmith, and smells like a
zugsmith, it's probably damn well a zugsmith.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur28304394/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>dallaswhiskey</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This movie has it all. There's Mamie van Doren as a super-intelligent
professor/tassel-tosser. There's her pet monkey that plays the piano
and the drums. There's a robot. There are gangsters. There's a
ten-minute dream sequence of topless strippers. There's a high-speed
firetruck driving scene with lots of nice 50s cars. There's Mamie
making an introduction to her new students by shooting two revolvers
all over the lecture room. Mamie shooting at the camera with a fire
extinguisher. Conway Twitty singing rock'n'roll. Vampira making an
appearance as a shaggy lab assistant. Brigitte's sister Mijanou Bardot
sweet-talking as a French exchange student. What more could you
possibly want? 103 minutes (uncut), never a dull moment. This is entertainment. If you
are looking for something clever, you don't pick a movie named "Sex
kittens go to college" anyway.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur28304394/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>dallaswhiskey</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This movie has it all. There's Mamie van Doren as a super-intelligent
professor/tassel-tosser. There's her pet monkey that plays the piano
and the drums. There's a robot. There are gangsters. There's a
ten-minute dream sequence of topless strippers. There's a high-speed
firetruck driving scene with lots of nice 50s cars. There's Mamie
making an introduction to her new students by shooting two revolvers
all over the lecture room. Mamie shooting at the camera with a fire
extinguisher. Conway Twitty singing rock'n'roll. Vampira making an
appearance as a shaggy lab assistant. Brigitte's sister Mijanou Bardot
sweet-talking as a French exchange student. What more could you
possibly want? 103 minutes (uncut), never a dull moment. This is entertainment. If you
are looking for something clever, you don't pick a movie named "Sex
kittens go to college" anyway.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur28304394/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>dallaswhiskey</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>