<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Il mulino delle donne di pietra</original_title><alt_title>Le Moulin des supplices</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Giorgio Ferroni</director><producer>C.E.C. Films</producer><producer>Explorer Film '58</producer><producer>Faro Film</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
Hans arrives in a town near Amsterdam to write a story on the reclusive sculptor, Professor Val, who lives on an island in the old mill house the locals call the Mill of the Stone Women...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Pierre Brice</actor><actor>Scilla Gabel</actor><actor>Wolfgang Preiss</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is one of the films that is very atmospheric, stylish, and
inventive in the European 60's fashion. The story is somewhat of a
cross between Nathaniel Hawthorne's short story "Rappacini's Daughter"
and the film House of Wax. An art professor is keeping a secret about
his invalid, beautiful, seductive daughter Elfi away from Hans von
Arnam, a man sent to write a piece on the centennial of the professor's
mill and its famous statues of women that move around on a
carousel-like machine. The statues are of famous women through history
as well as having local historical murderesses and victims displayed.
Living with the professor and Elfi is a strange doctor. Amidst this
strange four-sided triangle, women are disappearing. The story is'nt
too hard to figure out and much is given away early on. What it does do
quite nicely is create a slowly-paced mood that leads to an interesting
if not wholly imaginative denouement. The style infused throughout the
picture is a credit to Italian director Giorgio Ferroni. The use of
colors, the settings, the haunting carousel music, the "waxworks"
themselves all help create the oppressive almost hallucinogenic mood.
The acting is pretty good overall with Wolfgang Preiss as the complex
doctor and especially Robert Boehme as Professor Gregorious Wahl
standing out. Scilla Gabel as Elfi is just gorgeous as is Liana Orfei
as one of the girls that gets missing. The production looks very German
in manner and style - another compliment to the director. There are
several scenes which stand out: the first time we see the carousel
moving, nay, almost cranking itself away past those that have come to
gawk at it, the drug-induced dream sequence Hans goes through, and the
ending - a real barn-burner! Mill of the Stone Women isn't a fast-paced
horror film but if you like movies like Black Sunday or Bava's work in
general - Ferroni seems to have some similar directorial flair.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0295265/comments</url><from>from SanJose, California</from><name>LARSONRD</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Neatly expressionistic mood piece about a mad scientist/sculptor trying
to keep his afflicted daughter from turning to stone by transfusing her
with the blood of local babes. The storyline (a favorite of European
horror films - THE AWFUL DR. ORLOF and EYES WITHOUT A FACE also had to
do with a mad scientist trying to save a deformed daughter at the
expense of anyone within reach) has holes thick enough to bowl a
woman's severed head through, but the film is great on atmosphere and
ambiance. Completed without credit by Mario Bava after director Giorgio
Ferroni began it, the Mondo Macabro DVD version includes the uncut
French edition (massacred in bad US VHS prints till now). This film was
one of two that reportedly started the Eurohorror boom of the '60s and
'70s, of which Bava was a primary maestro.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2074560/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Gafke</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a nice, creepy film, reminding me of a cross between
"ReAnimator" (without the humor), "House of Wax" and the "Twice Told
Tales" episode with Vincent Price as the father of an untouchable
daughter. A young man staying at an old windmill-turned-wax museum is seduced by
the strange and beautiful young daughter of the man who runs the mill,
himself an eccentric old scientist. (is there any other kind?) But he,
his daughter, and the family doctor who cares for and loves her, are
all hiding a terrible secret...and there's a reason why the wax statues
of famous villainous women all look so lifelike! When the pretty,
innocent girl from the nearby village, (whom our hero has fallen in
love with, despite the best efforts of Creepy Girl) goes mysteriously
missing, it's off to the mill to learn the terrible truth! This is a dreamy, sometimes slow-moving, but never disappointing film
which features a great "acid trip" sequence and the surprising nudity
of several buxom young hotties. Should not be missed by fans of the
colorful Italian, Hammer- esque genre. Wonderfully atmospheric and
genuinely creepy. Great stuff!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Mill of the Stone Women is a regretfully undiscovered gem of authentic
Gothic craftsmanship that totally blew me away. It's not an easy puppy
to come across, despite the recent DVD-release, so I had to purchase an
entirely Frech version (called "Le Moulin des Supplices"). But
eventually beholding the beauty of this film was worth every effort I
took for finding it, for sure! Like stated in the review title, this is
one of the most atmospheric tales ever told and, even though the basic
premise might not be unique, a fascinating Gothic experience that will
mesmerize you from start to finish.The story is set in a remote Dutch village (the land of the windmills!)
where Professor Wahl slickly turned his mill into a macabre history
museum. He's an artist whose hand-made carousel and sculptures attract
many viewers, as also the young journalist Hans. But Wahl
simultaneously is a father whose exquisite daughter Elphi suffers from
an incurable illness that forces him to keep her hidden in the
windmill. When Hans meets Elphi during his stay, Professor Wahl fears
that his presence will have a bad influence on her fragile health.
Because of all the mystery and Wahl's distant behavior, Hans suspects
that he has more hidden secrets than just an ill daughter.... Because
of the period of release, the mood and the high-quality level, "Mill of
the Stone Women" often gets compared with the repertoire of Mario Bava.
I second this statement and – believe me – that's quite a compliment as
I consider Bava the greatest director cinema has ever known. This is a
slow-paced masterpiece that makes the most out of its eerie set pieces
and isolated locations. The ominous windmill emphases the intriguing
Gothic effect terrifically while the use of sound creates a constant
disturbance. Rather than to gross you out with immediate gruesomeness
or sleaze, the suspenseful plot builds itself up to somewhat expected
but still ferocious climax that will be memorized forever by fans of
classic horror. I won't spoil the actual finale, but it's not the
film's biggest anyway, as it combines the equally brilliant premises of
"Mystery of the Wax Musem", "Eyes without a face" and even
"Frankenstein". "Mill of the Stone Women" also influenced many
(euro)horror films afterwards, like for example Jess Franco's "The
Awful Dr. Orloff". And I'm not done yet, since simply every aspect of
this film is praiseworthy. The camera-work is stunning and often quite
groundbreaking. When it's believed that Hans is hallucinating, the
implementation of different shades and rough camera movements increase
the confusion-effect. The characters are efficiently spooky! Especially
Dr. Bolem (played by Wolfgang "Dr. Mabuse" Preiss) and Professor Wahl
(Boehme, who strangely hasn't got any other acting experience) are
impressive villains/mad scientists. "Mill of the Stone Women" is
essential viewing for Mario Bava fanatics and any other genre fan who
appreciates a solid goth-horror monument.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Mill of the Stone Women is the story of a researcher named Hans who is
finishing a book on the famous sculptor Professor Wahl and his
carousel. The carousel features wax representations of women being
tortured and killed in a variety of sadistic and inventive ways. A
meeting with the Professor's beautiful, seductive daughter, Elfi,
ignites conflicting passions within Hans because of his one true love
Liselotte. Things are even more complicated because breaking the news
to Elfi will not be easy. She suffers from a rare disease that can
cause death if she becomes too upset or disturbed. In addition, Hans is
convinced that Professor Wahl is up to some twisted experiments that
may involve several of the local women including his Liselotte. Hans
must solve the mystery of the windmill and the carousel if he is to
save himself and the one woman he cares about.What Works: - Atmosphere, Atmosphere, Atmosphere. If you're into atmosphere with
your horror, look no further than Mill of the Stone Women. Most movies
can't claim to have 1/10 of the atmosphere found here. The barren
landscape, the isolated windmill, the constant overcast skies, the dark
corridors with secret rooms in the windmill, the eerie music, the
twisted carousel of death, and the Gothic trappings everywhere you look
all add to a movie that just drips with atmosphere. The movie takes
it's time and doesn't rush or try to force things. There's a real
foreboding sense of unease that runs throughout the movie. There are
moments when you might think the atmosphere is going to literally ooze
from the screen into your living room.- Scilla Gabel. Gabel is one of those women of the 60s that I don't
think exist anymore. She's from that Sophia Loren - Claudia Cardinale –
Daliah Lavi mold of women that were a product of that time. She may
never be confused with a great actress, but she has a screen presence
that's hard to beat.- Prof. Gregorius Wahl. What a character! Robert Boehme does an
excellent job of playing a mad, but goofy, genius. By the end of Mill
of the Stone Women, though, it's easy to feel some sympathy for him as
his dreams are shattered. It's an excellent piece of acting from a man
whose acting credits only include this movie.- Wooden Shoes. Any movie with people wearing wooden shoes has to get a
bonus point from me.What Doesn't Work: - Slow Going. For me, this is a plus. But I put it here to warn those
who prefer a movie with a killing or explosion every five minutes.- Love Story. Because Hans represents a new, exciting life, it's easy
to see why Elfi might quickly fall for him. And, because Elfi is such a
looker, it's easy to see why Hans might be interested in Elfi. But the
fact that both are declaring their undying love for each other after
one five-minute meeting stretches the imagination quite a bit.In the end, Mill of the Stone Women is one of the finest examples of a
Gothic, atmospheric movie ever made. The film plays like a combination
of The House of Wax meets Eyes Without a Face. It's a wonderful movie
that I enjoy more each time I get the chance to watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0865972/comments</url><from>from Chyby, Poland</from><name>HumanoidOfFlesh</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A young artist named Hans is hired to do a study of a famous local
landmark,a windmill that contains stone statues of notorious female
monsters of the past.One day he meets a mysterious,dangerously
beautiful woman at the mill.Before long,he is drawn into her
clutches.Giorgio Feronni's gloriously colorful horror film "Mill of the
Stone Woman" is obviously influenced by Georges Franju's horror classic
"Eyes Without a Face" and Mario Bava's "I Vampiri".Admittedly the first
half of the film is pretty slow and rather confusing, however there is
enough eerie moments to satisfy fans of early 60's Italian Gothic
horror.The location sets are truly atmospheric,for example the
crumbling mill of the film's title is a decrepit place,filled
haphazardly with ominous statuary and ancient religious icons.So if you
are a fan of Italian horror you can't miss this gorgeously photographed
gem.9 out of 10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7588529/comments</url><from>from Salzburg, Austria</from><name>Benjamin Gauss</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
"Black Sunday", "House Of Usher", "Eyes Without A Face", "City Of The
Dead",... 1960 sure was one of the greatest years ever for Horror
cinema, especially for Gothic Horror. In the same year in which Mario
Bava brought us the arguably greatest Gothic Horror film ever (and, in
my opinion, one of the greatest films ever made) with his masterpiece
"La Maschera Del Demonio" (aka. "Black Sunday") and Roger Corman began
the arguably greatest Horror cycle in film history with the brilliant
"House Of Usher", director Giorgio Ferroni enriched the world of Horror
with this atmospheric and hauntingly beautiful gem called "Il Mulino
Delle Donne Di Pietra" aka. "Mill Of The Stone Women", a film with an
incredible sense of Gothic beauty and eerie atmosphere that no true
Horror fan could possibly afford to miss. A French/Italian
Co-production, the film is based on an unknown story by Pieter van
Weigen. The creepy, morbid and incredibly fascinating storyline is very
similar to that of Georges Franju's masterpiece "Les Yeux Sans Visage"
aka. "Eyes Without A Face", which was made in the same year, but the
execution is different in style. Morbid stories about mad scientists
who target innocent young women in order to restore life, youth or
beauty of one specific young woman were a very popular Horror theme in
the late 50s and early 60s, and tales of the kind are still among the
most fascinating topics the Horror genre has ever brought forth. What
also makes this film an absolute must is the eerie atmosphere, the
ingenious photography, superb settings and mesmerizing use of color.Journalist Hans (Pierre Brice) comes to the small town of Veeze in
order to write a story about the 'Mill Of The Stone Women', a macabre
museum in which female statues in morbid situations such as executions
are displayed on a mill-wheel. The museum is kept by Professor Wahl
(Herbert A.E. Böhme), who keeps his beautiful daughter Elfi (Scilla
Gabel) locked in the Windmill. The house is furthermore inhabited by
the sinister doctor Bohlem (Wolfgang Preiss)... I don't want to give
away too much of the story, but I can assure it gets morbid, haunting
and fascinating. The film's visual style and morbid atmosphere often
earns it comparisons to Mario Bava's masterpieces. The locations and
settings are beautiful and immensely eerie alike and the brilliant
camera-work and excellently eerie score contribute a lot to the creepy
and unsettling atmosphere. The performances are also very good and the
characters are intriguing. I am not a very big fan of Pierre Brice in
general (where I live he is mainly known for the incredibly cheesy
German Karl May flicks), but he delivers an excellent performance here.
The highest praise, however has to go to Herbert A. E. Böhme for his
brilliant portrayal of the sinister professor and, especially, to the
ravishing Scilla Gabel. Gabel is a stunning beauty and great actress
and she delivers a wonderful performance as the mysterious and
seductive Elfi Wahl. Wolfgang Preiss is very sinister as the doctor and
Dany Carell fits well in her role of the innocent girl. "Mill Of The
Stone Women" is an elegant and haunting masterpiece that no lover of
Gothic greatness can possibly afford to miss!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2951437/comments</url><from>from Mountains of Madness</from><name>fertilecelluloid</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Beautifully directed and photographed European horror film that owes a
debt to Franju's EYES WITHOUT A FACE.An evocative, creepy score by Carlo Innocenzi helps director Giorgio
Ferroni conjure a work of great atmosphere and intense drama.As in EYES and Franco's ORLOFF, the subject is a fanatic obsessed with
preserving the life of a dearly departed member of his family -- in
this case, his daughter Elfi, played by the achingly beautiful and
sensual Scilla Gabel.The setting, a windmill outside Amsterdam, is a superb arena for the
fantastic goings-on that provide frisson upon frisson of wonder and
dread. The "stone women" of the title are frightening, fascinating
figures of fear and are richly employed by Ferroni who demonstrates an
acute talent for fantasy.The superb opening sequence establishes a mood that never falters, and
the exciting finale, with the Stone Women ablaze, is pure magic.A handsomely produced gem.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0824217/comments</url><from>from North Carolina</from><name>Der_Schizoid_Tanzt</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Extremely entertaining Italian/French Gothic horror directed by Giorgio
Ferroni. The story concerns a young man who takes employment with (what
else?) a creepy professor. He becomes entangled in a bit of an affair
with the professors daughter and is soon led into a strange web of
deceit designed to hide a very ugly secret.This film gets big points for style and creepiness! It's both well
acted and directed. And anyone who enjoys films like Corman's 'House of
Usher' will certainly enjoy this one.The DVD, distributed by Mondo Macabro, is top notch with excellent
picture quality and sufficient bonus features.Highly recommended!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2925760/comments</url><from/><name>BrentCarleton</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Without question an inappropriate, inane, or pulpy comic book style
title has waylaid many a significant and otherwise worthy terror film.
"Curse of the Cat People," remains affixed to a story of child
psychology, "Kill Baby Kill," remains affixed to a wondrous 19th
century European ghost story, and here, perhaps worst of all, "Mill of
the Stone Women," is the awkward moniker stuck to this artistically
accomplished film.With a clunky title like "Mill of the Stone Women," it is scarcely any
wonder that the film has remained largely unknown,unremarked upon, and
unavailable for nearly 50 years ! What a pity, for here is a story
produced with such an aesthetically accomplished loving care that each
frame breathes a compositional beauty of the highest standard.The felicitous combination of Arrigo Equini's art direction and Pier
Ludovico Pavoni's photography in this picture, recalls the best of Jack
Asher, Floyd Crosby, Mario Bava, Bernard Robinson, and Daniel Haller
and has, in not a few of the tableaux rendered here, even surpassed
these masters. Even Mario Praz would probably approve!From the opening shot of the windmill on the lake under a leaden sky,
to its shadowy, beautifully appointed interior parlors, complete with
the anti-heroine, Scilla Gabel, peaking mournfully through the
portières--while the soundtrack gives forth with a disquieting numinous
wail--the film rarely fails to sound the genuine Gothic note.Add to that one of the most disturbing, (far more so than "House of
Wax") use of a waxworks yet seen on the screen. For here we have, not
merely figures of unsettling visage, but figures that mechanically
encircle a stage--Joan of Arc, Cleopatra, Mary Queen of Scots, sallying
threateningly towards the camera in a nightmarish parade--all to the
accompaniment of a tune that might have been composed by Truman Capote!
There are many exquisite scenes to savor: Miss Scabra's blood red
boudoir, a scene of her beneath the lid of a dusty glass coffin holding
yellow roses against her very dead, old ivory like complexion, a
laboratory sequence that pulls out all the stops, a charming stop at a
beer garden type pub, complete with accordions and pretzel stands, a
climactic fire with the dummies melting in grotesque close-ups, not to
mention a beautifully costumed, very accomplished, and handsome cast of
players.Miss Gabel seems very much in the Gina Lollobrigida mold, but manages
facial expressions of such uncanny yearning that is easy to imagine Mr.
Brice falling under her spell. In this sense, she joins company with
Barbara Steele, as one of the very few women able to combine beauty and
eeriness in equal measure.Pierre Brice approaches his assignment with convincing earnestness and
looks very much like a cross between Stephen Boyd and Horst Buchold.A special compliment should be paid to the Technicolor here, which
never shrieks, but delivers cold blues and unearthly reds in a fashion
that favorably recalls Pressburger's "Tales of Hoffmann." And take a
good look at the hutch in the ante-room of Mr. Brice's bedroom; it is
the same one featured in Jacqueline Pierreux's parlor in Bava's "Black
Sabbath"--the one she keeps her liquor in. Perhaps Mr. Brice had a yard
sale! In any case, to fans of the genre, this film is highly
recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2925760/comments</url><from/><name>BrentCarleton</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Without question an inappropriate, inane, or pulpy comic book style
title has waylaid many a significant and otherwise worthy terror film.
"Curse of the Cat People," remains affixed to a story of child
psychology, "Kill Baby Kill," remains affixed to a wondrous 19th
century European ghost story, and here, perhaps worst of all, "Mill of
the Stone Women," is the awkward moniker stuck to this artistically
accomplished film.With a clunky title like "Mill of the Stone Women," it is scarcely any
wonder that the film has remained largely unknown,unremarked upon, and
unavailable for nearly 50 years ! What a pity, for here is a story
produced with such an aesthetically accomplished loving care that each
frame breathes a compositional beauty of the highest standard.The felicitous combination of Arrigo Equini's art direction and Pier
Ludovico Pavoni's photography in this picture, recalls the best of Jack
Asher, Floyd Crosby, Mario Bava, Bernard Robinson, and Daniel Haller
and has, in not a few of the tableaux rendered here, even surpassed
these masters. Even Mario Praz would probably approve!From the opening shot of the windmill on the lake under a leaden sky,
to its shadowy, beautifully appointed interior parlors, complete with
the anti-heroine, Scilla Gabel, peaking mournfully through the
portières--while the soundtrack gives forth with a disquieting numinous
wail--the film rarely fails to sound the genuine Gothic note.Add to that one of the most disturbing, (far more so than "House of
Wax") use of a waxworks yet seen on the screen. For here we have, not
merely figures of unsettling visage, but figures that mechanically
encircle a stage--Joan of Arc, Cleopatra, Mary Queen of Scots, sallying
threateningly towards the camera in a nightmarish parade--all to the
accompaniment of a tune that might have been composed by Truman Capote!
There are many exquisite scenes to savor: Miss Scabra's blood red
boudoir, a scene of her beneath the lid of a dusty glass coffin holding
yellow roses against her very dead, old ivory like complexion, a
laboratory sequence that pulls out all the stops, a charming stop at a
beer garden type pub, complete with accordions and pretzel stands, a
climactic fire with the dummies melting in grotesque close-ups, not to
mention a beautifully costumed, very accomplished, and handsome cast of
players.Miss Gabel seems very much in the Gina Lollobrigida mold, but manages
facial expressions of such uncanny yearning that is easy to imagine Mr.
Brice falling under her spell. In this sense, she joins company with
Barbara Steele, as one of the very few women able to combine beauty and
eeriness in equal measure.Pierre Brice approaches his assignment with convincing earnestness and
looks very much like a cross between Stephen Boyd and Horst Buchold.A special compliment should be paid to the Technicolor here, which
never shrieks, but delivers cold blues and unearthly reds in a fashion
that favorably recalls Pressburger's "Tales of Hoffmann." And take a
good look at the hutch in the ante-room of Mr. Brice's bedroom; it is
the same one featured in Jacqueline Pierreux's parlor in Bava's "Black
Sabbath"--the one she keeps her liquor in. Perhaps Mr. Brice had a yard
sale! In any case, to fans of the genre, this film is highly
recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2925760/comments</url><from/><name>BrentCarleton</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>