<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Man in the Moon</original_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Basil Dearden</director><producer>Excalibur Films</producer><producer>Allied Film Makers (AFM)</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Scientists are looking for a man to send up to be the first man on the moon. A man immune to worry, disease and even the common cold. They think they have found him until the impossible happens at Woomera...
</synopsis><actor>Kenneth More</actor><actor>Shirley Anne Field</actor><actor>Michael Hordern</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1133909/comments</url><from>from Perth, Western Australia</from><name>DesperateIcon (kieran@murphyslore.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

If the British had ever mounted a moon exploration mission I wouldn't
expect
this film to be too far from the truth. Kenneth More plays Billy Blood, an
everyman selected to be the first man on the moon by three crackpot 'NASTI'
scientists who deem the trip too dangerous to be made by trained
astronauts.There follows a series of experiments, three jealous astronauts, a stripper
girlfriend and a baked beans tin in the Australian Outback...It's British, it's mad, and it's fanciful, if not a little wayward in
parts..look out for a young Charles Gray enjoying himself as the
upper-crust
astronaut brainwashed into being Blood's new best friend..."I say chaps, I shouldn't have had that last bit of tea and toast before
take-off"...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The concept that space flight is too dangerous to waste highly trained
astronauts on is so splendidly British.Spike Milligan would have been
proud to have thought it up.This forgotten film has many felicities,a
cast of top-drawer English comedy actors and is beautifully
photographed by one of the busiest cameramen in the business,Harry
Waxman who shot around 70 films including the superb "Brighton Rock"
and the cult classic "The Wicker man". Mr Kenneth More is cast as
William Blood,the very epitome of hale and heartiness,who has never had
a day's illness in his life,thus meeting the most important criterion
set out by the British Space Programme. The lovely Miss Shirley Anne
Field,displays a nice light touch as his nemesis.It seemed at the time
that Miss Field might be at the start of a long career in comedy as a
sort of "Liz Fraser with brains"character,but it never happened.Shortly
after "The man in the moon" she made the serious "The War Lover" where
she gave Mr Steve McQueen a run for his money. Mr More was a genuine
copper-bottomed star.He was far more versatile than often given credit
for.His "Freddy" in "The Deep Blue Sea" showed the depth beneath his
eternal cheeriness.Critics were forced to take him seriously after TV's
"The Forsyte Saga" ,but ordinary moviegoers had long recognised his
qualities. Like Samson of old he is undone by a beautiful woman,falls
in love with Miss Field and catches a cold. Those were the days when
our space programme,such as it was,was based in Woomera where the only
living things at risk from our falling rockets were a few kangaroos. We
liked to think we approached space exploration with the Corinthian
spirit but the fact is we were dabblers, the merest of amateurs
compared to the Americans and Russians.To them - the glory.To us -
Kenneth More sleeping on his iron bedstead in a field of cows.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10868510/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>christopher lyons</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I think this film is brilliant. It depicts an era in British history
that has long gone.Bubble-type cars, bars of chocolate at the railway
station where you could just hop on a steam train and go up to town
(London) or anywhere,without having to worry about pre booking or
reserving seats, leave your car on the road just outside the station,
and it would be there when you got back and no fee! There is a great
scene where the use an emersion tank very similar to the stress
relieving floatation tanks of today but this looks more fun. Another
great scene is near the beginning when Blood reports to the Common Cold
Research Station, which actually existed, and there are scenes of
galeforce winds in the corridors and rain stopping play in a cricket
match. The story line rattles along with pace and as usual in these
films, there's a great supporting British cast.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
While there are some slow spots here and there, I still enjoyed "Man in
the Moon" and thought it was a cute little curio from the era of the
Space Race. However, instead of showing the fledgling American or
Russian space programs, this movie is about the fictional British
program.The film begins with a team of scientists performing a wide variety of
grueling experiments on people--all of which take a serious toll on
them--causing the participants to get sick. Well, all but one becomes
sick. For some odd reason, a rather nice but dim bachelor seems immune
to all illnesses. Now you'd think this would be a case for the medical
community--as his genes must be incredible. However, the scientists are
only concerned about the space program--and none of these guinea pigs
knew that was the purpose of the study. What they also didn't realize
is that the egg-heads were looking for the perfect stooge to send to
the moon. You see, the scientists hated all the bad press they got when
animals were killed and they didn't want well-trained astronauts to
die--so they were looking for someone expendable and resilient...and
William Blood (Kenneth More) was their choice for this dubious honor.Much of the film is about both the training Blood undergoes as well as
his relationship with a nice stripper! But, because this lady might
distract Blood, for much of the film her letters are kept from him.
Later, he not only gets the girl but makes the first moon shot. To find
out what happens next, try watching this cute film.I liked the film's very cynical and tongue-in-cheek humor--though I am
sure younger people in the audience would be less impressed because
sometimes the humor was subtle and they really have no recollection of
this interesting period in history. Well done all around, but with a
few slow moments here and there.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
While there are some slow spots here and there, I still enjoyed "Man in
the Moon" and thought it was a cute little curio from the era of the
Space Race. However, instead of showing the fledgling American or
Russian space programs, this movie is about the fictional British
program.The film begins with a team of scientists performing a wide variety of
grueling experiments on people--all of which take a serious toll on
them--causing the participants to get sick. Well, all but one becomes
sick. For some odd reason, a rather nice but dim bachelor seems immune
to all illnesses. Now you'd think this would be a case for the medical
community--as his genes must be incredible. However, the scientists are
only concerned about the space program--and none of these guinea pigs
knew that was the purpose of the study. What they also didn't realize
is that the egg-heads were looking for the perfect stooge to send to
the moon. You see, the scientists hated all the bad press they got when
animals were killed and they didn't want well-trained astronauts to
die--so they were looking for someone expendable and resilient...and
William Blood (Kenneth More) was their choice for this dubious honor.Much of the film is about both the training Blood undergoes as well as
his relationship with a nice stripper! But, because this lady might
distract Blood, for much of the film her letters are kept from him.
Later, he not only gets the girl but makes the first moon shot. To find
out what happens next, try watching this cute film.I liked the film's very cynical and tongue-in-cheek humor--though I am
sure younger people in the audience would be less impressed because
sometimes the humor was subtle and they really have no recollection of
this interesting period in history. Well done all around, but with a
few slow moments here and there.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>