<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Too Hot to Handle</original_title><alt_title>La blonde et les nus de Soho</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Terence Young</director><producer>Wigmore Productions</producer><producer>Associated British Picture Corporation (ABPC)</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In London's Soho, Johnny Solo runs the Pink Flamingo Club. He's tough to intimidate. So when he starts getting threats and demands for protection...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jayne Mansfield</actor><actor>Leo Genn</actor><actor>Karlheinz Böhm</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1849630/comments</url><from>from Berlin</from><name>gnb</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

After the Hollywood successes of 'The Girl Can't Help It' and 'Will
Success Spoil Rock Hunter', 20th Century Fox were at a loss as to what
to do with the outlandish personality of Jayne Mansfield. So, as a way
of making some quick cash out of their star without having to put her
in a picture, they often loaned her out for cheapo European productions
such as this B-movie pot-boiler filmed in England.However, the finished results are surprisingly good. Jayne Mansfield
puts in an incredibly accomplished turn as jaded stripper Midnight
Franklin. Jayne acts so well in this movie - she really gives a great
impression of someone who can turn on the sexy, sleazy charm of a
showgirl on stage whilst being disillusioned and fearful behind the
scenes. Her pep-talk to a young Barbara Windsor is quite rightly often
highlighted as the high-point of Jayne's dramatic career.The story is at times a little muddled but is well acted by a solid
supporting cast including Christopher Lee, Leo Genn and Karl Bohm and
is presented in a seedy, gritty manner befitting the film's seedy
setting of London strip joints. The only complaint I could make about
the movie and its setting is that in basing the film around strip
joints the limitations of what could be shown due to censorship laws
(this was 1960 after all) are painfully obvious as all we are left with
are several musical numbers of supposed strippers writing around more
or less fully clothed. Although, it is not absolutely necessary to make
this movie a sordid nude-fest I think it is obvious how strict
censorship was in those days given what little nudity we actually get
to see. And why feature so many 'strip' numbers anyway...?All in all this is a pretty good movie and worth a look to see Jayne
Mansfield flexing her acting muscles. The version I managed to track
down on video is unfortunately in black and white and with a rather
poor sound mix but catch it if you can!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4422567/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>HarlowMGM</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
TOO HOT TO HANDLE was Jayne Mansfield's first film away from 20th
Century-Fox after achieving stardom in the mid 1950's. This British
drama is usually marked as the beginning of her descent into low-budget
productions but actually despite being set almost entirely in a
nightclub, it's clearly no cheapie with a large cast and somewhat
lavish production numbers with solid direction from Terence Young who
later did many James Bond films.Jayne plays the lead in this ensemble picture as the headline
attraction and longtime girlfriend of strip club owner Leo Genn who
lately has been the recipient of several extortion attempts. Tough guy
Genn is determined to fight back rather than give in much to Jayne's
distress. Jayne sings two numbers including the title song performed in
fairly transparent costume (reminscent of Marlene Dietrich's famous Las
Vegas gown) that covers the basics but not much else. This number is
badly shot with too many shots of the audience and not enough of Jayne
although this may have been the work of the censors. The movie's
American release was held up two years because of the racy numbers
(finally released in 1962 as PLAYGIRL AFTER DARK) but today it could
play on primetime TV and not raise an eyebrow although the numbers
remain sexy. Jayne generally looks gorgeous for the most but in a couple of scenes
is not photographed well and in some scenes appears to be unusually
plump (she may have been pregnant or had not yet lost post-baby weight,
she was cranking out kiddies almost as often as movies during this
period). She is appealing as always as the warm-hearted star of the
show whose good love may all be for naught. Give her credit too, for sharing the screen with a number of other
lovelies among the showgirls and entertainers at the club. Beautiful
brunette Danik Pattison gets almost as much screen time as Jayne as the
loner, secretive showgirl and she has a sensational faux strip number
set in a steamy train berth that still packs an erotic wallop. Barbara
Windsor is cast as the "jailbait" showgirl, "Ponytail", who wants to
grow up in the worst way. While Ms. Windsor is clearly not underage
like her character, she effectively captures the simplistic foolishness
of someone too young to understand the big picture. Ms. Pattison went
on to have a career in the French film industry that lasted into the
1970's, Ms. Windsor later became quite well-known in England for her
work in the "Carry on..." films and television programs and is still
active today in the series "East Enders".British star Leo Genn is very effective as the James Cagney-tough club
owner while Christopher Lee does well as his right-hand man. The movie
was filmed and released in Eastman Color but video and DVD prints are
regrettably black and white. It was fairly common for B&amp;W prints to be
struck of color films to be shown on television during the 1960's and
1970's for local stations. Surely color prints of this movie must exist
somewhere, hopefully eventually one will find it's way to DVD. This
movie is a low-key effort but it still interesting and actually has a
lot to offer with a fine performance by Genn, the warmth and glamour of
Mansfield, and a number of other beautiful young women on parade in
various stages of dress.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1813853/comments</url><from>from Southeastern US</from><name>thekettleblack</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

If you've seen Jayne in her two most successful movies ("Will Success
Spoil
Rock Hunter" and "The Girl Can't Help It"), it might be easy to dismiss
her
as a one-trick pony. However, she's startlingly good in her best dramatic
role as a clubowner's girlfriend in "Too Hot To Handle". I'm still looking
for the plot in this movie (if there even is one), but Jayne steals the
show
(her motherly talk to mixed-up, ambitious Ponytail played by Barbara
Windsor
is one of the best moments in Jayne's career). She also demonstrates her
singing and dancing skills in a couple of cute musical numbers (watch for
her ridiculously long cigarette holder, her see-through gown with
strategically placed beaded fringe, and a baffling feathered swimsuit).
After seeing this movie, it's hard to believe anyone ever called Jayne
Mansfield "the poor man's Marilyn Monroe". 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0445867/comments</url><from/><name>cableguy-5</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The plot concerns the owner of the "Pink Flamingo" club and his battles
with
rival club owners and the police.  Christopher Lee has a small role, but
the
main attraction for most viewers would probably be Jayne Mansfield, who
surprisingly, is very good in her role as the club owners girlfriend.  She
has a big musical number and you'll wonder how they squeezed her into some
of the tightest costumes you'll ever see.      
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3611732/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>hilljayne</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Jayne is at her loveliest and most voluptuous and demonstrates great
acting in this fast paced, suspenseful drama. Her costumes are great
and she acts incredible. We are even given 2 great musical numbers.
Don't believe those rumours that she couldn't act, she demonstrates
great ability far surpassing Marilyn Monroe's in this thriller. My only
complaint is that it is in black and white. I recently got a big screen
TV and this was the first film I viewed on it and Jayne looks
sensational! You can really appreciate all of her ASSETS in this pic!
Highly recommended to NEW Jayne fans. Will also be of interest to those
curiosity seekers of Jayne. Much more fun than THE GIRL CAN'T HELP IT
in my opinion.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11238641/comments</url><from>from Montreal Canada</from><name>titanicflint</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
For those who think that Jayne Mansfield's career was nothing more than
an overblown publicity stunt I boldly state they should at least see
this before making any final judgments. I too started watching this
with a fair amount of skepticism, and yet I was blown right out of the
water by both Jayne and the movie. Both are a lot better than I was
anticipating. This is the best Mansfield performance I've ever seen.
She is perfectly cast in the role of Midnight Franklin. She makes the
character all too human, and all too believable. The movie itself is
fast-paced, packing a lot into its 93 minutes. It's also well-acted by
everyone involved, and very well-directed. It's intriguing and holds
your interest. It has the air of a good Warner Brothers gangster film,
as well as a definite film-noir feel to it. I don't know what happened
to the color prints of this, but, in my opinion it's the sort of movie
that actually plays better in black-and-white. And Jayne's musical
numbers are always worth seeing. I definitely recommend this one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5971012/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ferbs54</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
A perfect example of a film whose sum is far less than its parts, "Too
Hot to Handle" (1960) proved to be a real letdown for me. On paper, the
film would seem to have a lot going for it: Jayne Mansfield playing a
stripper in a seedy London club; a moustachioed Christopher Lee as the
club's manager, who is plotting against the owner/boss (Leo Genn) with
the rival strip club owner across the street; Carl Boehm (so memorable
in that same year's "Peeping Tom") as a French reporter doing a story
on the club; AND direction by Terence Young, who in the next five years
would go on to helm three out of the first four Bond films.
Unfortunately, it doesn't work, although the multiple plot threads
(rival strip joints, Jayne's infatuation with her boss, an underage
dancer) keep things spinning along. Jayne does get to perform two sexy
and amusing musical numbers, and acts decently enough, but even her
assets aren't enough to float this picture. (In truth, she looks pretty
matronly during most of the film.) Part of the problem, for me, is the
level of tawdry sleaziness on display, with repeated shots of Brit
businessmen ogling at the dancers, who have only stripped down to their
skivvies. (No nudity at this club, it seems.) Worse for me was the
quality of the DVD itself that I just watched. It would seem that the
source for this DVD was a crummy 16mm print, and with lousy sound.
Heavy British accents PLUS lousy sound make for an exasperating and
difficult cinematic experience. (Potential viewers should also be aware
that, despite the Maltin book's claim that this is a color film, it is
in truth black &amp; white.) Perhaps if the DVD had looked and sounded a
bit better, I might have enjoyed the film more, sleazy and cheesy as it
is. But I still wouldn't have thought it was, um, too hot.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
What a shocker! Who knew that Jayne Mansfield could actually pull off a
role that required some real acting? No, she's no threat to knock
Ingrid Bergman off of anyone's top actress list, but she's surprisingly
good in Too Hot to Handle. It's quite a change of pace from her roles
that I'm more familiar with. Mansfield is definitely much more than the
blond sex-kitten I had thought.The other "names" in the cast are Leo Genn and Christopher Lee. Genn is
his usual solid self. In fact, I can't remember seeing Genn in anything
where he wasn't solid. It's a shame this man isn't better known by the
general public. Being something of a Christopher Lee completist, Lee is
the reason I wanted to see Too Hot to Handle in the first place. But
other than introducing a few dancers, he really doesn't do much.As for the movie, it's a total melodrama with one cliché after the
next. It may be listed as "Crime" on IMDb, but the crime elements have
very little to do with the actual plot. And, it's dull. Who would have
thought that a movie with Jayne Mansfield working in a strip club could
be so boring. I didn't care if Genn lost his club. I didn't care if
Mansfield got her man. I didn't care if there was an underage girl
working in the club. I didn't care about any of it. All I wanted was
for the thing to end.There's a sub-plot in the movie involving a dancer who is in the
country illegally and the writer who falls for and wants to help her.
Their story is the most interesting thing in the movie and keeps me
from rating the movie any lower. Unfortunately, this sub-plot goes
nowhere.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
What a shocker! Who knew that Jayne Mansfield could actually pull off a
role that required some real acting? No, she's no threat to knock
Ingrid Bergman off of anyone's top actress list, but she's surprisingly
good in Too Hot to Handle. It's quite a change of pace from her roles
that I'm more familiar with. Mansfield is definitely much more than the
blond sex-kitten I had thought.The other "names" in the cast are Leo Genn and Christopher Lee. Genn is
his usual solid self. In fact, I can't remember seeing Genn in anything
where he wasn't solid. It's a shame this man isn't better known by the
general public. Being something of a Christopher Lee completist, Lee is
the reason I wanted to see Too Hot to Handle in the first place. But
other than introducing a few dancers, he really doesn't do much.As for the movie, it's a total melodrama with one cliché after the
next. It may be listed as "Crime" on IMDb, but the crime elements have
very little to do with the actual plot. And, it's dull. Who would have
thought that a movie with Jayne Mansfield working in a strip club could
be so boring. I didn't care if Genn lost his club. I didn't care if
Mansfield got her man. I didn't care if there was an underage girl
working in the club. I didn't care about any of it. All I wanted was
for the thing to end.There's a sub-plot in the movie involving a dancer who is in the
country illegally and the writer who falls for and wants to help her.
Their story is the most interesting thing in the movie and keeps me
from rating the movie any lower. Unfortunately, this sub-plot goes
nowhere.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>