<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Make Mine Mink</original_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Robert Asher</director><producer>Rank Organisation, The</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
Zany collection of misfits led by aging military man (Terry-Thomas) go on a spree of robbing mink coats...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Terry-Thomas</actor><actor>Athene Seyler</actor><actor>Hattie Jacques</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2232026/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon</from><name>Greg Couture</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
For no reason I can fathom, this title recently popped into the disordered
clutter of my memory.  I haven't seen it since those halcyon days in
Southern California, before multiplexes, when admission prices were
affordable on a frequent basis, and when the area where I lived had theaters
that booked all sorts of films from all over the globe, or so it seemed. 
It's one of the few films I went back to see almost immediately, since the
uproarious laughter it provoked obscured some of the dialogue during my
first viewing.Terry-Thomas and his female partners-in-crime are truly hilarious and, for
me, the special bonus of two of my favorite British character actresses,
Irene Handl and Hattie Jacques, appearing in a film together, made this one
of those gems I'll never forget.  The slapstick elements are handled with
that special brand of wit for which English comedies are noted and the
modest production values actually enhanced the fun.  I note that it's not
currently available from American purveyors to the U.S. video market, but a
DVD is offered in the U.K.  Guess it's time to discover what's involved in
exchange rates, international shipping, and so forth.  It should prove worth
the effort to renew a happy memory.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0406825/comments</url><from>from Lyon, France</from><name>Marya Berry (maryaberry@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Saw MMM more than 300 times (yes!) because it has enough in it to amuse,
interest and make you wish you lived with these zany, big-hearted misfits.
Bored, would-be good-doers, Dame Bea and her lodgers get caught up in just
the opposite when excitement turns up unexpectedly on their front doorstep
(literally).  Then, there's no stopping them--altho they do bungle nearly
every heist.  Yes, they must (à la Robin Hood) steal from the rich to give
to the poor. And poor Lily, the ex-inside maid, trying to stay on the good
side!The actors, all lovable, eccentric characters, are too good to be true,
with special kudos to the female quartet (Athene Seyler, Hattie Jacques,
Elspeth Duxbury, Billie Whitelaw--in the flower of youth and yet already
on
her brilliant way to HER BRILLIANT CAREER) and their grumbling but more
than
willing hero (Terry-Thomas).  Picture the latter in gangster attire in
front
of a sleeze bar--better than the entire scene inside it!  Or Elspeth being
"attacked" in her bath (Oh, how she wishes!) by a
couldn't-be-further-from-his-mind!
Or, maybe best of all, a stunning, long-haired blond, high-heeled Hattie
Jacques (that's right) just AFTER her firebomb goes off in a plush fur
shop
in the Kensington District of London. But there are SO MANY perfect scenes
in this nearly perfect film (after 300 times you pick up 3 or 4 technical
bloopers, but who cares?), it is impossible to single them out without
telling the whole film.My only question is:  Why isn't it a FILM CLASSIC?Marya Berry, Film Buff and Critic
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2876002/comments</url><from>from March (or Die), ENGLAND</from><name>johnson50</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Very odd film. The sort of film that only the British could
make.Terry-Thomas is cast out of his usual flash, boisterous role as the
rather
timid Major Rayne, down on his luck and living in a boarding house with
the
weirdest collection of women you're ever likely to see, including a very
young Billie Whitelaw and a masterful Hattie Jacques.By pure mischance, they embark on a campaign of fur robbery in order to
support their landlady's charitable work. The film is a wonderful
caricature
of the down-at-heel gentry in Britain at that time, includes some very
endearing characters and is genuinely funny in its naive
fashion.Recommended to any fan of the wonderful Terry-Thomas and British comedies
of
this era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4676743/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>barleeku</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The last time I saw this film was about 40 years ago when I was a kid.
My sister and I would watch movies on Channels 9 and 11 in NYC and we
saw Make Mine Mink about 3 times, I figure. Since then, I have
unsuccessfully sought it in movie stores, like a man wistfully
returning to the haunts he frequented with his first love, hoping
against all odds to catch another glimpse of her. Part of my curiosity
is determining whether I would think it as funny today, and my sister
wonders the same thing. Terry Thomas was an absolute favorite of mine
back then, too, and I haven't seen anything of him on TV for a long
time. So what's this got to do with the movie itself? Well, it's just
that kind of film. There's such a combination of comedy, sweetness,
surprise, and intelligence in it that it sticks with you for a long
time. The combination of the odd British major living in a rooming
house with an extraordinary collection of women, the craziness of their
plans and the situations they get themselves into, and the smart
understating of the comedy that was such a British specialty before
they became so self-conscious about that particular gift, make it a
rarity in more ways than one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16161013/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>JohnRouseMerriottChard</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Make Mine Mink is based on Peter Coke's West End play Breath Of Spring.
The story centres around a group of odd-ball amateurs, who led by their
aging landlady Dame Beatrice Appleby {Athene Seyler}, venture into
crime by way of stealing valuable fur coats and then giving the
proceeds from their crimes to charity. Joining the eccentric Dame is a
has-been military officer {Terry-Thomas}, a larger than life etiquette
instructor {Hattie Jacques} and a batty china mender {Elspeth Duxbury}.
Oddly, and crucial to the plot of course, the house keeper is an
ex-convict {sexy Billie Whitelaw} who is not involved. Just as well
since her boyfriend is a Copper! This sets us up for a number of
delightful sequences as our "crims" blunder into one caper after
another, whilst trying to avoid capture by the increasingly baffled
police force. The film even has time to homage The Third Man in one
particularly funny scene as Thomas' Major Rayne goes in search of a
"fence" for their ill gotten gains.There are so many great things about Make Mine Mink, but what stands
out the most is that it's a testament to what good writing and a
quality cast can do for a basic premise. More known for being the
director of film's starring that bastion of Jerry Lewis a like British
comedy, Norman Wisdom, Robert Asher keeps it simple and lets the cast
run with the material. The pace never lets up and there is not one sign
of filler or awkward padding. Thomas is revelling in being the sole
male actor in the core group and both Jacques and Seyler light up the
screen regularly {look out for an hilarious smoke bomb moment from
Jacques}. But it's Duxbury's movie all the way, a relative unknown with
only 7 acting credits to her name {she passed away in 1967}, Duxbury
gives a performance of such high comedic quality, this film becomes a
fitting and lasting legacy to her name. As Pinkie she runs everywhere,
forgets everything and has all her co-criminals constantly in despair.
It's a truly joyous turn that for me personally has become a highlight
of my viewings this year.Available on Region 2 DVD, and part of the wonderful Terry-Thomas Box
Set, Make Mine Mink should hopefully now start getting more exposure.
It deserves it, a throwback to great British comedy days, and a film
that's sure to have you grinning from ear to ear. 8.5/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2788203/comments</url><from>from Paris, France</from><name>Colashwood</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Paris used to be the place where you can see all sorts of "rare" films.
But
how comes we
always have Man in the White Suit and Ladykillers when it comes to
British
comedy ? I
discovered Terry-Thomas in the Dr Phibes movies (IMDB kindly tells me
he's
showing as
well in that great French war classic, La Grande Vadrouille. How silly of
me) and, rather
charmed by the gap between the teeth, bought a Terry-Thomas DVD set in
London.
Mark that, readers ! It contains Make Mine Mink, Too Many Crooks and
Naked
Truth.
They're all very good but Make Mine Mink has the very special charm of
its
female cast,
from oddly beautiful Billie Whitelaw to wonderful Hattie Jacques (and a
special mention
to Penny Morrell in a faultless dumb blonde part). 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0643062/comments</url><from>from Virginia Beach</from><name>tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I liked this. I suggest you reserve it for a time when you want
something that isn't much work in viewing (which means that 1960 is
about the latest you can consider).The structure is a familiar one: we watch a bunch of actors portraying
unlikely characters who themselves play unlikely characters precisely
as far away. The joke of course is in the overlap, and the competence
of the first contrasted with the incompetence of the second. Its all
about coats and appropriation.There's an interesting performer here, one I haven't seen before. She
plays a painfully reserved spinster who's occupation is mending broken
china. Her character, Pinkie, is immensely inept and most of the
polished humor (this was a successful stage play) is hers. We are
introduced to her when the silly major breaks in on her bath because
she has extended into his time. This is moments after having the first long segment of the movie linger
on the sexy, pretty maid. And we see a naked skinny old maid in the
bath. The major is retired from his duty as commander of "portable
baths."That's the attention to detail you'll find in how this humor is
constructed.Anyway, Pinkie (with the wonderful name of Elspeth Duxbury) only lived
a few years after this. Too bad.Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3642561/comments</url><from>from new york</from><name>uszoni2003 (uszoni2003@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A n early 60's British "caper" film, that never fails to make me laugh,
whenever I get the rare pleasure of seeing it.Tery Thomas, and a cast comprised of mostly (hysterical) old women plot
to rob a bank.Where most movies today are not character driven, this little slice of
silliness shows the care that was once put into film, even in what
would've been considered a "B'" film.The comedy here is verbal, a little bit slapstick, and as such a lot
will pass you by if you don't pay attention. One of my favorite little
jokes involves a rather bosomy mature woman (who is quite obviously a
lesbian, but being as this is the early '60's, and also being England),
it is alluded too, rather than spoken. Her "job" is to "teach" young
debs(?) how to act like a lady.At one point one of her "pupils" leaves her "lesson," and the look she
gets from the "teacher" is hysterical. You know exactly what she's
thinking. Very few comedians excel at making you laugh simply with a
look (only two that come to mind are Lucille Ball and Molly Sugden-
from Are You Being Served?).The whole movie, which is relatively short will leave you with a smile
on your face, and fond recollections, which after all - isn't that what
a good movie should do?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15148330/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>calvinnme</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This film is the very definition of the word "droll", and is one of my
favorite comedies. The three residents of Dame Beatrice's rooming house
don't really have a place in the world, and Dame Beatrice herself is
upset that she isn't able to bring in the kind of money that she once
did for all of her favorite charities. They all feel that the world has
forgotten them until Lily, Dame Beatrice's maid, steals a mink from the
veranda of a man who has tried to give it to his wife to appease her
jealousy and his conscience over his extramarital affairs. Since Lily
has a criminal record, Beatrice and her tenants are afraid she will be
returned to jail, so they all work together to replace the mink without
the owners ever noticing it was missing. When they are successful they
realize it would probably be just as easy to steal furs as replace
stolen ones and use the proceeds for Beatrice's charities. This gives
all concerned a purpose in life, which is all they have been seeking.
The unlikely team of thieves makes many mistakes, but usually come away
with the furs, and only give up the game when Lily discovers what
they've been doing and makes them promise not to steal another fur.
However, a call to Dame Beatrice from someone seeking further
charitable contributions puts them back in action. However, they can't
continue to steal furs due to their promise to Lily. Thus, they turn
their attention to even bigger game at the end of the film.This film is a comedy completely without personal conflict - it is pure
comedy and farce from beginning to end. All involved work together for
the common good, and no selfish motives are ever seen, other than the
desire to be useful. You keep waiting for one of the members of the
little band of thieves to get greedy and want to keep at least some of
the money for themselves, but it never happens. At a time in American
cinema history when film noir was still popular, and crime dramas often
had no sympathetic characters, it is strange to watch a film from this
period in which all of the characters are sympathetic. This probably
has to do with the difference between American and British culture, and
also the period in British history in which this film was made. The
British had just come through a fifteen year period in history after
World War II in which they had attempted to remake British society, and
in many ways had fallen short of the mark. The gentry felt displaced,
but many of the common people didn't feel the inclusion they expected
this displacement to achieve. Thus there were several British films
from this period, such as "The Smallest Show on Earth", in which people
banded together to fulfill a common goal that achieved nothing more
than an affirmation of their own usefulness. This is one of those
films, and I find it not only funny, but completely charming.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0398791/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>howard-30</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Just saw it on TCM. It was much funnier than I expected. It is unusual
for a slapstick comedy to have so much sympathy for the characters. You
really get to like them. Even the love interest is well done. Its well
worth watching. Terry Thomas is superb. As good as I remembered him
from my misspent youth. The three women who worked with him were also
very good. I didn't remember any of them but will look for them in the
future. It is a shame that the wondrous tradition of British comedies
disappeared. From Guiness to Sellars to Margaret Rutherford. The Remake
of The Ladykillers proved just how good they were. It is amazing how
even a fine actor like Tom Hanks was unable to match the quality of the
original movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0398791/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>howard-30</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Just saw it on TCM. It was much funnier than I expected. It is unusual
for a slapstick comedy to have so much sympathy for the characters. You
really get to like them. Even the love interest is well done. Its well
worth watching. Terry Thomas is superb. As good as I remembered him
from my misspent youth. The three women who worked with him were also
very good. I didn't remember any of them but will look for them in the
future. It is a shame that the wondrous tradition of British comedies
disappeared. From Guiness to Sellars to Margaret Rutherford. The Remake
of The Ladykillers proved just how good they were. It is amazing how
even a fine actor like Tom Hanks was unable to match the quality of the
original movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0398791/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>howard-30</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>http://www.dvdtown.com/review/too-many-crooks--make-mine-mink/dvd/8965 /m/make_mine_mink/comments.php?reviewid=1977139</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
7/10
					</rating><comment>For the most part, the film is fun and funny, with Terry-Thomas at the top of his game.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117792883.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/make_mine_mink/comments.php?reviewid=1806703</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9E0CE4DE1531EF3ABC4851DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/make_mine_mink/comments.php?reviewid=1389886</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>