<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Bells Are Ringing</original_title><alt_title>Un numéro du tonnerre</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Vincente Minnelli</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Musical</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Ella Peterson is a Brooklyn telephone answering service operator who tries to improve the lives of her clients by passing along bits of information she hears from other clients...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Judy Holliday</actor><actor>Dean Martin</actor><actor>Fred Clark</actor><rt_rating>6.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>75</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239428/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name>harry-76</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Since the play, "Laurette," was never realized, the movie version of "Bells
are Ringing" serves as Judy Holliday's "final" performance.It's to her credit that she comes off as well as she does. The film is
extremely stagey, and looks contrived and bloated, despite a most competent
cast and director.Yet Holliday is buoyant, full of fun, and energetic--all hallmarks of her
theatrical persona.  I've read Holliday's complete bio, and am amazed she was able to overcome
the tremendous obstacles she endured, from her sad childhood and family
relationship through the communist "witch hunt" period--which left her
saddled with protest pickets that followed her around--to failed marriages,
lack of employment, and care giving responsibilities for her child and
parent. All the while working wherever she could and keep
smiling.In many respects her career is quite similar to that of Montgomery Clift. 
Both apparently gave their best work on the stage, night after night before
live audiences, rather than on film. Had both stayed in the theatre, their
respective careers and lives might have remained more stable and
healthy--and be alive today. "Bells are Ringing" is a final tribute to a great talent, an Oscar-winning
actress and comedienne who graced the stage and screen with a radiant
presence and winning demeanor.  Fortunately, as long as her films are shown,
Judy Holliday will live and be rediscovered by future generations.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"Bells are Ringing" is a must for Judy Holliday's fans. The bubbly star
of some of the best comedies of the fifties, is the main reason for
watching this musical, directed by Vincente Minnelli. Betty Comden and
Adolph Green were the creators of the book and lyrics with music by
Jule Styne.The film was an excuse for showcasing Ms. Holliday and Dean Martin, who
took over Sydney Chaplin's role. The two stars show an easy chemistry
in their scenes together, even though the transfer to the screen seems
somehow clumsy coming from an experienced director of musicals like Mr.
Minnelli."Bells are Ringing" is a nostalgic look at the New York of the 1950s.
It was quite a status symbol to have an answering service in those days
before the automatic devices of today. There is a hilarious second plot
involving illegal gambling by linking classical music works to the
different races in several horse race tracks that are channeled through
Susanswerphone service, which makes the police Ella is involved in the
scheme.Judy Holliday gave a tremendous performance in the film as the kind,
but somehow naive Ella. Dean Martin is fine also as the blocked writer.
In supporting roles Eddie Foy Jr., Jean Stapleton, and Dean Clark, are
seen among others.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

In contrast to the guy who wrote the comment on the main page in this board,
I saw this movie and I really enjoyed it.  I had never seen a Judy Holliday
movie before and I was totally taken in by her charm and good acting.  Dean
Martin (a favorite of mine) showed his usual suave personality and I thought
he was perfect for the role.  The songs and the choreography are excellent. 
I just love the mood of this movie and its message of healthy humanism,
whether or not it's something I really believe in.  I like the scene where
Judy and Dean say hello and introduce themselves to the man on the street. 
Also of note is Minnelli's smart direction.  One of the best musicals of the
60s, sadly one of the last.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1190980/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>petershelleyau</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Judy Holliday originated the role of Ella Petersen, the Susanwersphone
switchboard operator, in Vincente Minnelli's adaptation of the Broadway
musical, with music by Jules Styne and book and lyrics by Betty Comden and
Adolph Green. Although filmed in 1960, this musical belongs to the
conventions of the 1950's with a brassy orchestration, superfluous
supporting cast for comic relief, and a Brando impersonator. That Holliday
remains as the best thing about it, in spite of Minnelli's less flattering
treatment of her than George Cukor, is a tribute to her gifts as an actress,
in particular a Broadway performer with the subtlety to adapt for film
acting. Holliday's two solo numbers - It's a Perfect Relationship and I'm Going Back
- are triumphs of personal charm, in spite of the director. Minnelli has
trouble de-staging the switchboard environment and the film only comes to
life after Holliday leaves it to meet Dean Martin, as her favourite client,
in person. In the Better than a Dream number, where both Holliday and Martin
sing oblivious to the other's reality, this is Minnelli finally presenting a
musical sequence cinematically. This pattern continues with Martin's funny I
Met a Girl, sung as he battles street crowds. Minnelli treats Holliday's
plaintive ballad The Party's Over simply, if disappointedly in long and
medium shot presumably since he thinks Holliday's voice doesn't deserve a
closeup, in contrast to the botched Just in Time, the score's most lovely
song, wretchedly staged. The Drop That Name number is probably more about
Minnelli than Holliday, since he scores points off her, comparing her
perceived frumpiness to the vacuous stereotypical 1950's society
vamp.Holliday and Martin play off each other well, overcoming the oddness of
their union. Martin actually looks not at his best, which undermines the
romantic appeal, and his solo reveals he shouldn't be given one. It's hard
not to consider his character's fear of success without his partner and not
have thoughts of Jerry Lewis, though believing Martin as a playwright is
trouble enough. Thankfully there's Holliday. Far more likeable and
individual than say a Doris Day, Minnelli's having her lower her head for
pathos is the lowest appreciation of her potential. This wasn't considered a
great musical to begin with, and the film is pretty hard to take whenever
the supporting players take over, with excruciating bits featuring Eddie Foy
and The Titanic record company, vice squad surveillance, and the mafia,
however the songwriting dentist gave me a few chuckles.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Judy Holliday gained Broadway stardom and entry into Hollywood with her
performance as Billie Dawn in BORN YESTERDAY. She also would score on
Broadway for the last time in the musical THE BELLS ARE RINGING. I find
it amazing, given the paucity of her film career, that these two stage
performances were preserved, while so many great stage performances (of
Ethel Merman, Mary Martin, Ethel Waters) failed to get preserved in the
Hollywood system. Obviously the saleability of Holliday in 1960 was
higher than that of Merman (even after ANNIE GET YOUR GUN), most likely
due to her Oscar. One can only be grateful to providence or whatever
for coming to Holliday's aid here - one wishes it could have stepped up
for the others more often.THE BELLS ARE RINGING was directed by Vincent Minelli, and has some
great musical numbers in it: Eddie Foy's "It's a Simple Little System"
where his record sales mask a bookie operation, culminating in a mock
song spiel of serious music lovers singing the names of race courses to
the "Hallelujah" Chorus; the "Drop that Name" number at Fred Clark's
party, wherein the only name of a celebrity Judy can recall is Rin Tin
Tin; the "Just in Time" song and dance by Dean Martin and Judy Holliday
in a mini-park, and it's follow-up of "The Party's Over", probably
Judy's best sung tune in her career. Not all the show's tunes are in
the movie. Eddie Foy sings a song to Jean Stapleton (Sue of Sue's
Answer Phone) to romance her with his mock European elegance - the song
is called "Salzberg by the Sea" which shows how phony he really is
(Salzberg is in the center of landlocked Austria!).The film is well set in it's period, in two odd ways. One is a gag in
the story: Frank Gorshin as method actor Blake Barton, who is an
obvious spoof of Marlon Brando. The other is the appearance of Dean
Martin as Jeffrey Moss, the troubled composer hero of the musical who
romances Ella Peterson (Judy). In the Broadway production it was Hal
Linden who played opposite Judy (he appears in this film, in his first
film role, singing the song "The Midas Touch" at a nightclub). But
Martin was a nationally known singer, and movie star. But he was, in
real life, facing a situation exactly like Jeffrey Moss. Moss (before
the story of the show begins) has been in a successful theater team,
like Gilbert and Sullivan or Rodgers and Hammerstein...or like Martin
and Lewis. In fact, Moss's partner just broke up the partnership (and
is doing well on his own - like Lewis did at first). Moss's funk is
what the public in 1960 thought Martin had faced a few years earlier
when Lewis split with him.The movie showcases Judy's comic talents, as she stimulates Martin,
Gorshin, Bernie West (the musically inclined Dr. Kitchell), confronts
Dort Clarke (the ambitious Inspector Barnes), and aids a desperate Otto
when threatened by hoods. She handles the situations well, reminding us
of how talented a lady she was. It was a fitting conclusion to her
career - but a sad reminder that that career deserved to be far longer
than it was.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2030420/comments</url><from/><name>perfectbond</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Fans of Dean Martino and Judy Holliday (né Tuvim) will enjoy this musical.
I
am a fan of both of them so I could overlook the awkward staging of the
Susanswerphone set, the believeability of Maritn as a writer and the dead
weight of the subplot involving the racketeers. Still there are some
well-sung songs and good, if not great chemistry, between the stars. For
non-fans: 6/10. For fans: 7/10. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0568099/comments</url><from/><name>marcslope</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Made late in the cycle of great MGM musicals, with the reliable
producer-director combo of Arthur Freed and Vincente Minnelli, this is a
fairly clunky adaptation of a Broadway hit. Despite some location filming,
it looks stagebound, and the stylized playing and jerrybuilt musical-comedy
plot look false as hell. Some excellent musical numbers from the original
are badly truncated or left out entirely, and what's left is grotesquely
over-orchestrated. One senses that Minnelli, in particular, didn't trust the
material--look at how quickly he dispenses with the "Mu-Cha-Cha" number,
seemingly embarrassed by its musical-comedy silliness--and the supporting
cast seems to be playing to the second balcony.That's the bad news; now we get, thank heaven, to Judy Holliday. Having
played this part on Broadway for two years and toured with it longer, she
looks amazingly spontaneous. Given her health problems at the time, she
looks happy and healthy. And while we can't expect to experience her
legendary warmth and charisma as stage audiences did, it's an incomparable
performance. Every reaction, every inflection, every seemingly improvised
movement rings true and lends depth and poignancy to a paper-thin character
traipsing around in a contrived plot. What a lesson for any young actor in
transforming everyday material into something memorable. My favorite moment
comes early, when she's reclining on a sofa and looks up dreamily and starts
singing, a capella and with perfect naturalism, "I'm in love..." I'm in
love, too, Judy. We miss you.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5770688/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>Nick Zegarac (movieman-200)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Vincente Minnelli's "Bells Are Ringing" (1960) generally gets a bad
wrap from reviewers and critics alike. While it is true that the film
came at the tail end of MGM's reign of supremacy in musical motion
picture entertainment – and it is equally true that the film falls
short by direct comparison to, say, Minnelli's "Meet Me In St. Louis
(an unfair but often used example), all the pistons are firing on this
occasion with this delightful story of a phone operator who falls in
love with one of her clients.The story concerns lonely Ella Peterson (Judy Holliday in her final
performance). Working out of a basement apartment for Susan's-a-phone
(a personal message service), Ella longs for the good life and the
right fella to fill her needs. However, that doesn't prevent her plucky
personality from offering equal portions of good advice and smart talk
to her roster of happy clients. Ella's fraternization doesn't
particularly sit well with her employer, Sue (Jean Stapleton) who is
all dollars and cents, or police detective, Barnes (Dort Clark) who
advises Ella that it's illegal to provide unsolicited information in
the capacity of a business acquaintance. But Ella is all set to throw
caution to the wind when she falls in love with Plaza 0-double four,
double nine. That extension belongs to Jeffrey Moss (Dean Martin), a
once successful playwright who fears that his days of popularity are
numbered and has since turned to shallow women and hollow relationships
for solace.Screenwriters Betty Comden and Adolph Green transform their Broadway
original into a sublime cinematic treat. Minnelli directs adroitly and
– given the limited budget he had to work with – delivers a film that
appears to be on a much grander scale than it actually is. Particularly
in his execution of the "Drop that Name" sequence – in which Ella
lampoons her association with the hoi polloi, Minnelli's brisk camera
work and staging is flawless. The same is true during Eddy Foy Jr.'s
charming romp in "Oh, What A System". Delivered with comedic panache
and laconic savvy a la the darling Holliday and charming Martin, the
rest of the score, including such standards as "Just in Time" and "Drop
That Name" is brilliant and bouncy.Thanks to Warner's stunning new transfer, "Bells are Ringing" arrives
'just in time' on DVD. The anamorphically enhanced Cinemascope image is
outstanding. Colors are nicely balanced. Image quality is a marked
improvement over anything this film has looked like before on home
video. Blacks are rich, deep and solid. Whites are crisp, but never
blooming. There is a hint of film grain and the occasional shimmer of
fine detail but nothing that will distract you from wallowing in the
riotous splendor of this musical classic. The audio has been impeccably
remastered in 5.1 and delivers an unexpectedly powerful kick during the
songs. The one disappointment for admirers of this film is that the
featurette on the film "Just in Time" is way too short to be considered
a valid supplement. Others include two outtake musical sequences made
available previously, and the film's theatrical trailer. Regardless of
these shortcomings, "Bells Are Ringing" comes highly recommended as
great good time fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0395493/comments</url><from>from Pine Bluff, Ark.</from><name>bianca-13</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I found Bells Are Ringing accidentally when I was researching another film
project and it has become a favorite. While Holliday is sparkling in her
role, it is Martin's low-key reactions (which are, of course, what made
him
such a great straight man) that send me back to watch the film again and
again. It's a "don't-miss" for fans of Holliday, Martin and the musical
comedy - heavy on the comedy - genre.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
If I really loved musicals, I would have probably scored the movie a 9.
In fact, that I scored it as high as an 8 is an indication that, for
the genre, it was a heck of a film. That's because the story apart from
the songs is very sweet and romantic. Plus, the actors are so appealing
and good that this certainly improved the film a lot. Judy Holliday was
at her best and Dean Martin certainly was able to keep up with her and
I really liked him more in this musical than as a comedian. Despite
films like MATT HELM, he was a good actor and singer. Now, concerning
the songs, it's rare that I have seen a musical with so many songs I
have never heard before! But, after hearing them, I liked them a lot
more than many of the more famous Rogers and Hammerstein musical scores
from other pictures. This is because in addition to having nice music,
the words were so often funny and charming. I particularly liked the
song all the bookies sang as well as the name-dropping song! They were
terrific.The only thing is that watching the film I felt pretty depressed, as I
knew that this was Ms. Holliday's last film--cancer limited her ability
to act until she eventually succumbed six years later. It's a shame, as
I loved her in so many wonderful films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
If I really loved musicals, I would have probably scored the movie a 9.
In fact, that I scored it as high as an 8 is an indication that, for
the genre, it was a heck of a film. That's because the story apart from
the songs is very sweet and romantic. Plus, the actors are so appealing
and good that this certainly improved the film a lot. Judy Holliday was
at her best and Dean Martin certainly was able to keep up with her and
I really liked him more in this musical than as a comedian. Despite
films like MATT HELM, he was a good actor and singer. Now, concerning
the songs, it's rare that I have seen a musical with so many songs I
have never heard before! But, after hearing them, I liked them a lot
more than many of the more famous Rogers and Hammerstein musical scores
from other pictures. This is because in addition to having nice music,
the words were so often funny and charming. I particularly liked the
song all the bookies sang as well as the name-dropping song! They were
terrific.The only thing is that watching the film I felt pretty depressed, as I
knew that this was Ms. Holliday's last film--cancer limited her ability
to act until she eventually succumbed six years later. It's a shame, as
I loved her in so many wonderful films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/bellsareringing.htm /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1844415</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>Has too much plot and not enough music or comedy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=13899 /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1834385</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Minnelli's last collaboration with Arthur Freed is an old-fashioned, moderately entertaining musical that suffers from lack of chemistry between Judy Holliday and Dean Martin.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/minn.htm#Bells /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1748058</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Inventive, emotionally involving and visually stylish musical.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/douglas-pratt/</url><url>/m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1526533</url><name>Douglas Pratt</name><from>DVDLaser</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>a wonderful film</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1490935</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>One of Hollywood's last old-fashioned Broadway adaptations, with Holliday as endearing as ever. Not exactly Minnelli's finest, but well worth catching for musicals fans.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeremiah-kipp/</url><url>http://www.slantmagazine.com/film/film_review.asp?ID=1488 /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1369642</url><name>Jeremiah Kipp</name><from>Slant Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
1.5/4
					</rating><comment>Never translates into anything cinematic. </comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1258763</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>One of the most undervalued of musicals.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1263888</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-mermelstein/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117499760.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1807376</url><name>David Mermelstein</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/67596/bells_are_ringing.html /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1476235</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=101006 /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1146218</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/881_BELLS_ARE_RINGING.html /m/bells_are_ringing/comments.php?reviewid=1897</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>