<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La maschera del demonio</original_title><alt_title>Le masque du démon</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Mario Bava</director><producer>Alta Vista Productions</producer><producer>Galatea Film</producer><producer>Jolly Film</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
A vengeful witch and her fiendish servant return from the grave and begin a bloody campaign to possess the body of the witch's beautiful look-alike descendant...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Barbara Steele</actor><actor>John Richardson</actor><actor>Andrea Checchi</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7584010/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Stephanie Bishop (FrankensteinsDaughter@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
For some unknown reason, here recently I've been in the mood to watch a
lot of vintage 1960s-70s Italian horror movies. Hardly any other film
comes as highly recommended as Black Sunday and after viewing this
incredibly moody effort, I can easily see why. It's by far one of the
most beautifully photographed films I've seen of any genre. It's also
one of the most atmospheric; a sense of horror and dread hang over
every frame, and yet it is a film whose power does not lie entirely in
the narrative. It's hidden somewhere, pretty much everywhere... in dark
corners, in secret crypts, in fog, in shadows... The shots in this film
are brilliantly composed. It is a true triumph for director and
cinematographer Mario Bava, who provides such rich, dream-like
technical depth that (pardon the cliché) this film truly does transport
viewers somewhere else in time.Even though this movie is best appreciated as an exercise in style and
technique, the plot line (witch who is executed and returns centuries
later to get revenge on the descendants of her executioners) is also
enjoyable. So is Barbara Steele, who is ideally cast in a dual role as
both the evil witch and the pure heroine. She's an actress who can
switch from innocent and ravishing to hideous and horrific with the
flick of an eyelash. No wonder she's considered the queen of horror.
She deserves to be.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7790394/comments</url><from>from Leiden, The Dutch Mountains</from><name>Camera Obscura</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
BLACK Sunday (Mario Bava - Italy 1960).Mario Bava's first feature as a director (although he did uncredited
directorial work before), this classic and extremely influential piece
of Gothic horror really showed his cinematographic talent in creating a
haunting and stylishly shot film. "Black Sunday" also catapulted
Barbara Steele to horror stardom and would make her into the undisputed
horror queen of the sixties. Bava based "Mask of Satan", as the film
was originally titled, on the short story "Vij" by the Russian author
Gogol, which he adapted into a homage to the early Universal horror
pictures he loved so much. Barbara Steele is the beautiful 17th century
witch princess Asa, who is a vampire, and her lover Juvato (Arturo
Dominici), are put to death by her vengeful brother. He has iron masks
with spikes on the inside placed on both their faces and then
sledgehammered home (the brutal opening scene). Two hundred years
later, blood is accidentally spilled on Asa's face and she rises from
the dead along with Juvato to wreak revenge on the descendants of those
who executed her - including her look-alike Katia, also played by
Barbara Steele.Beautifully shot in black and white by Bava himself, "Black Sunday" is
a perfect showcase of his masterful control of light and shade, of
colour and movement (yes, one can play with "shades of colour" in black
and white) and playful camera angles, it's a feast for the eye. At
heart Bava would always remain the cinematographer he always was and in
all his films he took an active role in the design of each image by
setting up the lighting, the optical effects, the filters etc. The film
abounds in old-fashioned horror atmosphere and in that department, it
even manages to top the atmosphere of the Universal horror classics it
was based on with gnarled tree branches, fogbound sets, a decaying
castle, a dark foreboding crypt and much more.Of course, Bava's is well known for letting stylistic innovations take
precedent over storytelling and most other things involved, like
acting. Much of the script was reworked during shooting and even in
post-production. Barbara Steele reportedly never even saw a script and
got some pages every day of shooting. Variations of the story has been
told many times in one way or another and there are more than a few
echoes of Murnau's Nosferatu here. Much of the story is too derivative
to begin with, and has become too formularised in subsequent years to
retain much of its original power, just as the film's capacity to scare
or excite audiences has probably worn out a little over the years. It
doesn't really matter, because the film was chopped to pieces for over
four decades and the habit of Italian filmmakers of post-synchronizing
all the voices (even for Italian versions) made anything in that
department a pretty dire affair anyway.What Bava added however was some substantially more explicit violence
and gore, laced with sexual connotations. The opening scene in which
the mask is sledgehammered to Barbara Steele's face still packs quite a
wallop, not to mention the effect it must have had on audiences back
then. Still, horror fans can't really afford to miss this
quintessential Bava piece, but watch it for the splendid cinematography
and Bava's unique ways of visual wizardry.Camera Obscura --- 7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

"The sound that you hear is dripping blood. This...is the beginning of Black
Sunday !!" ...These two very atmospheric and mood-setting sentences are
heard when the Black Sunday DVD is put into the player. No need to tell you
that a better and more tense opening has yet to be created. This movie is an
undeniable masterpiece in its kind. A powerful and terrifying experience
that was way ahead of its time back in 1960 and now - almost 45 years later
- it still stands for an hour and a half of pure terror, devlish fun and
sinister fascination. I respect the opinion and dislikes of everyone but not
when it comes to this movie...you either admit that Black Sunday is a
masterpiece or you're wrong !!I could give you a thousand reasons why this movie should be seen as the
most important horror movie ever made but I'll just stick to the most
important ones. Black Sunday ( or The Mask of Satan, as you prefer ) is the
debut of Italian genius Mario Bava...Well, not really his debut but the
first full length movie after a series of short films and project he didn't
get credit for. In it, Bava presents us on a stylish and visually stunning
story with an extremely macabre and dark topic. It contains passages of
torturement, curses, witchburning, vampirism, massacres and resurrection but
it's all brought to us in a very artistic fashion. Bava's profesionalism and
style reminds me about the true masterpieces from Universal...Maybe also
because the whole movie is filmed in beautiful black and white but merely
because of the creepy atmosphere and the morbid topics. Black Sunday does
contain rather many violent and sadistic scenes, but it becomes unwatchable
or disgusting. Actually, when you look closer at it...it's a fairy tale !!
Think about it...: evil witch, ominous castles, dark forests and - on top of
it all - a tale of true love at first sight !
Barbara Steele should get as least as much credit and praise though. This
stunning beauty can easily considered "Queen of Horror" if it were only for
her performance here. Steele has a double role here ( the evil, vampiric
Prinses Asa and the virgin Katia ) and her appearance can only be seen as on
of beauty and pureness. Barbara Steele - once spit out by the glory of
Hollywood - succeeds in convincing the audience that she stars as both an
innocent virgin as well as a demonic ancient witch. The cinematic value
attached to her character comes extremely close to Karloff's Frankenstein
and Lugosi's Count Dracula. After all, Princess Asa was the first true
female monster and she has - literally - become immortal.You're not a horror fan if you haven't seen the perfection of Black
Sunday...I give this movie a very well deserved rating 10 out of
10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0605857/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>marquis de cinema</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

La Maschera del Demonio/The Mask of Satan(1960) is the film that
introduced
audiences around the world to the cinema of Mario Bava.  Responsible for
being the first horror film to have a formidable evil female villain.  Its
about a dead witch who returns from the dead with her lover to terrorize
the
descendents of their executioners.  Translitional picture that predates
the
broodish and moody style of Night of the Living Dead(1968).  Tim Burton
has
cited this movie as one of his favorites.After years as Assistent Director and Director of Photography, Bava was
rewarded with his first full directorial assignment and the results are
impressive.  Mario Bava was a talented filmmaker with a love for the fine
arts of Europe and Russian literature.  He didn't direct full time until
he
was in his late 40s.  Mario Bava's influences as a film director were
Riccardo Freda and Freda and Fritz Lang.  Nikolai Gogol is a writer that
along with Edgar Allen Poe played a major influence on Bava's supernatural
tales.One theme that is present in The Mask of Satan(1960) is the decay and
decline of a once happy and powerful family{more fully explored in Bava's
later films of Black Sabbath(1963), Whip and the Body(1964), Lisa and the
Devil(1974), and Shock(1977)}.  Deals with the notion of the
inescapability
of fate that is an important theme in Bava's work.  An example of this
motif
comes from Barbara Stelle with her line:"Here is the Very image of my
life".
Mario Bava was a fatalistic filmmaker who used imagery to convey his
beliefs in destiny or fate.  Part of his fatalistic style comes from him
experiences and memories of WW2.Some of the special effects are amazing for a film of this caliber.  Mario
Bava was a genius in creating special effects with only his creative soul
and imagination.  Makes one wonder what great special effects he could
create with a modest budget.  The gore effects although spread out in
small
pieces are gruesome for 1960.  Proves that great special effects don't
necessarily have to be done with mega dollars.The opening scene of the execution of Asa is a stunning combination of
atmosphere and violent imagery.  Barbara Stelle along with Christopher
Lee,
Peter Cushing, and Vincent Price are some of the greatest icons in 1960s
to
1970s horror films.  Many movie makers in horror films were influenced by
the opening scene.  Certain parts of the atmospheric opening can be seen
as
one inspiration for the prologue of Lucio Fulci's L'Aldila/The
Beyond(1981).
A special moment in horror cinema.The Mask of Satan(1960) came about as a result of the success of the Curse
of Frankenstein(1957) and Horror of Dracula(1958) in Italy.  Mixes the old
fashion horror of Univerisal Studios with the graphic violence of Hammer
horror.  The Hammer and Universal horror films are responsible for the
birth
of horror in Post war Italian cinema.  There are a couple of scenes that
are
obviously influenced by Horror of Dracula(1958).  The fact that Mario Bava
did this based on the success of Horror of Dracula(1958) must have
influenced Terence Fisher to respond to directing Dracula:Prince of
Darkness(1966).The Mask of Satan(1960) isn't interested in plot and story as much as
atmosphere and painting style visuals.  Mario Bava took the barebones
material of the film and turned it into something magnificent.  Mario
Bava's
direction has the look of a great artist.  Setting up atmosphere, dread,
mood, and terror were some of Bava's strengths.  His experiences as a
cinematographer really pays dividends in Bava's direction.A significant influence was placed on La Maschera del Demonio by the first
Italian horror film of the sound era, I Vamipri(1956).  A few references
are
made to I Vampiri(1956) especially in the discovery of a dead body near
the
river bank.  Also, the aging effect in Mask of Satan(1960) comes from
Bava's
work on I Vampiri.  Italian filmmaker, Riccardo Freda was the major
influence behind Bava's films and the main directorial mentor of Mario
Bava.
The romantic subplot of The Mask of Satan(1960) also derieves from I
Vampiri(1956).Has some of the best set designs in a low budget horror film.  Mario Bava
would use some of the set for his late 1960s horror classic Kill Baby
Kill(1967).  Amazing that Mario Bava could put together grandeur looking
art
and set designs with so little.  He also contributed to the dazzling
cinematography.  Mario Bava used many of the film's motifs and themes for
The Whip and the Body(1964).La Maschera del Demonio/The Mask of Satan(1960) is based loosely on a
short
story by Gogol called the Viy.  An interesting note on the making of The
Mask of Satan(1960) is that Bava made changes thoughout production because
of uncertainities about the screenplay.  Its one of the best horror films
of
the last fifty years.  The camera moves with a smooth feel typical of a
Mario Bava phtographed feature.  This is an item that many aspiring horror
filmmakers should watch in order to see how a great horror film should be
done.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0943351/comments</url><from>from West Hollywood, CA USA</from><name> (csdietrich@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

BLACK SUNDAY is not merely equal to the best of Murnau, Whale, Freund and
the Universal Pictures canon but surpasses all contenders with M.C.
Escheresque visuals informed with the dark poetry of stylish sadism.
Barbara
Steele imbues her portrayal of the vampire/witch with a demonic majesty
never before brought to the screen. Indeed, her visage a landscape of
puncture wounds bearing forth wild, burning eyes and thick, cruel lips
(promising the joys of eternal Hell) evokes the very standard of Italian
fantascienza of the Sixties. The genius of Mario Bava is celebrated in
highest form in this flagship effort, his directorial debut. This film
enshrines Italian horror at its best, and Arturo Dominici's performance as
vampire/sorcerer is nothing less than stellar. A chiaroscuro Black Mass.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1679475/comments</url><from>from Van Buren, Arkansas</from><name>krorie</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Be sure and watch the uncut version with the title "The Mask of Satan,"
not the censored "Black Sunday" copy, to get the full effect of this
living dead masterpiece of Italian cinema. More a movie of the undead
than a vampire flick, it reminds the horror aficionado of a Val Lewton
film from the 1940's, especially "The Leopard Man," not that "The Mask
of Satan" is about leopards, but the mood and atmosphere are similar.The film is about a woman of darkness and her mate who were executed
for witchcraft two centuries before the Napoleonic period of European
history. The most gruesome feature of the execution involved nailing a
mask of Satan to their faces by means of a giant sledgehammer before
they were entombed. By accident two hundred years later a doctor and
his assistant while journeying through the region by coach on a dark
stormy night filled with eerie devilish sounds, the doctor removes the
mask from Princess Asa Vajda supposed corpse. Now Princess Vajda and
her fiendish companion become free to seek their revenge. Their evil is
released on the world and must be stopped.This is undoubtedly director Mario Bava best film. The marvelous camera
work draws the viewer into the maelstrom of darkness and evil through
innovative movements and angles. The shadowy settings where the actors
are posed in ominous fashion are unforgettable. One obvious inspiration
for Bava was the contemporary British Hammer horror film popular in
America, especially with the drive-in crowd. The arrival of Katia Vajda
with what appear to be the dogs of Hell, standing like a silhouette of
damnation, reminds one of a Caspar David Friedrich painting from the
German Romantic art movement of the Napoleonic era. One wonders if the
director of "The Omen," Richard Donner, patterned his creepy scene in
the cemetery with the Rottweilers after this scene in "The Mask of
Satan."This movie remains a must see for horror fans, somewhat of a lost
treasure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0865972/comments</url><from>from Chyby, Poland</from><name>HumanoidOfFlesh</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

"La Maschera del Demonio" aka "Black Sunday" is an excellent Gothic
chiller
with plenty of uncanny atmosphere,a good script and an okay cast.Princess
Asa Vajda(lovely Barbara Steele)is executed as a witch.200 years
later,she
is revived and plots to take over the body of Katia(also Barbara
Steele)."Black Sunday" is a perfect combination of Expressionist lighting
and set designs and graphic bursts of gore and sensuality.The film is
full
of striking visuals and is truly one of the most beautiful black and
white
films I have ever seen.A must-see for fans of Italian horror.10 out of
10.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

'Black Sunday's reputation grows with every year that passes, and watching
it it's no wonder why! It is not only one of the three or four best horror
movies ever made, it is one of the most extraordinary movies of any genre
I've ever seen. Mario Bava went on to direct several movies of note after
this, but if he hadn't and this was the only movie he made, he would still
be a legend. On a relatively small budget, but with buckets of talent, style
and originality, Bava conjured up one of the most atmospheric and haunting
movies of all time. He may not be the household name he deserves to be, but
he is a film makers film maker with an enormous influence on not only
subsequent Italian horror giants Dario Argento and Lucio Fulci, but
directors as diverse as Tim Burton (who rates this as an all time favourite)
and even Martin Scorsese.  'Black Sunday' will also be remembered as one of
Barbara Steele's most memorable roles. Steele is best known for her work in
60s European horror movies, but in her career worked with everyone from
Fellini to Cronenberg. If she is to be remembered for only one movie it will
be this one. Steele was one of the most beautiful actresses to ever set foot
in front of a camera, and it is impossible to imagine anyone else in the
lead (duel) role. The supporting cast is fine, and includes the fondly
remembered John Richardson ('One Million Years B.C.'), but this is Steele's
show all the way. 'Black Sunday' is still fresh and exciting over forty
years after it was originally released. A landmark movie that deserves to be
watched again and again!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0605857/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>marquis de cinema</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

La Maschera Del Demonio/The Mask of Satan(1960) is the film that introduced
audiences around the world to the cinema of Mario Bava.  After years as
Assistent Director and Director of Photography, Bava was rewarded with his
first full directorial assignment and the results are impressive.  He didn't
direct full time until he was in his late 40's.  Its interesting to note
that two other directors named Lucio Fulci and Terence Fisher didn't get
international recognization until their big breaks(Zombie[1979] + Curse of
Frankenstein[1957]) when they were in their early to mid 50's.  Its about a
dead witch who returns from the dead with her lover to terrorize the
descendents of their executioners.  It was done due to the success of Horror
of Dracula(1958).The opening scene of the execution of Asa is a stunning combination of
atmosphere and violent imagery.  The Mask of Satan(1960) is based on a short
story by Nikolai Gogol.  Gogol is a writer that would play together with
Edgar Allen Poe as a major influence in Bava's Supernatural tales.  Its one
of the best horror films of the last fifty years.  Asa is resurrected when
the blood of a doctor is accidently dropped on her corpse(this is played
homage to in Lamberto Bava's Demons 2{1986}).  Tim Burton has cited this
movie as one of his favorites.The film was pratically butchered in the states when first released, but has
since been released on Home Video in uncut form(longest print in existence).
 This is an item that many aspiring Horror Filmmakers should watch in order
to see how a great horror film should be done.  The Mask of Satan(1960)
isn't interested in plot and story as much as atmosphere and painting style
visuals.  Barbara Steele emerges as the first horror queen of the modern
era.  Barbara Steele has a macabre beauty that bewitches the viewer and
gives her presence.  Barbara Steele along with Christopher Lee, Peter
Cushing, and Vincent Price were some of the greatest icons in 1960's-1970's
horror films.Barbara Steele does outstanding work as the witch Asa and her descendent
Katia.  Mario Bava's direction has the look of a great artist.  Bava also
contributes to the great cinematography.  La Maschera Del Demonio is a well
made mixture of the Universal Horror features of the 30's-40's and the
violence of Hammer Horror of the 50's-60's.  The fact that Mario Bava did
this based on the success of Horror of Dracula(1958) must have influenced
Terence Fisher to respond by directing Dracula:Prince of Darkness(1965). 
One theme that is present in The Mask of Satan(1960) is the decay and
decline of a once happy and powerful family(more fully explored in Bava's
later films of Black Sabbath{1963}, The Whip &amp; the Body{1964}, Lisa and the
Devil{1974}, and Shock{1977}).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The screenplay is hackneyed ,the story has been told told and told
again...And however,Bava's film is a sparkling diamond.How come?The direction
of course,the cinematography absolutely incredibly breath-taking,and
Barbara Steele ,the par excellence Gothic heroine:her fans will rejoice
for she plays two parts here! Bava has no match when it comes to use
the light the settings and the soundtrack.It's a black and white work
and had it been filmed in color it would not have been better.From the
gloomy family vaults to the forest where danger awaits on the young
peasant girl to the doomed castle where a family tries to fight against
a mysterious curse.The carriage which takes the doctor to the mansion and its coachman
reminds me of Murnau's "Nosferatu" .No less.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The screenplay is hackneyed ,the story has been told told and told
again...And however,Bava's film is a sparkling diamond.How come?The direction
of course,the cinematography absolutely incredibly breath-taking,and
Barbara Steele ,the par excellence Gothic heroine:her fans will rejoice
for she plays two parts here! Bava has no match when it comes to use
the light the settings and the soundtrack.It's a black and white work
and had it been filmed in color it would not have been better.From the
gloomy family vaults to the forest where danger awaits on the young
peasant girl to the doomed castle where a family tries to fight against
a mysterious curse.The carriage which takes the doctor to the mansion and its coachman
reminds me of Murnau's "Nosferatu" .No less.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>