<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Never Take Sweets from a Stranger</original_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Cyril Frankel</director><producer>Hammer Film Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
Peter Carter meets official resistance when he finds his 9 year old daughter has been the victim of the pedophile patriarch of the town's most powerful family.
</synopsis><actor>Gwen Watford</actor><actor>Patrick Allen</actor><actor>Felix Aylmer</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0679950/comments</url><from/><name>galensaysyes</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I saw this on video as "Never Take Candy from a Stranger," under which
title it was apparently released in the U.S. It was the one serious
film produced by Hammer Films, famous for its Gothic horrors, and I
found this much more suspenseful, as well as much better made, than the
lot of them. It begins with small tensions of frustration and mild
dislike among members of the academic community in a small town and
gradually, subtly builds to an atmosphere of dread that catches in the
throat. Every character, down to the bit parts, has something of
interest to say, and what they say and do, and how their actions
combine, lead step by step to the harrowing conclusion. The only fault
is the over-simplicity of its social viewpoint, as expressed by the
main character and justified by the events of the story, which are by
no means unbelievable but not inevitable either. Apart from that, I
thought it was a first-class B-picture, a small film in the good sense,
compact and economical, with all its resources, human and otherwise,
firmly in hand. Also, it has the grey photography that once used to
give films of this type the aura they needed: the grey of rain and fog
and dusk and uneasy feelings.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Never Take Sweets from a Stranger is yet another small scale and less
popular Hammer film, but still one that gives the studio's more well
respected efforts a run for their money. This film is macabre in a way
unlike most other Hammer movies. The frightening things about this film
don't come from overly maniacal characters or fantasy monsters - but
from a threat that has become more widespread in the past few decades.
The main theme here is paedophilia, and it feels odd watching this film
as the attitudes expressed towards the hideous act are nothing like
they are today. Because paedophilia is more often heard about now, the
film isn't quite so frightening - but somehow it feels like it wasn't
as frightening back in 1960 as it must have seemed like quite an
outlandish idea. The plot follows a couple of young girls. One of them
loses her 'candy money' and the other says she knows where they can get
some free candy. They go to Mr Olderberry's house, but when the young
girl comes home saying that the old man made them take their clothes
off and dance for candy - her parents, new in town, decide to take the
powerful Olderberry family to court.Aside from showing a real life monster, the film would also appear to
want to serve as a warning against immoral lawyers manipulating the
truth to get the wealthy off the hook. Director Cyril Frankel seems to
want to take a moral stance on these issues, and that's no bad thing.
There is a macabre atmosphere in the film, but the bulk of it happens
in a courtroom. Hammer may be famous for horror, and this film does
feature some towards the end - but on the whole it's more of a
courtroom drama than anything else. This isn't a bad thing, however, as
the courtroom action is always interesting and this is backed up by an
undercurrent of terror as we get to watch a guilty man walk free. The
acting is pretty decent, with Janina Faye standing out the most. It's
hard to judge the production values as my copy wasn't exactly great,
but I doubt that the film was short on budget; and there's nothing in
the film that would have been particularly expensive anyway. Overall,
Never Take Sweets from a Stranger is a damn good lesser known Hammer
flick that boils down to a terrifying and memorable conclusion, and it
therefore comes recommended to anyone who enjoys a good thriller!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0157899/comments</url><from>from Victoria B.C.</from><name>Castor-11</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

It is well over 30 years since I saw this film, and from time to time have
tried to track it down within this IMDB system, but, until now, due to its
title (I've always identified it as "The Pony Cart", the title of the
original play),was frustrated in my search.I'm a bit hazy about some of the details, but I do remember it being a
gritty cautionary tale of two missing children...it is grimly realistic,
without being exploitive, and years ahead of its time, in warning of, when
it comes to children's safety, who can one trust?Its story is set in Canada, thus leading me to the impression
that it was a Canadian production - it is, in fact, English, and all
concerned did a splendid job with a harrowing tale.I can't recall ever seeing it advertised as appearing on t.v., or anywhere
else, so it maybe it's gone where many other
good films go - celluloid heaven, leaving us with lots of garbage which
drifts around forever. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3917380/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>gordonl56</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A rather unseen film from Hammer Films. A pair of 9-10 year old girls
are lured into a house by an old man offering candy. He has them dance
naked for him though he stops short of sex. After discovering what has
happened, the family of one girl call the police and insist the old man
be charged. The police are somewhat reluctant to go after the man. It
seems that he is the elder member of the most powerful family in the
town. They own the local factory where the majority of the town is
employed. The old man's lawyer lets the girl's family know that he will
destroy the girl on the stand if the matter goes to court. The girl's
family stick to their guns and the old guy is charged. Witnesses for
the young girl suddenly leave town and the family is shunned by the
rest of the town. The lawyer is true to his threat about destroying the
girl. They can only take so much and decide to withdraw the charges.
Two weeks later the same old guy lures another girl to a small cabin
and kills her. A rather intense film which handles the subject matter
in a thoughtful mature way. A good film.Gord
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6471210/comments</url><from>from Edinburgh, Scotland</from><name>b_moviebuff</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This was one of the most controversial films of its time, I remember
vividly the the bad press this movie got,but what we have here is now
so relevant to today's society and Hammer should ensure this is
restored and put on DVD, I managed to track a copy down from the US
where it had been on television, the owner of the disc can be found on
a very well known auction site, to my knowledge this has never been
shown on British TV.Starring veteran and distinguished theatre actor Aylmer, who does not
breath one word in the movie by the way is accused by a young girl of
being a child molester and is taken to court by the girl's father
Patrick Holt, sadly Aylmer is the town's big-wig and is a much
respected professor as well as owning most of the land in the town, the
case against him is thrown out due to lack of evidence from the young
girl.What follows is a harrowing chase scene involving the same girl and her
friend from school both chased through the woods by a psychopathic
Aylmer and ultimately leads to death of one of the girls before he is
caught.Curiously set in Canada with an uneasy blend of stiff British upper lip
and north American accents, talky in parts but stick with it to the end
where the final scene's are shattering and every parent's nightmare,
this movie should be seen by all.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11057494/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>stephen-alexander-2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Vastly under-rated (no doubt due to it's lack of release and being
regarded as just another Hammer Horror) it is yet another offering from
that studio that shows just what crafted film-makers the team from Bray
studios actually were.Director Cyril Frankel extracts first-rate performances from the
leading performers, with Janina Faye worthy of special mention as the
key victim in the saga.Production values are the usual high standard from the Hammer team of
the late 50's - Early 60's, Bernard Robinson's production design
triumphant transforming Pinewood's Black Park locations into a small
Canadian town. Freddie Francis does his sterling filter work yet again, adding menace
to the lakeside finale and offering more in monochrome than could have
been achieved in colour.Considerably superior to most films that broach the subject matter and
(although the copy I have seen is no better than average quality) it is
hoped that the upcoming DVD release will restore the widescreen ratio
thus allowing us to see it as it was intended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8239592/comments</url><from>from The Last New Jersey Drive-In on the Left</from><name>Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Hammer is best known for their horror pictures, but this studio also
made a sizable number of thrillers as well. This particular thriller is
perhaps one of Hammer's most powerful and unsettling entries in the
genre because it's about something that can actually happen -- and
sadly does happen all the time even to this very day. The Carter family
arrive in a prosperous small Canadian town. When sweet and innocent
daughter Jean (a fine and touching performance by Janina Faye) accuses
the elderly Clarence Olderberry Sr. of making her and her friend
Lucille dance naked in front of him for some candy, her parents decide
to take Olderberry to court despite the fact that he's the patriarch of
an extremely rich and influential local family. Director Cyril Frankel,
working from a gripping and intelligent script by John Hunter, handles
the delicate subject of pedophilia in a commendably tasteful,
nonexploitative, and straightforward manner; while the subject matter
is undeniably unpleasant, it's nonetheless made tolerable by Frankel's
wise decision to avoid explicitness in favor of suggestion instead.
This film further benefits from uniformly outstanding acting from a
top-rate cast, with especially stand-out work from Gwen Watford as the
concerned Sally Carter, Peter Allen as the resolute Peter Carter, Bill
Nagy as Olderberry's protective and formidable son Richard, Nial
McGinnis as the shifty and aggressive defense counsel, Michael Gwynn as
the shrewd and compassionate prosecutor, and MacDonald Parke as a wise
no-nonsense judge. Felix Aylmer contributes a memorably creepy
portrayal as the odious Clarence Olderberry; he manages to project a
genuine sense of menace without ever uttering a single word. Moreover,
we've also got a strong and provocative central message about the
corruption of both justice and innocence and the abuse of power. But
what really makes this film so potent and effective is the fact that
it's firmly grounded in a thoroughly plausible everyday world populated
by equally believable characters (Clarence in particular is an
all-too-real human monster). The uncompromising grim ending packs a
devastating punch. Both Freddie Francis' crisp black and white
cinematography and Elisabeth Lutyens' moody score are up to par. An
excellent, albeit quite harrowing and disturbing film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1395086/comments</url><from>from sweden</from><name>Karl Ericsson (karlericsson@telia.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Just as there is no difference between bad and good fudge, as some
people might say, there is also no difference between good power and
bad power. You see, power is the problem, period.This may be difficult for some people to understand, especially to
those who pray to a good power as if there was such a thing. What makes
such confusion possible is probably, more than anything else, the
deterioration that the word "power" has undergone since the days of the
old Greeks, as seen in Platon's dialogues, in which power was clearly
and only what we now call "might" or "abuse of power" and not such
things as "knowledge", "strength" and "ability", which may all be used
for good as well as for evil purposes. For the old Greeks as well as
for all of us when we are affected (and not carelessly affect!), power
meant the possibility, lent by society, to rule over other person's
lives, more or less gratuitously (depending on what kind of society).
In short one might also say that "he or she, who cannot abuse power
without punishment, simply have no power to begin with".In this film, a man of power is a pedophile and can allow himself much
more than if he was a black man in the South, for instance. This is
shown very clearly in this film, which makes this film rare, since it
is an attack on power.In the fifties, in which this story takes place, there were many
opportunities to work and less opportunities to control the
working-force, which is probably why people still dared to speak up
against power. This kind of film has become very rare these days. The
film industry seems to have sold out to brainless entertainment or
artsy-fartsy "literature" - it's safer that way, so most artists and
journalists seem to argue.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3036948/comments</url><from>from Vanuatu</from><name>jimtabor2002</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
An excellent movie which,in my opinion,did not get the recognition it
deserved.I saw this film on the cinema,more years ago than I care to
remember.At that time it was rated with what was known as an "X"
certificate,which meant that anyone under the age of sixteen was not
legally allowed to go into the cinema to watch this film.I also felt
that this rating was ill-judged,since it is a film that children ought
to be allowed to see,since it sounds out a powerful warning. A film
which ought to be revived,particularly in the light of Soham.The title
of the film is very misleading,since the offender in this film was,as
in the Soham case,not a stranger to the children concerned. I do know
how to obtain a copy of this film on video.It is a must for parents
with young children,they should allow their children to watch it and
heed the warning!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0347711/comments</url><from>from Panama</from><name>Edgar Soberón Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This fine drama as well as "Cash on Demand" are, in my opinion, two of
the best dramas produced by the Hammer Film, though not as well known
as Joseph Losey's science-fiction drama"The Damned", or Michael
Carreras' thriller "Maniac", which had casts with better known actors
as Kerwin Mathews, Viveca Lindfors, Macdonald Carey, Nadia Gray and
Alexander Knox. In the line of New York scholar Ruth Goldberg's recent
studies of the evolution of horror film, this is definitely a precursor
to her approach, according to which characters from films as "No
Country for Old Men", "Safe", "Fargo", "Precious", "Monster", and
others, are really monsters that convey the feeling of horror found in
the traditional motion pictures of this genre. The old man (Felix
Aylmer) who abuses two little girls, who is taken to court, and finally
follows them in the woods, is definitely one of the most terrifying
monsters to come out of Hammer Film. If it still works today as an
effective and startling drama, in 1960 it must have been shocking to
audiences. Very good black &amp; white widescreen cinematography by maestro
Freddie Francis ("The Innocents", "The Elephant Man"). Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0347711/comments</url><from>from Panama</from><name>Edgar Soberón Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This fine drama as well as "Cash on Demand" are, in my opinion, two of
the best dramas produced by the Hammer Film, though not as well known
as Joseph Losey's science-fiction drama"The Damned", or Michael
Carreras' thriller "Maniac", which had casts with better known actors
as Kerwin Mathews, Viveca Lindfors, Macdonald Carey, Nadia Gray and
Alexander Knox. In the line of New York scholar Ruth Goldberg's recent
studies of the evolution of horror film, this is definitely a precursor
to her approach, according to which characters from films as "No
Country for Old Men", "Safe", "Fargo", "Precious", "Monster", and
others, are really monsters that convey the feeling of horror found in
the traditional motion pictures of this genre. The old man (Felix
Aylmer) who abuses two little girls, who is taken to court, and finally
follows them in the woods, is definitely one of the most terrifying
monsters to come out of Hammer Film. If it still works today as an
effective and startling drama, in 1960 it must have been shocking to
audiences. Very good black &amp; white widescreen cinematography by maestro
Freddie Francis ("The Innocents", "The Elephant Man"). Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0347711/comments</url><from>from Panama</from><name>Edgar Soberón Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>