<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sergeant Rutledge</original_title><alt_title>Le sergent noir</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>John Ford</director><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><producer>Ford Productions</producer><genre>Western</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
Respected black cavalry Sergeant Brax Rutledge stands court-martial for raping and killing a white woman and murdering her father, his superior officer.
</synopsis><actor>Jeffrey Hunter</actor><actor>Woody Strode</actor><actor>Constance Towers</actor><rt_rating>6.9/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0797215/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>laholly</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

  When I was scannning the reviews of this excellent movie, I found one
comment that really flipped me out... REMAKE A JOHN FORD CLASSIC like
Sergeant Rutledge????? Good Lord, what are you thinking. I am basically
opposed to most remakes anyway,but this film in particular has stood the
test of time just fine.... As another reviewer said,it is NOT a typical John
Ford film,but it has to be one of his best.  Woody Strode,one of the most
under rated black actors of his generation is superb as in the title role. I
would have to do some research to see how many films he did for Ford..in
this film he is amazing.  Jeffrey Hunter as defense attorney Tom Cantrell
also turns in an excellent performance,caught between the proverbial rock
and hard place when he is 'forced' to defend Rutledge.  Constance Towers as
Hunter's conscience, the school teacher, Mary is also quite good. Comic
relief is provided by Billie Burke(Glinda the good) as the commanding
general's wife,who cannot understand why she cant sit in the front row.   I have drawn a complete blank as to the actor who plays the prosecutor at
Rutledge's courtmartial, but he is also very good... shades of Hamilton
Burger.
   As much as I respect Denzel Washington as an actor ,I can't imagine him
agreeing to remake this excellent film.... as for Ben Affleck as Cantrell,
NEVER IN A MILLION YEARS.   As I said in a previous review, if it ain't
broke,don't fix it.....Bearing in mind that Ford, Hunter and Strode are all
gone, it just wouldnt be right.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2661632/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Essex_Rider</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie was a wonderful piece of social history. It was filmed during a
turbulent time in the United States when Civil Rights marches were really
making headlines. It was a well crafted and movingly brave attempt to
address in celluloid what the Civil Rights movement was addressing on
placards. Throughout the trial, colour isn't mentioned at all until near the end, but
the underlying issue is one of race and how easy it would have been to jump
to the wrong conclusion and ‘Hang ourselves a nigger'. It was also
incredibly brave to show how the protagonist, Sergeant Rutledge,
(beautifully played by Woody Strode) was helped by a white woman; again very
rare at that time. This is a hidden gem of a movie, and although the dialogue gets a little
stilted at times, it doesn't detract from the central issue. Judging by his
performance when under oath, Woody Strode is up there with the best of the
marvellous Black actors that have changed the face of social America.I rate this 10 out of ten.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0461119/comments</url><from>from Tucson, Arizona</from><name>Ronald J. Foreman</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I first caught the tail end of this John Ford masterpiece on AMC during
Black History month, and couldn't wait for it to pop up on the schedule
again so I could see the whole thing. I couldn't believe I had never heard
of this film before, and after I did some research and discovered how
reviewers in 1960 had dismissed it, I understood why. They went expecting
To
Kill A Mockingbird and got Breaker Morant instead. Ford was WAY ahead of
his
time with this one. Woody Strode, who plays the title character, helped
break the color barrier in professional football years before Jackie
Robinson did so in baseball. And he broke some huge barriers in this film,
too. Every young black man -- heck, every young American male today --
should be required to watch this film. As Strode later said, Ford and
script
writers "put classic words in my mouth." Words that would be echoed three
years later by Dr. Martin Luther King in his immortal "I Have A Dream"
speech at the Lincoln memorial.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
John Ford who was among many who perpetuated black racial stereotypes,
notably in Judge Priest and The Sun Shines Bright, got a chance to
redeem himself with the making of Sergeant Rutledge. A year before in
the Robert Mitchum film, The Wonderful Country, Negro League baseball
legend Satchel Paige played a black cavalry sergeant in a supporting
role. But in Sergeant Rutledge the story centers around such a
character and the ordeal he goes through when accused of rape and
murder. The victims are his commanding officer and his daughter.The leads are Woody Strode as the accused Sergeant Braxton Rutledge and
Jeffrey Hunter as the lieutenant who defends him in a court martial.
The story is told in flashback through the accounts of the many
witnesses at the court martial and in some of those scenes, John Ford
got to revisit his beloved Monument Valley for some good old Indian
fights.The murders at the fort take place simultaneously with an outbreak from
the Apache reservation. Constance Towers who discovers both the results
of an Indian attack and the fleeing sergeant at the railroad station,
becomes both Rutledge's biggest champion and the object of Jeffrey
Hunter's romantic intentions.The dilemma that Strode faced was that by so many black people,
especially in the south. He comes upon the dead girl who he knows from
the fort and the fact she's been sexually violated. Her father sees him
together with his dead daughter and assumes the worst about him and
shoots him. Strode is forced to kill him in self defense and then has
to run. A white man might have stayed and explained. The father might
not have fired on a white man either.Woody Strode had he come along ten to fifteen years later might well
have become an action hero star like Wesley Snipes for instance. As it
was here and in his small role in Spartacus as Kirk Douglas's opponent
in the gladiator school he plays both with impassive dignity and
strength. These became his career roles, too bad he didn't build on
Sergeant Rutledge to get better parts like black actors did in the next
generation.Two of John Ford's stock company regulars shine in Sergeant Rutledge,
Carleton Young and Willis Bouchey. Carleton Young is Captain Shattuck,
the prosecutor at the Rutledge court martial and he's not above playing
the race card to win his case. Very similar in fact to William Windom's
prosecutor in To Kill a Mockingbird. Unfortunately for Young, he's not
dealing with a jury of uneducated sharecroppers.Willis Bouchey is the presiding judge at the court martial and besides
the court martial he has to deal with Billie Burke, his flibbertigibbet
of a wife. He's got a lot grief to deal with, made double by the fact
that Burke is called by Young as a witness. A lot of the comic relief
in Sergeant Rutledge centers around Burke. This was her farewell screen
role and she went out in scatterbrained style.Jeffrey Hunter turns out to be a pretty good lawyer himself and he
brings the trial to a sudden end with a bit of fast thinking on his
feet worthy of Perry Mason.This very first film dealing with the black buffalo soldiers of the
U.S. Cavalry is great viewing for those who like both courtroom drama
and westerns. If you like both, this is your film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0427276/comments</url><from>from Paddington, Brisbane, Australia</from><name>frankie-47</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

John Ford, ever the director of the under dog creates another masterpiece of
forgotten American history.Ford, who called himself a social democrat creates another film of nobility
and personal convictions, both his and his characters.  It is Fords great
humanity and sense of justice which makes this film so
appealing.Some of the narrative is forced and the resolution is pat. What we do have
is Fords beautiful colour camera in Monument Valley, ala "The Searchers (
1956 )", broad humour, defined characterizations and attention to detail
both individual and historical.Jeffrey Hunter, always an underrated actor, is fine as the lead, but it is
Woody Strode as the title character that is a stand out. His courtroom scene
defending his beliefs and humanity is truly moving as is his scene as he
rides back to save his troop.
A " man mountain" he is ! Through his physical presence Ford coaxes out
subtle nuances of character which give the role a ring of truth. Supporting
him we have Fords usual wonderful stock players. Although not as poetic or
thought out as some of Fords other films this is still miles ahead of other
peoples efforts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1186595/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>sultana-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Western is not my favorite genre, but good character studies are, and Ford
specialized in these in the 50's and 60's to a greater extent that most
moviegoers realize.  The boundaries of what Strode is willing to share with
Hunter and what cannot be broached are fascinating enough, but Ford takes us
deeper into all the characters and their motivations. I agree with an
earlier observation comparing it with Breaker Morant and saying it was more
than 20 years ahead of its time; I would say a mix between some of the most
compelling aspects of Breaker Morant and A Soldier's Story.  Watch this
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0191880/comments</url><from>from la</from><name>F_Jenkins</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

To say this is a great film may be an understatement.  I can't believe this
is not a more known movie, especially with Ford as the director. Jeffery
Hunter plays a lawyer defending Woody Strode for murder in 1881, a very
short time after Lincoln freed the slaves. It was a time of racism, but so
was 1960, when this film was released.This is a great character study, and a marvelous script. There's some humor
and great performances. This should be considered a classic and I hope it
really gets its due at some point.  Could you see this remade? Maybe Denzel
and Ben Affleck in the lead roles?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0675231/comments</url><from>from Padova, Italy</from><name>pzanardo (pzanardo@math.unipd.it)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
John Ford openly displays his poetry in this magnificent film "Sergeant
Rutledge". Maybe the great director and artist was annoyed that many
did not get the anti-racist messages that permeate all his works
(starting with "The Searchers": ever noted it?) and decided to make a
definite, open statement.To be as clear as possible, Ford willingly shows his art, poetry and
trade-mark techniques in the most evident way. He masterly uses images
and camera-work to convey emotion. We see Woody Strode (Sergeant
Rutledge) constrained in a small chair, his never-ending shoulders
covering half of the screen. And we feel uneasy. We feel that something
evil is going on, that it's deeply wrong to keep such a man in chains,
let alone to hang him. And then we see Woody Strode standing out, the
Monument Valley on the background, like John Wayne in many other Ford's
movies. I'm sure that such parallel Wayne-Strode was Ford's deliberate
choice. Ford uses his skills of epic poet to describe characters. Rutledge is
arrested and searched. They find no money or other goods, just his
emancipation papers. So, here we have a Man with all his richness: his
honor, his courage, his strength and an emancipation paper. Great
stuff! And then Rutledge says to a wounded mate "We don't fight the
whites' war. We fight for our honor". Only Ford always manages to turn
military rhetoric into poetry, mainly thanks to the visual beauty of
the scene. Woody Strode makes an outstanding, deeply touching job as the black
cavalry sergeant. His acting is sober, poised but intense, with no
melodramatic sides, and he physically dominates the screen (by the way:
what an amazing athlete Strode was, at age forty-six!).Rutledge is the Hero, the Legend of the movie. Yet Lt. Cantrell
(Jeffrey Hunter) is as interesting a character as Rutledge is. Cantrell
is a man of the 19th century. Unavoidably, he does have racial
prejudices, but he nobly endeavors to overcome them, and certainly at
the end of the story is a better person than at the beginning.I guess that the two female characters represent Ford's dream. Indeed,
they both do not even understand racism. The poor murdered girl loved
his friend "uncle" Rutledge, and that's all. She doesn't even get the
hints of the old ladies, who disapprove this friendship. And the same
can be said of Cantrell's fiancée Mary Beecher, very well played by
Constance Towers. She nurses the wounded black horse-soldiers with no
attitude of doing something special. And some lines of Mary's show
Ford's wonderful subtlety. She has been over-night with Rutledge in a
deserted hut. Mary says to a concerned Cantrell "I wasn't alone.
Sergeant Rutledge was with me and he protected me as well as any
officer could do". That's a lesson for Cantrell: the fact that Mary
pretends to think her boy-friend just concerned about military ranks,
implies that she does not even notice the color of the skin and
requires Cantrell to be the same way. Well, probably the two women are
not fully realistic characters, especially for the 19th century. They
are idealized by Ford, as a poet has the right to dream. A small remark. Most Ford's films (not this one, actually) raise some
controversy. Many heartily love them and many strongly dislike them. I
think it rather expectable. Ford is a poet, and a poet cannot please
everyone. Personally, I was indifferent if not displeased by the works
of some much celebrated poets. Thanks God, poets follow their own way,
not caring people's taste. "Sergeant Rutledge" is not perfectly constructed and chiseled like
other Ford's masterpieces. Small defects may be found in some
court-room scenes and flash-backs. However, this splendid movie
deserves top grades, due to the importance of its message and Ford's
sincerity in displaying his art. "Sergeant Rutledge" is another top
work by the Master.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This is a marvelous Western starring Jeffery Hunter and Woodie
Strode--thanks in large part to the always wonderful direction of John
Ford and the fact that this film dared to take a big risk. In the 1950s
and 60s, American was still struggling desperately with racism and it
was still widely acceptable to demean or mistreat Black people.
However, this film deliberately tries to debunk this myth that Black
people are in some way inferior. The film attacks racism without being
preachy or ridiculous (something that makes me hate GENTLEMEN'S
AGREEMENT due to its very heavy-handed way of dealing with
antisemitism).Woody Strode, as usual, plays a very dignified and wonderful role as a
soldier on trial for rape and murder. He was a very fine actor and you
wonder how much further he could have gone in life had he been White.
Hunter plays the man defending him and shows more than he could in most
of his other pretty forgettable films. The actual story of what
occurred unfolds in flashbacks told during the course of the trial and
the style is very reminiscent of Akira Kurosawa's film Rashômon. This
is VERY ironic, as for years, Kurosawa had been a huge fan of Ford and
tried to emulate the master director! In this case, it is the other way
around! The film is near-perfect in the acting, story and execution.
Watch this film and see that Westerns CAN be more than just the typical
horse and Indian flick.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0461119/comments</url><from>from Tucson, Arizona</from><name>Ronald J. Foreman</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I first caught the tail end of this John Ford masterpiece on AMC during
Black History month, and couldn't wait for it to pop up on the schedule
again so I could see the whole thing. I couldn't believe I had never heard
of this film before, and after I did some research and discovered how
reviewers in 1960 had dismissed it, I understood why. They went expecting
To
Kill A Mockingbird and got Breaker Morant instead. Ford was WAY ahead of
his
time with this one. Woody Strode, who plays the title character, helped
break the color barrier in professional football years before Jackie
Robinson did so in baseball. And he broke some huge barriers in this film,
too. Every young black man -- heck, every young American male today --
should be required to watch this film. As Strode later said, Ford and
script
writers "put classic words in my mouth." Words that would be echoed three
years later by Dr. Martin Luther King in his immortal "I Have A Dream"
speech at the Lincoln memorial.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0461119/comments</url><from>from Tucson, Arizona</from><name>Ronald J. Foreman</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I first caught the tail end of this John Ford masterpiece on AMC during
Black History month, and couldn't wait for it to pop up on the schedule
again so I could see the whole thing. I couldn't believe I had never heard
of this film before, and after I did some research and discovered how
reviewers in 1960 had dismissed it, I understood why. They went expecting
To
Kill A Mockingbird and got Breaker Morant instead. Ford was WAY ahead of
his
time with this one. Woody Strode, who plays the title character, helped
break the color barrier in professional football years before Jackie
Robinson did so in baseball. And he broke some huge barriers in this film,
too. Every young black man -- heck, every young American male today --
should be required to watch this film. As Strode later said, Ford and
script
writers "put classic words in my mouth." Words that would be echoed three
years later by Dr. Martin Luther King in his immortal "I Have A Dream"
speech at the Lincoln memorial.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0461119/comments</url><from>from Tucson, Arizona</from><name>Ronald J. Foreman</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/sergeantrutledge.htm /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1931594</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>Noted as the first major Hollywood western to feature an African-American hero.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/sgtrut.shtml /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1791327</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>An astonishing film not only for its sheer visual and narrative excellence but also for its early acknowledgement of race relations in America.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1186760</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Effective anti-racist western from Ford.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/thomas-delapa/</url><url>/m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1433722</url><name>Thomas Delapa</name><from>Boulder Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1403742</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794754.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1806049</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/74326/sergeant_rutledge.html /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1518323</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/mem/movies/review.html?title1=&amp;title2=Sergeant%20Rutledge%20%28Movie%29&amp;reviewer=&amp;v_id=114440&amp;pdate=19600526&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1389636</url><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/andrew-tracy/</url><url>http://archive.sensesofcinema.com/contents/cteq/04/sergeant_rutledge.html /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1283316</url><name>Andrew Tracy</name><from>Senses of Cinema</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=108115 /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=1149490</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/12205_SERGEANT_RUTLEDGE.html /m/sergeant_rutledge/comments.php?reviewid=28783</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>