<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hell to Eternity</original_title><alt_title>Saïpan</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Phil Karlson</director><producer>Atlantic Productions</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
When his adoptive Japanese-American family is sent to Manzanar after Pearl Harbor, a young Chicano enlists in the marines to become a hero in the Battle of Saipan.
</synopsis><actor>Jeffrey Hunter</actor><actor>David Janssen</actor><actor>Vic Damone</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0692247/comments</url><from>from Boulder, Colorado</from><name>reelguy2</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
World War II hero Guy Gabaldon's story could hardly have been entrusted
to a more suitable director than Phil Karlson. Karlson brings a tough
masculine style, as well as an emotional impact that would have eluded
many a director of action films. Operating as usual on a less-than-A
budget, Karlson nonetheless makes the most out of every scene and
elicits excellent performances from his cast.Hell to Eternity is by far the most violent war film made up to that
time. But Karlson's outbursts of violence are always tied to a strong
emotional response, making the violence anything but gratuitous.The film is also notable for a surprisingly provocative striptease by
Patricia Owens and and an equally provocative kiss between her and
Jeffrey Hunter. In terms of its violence and sexual content, Hell to
Eternity probably went as far as the censors would allow in 1960.As Gabaldon, Jeffrey Hunter gives a performance of great sympathy, but
also one of considerable edge in his battle scenes. It's a difficult
role, because he has to express the moral dilemma of a man raised by a
Japanese-American family who is tasked with fighting the Japanese
during WW2. The fact that Hunter made King of Kings only one year after
this film and also offered diverse characterizations in Key Witness and
Sergeant Rutledge the same year as Hell to Eternity is a testament to
his versatility as an actor.Leith Stevens provides an outstanding dramatic score, which
unfortunately was poorly represented by the soundtrack album, which
contained mainly his jazz-oriented incidental music.The lower-than-A budget for this film more than likely accounts for it
not being better known. But make no mistake about it - it's one of the
most powerful war films ever made.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2132053/comments</url><from/><name>stevenchavez68</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A great war/personal true story, as previously commented, about a
Mexican-American young man from Boyle Heights (just east of Los Angeles)
CA., who worked close with the migrant Japanese-American workers and
learned
to speak Japanese. He joined the USMC First Marine Division and was the
recipient of the Naval Cross for his exploits on Saipan Island. He has
since
written a book "Saipan: Suicide Island" and comments heavily on the
movie.
Guy is proud of his Mexican-American heritage and very very proud of the
First Marine Division - USMC. He lives in Northern California and is a
great
American. I say this because of his continued service to this country. He
continues to get involved in services for the community and especially
our
youth.
I was 11 years old when I saw this movie (1962) two years after it's
release. I loved it for the war action and the personal story. I was
impressed that this person cared and tried hard to do what he thought was
the right thing. Vic Damone and David Jansen played good roles as well as
Jeffery Hunter. Hollywood was reluctant to depict Mexicans on the screen
as
regular people. That is why Jeffery Hunter played an Italian-American in
this film. Anthony Quinn had just completed "Requiem for a Heavyweight".
Mr.
Quinn lived in the same heights as Guy. My parents would tell us kids
that
he was one like us.
I am not negative buy simply express my feeling and recollections.
Anyway, I always recommend this movie to my friends and consider it in
the
Top 10 for war films. If ever the chance to read Guy's book or speak with
him, do not pass on the opportunity. Check out this movie - there are
wheels
turning to remake this movie. Guy's story continues. ..
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2616470/comments</url><from>from Cave Spring GA</from><name>mpdeaton</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw the movie many years ago and would love to have this movie on DVD.
Jeffrey Hunter looses his best friend, David Janson, to the enemy and
after
that develops a deep hatred for the Japeneese.  At times risking his own
life to flush them out of their hiding places and kill them.  At one point
where he is watching the japeneese women and children hurl themselves off
of
the cliffs rather then be captured, he sees his own adopted Japenese
family
back in the states.
An excellent movie that I would go the the movies to see
again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7882369/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>nancy-214</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
My father recommended this movie and I found a copy that I had
privilege to watch. It was a great movie that was touching and moving
to watch. I never heard of this Hispanic man who was a hero and I think
that it should be updated and played today for the newer generation
today. This movie starts from the beginning to the end on what the main
character went through and why he did what he did. It has much family
value no matter what race or color a person is. The war scenes were
magnificent even considering the year that the movie was made. I think
that if this movie were remade for this day and age with all of the
facts in order, that it would be better than some of the war movies
that are out now because it is in fact a true story. If you have a
chance to see this movie, I rate it a "10".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1723993/comments</url><from>from Boston</from><name>georgefor1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Huge shame that it is not available on VHS or DVD.  I saw it many years
ago
on TV and enjoyed it immensely.  The acting was top notch.  I've always
liked David Janssen and Patricia Owens (both of whom are dead now, as well
as Jeffrey Hunter, who died very tragically).  Why does Hollywood refuse
to
issue certain old movies on media?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10399190/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>emc22</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I have been trying to buy this movie but the prices are out of reach. I
was on Okinawa in 1960 when this movie was filmed. Our battalion was
the first to occupy the brand new barracks at Camp Schwabb. A lot of us
marines were chosen to be in the Japanese army because of our looks or
physical stature. yes I played the part of a Japanese soldier and
during the bonsai attack I was killed. I must say I died very
dramatically. I had the pleasure of meeting Jeffery Hunter, David
Janssen, and Vic Damone. I think the movie was pretty good even though
some important parts were omitted. I have read several articles on the
life of Guy Gabaldon and he looked nothing like Jeffery Hunter. Have a
nice day.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0298934/comments</url><from>from San Diego, CA</from><name>Richard L. Skinner (akskurgis@webtv.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

"Hell to Eternity" represents a true story of spiritual development in an
individual involved in a spiritual conflict from the beginning of the film
to it's conclusion.  It depicts a real person, Guy Gabaldon, who was
raised
in California by a Japanese family and his reluctance to kill the Japanese
enemy in WWII, a hardening of his heart and a means of reconciliation that
borders on miraculous.  The movie is able to capture the full impact of
this
part of a man's life.  This is a great war film without the impact of
Audie
Murphy's story in "To Hell and Back" (1955) only because that film starred
the hero that wrote the book about his personal exploits.  The movie "Hell
to Eternity" still stands out as a great biography of an American hero,
Guy
Gabaldon!   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4311871/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jon Schmidt (jontheeinstein@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Walter Roeber Schmidt is/was my grandfather. I still have an original
screenplay in bound condition that was his. From what I've seen/heard,
the story was a great one, and is truly a movie that one will never
forget. I recommend it to all who wish to know some of the real stories
from World War Two. What is interesting however, is that my grandfather
was in the Air Force I believe during World War Two, and his brother
was employed by the government to take movies and pictures of the war,
which, quite ironically, lead him to meet his wife in Italy, who
consequently, was a very beautiful woman. For those of you wondering
what my grandfather looked like, I hope to submit a picture soon to the
site.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12518244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>texohio</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I remember seeing this movie many times in the 60's and 70's at the
theater, on television, and on VHS. I grew up watching WWII movies and
remember this as one that had a special appeal to me. I guess because I
lived in Japan in the 1950's and visited some of the locales from the
movie. The acting was well done and the story was well told and
realistic. It is interesting to view the cast when they were relatively
new to movies. David Janssen and Vic Damone stand out in my memory and
Jeffrey Hunter was always a class act in films. I highly recommend
seeing it if possible. I do find it hard to believe that it is called a
"lost classic" and runs so high for a copy. Anyone know where I could
get a cheaper copy, I would like to hear from you.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10234621/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>goodspee-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw Hell to Eternity when it first came out in 1960. It anticipated
the newsreel quality of "Saving Private Ryan" and was very timeless in
style. A must see movie about a real hero in a real war. Warning! Like
"Ryan" very violent and graphic simulation of actual war battle scenes.
Jeffery Hunter turns in an excellent performance of a man struggling to
overcome rejection from joining the war effort because of his ethnic
background. He finally overcomes the obstacles with his skills as an
interpreter, knowing the Japanese language which also saves his life
and helps bridge the gap with the Japanese high command of the occupied
island where he eventually convinces the commander to surrender.
Seeking vengeance for his slain friend (David Jansen) he turns to
compassion upon witnessing a suicide of a young mother fearful of
Japanese propaganda of anticipated American brutality to then convince
the Japanese to peacefully surrender.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10234621/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>goodspee-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw Hell to Eternity when it first came out in 1960. It anticipated
the newsreel quality of "Saving Private Ryan" and was very timeless in
style. A must see movie about a real hero in a real war. Warning! Like
"Ryan" very violent and graphic simulation of actual war battle scenes.
Jeffery Hunter turns in an excellent performance of a man struggling to
overcome rejection from joining the war effort because of his ethnic
background. He finally overcomes the obstacles with his skills as an
interpreter, knowing the Japanese language which also saves his life
and helps bridge the gap with the Japanese high command of the occupied
island where he eventually convinces the commander to surrender.
Seeking vengeance for his slain friend (David Jansen) he turns to
compassion upon witnessing a suicide of a young mother fearful of
Japanese propaganda of anticipated American brutality to then convince
the Japanese to peacefully surrender.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10234621/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>goodspee-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/karlson.htm#Eternity /m/hell_to_eternity/comments.php?reviewid=1661261</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Powerful anti-war drama, with a unique point of view on Japanese-American relations.</comment></review></movie>