<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Messalina Venere imperatrice</original_title><alt_title>Messaline</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Vittorio Cottafavi</director><producer>Cineproduzione Emo Bistolfi</producer><synopsis/><actor>Belinda Lee</actor><actor>Spiros Focás</actor><actor>Carlo Giustini</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

In this opulent spectacle the corruption that was at the heart of the
Roman
Empire is embodied by the infamous empress Messalina, portrayed by
Belinda
Lee with surprising range from a vulnerable Vestal to the power mad,
sexually insatiable, callous mudereress she supposedly became. If
anything,
the film underplays her infamy, though she is certainly evil enough.In a memorable scene, a young would-be assassin (Giuliano Gemma) is lured
into her bed only to be beheaded before fully awake the following
morning.
Messalina triumphantly parades into the palace quarters of the desperate
plotters bearing the gift of his severed head.
Spiros Focas is fine as the naif and devoted centurion who fell in love
with
her before the rot set in.  As mounting evidence of her treachery and
licentiousness builds, the enamored lover struggles to break free of her
amorous toils and to eventually oppose her reign.
Although present and participating in her last violent moments, he at
last
admits the necessity of her death.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
To begin with, years ago I had watched a 1951 film (with Luis Bunuel
alumni Maria Felix and Georges Marchal, the latter also a Cottafavi
regular) about the same notorious historical figure – for the record,
she would be played in the interim by Susan Hayward in DEMETRIUS AND
THE GLADIATORS (1954). I would love to be able to re-acquaint myself
with that earlier version (incidentally, I still recall the
protagonist's hysterical come-uppance) also for the sake of comparison
with this one. By the way, the film under review makes for an indirect
addition to my stalled Josef von Sternberg retrospective, given that it
deals with the era of the Roman Emperor Claudius (though he is a rather
ineffectual presence here). While I did manage to acquire a
much-superior copy to the one I already owned in time for the Epic
Easter marathon I have embarked upon all through this month, my viewing
of it still did not occur under the most congenial of circumstances –
as the English-dubbing left a lot to be desired! The short-lived Belinda Lee is ideally-cast in the title role: Cecil B.
De Mille had described Cleopatra – actually dealt with by Cottafavi in
his subsequent effort LEGIONS OF THE NILE, released the same year and
which I have just checked out – as "the wickedest woman of all time",
but this epithet would serve this famous harlot ruler even better!
Ordained to be a Vestal Virgin, she still manages to seduce her way to
the throne (albeit ridding herself of any conquest/associate once his
purpose is fulfilled) and even causes discord among childhood pals! The
male lead, then, is Spiros Focas – why the role was not given to an
Italian actor is a mystery, but he acquits himself quite well under the
circumstances. The hero falls for Messalina before her ascent to power,
which happens while the young officer is off to war; later, he even
commits atrocities in her name – before being brought back to his
senses as much by the death of a Senator friend as the love of a
Christian girl played by a young Evelyn Stewart (still billed under her
Italian birthname).The rest of the cast includes: Giulio Donnini, a minor genre fixture as
virtually the only man not to fall under Messalina's spell and, in
fact, is the one to deal her the deadly blow; Arturo Dominici, who
bafflingly exchanges loyalties along the way and even becomes Emperor
prematurely (after an attempt on Claudius' life is thwarted but,
ingeniously, he still sends news to Rome of its success!); and a
pre-stardom Giuliano Gemma in a brief role early on as a would-be
assassin, subsequently lover/victim, of Messalina's – his head being
disdainfully presented on a plate to her befuddled enemies (with this
in mind and in view of the vibrant colors on display here, one regrets
the fact that Cottafavi steered clear of the horror genre throughout
his career)!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
1960's Messalina could never be described as a great movie, but it's at
times slightly more interesting than the average peplum that was
trotted off the Italian production line. Set shortly after Caligula's
assassination (the opening image is of his blood slowly flowing down
steps to his discarded laurel wreath) and dealing in part with the
schism between the marginalized aristocrats and the new Emperor
installed by the power of the Praetorian guard, it offers an
interesting alternative take on Claudius' reign to the Robert Graves
version. Here Claudius is an almost disinterested observer in the
course of history – even an assassination attempt just provokes a
curious glance to confirm that the force of history is conforming to
its usual pattern before returning to discussion of matters academic
while battle rages around him, aware he bores his courtiers but just as
aware that they have to at least pretend to listen to him anyway.Unfortunately Claudius is just a minor character (he probably gets only
five minutes of screen time) and none of the leads are interesting
enough either as characters or performers to really carry the picture:
that he's far more memorable than tragic former St. Trinian's pupil
Belinda Lee's scheming vestal virgin gone bad Messalina is a bit of a
problem in a film called Messalina. It's only when she seduces an
assassin at night, has him decapitated in the morning and then delivers
his head on a platter to the disgruntled nobility who sent him in the
afternoon that she makes much of an impression, and scenes like that
are few and far between. As usual there are some persecuted Christians
to save and a conspiracy to thwart along the way to a palace massacre
that would do a Jacobean revenge tragedy proud, but it all feels a bit
too business as usual to really stand out from the crowd.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The screenplay itself is a Messalina mess:combining politics
,love,ambitions,crimes,persecutions of Christians (I thought they began
during Nero's reign?),it may entertain you if you do not take it
seriously.There's nothing "cultural" here as in Cottafavi's notorious
"legioni di Cleopatra" (1960) where Linda Cristal(The queen of Egypt!)
went to dance in Alexandria's taverns .Here,in a cheap junk antiquity, Belinda Lee is making it rough all over
.But only the last scenes (the orgy turning into a slaughter)have
something to do with cinema.A young Giuliano Gemma appears briefly as a
killer who falls for the empress:he will lose his head! (in the literal
and figurative senses )
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The screenplay itself is a Messalina mess:combining politics
,love,ambitions,crimes,persecutions of Christians (I thought they began
during Nero's reign?),it may entertain you if you do not take it
seriously.There's nothing "cultural" here as in Cottafavi's notorious
"legioni di Cleopatra" (1960) where Linda Cristal(The queen of Egypt!)
went to dance in Alexandria's taverns .Here,in a cheap junk antiquity, Belinda Lee is making it rough all over
.But only the last scenes (the orgy turning into a slaughter)have
something to do with cinema.A young Giuliano Gemma appears briefly as a
killer who falls for the empress:he will lose his head! (in the literal
and figurative senses )
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>