<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Visit to a Small Planet</original_title><alt_title>Mince de planète</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Norman Taurog</director><producer>Hal Wallis Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
The weirdest alien of the galaxy pays a visit to Earth...
</synopsis><actor>Jerry Lewis</actor><actor>Joan Blackman</actor><actor>Earl Holliman</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Goofy alien Jerry Lewis lands on Earth, decides to try the suburban way
of life for awhile, angering his superior officers in space.
Screenwriter Edmund Beloin adapted Gore Vidal's play, but it doesn't
seem directly tailored for Lewis' mugging talents--which is a blessing.
The material is actually quite sophisticated, with a fair amount of
witty lines and good supporting performances by Joan Blackman, Earl
Holliman and Gale Gordon. Jerry Lewis himself isn't bad; he had yet to
be reeled-in by a strong director, but he isn't grating or overtly
offensive here. There's some surprising, modern humor in this scenario,
while the production, the (minimal) special effects, and Loyal Griggs'
black-and-white cinematography are all first-rate. Lots of fun! **1/2
from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2029693/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, California</from><name>Dejael</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A bumbling, clowning alien visitor named Kreton observes the ways of humans
here on Earth. Arriving in Richmond, Virginia in Civil War costume in 1960,
he believes he is just in time to witness the beginnings of the Civil War,
but is off by 100 years. He then decides to observe the customs of 20th
Century American life, including such things as lovemaking rituals and what
people do for entertainment: he watches two people romantically involved
with each other (Holliman &amp; Blackman), billing and cooing at one another,
and ends up getting between them; he goes to a Beatnik nightclub, and
realizes that the Beatniks are more like the aliens he knows than humans.
Lots of hilarious Jerry Lewis mugging, sight-gags and comedy routines,
terrific special effects work by the master John P. Fulton; great flying
saucers! Terrific counterpoint with Lewis' Kreton and his professor back
home, Mr. Delton, played by the distinguished English actor John Williams; a
few Lewis gems: "Keep your nose out of other people's planets", even if you
think "the grass is greener on the other side of the galaxy"! A really fun
picture. I saw this when it first came out in the summer of 1960. Too bad it
wasn't filmed in Technicolor; that's really the only flaw I find in it - it
was made in b&amp;w. It would have been so much better in Technicolor. This is
probably why it wasn't more popular.  Great fun for the whole family, with a
terrific cast. This was Lewis' last studio picture under his old Paramount
contract before he formed his own independent production company; he made
"The Bellboy" in six weeks completely on his own, right after completing
work on this movie, and sold it to Paramount. This would be his arrangement
with the film studio on all his subsequent films of the 1960s at the studio
until he went on to other studios. Delightful for Jerry Lewis fans, and a
delightful music score by Leigh Harline. So why isn't this out on
video?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1305623/comments</url><from>from Charlotte North By God Carolina</from><name>Ghenghy</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Thank you Cinemax for dusting off this rare gem. You don't get too many
chances to see this on the tube. The idea of Jerry Lewis popping in from
8
million light years away in his saucer to help Gen. Lee's troops fight
the
"damn yankees" should be enough incentive for anyone to make time for
this
and it doesnt disappoint. Unfortunately Jerry miscalculated and landed
on
Earth 100 years later-he's a student, not a very smart one but he is
majoring in the "Earth" so his natural curiosity brought him down for a
short stay, much to the frustration and eventual amusement of his mentor
Mr.
Delton on his home planet where his every move is monitored on the first
60"
wide screen I can remember seeing. The movie is just hilarious with
sight
gags galore. I thought I was going to fall out of my chair watching
Jerry
take his first glass of whiskey and then walk up the wall and stand on
the
ceiling to have a conversation with his host. And the Beatnik scene at
the
"Hungry Brain" is a real keeper although many probably wont get
it-beatniks
were the 'way cool' hipsters that preceded the flower child movement of
the
60's. Koo koo baby! Earl Holliman is very funny in an early role and
Joan
Blackman is scrumptious as Holliman's love interest that he can never
seem
to keep his hands off of. She later appeared in two Elvis flicks so you
know
she's got to be pretty hot. Just a great movie and I think ranks in
Lewis'
top three with The Bellboy and The Errand Boy. Don't miss it.
9/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0200612/comments</url><from>from The Beach</from><name>SanDiego</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Film version of Gore Vidal's stage hit was later re-made as TV's Mork and
Mindy.  UFO movies in the 50's and early 60's usually dealt with unfriendly,
intellectually superior aliens out to kill helpless and somewhat naive
humans.  Then comes Jerry Lewis as a friendly, intellectually lacking alien
who is out to study the "human condition."  Most of the gags have been used
and reused again on countless sitcoms but they are done well.  Great
character actors give hilarious supporting performances.  Supposedly Gore
Vidal was not happy with this version of his play.  I've seen Vidal on TV
many times over the years and never once ever seen him laugh or smile so
maybe he has a different definition of comedy than the rest of the planet.  
 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0222418/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Jerry Lewis plays a space man called Kreton, who comes to this small
planet
called Earth.There he meets these weird Earth people and gets in
troubles.Visit to a Small Planet is a nice Jerry Lewis comedy from
1960.It's
not his greatest works, but
it has some funny parts, as Jerry Lewis comedies usually.
Watch the movie if you're a Jerry Lewis fan and even if you're not.Give it
a
chance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur21317354/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ruthann-renaud</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I was five years old when this movie came out and was intrigued more by
the special effects (Jerry floating in air and walking up the wall and
onto the ceiling). It was also of not that this was his last film for
many years where he had someone else direct the film (the veteran
Norman Taurog). From this Jerry went to make his kind of movies. My
parents were big Lewis fans and I am to this day. This may not be up
there with "The Nutty Professor" but it's close. This film also had a
good supporting cast and had a "stagy" look befitting its origins as a
play. I mentioned being intrigued by the FX (floating and walking on
walls). Being a typical kid I thought I could walk on walls and quickly
found out I couldn't. This is definitely something that shouldn't be
tried at home-only in the movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1802829/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>satinspiderr</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

This has to be where Robin Williams drew his inspiration from for Mork of
Ork. While this movie is by no means the funniest fish out of water film
you
could see, I think it still rates a look IF you could just find it
somewhere...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0548344/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>alessio-6</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

This is a rare one to be seen around, so you may want to watch it just
because you might never see it again... but don't expect the same quality
as
other Jerry Lewis movies. Although there are some really funny scenes,
Kreton is not half as funny as that other crazy alien, Mork (played by
Robin
Williams), and the movie lacks action and moves on very slowly through a
thin plot a a lot of standard gags. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0548344/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>alessio-6</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

This is a rare one to be seen around, so you may want to watch it just
because you might never see it again... but don't expect the same quality
as
other Jerry Lewis movies. Although there are some really funny scenes,
Kreton is not half as funny as that other crazy alien, Mork (played by
Robin
Williams), and the movie lacks action and moves on very slowly through a
thin plot a a lot of standard gags. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0548344/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>alessio-6</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>