<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Apartment</original_title><alt_title>La garçonnière</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Billy Wilder</director><producer>Mirisch Corporation, The</producer><genre>Romance</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A man tries to rise in his company by letting its executives use his apartment for trysts, but complications and a romance of his own ensue.
</synopsis><actor>Jack Lemmon</actor><actor>Shirley MacLaine</actor><actor>Fred MacMurray</actor><rt_rating>8.3/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>91</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2066951/comments</url><from>from Chapel Hill, NC, USA</from><name>David (davidals@msn.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Ohhh - after my 4th or 5th viewing, I think this may be one of the most
remarkable blends of comedy and drama to have ever been filmed - THE
APARTMENT - in subtle ways - rises well above the conventions of any
genre. It was my introduction to the great Billy Wilder, and my
fondness for Jack Lemmon (a remarkable and sorely missed actor) begins
here as well.*SOME SPOILERS* The cold take on the sex-and-money ethos to be found in many corporate
environments hasn't dated one bit; it could be argued that THE
APARTMENT stands a bit ahead of its' time in the depiction of (what
would appear to be) educated employees treated like (and feeling like)
tools to be used in generation of someone else's income. Lemmon's
character never forgets that he's disposable, even if the optimist in
him hopes that something better may be found in his superiors. Deep
down he knows this to be a pipe dream - the sexual adventurism of those
same superiors betrays their utter lack of ethics. Of course, Lemmon's
character isn't entirely above it all; he's been more than willing to
hire out his own apartment as a place for his colleagues' peccadilloes,
in exchange for career advancement, which of course - as Wilder early
on links amoral sexual conduct and professional/corporate/financial
misconduct in a greater social critique - gets him into trouble.The dialogue is - as is always true with Wilder - very finely crafted,
yet seems natural - this film is a remarkable display of the kind of
reactions any of us would offer in similar situations. Interestingly,
our two protagonists are also wonderfully imperfect as human beings -
Lemmon and MacLaine bear some responsibility for the very serious
situations they've gotten themselves into; they manage to realize this
("Be a mensch!" Lemmon's doctor neighbor exclaims) just in time to set
things right. MacLaine in particular delivers a remarkable, complex
performance - sweet and smart in her earliest scenes, bleak and
emotionally ravaged in her climactic scene with MacMurray, naive
elsewhere, sharp but hopeful at the end. The cinematography captures
the entire cast beautifully - with minimal movement, abundant long
takes, and a sleek lack of visual clutter, all of the principals are
free to reveal their own best and worst impulses, within an environment
that is stripped of artifice. The end result is a film filled with
great moments one can easily identify with.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1579047/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>gaityr</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

What a wonderful way to spend an evening--dinner, Christmas and New Year's
with CC Baxter (Jack Lemmon) and 'friends', accompanied by much champagne
and laughter, and spaghetti and meatballs lovingly prepared by the host
himself. There's even a game of gin rummy to get into that Baxter and Fran
can't ever seem to finish--here's hoping it never does!THE APARTMENT is one of those truly classic classic movies--for one thing,
it has an absolutely top-notch cast, featuring Jack Lemmon (at his wryly
humourous best); Shirley MacLaine (a glowing screen presence); Fred
MacMurray (smarm personified); and a younger Ray Walston (still
wisecracking, still hilarious). They also benefit from a clever, perceptive
and timelessly relevant script by Billy Wilder, under his capable direction.
Though there are plenty of brilliant one-liners, the best of the dialogue
feels true and real, which adds to the feeling that you've known Baxter et
al for years. I loved the score to the movie as well, artfully attributed to
the Rickshaw Boys and used to great effect.There are so many good moments scattered throughout the film (I can't even
begin to enumerate them all here!). A lot of them are little touches that
must have been added by the actors themselves (Jack Lemmon humming as he
prepares the meatball sauce is just *so* funny!). I love the madness of the
Christmas party scene, and when Baxter's doctor-neighbour takes charge of
the situation with Fran, slapping her awake and marching her around the
living room. I also love it when Baxter first starts playing gin rummy with
Fran, and she reveals how she has a talent for falling for the wrong guy all
the time. Best of all, Lemmon makes such a believable, sweet pushover that
you often want to shake him and hug him at the same time--the things he
would do for Fran! It makes his final scene with MacMurray that much more
satisfying for the audience.If you see this gem of a movie on a video store shelf, or (even better)
playing in the cinema, don't let it pass you by. Join Baxter, Fran, Mr.
Sheldrake and everyone else, and have a great time! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2158588/comments</url><from>from Orlando, FL</from><name>cwelty1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Written by the great filmmaker Billy Wilder, this is a serious,
sardonic comedy for people who've known what's its like to feel the
pressure of compromising your principles or your self- respect for the
sake of getting ahead in life. And there are very few over the age of
consent who haven't had to at one time or another. This isn't the laugh
out loud comedy of Jim Carrey or the Farrelly brothers, but a subtle,
nuanced comedy about two people who have both been jaded in love and
yet continue to hope again and again that it will someday work out for
them -- mainly because despite the unlikeable things they do, they are
both basically decent, nice people. Flawed and even weak at times, but
good people. This is a movie that doesn't just make it you laugh, it
makes you think. A rare find indeed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2215962/comments</url><from>from Santa Cruz, CA</from><name> (jtmudge)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Billy Wilder knew how to make a great movie. Of course it helps to have
one of the greatest all-time actors, Jack Lemon, play in your movies,
but Lemon aside, Wilder was a genius. His gift for the comedic moment
showed brilliantly on screen and reached deep inside the audience.The Apartment, the last of the great Black and White films, showed a
bit darker side to comedy than some of his other romps such as the
hilarious Some Like It Hot. Some Like It Hot is just as funny today as
it was in 1959. It is pure fun. At no point in the film are we
approached with anything that we would take seriously. Let's face it,
most of us are not running from the mob disguised as a member from the
opposite sex.The Apartment, however, brings up much more human themes and issues.
Wilder is an expert and at no time does he leave you worried that it
will turn out badly. This is, after all, a comedy. One mistake in the
script and the movie could quickly become a deep film about suicide,
loneliness, and peer pressure, but Wilder balances the subjects on the
edge of a knife and allows us to smile at what could otherwise be a
very depressing movie.Wilder and his films like The Apartment are very similar to
Shakespeare's comedies. It can be said that the difference between a
Shakespeare comedy and tragedy is often not the story, but the ending.
In a comedy, everyone is married; in a tragedy, everyone dies. the same
is true with The Apartment, it all hinges on the outcomes. If Kubelik
dies or Baxter is left alone, the movie would be a tragedy. But since
they prevail in the end, the movie comes off as a great comedic
success, albeit a bit dark.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1394028/comments</url><from>from los angeles, CA</from><name>john zapata (johnpaulzpt@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

After the first time I saw The Apartment, I admired it so much and placed it
in my favorite  movies list. After watching it a second time on widescreen
and digitally remastered DVD, my love for it just deepened. I was once again
touched by Shirley MacLaine's portrayal of Miss Kubelik, a lovely but
unlucky in love woman. I also laughed again at Jack Lemmon's perfect
delivery of one-liners and other mannerisms. Billy Wilder made The Apartment right after the huge success of his last
film, Some Like It Hot,  also with Jack Lemmon. The Apartment is not as
funny, but it is more accomplished and deeper in meaning. Watching it in
widescreen made me appreciate more the complexity of the story. Widescreen
shots of C.C. Baxter's (Lemmon) apartment shows emptiness and loneliness.
The shot of Baxter's office, which has employees in desks that seem to
extend into eternity, shows that Baxter is just a faceless man in a
populated world. C.C. Baxter is an ambitious employee in an insurance company. He tries to
work himself to a promotion by allowing his philandering bosses to use his
apartment as a perfect hideaway. As an exchange for the use of his
apartment, his bosses put him in the top ten of the efficiency reports.
After getting a promotion and successfully asking the elevator girl Fran
Kubelik (Shirley MacLaine) on a date, everything was going well for Baxter.
Until he finds out that Miss Kubelik is the mistress of his big boss J.D.
Sheldrake (Fred MacMurray).Miss Kubelik and Sheldrake had a summer affair and Sheldrake wants Kubelik
back admitting that he still loves her. Showing vulnerability, she agrees to
get back together and ends up using Baxter's apartment twice a week.
Naturally there will be problems. Sheldrake could not break up his marriage,
and Kubelik does not like how the relationship is going but couldn't help
being in love with him. Kubelik summed it up when she said `when you're in
love with a married man, you shouldn't wear mascara.'For Baxter, things couldn't be more complex. He wants to keep getting
promotions but he might lose Kubelik in the process. He adores Kubelik but
he doesn't want to be unemployed. Billy Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's script
couldn't have been better written. It ranks up there with the likes of great
scripts of Casablanca and Citizen Kane. They filled it with small intricate
details and such funny lines. The Apartment is very ingenious and
inspirational. When I wasn't laughing, I was smiling. Billy Wilder perfected the style of satirical filmmaking. In The Apartment,
he touches a lot of subjects. The movie deals with adultery, suicide,
loneliness, and corporate cutthroats. The movie won five Academy Awards,
including Best Picture, but surprisingly, no acting Oscars. I have seen many
romantic comedies, and while many are good, most of them do not have the
same heart and warmth as The Apartment. It is in my list of top ten favorite
movies because it entertained me, inspired me, and showed me how to live…
human-wise. 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
One of the finest examples of smart, satiric comedy-drama ever created
for the screen. Jack Lemmon (in amazing comic form) plays a working
stiff in Corporate America--via New York City--whose bachelor apartment
inadvertently becomes a love-nest for amorous, married executives. The
film is extremely modern for 1960 and features a non-stop barrage of
funny, clever talk. Lemmon is a mad genius at frenzied (yet
sympathetic) characterization, and "The Apartment" catches him at his
professional peak in the movies. Working alongside huggable neurotic
Shirley MacLaine (also at her peak) and shady Fred MacMurray (parlaying
his slimeball role with curt persuasion), Lemmon creates a new kind of
acting: screwball realism. **** from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
In the recent biography of Billy Wilder by Ed Sikov, it is mentioned
that for the first time Wilder used as his protagonist a lovable loser.
Think about it. In a whole lot of his previous films the main lead in
Ace in the Hole, Double Indemnity, Stalag 17 are the people who are the
takers as Shirley MacLaine describes Fred MacMurray here.In The Apartment, it's the schnook that's took who the story focuses
on. Jack Lemmon creates one of his immortal characters in C.C. Baxter,
a minor cog in the machinery of the insurance company he works for.Lemmon has maybe found a way to move up the corporate ladder, but it's
driving him nuts. He lives on West 67 Street in Manhattan, a most
convenient location for kanoodling. Only it isn't him that kanoodles.
One time he allowed one of the middle level managers to use his
apartment for a little nookie. One guy tells another and so on and so
on and pretty soon Lemmon can't call his place his own.In walks big boss Fred MacMurray to seemingly save the situation. But
it turns out he only wants exclusive use for himself and he actually
does vault Baxter several steps up the corporate ladder. And
unfortunately MacMurray is currently kanoodling with elevator operator
Shirley MacLaine who Lemmon has a thing for.The Apartment was years ahead of its time in that it was one of the
first major films to deal with sexual harassment. The whole group of
middle executives Ray Walston, David Lewis, Willard Waterman, David
White and the big cheese Fred MacMurray just look on that insurance
company as one gigantic harem. As typical for 1960 note there are no
women in any managerial positions at all.Fred MacMurray almost didn't play Mr. Sheldrake. Paul Douglas was cast
originally, but died suddenly just before shooting on The Apartment
commenced. MacMurray stepped in and got great critical reviews for
another effort with Billy Wilder as a heavy. MacMurray was also
starting at this time a long run in the family comedy My Three Sons on
television. There would be no more bad guys in his future.Billy Wilder held out in casting for Jack Kruschen as Doctor Dreyfus
the next door neighbor who is available to save Shirley MacLaine's
life. The folks at United Artists were ready to sign Groucho Marx for
the part. Wilder's faith in Kruschen was justified, he got an Oscar
nomination for Best Supporting Actor, but lost to Peter Ustinov for
Spartacus. Lemmon and MacLaine were also nominated for the leads, but failed to
win. But The Apartment was chosen Best Film of 1960 and Billy Wilder
was Best Director.Also look out for a biting performance by Edie Adams who really makes
her role count as MacMurray's secretary and former flame. During a
Christmas party she tips off MacLaine to MacMurray's philandering ways
and then later on brings the house of cards all around Fred.The Apartment is so timeless in so many ways although women in the
workplace have made great strides in the last 46 years. One thing
though that does show how dated it is. It's mentioned that Lemmon pays
$94.00 a month, presumably rent controlled, for a one bedroom apartment
in the West Sixties in Manhattan.Now that is dated.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0099933/comments</url><from>from Langley</from><name>Primtime</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Jack Lemmon is the man.The Apartment really surprised me. The Best Picture winner starts off
right
in the middle of the action, but yet the first hour seems long and
overrun.
Too much time seems spent in trying to develop the characters (and oh so
many of them) and not enough time is spent on just seeing what will
happen.
Just when I was about to lose faith, the film picks it up like I have
never
seen before. The whole sub-plot of the four guys wanting to use Lemmon's
apartment for their evening tyrsts is dropped and Wilder smartly
concentrates on Lemmon, MacLaine and MacMurray and the film creates true
magic.The Apartment is more of a drama than a comedy and balances the two
elements
perfectly. Just after one of the more dramatic moments of the film, we see
Lemmon straining his pasta with a tennis racquet. The use of the doctor
and
his wife in supporting roles are completely there for comedy and yet add
so
much to the film. The ending also rates up there with the best of all time
using an old device that doesn't seem at all cliched in this film. Some
say
that "Some like it hot" was Wilder's best, but now I have to disagree. The
Apartment is better and surely would have made my top ten had the first
hour
not been so predictable.How Jack Lemmon didn't win Best Actor is beyond me. His is a great
performance, getting to act on more than one scale. MacMurray, another
Wilder favourite is perfectly cast in the role of a family-wrecker. I wish
they would have put a scene in which his wife confronts him with "The
News".
MacLaine glows on the screen even when she is sick and in bed.I fully recommend this film to all, it being Wilder's best makes it a must
see.8/10 stars.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0088706/comments</url><from>from Ocean Beach</from><name>DukeofPearl</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Billy Wilder's "The Apartment" is a film which can produce some of the
biggest laughs and at the same time... can bring many viewers to tears,
Billy Wilder's quaint little tale about everyday people who get tangled
up in love, jealousy and infidelity boasts a top-notch cast led by the
trio of Lemmon, MacLaine and MacMurray who are tremendous. The plot
revolves around C.C. (Lemmon) who unknowingly makes the unethical
attempt of climbing the corporate ladder by 'loaning' his apartment to
members from his management chain to entertain their 'women on the
side'. Given the change of circumstances, this premise certainly could
even hit home in the current office environment. Although the office
party and secretarial gossip scenes could be viewed as dated, the power
and attitude of the corporate executive, Mr. Sheldrake (MacMurray) is
certainly symbolic. The character of Fran (MacLaine) for today's
standards of course seems too submissive and vulnerable but the reward
of her finding true, admirable, unconditional companionship is quite
enriching and fulfilling to any who see this memorable film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467778/comments</url><from>from Tijuana, Baja California, Mexico</from><name>mgrindberg</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A struggling office worker in a giant insurance company lends his
apartment to higher ups in order to get a promotion. Set during the
Holidays, the theme of infidelity turned a lot of viewers off. The
Holiday setting however is what provides a lot of the film's best
scenes, as in the fantastic office Christmas party where the
secretaries are doing a CanCan on the table and couples are making out
in the corner. The one-two punch of Jack Lemmon's classic performance
and that of Fred MacMurray is fabulous, and the triangle of sorts that
forms with Shirley McClaine makes this much more than the comedy that
it is known for.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467778/comments</url><from>from Tijuana, Baja California, Mexico</from><name>mgrindberg</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A struggling office worker in a giant insurance company lends his
apartment to higher ups in order to get a promotion. Set during the
Holidays, the theme of infidelity turned a lot of viewers off. The
Holiday setting however is what provides a lot of the film's best
scenes, as in the fantastic office Christmas party where the
secretaries are doing a CanCan on the table and couples are making out
in the corner. The one-two punch of Jack Lemmon's classic performance
and that of Fred MacMurray is fabulous, and the triangle of sorts that
forms with Shirley McClaine makes this much more than the comedy that
it is known for.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467778/comments</url><from>from Tijuana, Baja California, Mexico</from><name>mgrindberg</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/matt-brunson/</url><url>http://blogs.creativeloafing.com/theclog/2010/03/12/checking-out-the-apartment/ /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1874733</url><name>Matt Brunson</name><from>Creative Loafing</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>A screen gem that attained classic status in about as much time as it takes to comb one's hair.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,874130,00.html /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1797566</url><from>TIME Magazine</from></reviewer><comment>A comedy of men's-room humours and water-cooler politics that now and then among the belly laughs says something serious and sad about the struggle for success, about what it often does to a man, and about the horribly small world of big business.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-french/</url><url>http://film.guardian.co.uk/News_Story/Critic_Review/Observer_review/0,,412372,00.html /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1768950</url><name>Philip French</name><from>Observer [UK]</from></reviewer><comment>[Lemmon's character is] a whingeing, self-pitying figure who, like other Wilder practitioners, cannot recognise the extent of his turpitude, and this is both the strength and weakness of a remarkable movie.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/peter-bradshaw/</url><url>http://film.guardian.co.uk/News_Story/Critic_Review/Guardian_review/0,,2290094,00.html /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1768951</url><name>Peter Bradshaw</name><from>Guardian [UK]</from></reviewer><comment>Not to be missed on any account.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/daniel-etherington/</url><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=100560 /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1755592</url><name>Daniel Etherington</name><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>A true classic. It's about advancement, ambition, corruption and adultery, and it operates as both a satire and a sorrowful romance.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-berardinelli/</url><url>http://www.reelviews.net/php_review_template.php?identifier=775 /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1733845</url><name>James Berardinelli</name><from>ReelViews</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>With tremendous performances by the two leads (Lemmon and Shirley MacLaine), this is yet another "must see" title to be found on Wilder's resume.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>/m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1717076</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Ah, Lemmon and MacLaine... what poetic chemistry.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117488039.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1662894</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment> Most of the time, it's up to director Wilder to sustain a two-hour-plus film on treatment alone, a feat he manages to accomplish more often than not, and sometimes the results are amazing.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/apartment.htm /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1607296</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>The overlong drawn-out one-hook themed Apartment seemed a tad more bare than furnished.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/joe-baltake/</url><url>http://thepassionatemoviegoer.blogspot.com/2006/08/apartment-film-that-defines-me.html /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1598678</url><name>Joe Baltake</name><from>Passionate Moviegoer</from></reviewer><comment>'The Apartment': The Film That Defines Me</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/apartment.shtml /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1567929</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>Billy Wilder somehow took a story about infidelity and suicide and made it into a comedy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/454_APARTMENT /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1562076</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>I wouldn't call this 1960 picture one of Billy Wilder's best comedies -- it's drab, sappy, and overlong at 125 minutes.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/wesley-lovell/</url><url>/m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1556947</url><name>Wesley Lovell</name><from>Oscar Guy</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>Billy Wilder further enhances his filmic resume with this tender portrayal of a lonely man who may soon get what he deserves. Jack Lemmon is terrific.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/78098/the_apartment.html /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1518365</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Diamond-sharp satire with a brilliant performance from Lemmon.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/apartment-the-1960-3/ /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1398746</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Billy Wilder's second film to win the Best Picture Oscar, this bitter-sweet tale "little people" in the urban jungle is well-acted by Jack Lemmon and Shirley MacLaine.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-villarreal/</url><url>http://www.azstarnet.com/sn/ent_movies/73613.php /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1386707</url><name>Phil Villarreal</name><from>Arizona Daily Star</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>Humanism and cleverness age like fine wine, even if served with spaghetti strained with a tennis racket.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-cornelius/</url><url>http://efilmcritic.com/review.php?movie=3330&amp;reviewer=392 /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1359361</url><name>David Cornelius</name><from>eFilmCritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>It's one of the most heartbreaking films I've ever seen.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bob-bloom/</url><url>/m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1254751</url><name>Bob Bloom</name><from>Journal and Courier (Lafayette, IN)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>A classic comedy, showing Billy Wilder at his cynical best.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=1129144</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>It probably seemed more daring in 1960, but it's still adult entertainment in the best sense of the term.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/marjorie-baumgarten/</url><url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gbase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3a141300 /m/1001115-apartment/comments.php?reviewid=850167</url><name>Marjorie Baumgarten</name><from>Austin Chronicle</from></reviewer><comment>This essential Billy Wilder film smoothly combines trenchant social observation with hilarious comedy.</comment></review></movie>