<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>School for Scoundrels</original_title><alt_title>L'académie des coquins</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Robert Hamer</director><producer>Associated British Picture Corporation (ABPC)</producer><producer>Guardsman Films</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
Based on the Stephen Potter "One Upmanship" and "Lifemanship" books, Henry Palfrey tries hard to impress but always loses out to the rotter Delauney...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ian Carmichael</actor><actor>Terry-Thomas</actor><actor>Alastair Sim</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3891292/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>freddievalentine</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This fabulous film is available on DVD at last, twinned with another
Alaister Sim classic, THE GREEN MAN. But, the star of this film is the
dapper TERRY-THOMAS. Every scene he is in is superb. From the suave cad
in the first half of the film to the flustered toff in the second, this
is one of his finest performances and stands up to repeat viewings due
to his expressive faces and masterful comic timing.I hear there is going to be a Hollywood remake of this film, which will
be a huge mistake as there has been no one like T-T since. I recommend
anyone who is a fan of British comedy to see this classic or you will
forever be crying 'hard cheese'!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2527294/comments</url><from>from notts, england</from><name>ianginge</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is the ultimate Terry Thomas film. He gets to act out being the most
wonderful cad, stealing girls off poor saps arms, driving open top sports
cars are a furious pace, and generally getting the chance to utter 'hard
cheese old boy'.
Carmicheal is excellent, bewildered to begin with and slowly learning the
dark arts of Upmanship.
I implore all to see this film, as always the golden rule is - if a film
as
Alistair Sim in it, its got to be worth a look.
Currently avialable on a 2 film DVD release, with another UK B&amp;W comedy
classic.
Buy and enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0219957/comments</url><from/><name>Richard Spurr</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I cannot remember how many times I have watched this film now - it takes me
back to a time of charming English etiquette which, being too young, I never
witnessed.  The range of social situations through which we are taken in the
apprenticeship of 'Lifemanship' are hilarious, and in a gentle and
exquisitely-understated way.  Ian Carmichael is, of course excellent, but my
all-time hero, Terry-Thomas, is on the toppest of forms delivering the
"Look's like a Polish stomach pump" and "Oh I say, smashing cricket stroke"
lines with his unshakeable aplomb.  A nostalgic treasure of a
film. 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3399108/comments</url><from>from New Zealand</from><name>mundsen</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Don't hesitate: this jolly little movie is pretty much impeccable.An excellent script, which never falters. And a BOFFO cast of British
actors. The quintessential role for Terry-Thomas (tho' "Magnificent
Men" is a close second).But also fine turns from Alistair Sim, John Le Mesurier, Hugh Paddick,
Peter Jones. Hattie Jacques does an hilarious voice-parody of Joan
Greenwood. Janette Scott is VERY good in a thankless "skirt" role; what
a charming personality.Old car fans will love this. The sport-cars and the mocked-up vintage
"Swiftmobile" are worth the price of admission alone. (Sadly, the
production designer / props chaps are as yet uncredited at IMDb:
perhaps the information is lost.) Very nice camera-setups. Amusingly
cheesy sets. A really excellent score from John Addison that is up to
Georges Auric's standard.This has a very jolly, intimate ambiance: a sense of small scale. Feels
rather like the b&amp;w Tati movies.Ahem. Unlike many British comedies, I can really see the attraction of
remaking this: the material is so damned good that it could use another
go-round, without necessarily insulting the original.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2014741/comments</url><from>from washington, D.C.</from><name>andrew</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I read all the Stephen Potter books and this movie captures their charm
and
wit perfectly.  I especially love how Ian Carmichael, as the fledgling
gamesman, gets sweet revenge on the car salesman who dealt him an antique
lemon. And just to look at Terry Thomas' twitching moustache and gapped
tooth semi-sneer sent me into convulsions.  A perfect 10!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When Henry Palfrey meets the lovely young April Smith he thinks he has
things good.  However a meeting with them and Raymond Delauney sees Palfrey
made to look a fool by the caddish Delauney.  To counter his wishy washy
ways, Palfrey joins the `Lifemanship' school of Mr Potter.  Here he learns
all the ploys of a cad.  Upon completion of the course he sets his sight on
Delauney – but can he avoid becoming that which he hates?Terry Thomas is famous for his lecherous wretch and here he not only plays
it to perfection, but also gets out played at his own game.  The plot here
is in three acts.  Firstly the caddish Delauney outplays Palfrey. Second act
Palfrey attends the school and finally Palfrey returns to his life a changed
man.  All three acts play out very well for different reasons, only the end
of act 3 drags a little bit but ends well.  The gentle comedy of the time
runs through it – it is a very English film in its own way.  I enjoyed the
vast majority of it.Ian Carmichael appears a weak choice for the lead but his transformation
from coward to cad is well played and he was actually very good.  Thomas is
well cast although this is what he is famous for I suppose.  Sim is pretty
good but given too little to do and there are some nice little cameos from
Hattie Jacques and (even better) John Le Mesurier.Overall this is very slight but it is also very enjoyable.  It isn't
hilarious but it is a very enjoyable film with a good sense of wicked humour
running through the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16161013/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>JohnRouseMerriottChard</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Humilliated in sport,losing his girl to a cad, and always taken
advantage of-Henry Palfrey decides enough is enough and enrols himself
at the College Of Lifemanship to learn self improvement strategies.School For Scoundrels is inspired by a trio of parody self-help books
written by Stephen Potter called Gamesmanship, Lifemanship &amp;
Oneupmanship, with the subsequent result being a deftly charming satire
backed up with very knowing comedy. Taking the lead role of Henry
Palfrey is Ian Carmichael, tho a star of many funny and successful
British comedies, Carmichael is not someone I would normally term as a
confident leading man, but here he does well and I think that is
probably down to having the ebullient Terry-Thomas to feed off.
Terry-Thomas is here in full caddish rapscallion mode as Henry's love
rival Raymond Delauney, a devilishly funny character who firmly has us
begging Henry to get the better of him come the end. Some delightful
laughs to be had here, from the duos tennis matches, to Henry's turning
of the tables on an unscrupulous car salesmen. School For Scoundrels is
never ever less than a funny movie.However the film is far from perfect, Alistair Sim isn't given that
much to do as Henry's mentor, Professor Stephen Potter, and this
ultimately feels like a wasted opportunity. The direction is also
pretty patchy, which when I delved further is sadly understandable.
Robert Hamer was the perfect choice to direct because nestling on his
CV is the majestic Kind Hearts And Coronets. But Hamer was fired
shortly after filming began after lapsing back into alcoholism {he
would die three years later}, so the film was completed by Hal Chester
and Cyril Frankel.Frayed edges aside tho, School For Soudrels still holds up well today,
and when one witnesses the poor standard of the 2006 remake, this 1960
offering is something of a comedic gem to be cherished forever and
always.Hard cheese old boy 8/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0158105/comments</url><from>from Ascot, England</from><name>adam jezard</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Stephen Potter's biography tells that, before this happy film version was
made, Cary Grant was keen, with American producer Carl Foreman, to make a
film about Potter's brilliant (now sadly out-of-print)Oneupmanship books.
The problem that confronted Grand and Foreman was that they couldn't find
anyway to make the humour "American". In the end they dropped it and this
rather Ealing-esque film was made instead. This film is just great fun and a
reminder of what British cinema at its best can offer. Thank goodness Grant
and Foreman didn't give it the "American" treatment. Thank heavens also for
a sterling case, in which Terry-Thomas particularly stands out. Tennis,
anyone?   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0797119/comments</url><from>from Kent, England</from><name>heyyoubigthumb</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This film is perfect for a rainy Sunday afternoon, when you can set back
and
enjoy a sunny English summer, complete with cads, bounders and unsportsmen
like behaviour. Lovely. This is the perfect Terry-Thomas movie, doing
exactly what he does best, being suave and impressing the ladies with his
nifty sportscar and well waxed moustouche. Tip Top.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0730547/comments</url><from/><name>mcgoverngarrett</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I first saw this film about ten years ago and in that time I must have seen
it two hundred times.It stands for everything great in British comedy.It
tells the story of a young man who always seems to come a cropper in the
lifeman stakes.He joins  classes for one-upmanship and turns into an
arrogant idiot.Alastair Sim is at his lugrubious best.Terry-Thomas plays the bounder to a
tee with some wonderful lines.If I have one gripe it's the casting of Ian
Carmichael in the lead role.Leslie Philips would have been much better But
that's a personal choice.Now I'm off to watch it again for the two hundred and first time! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0730547/comments</url><from/><name>mcgoverngarrett</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I first saw this film about ten years ago and in that time I must have seen
it two hundred times.It stands for everything great in British comedy.It
tells the story of a young man who always seems to come a cropper in the
lifeman stakes.He joins  classes for one-upmanship and turns into an
arrogant idiot.Alastair Sim is at his lugrubious best.Terry-Thomas plays the bounder to a
tee with some wonderful lines.If I have one gripe it's the casting of Ian
Carmichael in the lead role.Leslie Philips would have been much better But
that's a personal choice.Now I'm off to watch it again for the two hundred and first time! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0730547/comments</url><from/><name>mcgoverngarrett</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794679.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1061238-school_for_scoundrels/comments.php?reviewid=1808083</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/74127/school_for_scoundrels.html /m/1061238-school_for_scoundrels/comments.php?reviewid=1653474</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=108015 /m/1061238-school_for_scoundrels/comments.php?reviewid=1147797</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>