<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ten Who Dared</original_title><imdb_rating>5.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>William Beaudine</director><producer>Walt Disney Productions</producer><genre>Family</genre><genre>Western</genre><synopsis/><actor>Brian Keith</actor><actor>John Beal</actor><actor>James Drury</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0645539/comments</url><from>from Bath, UK</from><name>billyhitchcock (billy_hitchcock@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Many of the Disney live-action films from the 50's and 60's are too
easily derided these days for their sepia-toned view of the past, and
American past in particular. The main example of this would be Disney's
interpretation of Davy Crockett. But without Walt's enthusiasm for the
creation of America and it's people many a folk hero would be lost in
time. So even though Disney may have painted a sugar-coated vision of
these stories at least they were brought to the attention of a wider
audience who could then discover them for real.Ten Who Dared is a perfect example of this with it's exploration (pun
intended) of the adventures of John Wesley Powell and his team who were
the first people to explore and chart the Colorado River through the
Grand Canyon in 1869.As you can expect they get in to some scrapes with Native Americans as
well as the river itself and a rebellion in the camp has some dire
consequences.Although the film may not sit with the best westerns ever made it is a
fun journey, with a group of characters recognisable to any fan of men-
on-a-mission movies, and is a great way to spend 90 minutes and learn
some American history at the same time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

Supposedly factual account of the first group of men to explore the
mysterious Colorado River, led by one-armed Civil War Major John Wesley
Powell. Disney-made adventure isn't well-produced or well-written, but it
does have a sort of ambling charm. Brian Keith is terrific as usual
playing
a grizzled amateur astrologist, Ben Johnson lends his solid support, but
who
is responsible for casting John Beal as Powell? He's unbearably wooden and
has about as much screen-appeal as a desert tortoise. Overall, pretty
slack,
and not likely to engage youngsters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

Supposedly factual account of the first group of men to explore the
mysterious Colorado River, led by one-armed Civil War Major John Wesley
Powell. Disney-made adventure isn't well-produced or well-written, but it
does have a sort of ambling charm. Brian Keith is terrific as usual
playing
a grizzled amateur astrologist, Ben Johnson lends his solid support, but
who
is responsible for casting John Beal as Powell? He's unbearably wooden and
has about as much screen-appeal as a desert tortoise. Overall, pretty
slack,
and not likely to engage youngsters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>