<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Plein soleil</original_title><imdb_rating>7.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>René Clément</director><producer>Robert et Raymond Hakim</producer><producer>Paris Film</producer><producer>Paritalia</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Tom Ripley is a talented mimic, moocher, forger and all-around criminal improviser; but there's more to Tom Ripley than even he can guess.
</synopsis><actor>Alain Delon</actor><actor>Maurice Ronet</actor><actor>Marie Laforêt</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14508164/comments</url><from>from Paris, France</from><name>alainbenoix</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I saw Minghella's "The Talented Mr. Ripley" and Clement's "Purple Noon"
back to back. Two entirely different movies based on exactly the same
book. The differences are personal of course. Minghella has a
moralistic view of his characters and their darkness must be, somehow,
explained if not justified. Clement's allows the amorality of his
characters to run loose. Minghella casts Matt Damon as Tom Ripley, a
rather invisible actor in every way and although he's pretty good here,
he's not good enough to overshadow his rival: Jude Law. Clement casts
Alain Delon as Ripley and you will be with him all the way, you'll go
where he goes you will turn out to be as amoral as he is - at least I
did, I just wanted him to get away with it and why? Because he was
Alain Delon, the Tom Ripley that, clearly, Patricia Highsmith intended.
His rival is Maurice Ronet, good as he is, I didn't miss him when he
left. You know why? Because I was left with the dangerous, magnetic,
amoral, riveting Alain Delon. Clement allows us to see the difficulty
and danger of the murders, we see them, we are there. Minghella plays
it rather hurriedly. There is no real tension or horror. The most
suspenseful moment is at an Opera house. The pluses on "The Talented Mr
Ripley" - besides the aforementioned Jude Law - are Gwyneth Paltrow and
Cate Blanchett in two beautifully written and performed parts. In
"Purple Noon" Marie Laforet is left rather to her own devices. Once all
said and done you can watch both films as if they weren't even related.
I prefer "Purple Noon" but that's just me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3618252/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>rlshuster</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Extremely well done, tightly edited, well acted (by everyone, including
the small roles, especially the actor who has to appear dead with long
camera shots in a tense scene in the hotel). Delon is perfectly cast,
with his calculating cool. The cinematography is gorgeous, especially the scenes on the
yacht---nothing gimmicky, but shot with an expertise that gives true
drama to the action. You can feel the waves, the wind, and the sun. The
colors are vibrant on the DVD. Though a scene like this in a typical
movie today would include a heavy ominous score, the director simply
lets the sound of the wind create the tension. The score (by Nina
Rota), in fact, is understated, unlike anything today. Even the opening
credits have style.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0904645/comments</url><from/><name>tonstant viewer</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I found this film more interesting than the recent Minghella opus because
the people were more disturbing. Alain Delon is too good-looking to be dismissed as the geeky wannabee Matt
Damon plays. His insanity in a pretty package is as unsettling as Gene
Tierney's in "Leave Her to Heaven." Delon looks like Maurice Ronet's
brother, and you can see him wonder why if he's just as handsome as the
other guy, why doesn't he have as much money? Ronet is more unpredictable
than Jude Law as the whimsical rich boy and his death is every bit as
shocking.I can't imagine that Anthony Minghella hadn't seen this version before
making his own. He probably regrets Scorsese's reconstruction of Rene
Clement's film so we can all make the comparison. Some scenes play like a
shot-for-shot remake. Billy Kearns's brutal Freddy Miles is an obvious
template for Philip Seymour Hoffman's more calculated and less powerful
performance, and Gwyneth Paltrow's final breakdown is VERY close to that of
Marie Laforet's.All through the 1999 film, I kept wondering why everybody couldn't see what
was wrong with the toad-like Damon. In this one, Delon's plausible, even
glamorous exterior made the success of his deceptions more understandable,
and more frightening.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0679729/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>J. Spurlin</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I'm fascinated by a scene at a restaurant. We get an extreme close-up
of a woman who is kept out of focus while another character in the
background, who is speaking and is in the center of the shot, remains
in focus. Is the woman who is out of focus important or not? More to
the point, was shooting it this way a good idea? It illustrates by
contrast how sure-footed René Clément is most of the time. Usually
there can be no debate.I wasn't familiar with Clément's work until this film, but my God, he's
good. His camera is always in some unexpected place that enhances the
drama and tightens the suspense. He shares that talent with Orson
Welles (meaning the Welles of "Citizen Kane" and "The Magnificent
Ambersons," not, say, "Lady from Shanghai"), who also made decisions
that are surprising yet invariably right.Tom Ripley (Alain Delon) and Phillipe Greenleaf (Maurice Ronet) are
lately inseparable friends. They're both idling in Europe, but on papa
Greenleaf's dime. Phillipe's fiancée Marge (Marie Laforêt) feels sorry
for Tom but resents his presence. Phillipe's other friend, Freddie
(Billy Kearns), considers Tom Ripley a worthless moocher. But there's
more to Tom Ripley, the mimic, the forger, the talented criminal
improviser, than anyone, even Tom Ripley himself, can guess.Alain Delon, with his chiseled looks and cold beauty, makes an
excellent Tom Ripley. The script is brilliantly adapted from Patricia
Highsmith's terrific suspense novel, "The Talented Mr. Ripley": the
dialogue is always bringing the themes of duplicity, love, self-love,
the nature of identity, ruthlessness and murder to the surface where
they are given a brilliant sheen by Clément and his cinematographer
Henri Decaë. We're left to figure things out for ourselves, which is rare. Do we
need to be told what Tom thinks of when he sees all those dead fish?
When a door with a mirror swings open toward Tom, do we need to see
Tom's mirror image to understand the mirror's significance? Or is it
enough that we know there's a mirror next to Tom? I know what the
answers would have been in Hollywood—in 1960 and now. Here, the answers
are no, no and yes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1763368/comments</url><from>from Planet Earth</from><name>Carrie k</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Up until he starred in this movie, Alain Delon was considered a light
romantic lead--not surprising at all since his breathtaking good looks
would
naturally lend itself to that sort of matinee idol typecasting.  It was
only
when director Rene Clement tapped into the dangerous undercurrent held in
reserve behind the placid, beautiful surface that Delon's wholly unique,
dark, sociopathic persona would emerge--the persona which would put him on
the map and he would forever be identified with.  In "Plein Soleil" AKA
"Purple Noon," Delon exudes all the stealth and sleekness of a
panther--dark-haired, riveting gaze, smoldering, seductive and sinister.
And like a panther, he proves himself to be just as lethal.  Delon stars as
Tom Ripley, a pretty-but-poor young man who takes off to Rome as an errand
boy to fetch the wayward Philippe Greenleaf (Maurice Ronet), and bring him
back home to San Francisco to his impatient, rich father in exchange for
$5000.  Not surprisingly, the spoiled, unsupervised Philippe doesn't want
to
return and give up his profligate, libertine lifestyle, and neither does
Tom, when he gets a taste of how the other half lives.  And he soon
determines he doesn't have to, when he concocts to take over Phillippe's
money, his beautiful girlfriend Marge Duval (Marie Laforet), his identity.
But of course, even in a perfect scheme devised by a cunning mind, one
can't
plan for everything and things eventually go south for our man
Ripley.I haven't read the Patricia Highsmith book on which this is based, but I've
seen the other film version of it, "The Talented Mr. Ripley" so I have only
that to compare it with.  First the titles: The latter one gets right to
the
point and is intriguing for that; the original has a certain romantic
appeal, but is sinister behind the pretty sound of it--it portends of dark
(purple) clouds (of evil) converging upon a bright sunlit horizon.  The
latter film has outward homoerotic aspects that is very latent in this
version (so much so that those expecting it to be overt will probably not
notice--but it had to be given the era in which the movie was released),
but
it's there all right.  Tom is ostensibly supposed to covet Marge, but even
when she's in a scene with him and Phillippe, the tension and electricity
fairly crackles between the two intense young men, but not with her.
Another difference, and I understand the latter version to be faithful to
the book in this way, is Marge is not affluent, which rather puts her more
in Tom's position as she is also at the mercy of Phillippe's money and
volatile moods, and that lends another aspect to the film.  These
differences I found negligible and didn't take away anything for either
movie to me.However, I must say I found Delon's Ripley far more appealing than Matt
Damon's one.  Not taking anything away from Mr. Damon as he is a capable
actor and an attractive man, but he simply is not in Delon's league, either
in the looks or magnetism department.  Damon really downplayed his pleasant
looks for the role, and I really think that was a minus--he not only looks,
but acts so unsettling that even a new born babe wouldn't take candy from
this man.  Delon, on the other hand, is a much more refreshing villian and,
strangely enough, more believable.  Refreshing because he's such a change
from the usual villians that you would peg right from looking at them
they're a heavy--they look unsavory (or at the very least not attractive).
Believable because despite whatever sinister intentions Delon's Tom might
emit, he's outwardly likeable and what's more, is so devastatingly handsome
that it's easy to see how people would not take their instincts about such
a
person seriously and would let their guard down.  Ronet is fine in his
portrayal as the not-so-nice rich boy Phillippe, but Laforet as Marie--to
me
she came across like an afterthought, she's bland and forgettable, but
that's ok because the dynamics are between the two men, and later with how
Tom handles his predicament.  This being said, I didn't care much for the
pat crime-doesn't-pay finale in this one and thought the latter version far
more satisfying in that respect.  Both are excellent movies in their own
respective ways, I don't know if anyone can really say one vastly outdoes
the other, but see this one  if you want to see Delon unleashed.P.S. Look for Romy Schneider, Delon's fiancee at the time, in the beginning
of the movie as one of Phillippe's companions.  The beautiful,
Austrian-born
Ms. Schneider followed Delon back to France after she fell in love with him
during the making of "Christine."     
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2420383/comments</url><from>from Dallas, Texas</from><name>Lechuguilla</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Visually, this film could serve as a cinematic poster for a
Mediterranean cruise. Cinematographer Henri Decae draws us into the
film with its alluring Italian locales and gorgeous panoramic vistas.
Bright, complementary hues and high color contrast translate into
eye-popping reds and yellows. And, of course, there's the deep blue
color of the sea, and a brilliant sunlit sky. Such is the setting for a
story wherein three attractive, young adults (Tom, Philippe, and Marge)
test a 3-way relationship that is far more complex than it first
appears.Indeed, trouble lurks beneath the surface (so to speak), in this
"Italiano paradiso" thriller. In the first forty minutes, the
psychological motivations of our three beautiful people are unclear and
subject to change. It's hard to tell who is doing what to whom.
Subsequent to this narrative setup, we see exactly where the story is
headed. Because "Plein Soleil" is a psychodrama, casting is important.
The three leads (Alain Delon, Maurice Ronet, and Marie Laforet) are all
convincing in their roles.I have not read the Highsmith novel on which the screenplay was based.
So I cannot make an intertextual analysis. I do think this 1960 film is
superior, for various reasons, to the more recent remake. Adroitly directed by Rene Clement, with a buoyant musical score by Nino
Rota, "Plein Soleil" is a character study of an amoral pleasure seeker
whose charming personality masks the evil within. The juxtaposition of
inwardly criminal intent with outwardly idyllic scenes of Italy and the
Mediterranean results is an art house film that is both picturesque and
suspenseful. It's a film that appeals both to our eyes and to our
brains.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0835751/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>esteban hernandez</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Two stars of the French cinematography, Alain Delon and Maurice Ronet,
combined their efforts in this excellent film, which showed good views of
Rome and Italy in its first half. The second part becomes the decisive one
when Ripley (Delon)jealous of the wealthy position of Philippe Greenleaf
(Ronet) decides to kill him in a yacht. Ripley intelligently was able to
behave and sign bank checks as if he was Greenleaf. Even he conquered the
love of Greenleaf's girl friend, but the end surprised him and everyone
watching the film. This type of films should be among the 250 best of the last century, but for
unknown reasons it is not included.       
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10879013/comments</url><from>from CGSM, Soseaua Nationala 49</from><name>Cristi_Ciopron</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
One of the most exquisite ten thrillersThe work of a very sardonic,mordant,straightforward and prompt
intelligence,Plein Soleil (1960) amazes firstly by its stunning visual
quality;such a film confirms the instinct that makes one reject a whole
quantity of other movies that try to pass as thrillers.When you see
such a movie you instantaneously have the feeling that most other
so-called thrillers are mere bluffs and deceptions. Plein Soleil (1960)
is so sensationally good it is the one worthy heir of
Diabolique;indeed,it ranks with that other masterpiece.Delon's
rancorous ,heartless and evil Tom is the coolest character this actor
ever performed;truly, the chance of a lifetime. His easiness in
Ripley's role is amazing;dressed up,dogged and sharp.Yes,but how almost
equally good is the rest of the cast!And Delon is seconded by the
upbeat and ambiguous,easy-going,cruel and injudicious "Philippe" and
the hearty "Marge".The sordidness of the facts is intact.As
narrative,Full Sun is a wonder of economy.There is a powerful stream of
fresh eroticism,beginning with the fat and lovely blonde picked out by
the two friends,Tom and Philippe.The violence and insanity are of a
Hitchcockian precision and force.These are the innards of violence and
iniquity.And these are the artistic things as one would like to see
them always.The execution is flawless and the showmanship is
impressing.How interesting and thrilling this movie is,how well narrated.The score
is fine and the photography is physically delighting.The movie is a
feast for the intelligence.On the other hand,this kind of algebra is
the product of a lively perspicacity.For the connoisseurs,Full Sun is
matchless.And one of the best movies of the '60s.As such,it reunites
these three privileges:to be one of the best ten thrillers ever;to
offer Delon's best role;to be one of the very best '60s movies.The
atmosphere is one of the main kudos of this suspenseful and lapidary
film.Its director did know cinema.For me,Full Sun was an astounding
experience :one of those films that are so good that surpass all
previous expectations.So,movies do not have to be stupid,clumsy and trite and insipid;on the
contrary,Full Sun shows how they ought to be always:bright and
beautiful,of a striking beauty,with much gusto and having something to
say and straightforward.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8506382/comments</url><from>from Turkey</from><name>buktel</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I watched "The Purple Noon" with the Turkish title "Kizgin Günes" which
means "The Scorching Sun" at cinema Elhamra in Izmir when I was 12 or
so. (My birth date is 1950.) It was the first time when I saw the name
and the image of Alain Delon on a movie poster. On the poster Delon was
seen naked on the upper part of his body, directing a yacht's steering
wheel. Years later I would read Highsmith's "Talented Mr. Ripley" and
realize that, the screenplay of the movie had some fortunate
differences from the book. One of these differences was the interesting dialog between Delon and
Ronet on the latter's yacht just before the murder. This dialog which
is written by the director Rene Clement (or his co-writer Paul
Gogeoff), is, in my opinion, one of the finest, in all film history.
Delon, tells Ronet, as a joke, about his plan to kill him and adopt his
identity. Ronet enjoys the joke and criticizes the plan on its weak
points. Delon logically answers all the criticisms Ronet has made.
Ronet gradually realizes that the plan is too thoughtfully conceived
and too minutely prepared. He begins to suspect that it may not be a
joke. He gets nervous and then frightened, but only too late. Delon,
suddenly initiating to materialize the plan, gets up and stabs Ronet
with a knife. Ronet dies with a shock in his eyes. Delon throws away Ronet's body off the yacht into the sea. But he is
unaware that he has failed to get rid of Ronet's body. At the final
episode of the movie when the yacht is laid on the stocks,
policemen(differently again from the book) find Ronet's moss covered
body entangled with the propellers. In the film, Delon is caught by law
whereas in the book, Ripley is not. After 40 years, all I remember of the film are the things which are
absent (maybe missed) in the book. I also like the Highsmith's book and
don't like the idea of changing books text just for the fancies of
directors of cinema or stage. But Clement's (and Gogeoff's) script, I
think, was full of creativity. I like Minghella's recent version of
"Talented Mr. Ripley" much less than the Highsmith's book and Clement's
film version of it. Minghella, seems to me, among many other things,
especially missed Delon and the Fifties and the subtleties of Clement's
script. After seeing the film and the fascinating personality of Delon as an
actor, I had resolved that I would see any Delon film I would come
across thereafter and did so.COSKUN BUKTEL
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8065404/comments</url><from>from Dallas, TX.</from><name>sunlily</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Purple Noon with Alain Delon, Maurice Ronet,and Marie Laforêt, is the
chilling original to The Talented Mister Ripley. The blindingly
beautiful Mediterranean background serves as a stark contrast to the
lives of three spoiled and amoral characters on holiday in Italy. This
original of The Talented Mr. Ripley is far different from the more
recent movie, with Delon being more believable as Tom Ripley, his
unbelievably handsome face hiding an evil mind, willing to do whatever
it takes to trade places with Philippe Greenleaf.There are some gratuitous shots here for 1960, and I wasn't real
impressed with Maurice Ronet,who seemed too old for the part of
Philippe, but on the whole, an enjoyable experience with great plot
development and cinematography. The movie pulled you in like a day in
the Riviera.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8065404/comments</url><from>from Dallas, TX.</from><name>sunlily</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Purple Noon with Alain Delon, Maurice Ronet,and Marie Laforêt, is the
chilling original to The Talented Mister Ripley. The blindingly
beautiful Mediterranean background serves as a stark contrast to the
lives of three spoiled and amoral characters on holiday in Italy. This
original of The Talented Mr. Ripley is far different from the more
recent movie, with Delon being more believable as Tom Ripley, his
unbelievably handsome face hiding an evil mind, willing to do whatever
it takes to trade places with Philippe Greenleaf.There are some gratuitous shots here for 1960, and I wasn't real
impressed with Maurice Ronet,who seemed too old for the part of
Philippe, but on the whole, an enjoyable experience with great plot
development and cinematography. The movie pulled you in like a day in
the Riviera.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8065404/comments</url><from>from Dallas, TX.</from><name>sunlily</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>