<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The 3 Worlds of Gulliver</original_title><alt_title>Les voyages de Gulliver</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Jack Sher</director><producer>Columbia Pictures</producer><producer>Morningside Productions</producer><genre>Animation</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Family</genre><synopsis>
Doctor Gulliver is poor, so nothing - not even his charming fiancée Elisabeth - keeps him in the town he lives...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Kerwin Mathews</actor><actor>Jo Morrow</actor><actor>June Thorburn</actor><rt_rating>5.7/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>80</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0788656/comments</url><from>from Houston, TX</from><name>wannall</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The special effects that let Gulliver be a giant in Lilliput and a mite in
Brobdingnag are by the reigning genius of the day, Ray Harryhausen, but
writer/director Jack Sher's 1960 film wisely uses them only in the service
of the story.  They have held up quite well, in part because they were
used
with restraint to begin with and they do nothing to interrupt or distract
from the story and its points.  (A minor exception could be the fight with
a
giant animated crocodile that must have been damn fun for the effects
team,
but even it is kept within reason.)Is this a film for children or a film for adults?  The too-easy answer is
that it is obviously a children's version: There is none of the trumped-up
insanity element that the dreary-but-great-looking 1996 TV movie
shoe-horned
in for cheap drama.  Neither is there the despair or genuine misanthropy
of
the book.Only Lilliput and Brobdingnag are visited.  (No Laputa, Balnibari,
Luggnag,
Glubbdubdrib, Japan, or Houyhnhnms.  The third world is Gulliver's own
normal-sized world.)  Gulliver puts out the fire in Lilliput by spitting
wine.  (In the book, the wine has been processed by Gulliver's bladder
before he douses the fire with it.)  Many characters, though not all, are
all done in a cartoonish way clearly aimed at children.  The travels are
framed within the added-on love story of Gulliver and his fiancée
Elizabeth.These are good choices.  Children are inherently interested in the size
contrasts.  (It must add something to the experience that first they
identify with the Lilliputians but later identify with Gulliver.)
Spitting
the wine is good enough.  The cartoonish-ness makes the characters less
threatening than they could have been.  The love story is light and easy
to
follow, and promotes marriage.There are even a couple of musical numbers, one a love song that Gulliver
sings.  The Bernard Herrmann score is a fine complement to the film, as
you
would expect from the composer of music for the original Psycho, Citizen
Kane, Magnificent Ambersons, Ghost and Mrs. Muir, Day the Earth Stood
Still,
Alfred Hitchcock Presents (tv), Have Gun Will Travel (tv), Perry Mason
(tv),
Twilight Zone, Cape Fear (1962), Taxi Driver, and on and on and
on.But Sher's script and direction have preserved some important points and
spirit from the book: The gratitude of princes is short-lived.  The causes
of war can be shockingly petty.  Vanity and unreason among the powerful
make
truth an early casualty in the pursuit of power.  The various unpleasant
characters (and the few nice ones) actually reflect things inside all of
us.
If it's okay for an adult to be reminded of these things in a playful way
(certainly more playful than the original), then this film will amuse and
inform that adult.And what are Gulliver and Elizabeth doing when their ball-field sized
marriage license falls over them like a tent, and King Brob, peeking under
it, is moved to say, "You're right dear.  I'd better marry them at
once."Ultimately, it has to go down in the books as a children's film, but
surely
an uncommon one: an intelligent adaptation, if abridged and lighthearted,
of
a great classic, that stands on its own for entertainment and, if you
like,
can whet your child's appetite for the book when that time
arrives.Like the tacked-on love story, there is a tacked-on ending that suggests
that the whole thing might have been a dream.  I originally found this
annoying.These days, watching with my little girl, I find that I'm glad for the
admittedly sore-thumb reminder that the value of the story is not in
whether
those characters do or don't exist, but in what the story says about what
is
within us.  As with all such points in the film, you'll have to talk with
your child a bit to be sure that it comes across, but what a pleasure - to
find a film that sparks such a discussion with your child.--------------------------------------------------------------------------
--------------------------------------Other works by Jack Sher:--------------------------------------------------------
Writer - filmography
--------------------------------------------------------
Female Artillery (1972) (TV) (story)
Goodbye, Raggedy Ann (1971) (TV)
Move Over, Darling (1963)
Critic's Choice (1963)
Love in a Goldfish Bowl (1961)
Paris Blues (1961)
3 Worlds of Gulliver, The (1960) ... aka Worlds of Gulliver, The (1960)
Wild and the Innocent, The (1959)
Kathy O' (1958) (also story)
Joe Butterfly (1957)
Four Girls in Town (1956)
Walk the Proud Land (1956) ... aka Apache Agent (1956)
World in My Corner (1956) (also story)
Kid from Left Field, The (1953)
Off Limits (1953) ... aka Military Policemen (1953) (UK)
Shane (1953) (additional dialogue)
My Favorite Spy (1951)--------------------------------------------------------
Director - filmography
--------------------------------------------------------
Love in a Goldfish Bowl (1961)
3 Worlds of Gulliver, The (1960) ... aka Worlds of Gulliver, The (1960)
Wild and the Innocent, The (1959)
Kathy O' (1958)
Four Girls in Town (1956)(with thanks to The Internet Movie Database  http://www.imdb.com)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0382004/comments</url><from>from CARDIFF, WALES</from><name>ALAN MOUNT</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

From the same production stable as "THE 7TH VOYAGE OF SINBAD",this movie is
not quite in the same class as the latter but remains a highly enjoyable
piece.A very much watered down version of part of "GULLIVER'S TRAVELS" the
film benefits not just from typically superb Harryhausen effects but also
from a fabulous score from Bernard Herrmann (one of his very best and sadly
neglected)and a performance from Kerwin Mathews as Gulliver that displays
the usual integrity displayed by this pleasing actor. The leading female
role is attractively played by a very pretty British actress of the
period,June Thorburn who fantasy fans may remember from "TOM
THUMB".Although
it is not as well known or as revived as often as  "SINBAD" or " JASON" it
is hard to imagine anyone being disappointed by this "GULLIVER" which is
far
more fun than the Ted Danson version of the mid 90's.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1769780/comments</url><from>from Colorado, USA</from><name>Timothy A. Buchser</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This pleasant yet dated little 1960 family movie arrives is part of
Columbia
TriStar's "Ray Harryhausen Signature Collection." However, unlike Jason
and
the Argonauts, First Men in the Moon, The 7th Voyage of Sinbad, The Golden
Voyage of Sinbad, and 20 Million Miles to Earth, there's not much here to
thrill the average Harryhausen fan. Other than a quick battle with a giant
alligator and a dino-sized squirrel that's more mirthful than menacing,
The
3 Worlds of Gulliver doesn't depend on Harryhausen's famed stop-motion
monsters to menace our hero. Instead, it features cinematic effects that
make seafarer Dr. Lemuel Gulliver (7th Voyage's Sinbad, Kerwin Mathews) a
skyscraper-tall behemoth on the isle of Lilliput and a doll-sized castaway
"witch" in the court of Brobdingnag. The script is just a wire hanger for
the "giant/tiny" effects scenes, but the story moves briskly (even a pair
of
treacly song-breaks don't get much in the way), and it should particularly
appeal to the under-10 set who haven't yet become jaundiced to anything
pre-dating modern CGI gloss. Mathews is plenty wholeseome and likable in a
role first offered to Danny Kaye and (no kidding) Jack Lemmon. And
Gulliver's fiancé/wife (June Thorburn) is perfunctory but not too much of
a
drip. Look for Peter Bull, Dr. Strangelove's Russian ambassador, in a
small
role. Of course the script is loosely based on the first half of Jonathan
Swift's ribald 1726 novel, Gulliver's Travels. While the book remains one
of
the hardest-biting social satires ever to draw blood from the pompous and
the political, few of those teeth remain in this truncated adaptation.
Nonetheless, the Lilliputian social order and its Emperor's single-minded
war against a neighboring island - fought over an absurdly trivial matter
inflated to genocidal levels by unbending ideological fervor - are still
recognizable targets. Visually, Harryhausen's tall/small effects are well
done, though a viewer accustomed to more recent breakthroughs should
expect
to see the seams showing and hear the floorboards creaking. For a good
number of fans, Bernard Herrmann's fine score is the chief appeal
here.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The 3 Worlds of Gulliver could easily have been made into an adult
satire as Jonathan Swift originally intended, but I daresay Columbia
Pictures would not have realized too much box office had they gone that
route.I saw it as a 13 year old back in the day in theater which is really
the only way to appreciate the special effects of Ray Harryhausen. It's
a wonderful film for a juvenile, but later in reading about the times
one can appreciate what Swift was trying to say and the humorous way he
said it.At the time Gulliver's Travels was originally written the age of the
religious wars of the 17th century was coming to an end. Swift was a
member of the Tory Party who sought to put an end to the War of Spanish
Succession which the Whigs in power seemed to drag on and on. For the
Whig view of the conflict I suggest strongly reading Winston
Churchill's Life of Marlborough which equates the Tories of the day
with the Baldwin-Chamberlain led Tories of the Thirties. Swift looked
about and just saw a lot of carnage with power politics and religion
all jumbled together so that you could not tell where one left off and
the other began. Gulliver's Travels is how Swift saw the world of his day, religious
intolerance and a budding imperialism. Swift was in fact an ordained
minister who apparently had a vision that HIS way of worship was not
necessarily THE way of worship for all. A novel idea back then,
expressed in the war the Lilliputians and Blefescuans wage over which
end of the egg to break. The Brobdingnag tale where Gulliver once a giant in Lilliput is now a
small wee creature in a land of giants. And these giants think that
because they're bigger and mightier they can rule over all. They see
Gulliver and his bride as pets to kept as long as they amuse. It's a
classic commentary against imperialism, unusual in its day and made
Swift most unpopular in high places.These issues aren't for kids of the Saturday matinée crowd and Kerwin
Matthews as Gulliver is playing for them. Matthews had a great career
doing these fantasy things and he was real good in them. Maybe because
he played the roles absolutely straight and we believed because he
believed the part.Ray Harryhausen is at the top of his game and the film holds up very
well. Even better in fact when you know the background from which the
material came from.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16161013/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>JohnRouseMerriottChard</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The Three Worlds of Gulliver is produced out of Columbia Pictures and
is directed by Jack Sher. It stars Kerwin Matthews as Lemuel Gulliver,
June Thorburn as his fiancée Elizabeth, with support coming from Basil
Sydney (The Emperor of Lilliput), Grégoire Aslan (King Brob), Mary
Ellis (Queen), Charles Lloyd Pack (Prime Minister Makovan) &amp; child
actor Sherry Alberoni as Glumdalclitch. Filmed in England and Spain, it
features stop-motion animation and special visual effects by
Superdynamation genius Ray Harryhausen. Sher &amp; Arthur Ross adapt for
the screen with a loose reworking of the 18th-century English novel
Gulliver's Travels written by Jonathan Swift. And music maestro Bernard
Herrmann provides the score.Swift's biting satirical novel has been watered down and given a
romantic edge for the family market. That said, as the kids are
enjoying the froth and tickle, the adults will note that there's just
enough caustic comment in the piece to get the message across. This
adaptation has slimmed down the four parts of Swift's work to just the
two; Lilliput land of the little people and Brobdingnag land of the
giants. With our intrepid normal sized hero Gulliver and his stowaway
fiancée Elizabeth under threat either way.While the script has its pleasing moments it is still only serving as a
bridging work for Harryhausen's effects to be shown. Be it the giant
and tiny people sequences or the perils that come to our undersized
protagonists courtesy of a Gator and a Squirrel, it's these that the
children will find beguiling. This, however, can not be said for
Harryhausen aficionados or adults more accustomed to more modern
advancements. For this is bottom rung for Harryhausen, not bad at all,
yet although there's a charm here, and no one should ever dismiss the
painstaking amount of time it took him to weave it together, the work
is creaky and lacking the dynamism so befitting his best work.Major bonus' come with the swirling and pounding score from Herrmann
and the vibrant performance of Matthews. The role of Gulliver was first
offered to Danny Kaye, which naturally makes sense given Kaye's
previous work on Hans Christian Andersen some years earlier. That it
was also offered to Jack Lemmon, tho, makes no sense at all. Anyway,
Matthews got the gig, and following on from his fine work in The 7th
Voyage of Sinbad, he laid down a marker in the fantasy adventure genre
that secured him fondness from legions of fans throughout the years. A
safe, colourful and pleasant enough piece if ultimately not one for
most fantasy adventure fans to revisit often. 6/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12394529/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The 3 Worlds Of Gulliver I first saw on the big screen, and in color,
and later saw it a few times on television, but not for a quarter
century or so. So, I had to rewatch the 100 minute film. Kerwin
Matthews, from The Seven Voyages Of Sinbad, does a surprisingly good
job as the semi-zomboid, but buff, Dr. Lemuel Gulliver. He plays
Gulliver as a real guy his genuineness makes up for his sometimes
wooden reactions. June Thorburn plays his fiancée (then wife)
Elizabeth. She's sufficient eye candy, and that alone is reason enough
to justify her sweet insertion into the tale (she is not in Swift's
novel). Gotta love her silly 'Don't ever wanna lay eyes on you again
moment' after Gulliver objects to her naïve-te regarding the purchase
of an old shack. None of the other actors who play any of the other
characters leaves that great an impression, although the girl who plays
Glumdalclitch (Sherry Alberoni, a child star on the original The Mickey
Mouse Club on television) does a solid job with the little she's given.
Her petulance and warmth make her the only semi-realistic character in
all of Lilliput (land of the tint people) or Brobdingnag (land of the
giants).This film features less of the stop motion photography Harryhausen was
noted for, and more visual tricks involving split screens and traveling
mattes, to make use of forced perspective in portraying Gulliver
against his smaller and larger costars. Cinematographer Wilkie Cooper
is credited in the film, but, realistically, he was, in effect, just a
cameraman for Harryhausen.The story is a simplified version of the Swift novel. Gulliver
reluctantly aids the King of Lilliput in his war against the rival
state of Blefescu. The war is over which is the proper end of an egg to
be opened. After Gulliver steals the Blefescuan Navy ships, the King is
still not satisfied, and orders Gulliver to commit genocide on
Blefescu. As a doctor and man of honor, he refuses, and is accused of
treason. He then flees, and washes up on the shores of Brobdingnag,
where Glumdalclitch finds him. The King of Brobdingnag offers to barter
for him, then accepts the girl as his protector. Fortuitously,
Elizabeth ended up there when she stowed aboard Gulliver's ship. He had
been washed overboard to Lilliput, and the ship later destroyed. She
seems to have been the lone survivor. The King's doctor accuses
Gulliver of witchcraft after he saves the Queen's life with modern
medicine, and the two lovers (married by the King) are persecuted.
While the Lilliputians and Blefescuans are small in mind regarding
politics, the Brobdingnagians are backwards regarding science and
medicine. Glumdalclitch therefore rescues the couple, tosses them into
a basket, and throws them down a river which washes out to the sea,
where the two end up back in England at film's fade. Yes, there's some
petty philosophizing by Gulliver, but it works in a campy way. Even the
ending which questions whether or not the adventures were all a dream-
while trite, is not too big a deal because the film handles everything
in a lighthearted way. Had the film been more sober in its claims and
portrayal, such an ending would have bombed, especially since it veers
so far from the original.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0463200/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This takes place in 1699 England. Dr. Gulliver (Kerwin Mathews) is poor
and miserable in England. He takes an ocean voyage and is swept
overboard during a storm. He comes to in a land named Lilliput which
are all people shorter than him. He agrees to help the people of
Lilliput to stop a war and build him a boat to get off. Then he ends up
in another land where he's the small person and everybody else is a
giant.I never read the book it was based on so I can't make comparisons...but
the book was a political satire. Obviously this does not make it into
the movie--this is aimed squarely at kids. The characterizations are
broad (to say the least) and some of the characters act like total
idiots (to amuse the kids). It also has simplistic (if amusing) remarks
on how war is evil and people have to live for themselves. The story
moves haltingly--it seems large chunks were either not filmed or left
on the cutting room floor. Also Mathews breaks into song (!!!) at one
point. It's more than a little silly but Mathews does have a great
singing voice. Also the special effects by Ray Harryhausen aren't
really that special--they're more than obvious.The film is very colorful and I was never really bored--most of the
time though I was trying to figure out what was going on. Kerwin
Mathews was easily one of the best-looking men ever to come out of
Hollywood. His acting is just OK but really--the guy had to react to
things that just weren't there. That couldn't have been easy. So the
color and Mathews kept me entertained...but most adults will probably
be thoroughly bored. I think kids will like it but I can only
truthfully give it a 6.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Jonathan Swift's novel, "Gulliver's Travels," is a classic satire from
1726. I once managed to get around to reading his "A Modest Proposal",
in which -- apparently in all sincerity -- he suggests that the problem
of overpopulation and malnutrition in his native Ireland can be cured
simply by having the Irish eat their own children.Well, that's what satire is, I guess. A send up of current social
issues with an element of viciousness that's usually absent from a mere
parody. Swift must have found the mores of his time easy targets, just
by reducing their characteristics to the absurd. Are the Irish causing
you problems? Get rid of them.In "The 3 Worlds of Gulliver" the problems dealt with are (1) the
causes of war among the tiny Lilliputians, and (2) science versus
religion among the giant Brobdingnagians. I think some other adventures
were deleted. I seem to remember Yahoos and Houyhnhnms and maybe one or
two others. But the elisions are okay. Just two of the strange worlds
Gulliver visits are enough for one movie. (The third world of the title
is his home in England.) I don't know that this story has the same
impact as it originally did. Maybe you need some kind of Skeleton Key
to pick up the more arcane references, as with "Finnegans Wake," "Alice
in Wonderland," or "The Master and Margarita." However, the broader
points of the satire should be clear enough to everyone except the
kids, who will be tickled by it because it's such a colorful fairy
tale.Kerwin Mathews is an idealistic English doctor, Lemuel Gulliver who is
washed overboard at sea and finds himself on an island inhabited by
tiny people, the vaguely Arabic Lilliputians. Once the little people
get over their astonishment -- because compared to them Gulliver is
really HUGE -- they try to talk him into using his immense strength to
destroy their enemies on a neighboring island. Man, are the
Lilliputians petty, especially the sputtering king. "I have abiding
faith in the trustworthiness and reliability of any man that I can
kill," he announces. He's dying to go to war and kill his enemies
because they open their eggs from the big side rather than the small
side, as civilized Lilliputians do. The perceptive adults in the
audience are, at this point, permitted to explain to the children that
sometimes wars are fought for silly reasons. He wants a warmonger for a
Prime Minister, although, "I don't need a Prime Minister to fight a
war. I need one to blame if it goes wrong." Here, please explain to the
children the meaning of the phrase, "The buck stops there." Gulliver
promises to end the war and he does, by stealing the enemy's fleet so
they can never attack Lilliput. This doesn't satisfy the king because
it wasn't a proper war. How can you have a war without sacrifice and
heroism? And besides, since Gulliver robbed the enemy of their fleet,
we now have no need for Admirals and everybody in the Navy is now out
of a job.A disgusted Gulliver finally manages to get off Lilliput but then lands
on Brobdingnagia, a land of superstitious giants living a Medieval life
style. (J. B. S. Haldane once wrote a famous essay explaining why giant
humans were physically impossible.) At first they treat him well, an
amusing toy for one of their gentle children, a pretty young girl named
Glumdalclitch. But soon, after he beats the self-important king in a
game of chess, and exposes the court magician as an ignoramus, he falls
out of favor. He's smarter than they are. After all, he's a doctor and
knows chemistry and science. The Brobdingnagians believe in witches and
some of the stunts pulled by Gulliver -- treating the Queen's upset
stomach with a mixture of opium and paragoric -- smack not just of
elitism but of witchcraft. Besides, there is still that damme chess
game. Who but a witch could check mate the King? So the Royal Court
tries to burn him. Glumdalclitch makes it possible for him to escape.Gulliver barely makes it back to England. We see him on the beach with
his bride, who was swept up in his adventures. It's not a happy ending.
Nobody finds satisfaction right in his own back yard, like Dorothy in
"The Wizard of Oz." His wife asks what will happen to the Lilliputians
and the benighted Brobdingnagians. "They'll always be with us," he
admits with chagrin. "And what of Glumdalclitch", the truly benign and
compassionate kid who looked after them? "Waiting to be born," answers
Gulliver solemnly. I don't think Dean Swift would have been surprised
to find that 280 years later, she's still waiting. Maybe, as I age, my
emotional apparatus is becoming more primitive or something, but I
found that final exchange rather moving.There are many special visual effects but only two instances of Ray
Harryhausen's stop-motion animals, one a squirrel and the other a
crocodile. This isn't a monster movie. Bernard Hermann's score doesn't
sound much like that of a monster movie either -- no galumphing BROOP
broop, BROOP broop. It echoes the light-hearted quality of the story
itself and the composer only rarely lapses into his usual effects. I
think it's the best score Hermann wrote for any of his fantasies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Never viewed this 1960 film dealing with Gulliver's travels and found
it very enjoyable to view along with excellent photography. The story
starts out with Dr. Lemuel Gulliver, (Kerwin Williams) having a fight
with his girlfriend, Elizabeth, (June Thorburn) about his wanting to go
aboard a ship as a doctor and she does not want him to leave. The ship
sails and becomes shipwrecked and Gulliver finds himself in a
completely different land where there are miniature people and he
appears to them as a huge giant who must be captured and tied up. The
rest of the story will hold your interest from the very beginning to
the end and I almost forgot, a war was almost started over cutting an
egg on the top and other people who cut their eggs on the bottom of the
shell. Enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0937743/comments</url><from>from fairview, nj</from><name>george.schmidt (GSchmidt0609@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The 3 Worlds of Gulliver (1960) ***  Fantastic adaptation of Jonathan
Swift's classic tale about Dr. Lemuel Gulliver (Kerwin Mathews) who
embarks
on an unusual odyssey involving the tiny denizens of Lilliput and the
giants
of Brobdignagnan including the adolescent giantess Glumdalclitch (Sherry
Alberoni)  with a wonderful blend of action and the great stop-motion
animations of Ray Harryhausen's.  Fun for the entire family.  ** Personal
note: Begging for a Hollywood remake with a female Gulliver (Gina Gershon
anyone?)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0937743/comments</url><from>from fairview, nj</from><name>george.schmidt (GSchmidt0609@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The 3 Worlds of Gulliver (1960) ***  Fantastic adaptation of Jonathan
Swift's classic tale about Dr. Lemuel Gulliver (Kerwin Mathews) who
embarks
on an unusual odyssey involving the tiny denizens of Lilliput and the
giants
of Brobdignagnan including the adolescent giantess Glumdalclitch (Sherry
Alberoni)  with a wonderful blend of action and the great stop-motion
animations of Ray Harryhausen's.  Fun for the entire family.  ** Personal
note: Begging for a Hollywood remake with a female Gulliver (Gina Gershon
anyone?)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0937743/comments</url><from>from fairview, nj</from><name>george.schmidt (GSchmidt0609@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-bourne/</url><url>http://www.dvdjournal.com/quickreviews/00/3worldsofgulliver.q.shtml /m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1497103</url><name>Mark Bourne</name><from>DVDJournal.com</from></reviewer><comment>For a good number of fans, Bernard Herrmann's fine score is the chief appeal here.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bob-bloom/</url><url>/m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=757444</url><name>Bob Bloom</name><from>Journal and Courier (Lafayette, IN)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Not a top-notch Harryhausen, but still descent with a fine Herrmann score.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1447186</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rich-cline/</url><url>/m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1288569</url><name>Rich Cline</name><from>Shadows on the Wall</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1267347</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/79369/the_three_worlds_of_gulliver.html /m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1832688</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117795713.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1807123</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eugene-archer/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9400E5DA103FE63ABC4F52DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/three_worlds_of_gulliver/comments.php?reviewid=1390458</url><name>Eugene Archer</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>