<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Wackiest Ship in the Army</original_title><imdb_rating>6.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Richard Murphy</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
Lieutenant Rip Crandall is hoodwinked into taking command of the "Wackiest Ship in the Navy" - a real garbage scow with a crew of misfits who don't know a jib from a jigger...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jack Lemmon</actor><actor>Ricky Nelson</actor><actor>John Lund</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1450967/comments</url><from>from Midwest</from><name>Mr. Whispy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is one of those overlooked films Lemmon made in the early years of
his
legendary career. It kind of became lost in the midst of such higher
profile
films as "Some Like it Hot" and  "The Apartment", and never truly found
its
way out. "The Wackiest Ship in the Army"  represents a list of forgotten
Lemmon titles that deserve recognition. Such films include, "It Happened
to
Jane", "Operation Mad Ball", "The Notorious Landlady", and "Alex &amp; the
Gypsy"."Wackiest" is a one of those type of films that is perfect for a lazy
afternoon. Often amusing and boasting a quintessential Lemmon performance,
it's worth checking out just for pure nostalgia!*** (out of 5) 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12000291/comments</url><from/><name>benbrae76</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I've just watched this movie again (and taped it), and found it just as
amusing as when I first watched it 40 odd years ago (just after it's
release in fact). Jack Lemmon never fails to impress, but after all
this time I now realise that Ricky Nelson (although a great loss to the
music world) wasn't the greatest of actors. However his naivety in this
department somehow added charm to this movie.The WWII storyline based on true events couldn't be simpler. An
American naval officer/ex-yachtsman Lt Rip Crandall (Jack Lemmon), and
a young Ensign Tommy Hansen (Ricky Nelson), are ordered to sail an old
sloop, the "USS Echo", with an unexperienced crew across the Great
Barrier Reef to Port Moresby, where (although Crandall doesn't know
until later) the boat is to be used to convey an Aussie coast-watcher
to his destination, with a different crew. Crandall doesn't like the
change-over so steals the mission. End of plot...almost.The only real down side of this movie was the awful "Austroylian"
accent of Irish actress Patricia Driscoll. Almost as bad as Dick van
Dyke's Cockney accent in "Mary Poppins". Almost, but not quite.
Although lovely to look at, it's a blessing Patricia only had a minor
role. However I find it strange that the part couldn't have been given
to a genuine Aussie.All in all, I always found this movie very entertaining, and strangely
enough, for a war film, and rather like "Mr Roberts", no violence worth
worrying about. Which rather pleases me now, for my grandkids love it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0154569/comments</url><from>from New York, N.Y.</from><name>Ralph Michael Stein (riglltesobxs@mailinator.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Based on true events (we were at war with the Japanese in 1943 in the
Pacific), "The Wackiest Ship in the Army" stars Jack Lemmon as, once again,
a naval officer.Lemmon made his first big film in 1955 when he played the con artist, Ensign
Pulver, in "Mister Roberts," a movie that's attained classic status.  In
this 1961 film he dons the navy uniform again, this time as a lieutenant
(senior grade).  A reserve officer who was a dapper yachtsman in California
before the war, Lemmon is assigned to command a sailing vessel with (barely
functioning) auxiliary mechanical propulsion.The U.S.S. Echo is hardly the dream command of any officer, reserve or
regular.  But the new C.O. gamely takes on training an eager but totally
bemused crew in the art of sailing a vessel.The Echo is assigned to land an Australian coast watcher on an island
occupied by the stereotypically portrayed Japanese (more Japanese officers
with U.C.L.A. degrees appear in film than ever showed up on the front).  The
heroic coast watchers were very important during the island hopping campaign
and they deserve every bit of cinematic recognition they have received. 
Many died, some after being tortured by their captors.Nowhere nearly as smoothly directed as "Mister Roberts," "The Wackiest Ship
in the Army" (and there's no rational reason for the title-the Army doesn't
even play a role here) teeters unevenly between some nice comedy and some
very 1950s-1960s war action supplemented by combat footage (one Japanese
plane has been shown blown out of the sky so often in movies that if the
pilot's estate was entitled to royalties the heirs would be richer than Bill
Gates).The exploits of the Echo's crew led, we are told, to the American victory in
the Battle of the Bismarck Sea, an important engagement.This is a good film for renting.  Jack Lemmon plays the competent and caring
C.O. very nicely and is the center of the story.The Navy must have really liked the script.  They put a fleet anchorage at
the filmmaker's disposal.  Here's a quiz for the sharp-eyed.  At one point
the stern of one of the most famous and important smaller combatant vessels
of World War II is shown while Lemmon is instructing his crew.  What ship is
it?6/10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1648023/comments</url><from>from Lawrence, KS</from><name>broosr</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

It's too bad Hollywood stopped making war flicks like this one. They were
much more enjoyable than the kind of hand-wringing performances you see
nowadays. Lemmon took a break from chewing the scenery in the classics
"Some
Like It Hot" and "The Great Race" and returned to a more straight-man
character of the kind he played in Mister Roberts. Although Lemmon is, as
usual, great, the movie suffers somewhat from a bland supporting cast and
the insufferable Ricky Nelson, whose acting is as wooden as it was in "Rio
Bravo." Although slow to get going, the movie eventually takes off and
maintains a robust pace to the conclusion. Note that TV showings tend to
trim this one heavily, so if you see it sitting in the bargain bin, be
sure
to pick it up!For fans of Lemmon or the genre only!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
As military service comedies go, The Wackiest Ship in the Army isn't
the best one going, but it is pretty amusing. Jack Lemmon plays a naval lieutenant who in civilian life had sailboat
racing experience. Therefore he's just the man to command a sailing
craft made up to look like a native trading vessel. The object being to
land Australian coast watcher Chips Rafferty in the middle of Japanese
held territory. Lemmon has a callow young ensign as his executive officer in Ricky
Nelson and a crew of men, none of whom have any kind of experience in a
sailing craft. The laughs come as he tries to whip this crew into some
kind of shape before the mission.Jack Lemmon had just come off Some Like It Hot and The Apartment so he
was hot box office back then. The Wackiest Ship in the Army isn't in
the aforementioned league of films, but it's still good and unlike the
other classics was turned into a television series, albeit a short
lived one, just like that other Lemmon film, Mister Roberts.Ricky Nelson was never the greatest actor going, but he was their for
the teenage girl market at the box office. What he was though was a
very good singer and he does get to sing Do You Know What It Means to
Leave New Orleans which sold a few platters back in the day.Outstanding other performances in the film are from Chips Rafferty,
Australia's greatest cinema star, Mike Kellin playing the CPO of the
sailing crew and Tom Tully who seems to continue where he took off from
in The Caine Mutiny.Even today I think cinema fans will enjoy the comedy of Jack Lemmon in
The Wackiest Ship in the Army.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When Lieutenant Rip Crandall is offered his first command he jumps at
the chance. However when he arrives at his 'ship' he finds that the
Echo is more of a tub than a destroyer – being practically a yacht!
With an inexperienced or inept crew and a second officer who has barely
ever been on water for any length of time, Crandall is ready to drop
out until guilt gets the better of him and he decides not to leave the
young Ensign Hanson carrying the bag. After a few days of intensive and
quite unsuccessful training, Crandall's ship sets off on its mission.Starting out with a credit sequence and opening 10 minutes that
suggests that the film may be as 'wacky' as the title suggests, it
gradually settles into humour that is rather basic but passable before
going for a more traditional plot that lacks humour and fails to really
be that interesting. In some regards the turn away from the 'wacky'
first few minutes was a relieve because I really don't like things that
knowingly describe themselves as 'wacky' (personal ads with the words
'bubbly' or 'wacky' are generally my idea of hell) and the humour at
the start of this just seemed too forced. However once it settles, it
settles into humour that isn't very funny but is amiable enough. This
continues with the usual 'training' stuff and 'mishaps' that passes for
entertainment just about but then in the final 30/40 minutes it tries
to actually have a plot – and falls to pieces as a result.By this point I didn't really care about the plot more than a basic
description and it was too late in the day to try and suddenly become
engaging or exciting. The film also completely drops the humour (for
what it was) and creates such a sudden change of tone that its like
watching another film – something that damages it even further. Of
course, its not awful, its just a film of two halves, neither of which
are much cop but neither of which are really bad. The cast doesn't help
much either since most of them are fairly average and just play to the
level of the humour. Lemmon tries hard but cannot do much other than
his usual stuff – which isn't as good when it is built on material like
this. Nelson is about as wooden as you could get and only has presence
when he is given a musical number – he was a singer after all and never
really convinced me as an actor. The support cast are pretty average
and you can see their basic characters in almost any other 'useless
ensemble crew' movie that you can pick.Overall this is a strange film that doesn't really work. It tries to be
wacky and funny but the material is weak and it never really gets
going, with the humour tailing off with every passing minute. When it
eventually drops off altogether, the plot becomes more of a traditional
war story but by then it is too hard to really care what is going on
and it more or less fails too. As a total film it is a strange split;
neither of the two halves really work but neither of them are bad. The
end result is a film that is just about passable but one that will
disappoint many who view it regardless of their expectations.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1351390/comments</url><from>from Vienna, Austria</from><name>eva25at</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

(Contains spoilers)Feb. 1943. The Japanese were stopped at Guadacanal and the Allies hunt for a
bright young naval officer to lead an extremely delicate mission. Lt. Rip
Crandall (Jack Lemmon) is the commander of their choice and this capable
fellow strikes his head against every door-frame. He is so qualified that he
has to consult a reference-book on "How to take command of a ship". The USS
ECHO is, to put it euphemistically, " in a class by itself" and the "picked
crew of specialists" liked life on a ship better than life in jail.Crandall sinks in despair when he sees this wreck and this crew but ensign
Tommy Hanson (Ricky Nelson, as guileless and polite as Elvis) follows him
like a puppy and sings the praises of ship &amp; crew. Crandall's task is to
pass through the Great Barrier Reef and bring the ship to Port Moresby.
General MacArthur in person devised this operation. Hanson butters Crandall
up and sings a song (what did you expect?) and next morning the new-fledged
and morning-afterish commander is more tractable.The crew is anxious to make a good impression - what does it matter if the
lifeboat is not watertight, the engine not functioning and the Coral Sea
gale-lashed? The Allies want Lt. Foster (Richard Anderson) to take the ship
over. He observes, half appalled, half gloatingly how the ECHO gets caught
in a mine area and insists on firing the crew. But Crandall is not willing
to give up his command. When Port Moresby is attacked he steers for the
Salomon Islands to localize the japanese convoy.The passage is dangerous (storm, reefs, tidal waves) but they manage to
escape a bomber attack by dressing up as island beauties. They reach the
Salomon Islands, fight their way through the jungle and witness atrocities.
They discover the convoy, but the ECHO and their commander fall into enemy
hands. A japanese major threatens the  POW's with "questioning" and runs a
sword through Crandall's breast. But the "inefficient" crew surpass
themselves and transmit the position of the convoy: prelude to the
little-known but decisive battle of the Bismark Sea. Ostensibly a true story, the film is typical for the early Kennedy era.
During the election campaign the public had an appetite for the president's
war time adventures which were also filmed (PT 109) with Lemmon's old rival
Cliff Robertson (he married Lemmon's first wife and made the first version
of DAYS AND WINE AND ROSES) as JFK. The purpose of those films was to raise
patriotic feelings by representing WWII as "boy's own adventure": A motley
crew grows together under the moral leadership of stout captain Jack who
makes naval heroes out of them in just three days. Lemmon cannot have been
too enthusiastic to make this film right after THE APARTMENT, but, to his
credit, his performance does not suffer. He is lissome like a cat when he
swarms up a mast and most of the film is cheerful and hearty. The scene in
the mine-area, however, is nerve-racking and the combat scenes brutal. The
production values are higher than you may expect. Not a terribly important
film, but if it's a rainy afternoon and you have nothing better to
do...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1033959/comments</url><from>from North Dakota</from><name>Charles Tatum</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

In this WWII comedy, Jack Lemmon plays a young lieutenant whofinally gets command of his own ship- a small sailboat with aninexperienced crew. Rick Nelson is his second in command, andthe ship must sail. This lightweight comedy is not terribly funny, butnot bad, either.The breezy feel of the film is helped by an almost complete lack ofplot. Lemmon takes the boat through dangerous waters watchedby the Japanese, picks up an Australian spy who tracks Japanesenavy positions from the jungle, and sails him to the jungle. Theship is captured, but our heroes escape and return back to base.Aside from the Japanese, the only other conflict is betweenLemmon and the ageless Richard Anderson, who plays a hardnosed commander ready to take over the sailboat.The film works mostly because of Lemmon. He is so good and solikable here, you forget little things like a romantic subplot thatnever pans out. Nelson even finds a chance to croon a song,giving us a break from the loud, unsubtle musical score.Despite the title, most of the humor here is derived from the men'swar situation; not anything terribly wacky happens. There arelaughs, two running gags involve people knocking themselves onthe head, and a funny one involving Lemmon's quest for a decentcup of coffee. Another light moment that is not pounded into theground- the men dress as natives, complete with grass skirts andcoconut shell bras, to fool the enemy into thinking they are a localtrading ship. The scene is funny without being racist and
offensive.The suspense about the mission is often undermined by areliance on stock footage to show battle scenes. This is a comedy,yet we are watching actual footage of war, and this is a littleunsettling. When director Murphy is allowed to shoot his ownaction sequences, they work, especially the cruise through themined harbor."The Wackiest Ship in the Army" spawned a television show, andthat is about the level of the script. This is nothing that will changeyour life, but watching Lemmon's comic skills and good naturemake this an enjoyable enough time filler. I slightly recommend
it.This is unrated, and contains some physical violence, some gunviolence, and mild adult situations. 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
The Wackiest Ship in the Army is also rather odd, neither the service
comedy the title promises nor the straight war movie it almost seems to
want to be. Instead it's a lightweight star vehicle for Jack Lemmon,
back in uniform after Mister Roberts and Ensign Pulver but this time
playing a career officer who finds his first command is a decrepit
yacht with a crew of misfits assigned to deliver Chips Rafferty's coast
watcher to an island occupied by the Japanese (stereotyped, of course –
this was 1960, after all). It's the kind of film that just drifts by
inoffensively without ever making much of an impression either way,
although it does make good use of the CinemaScope screen.Incidentally, the film's poster bears no relation to the film whatever.
At no point do Lemmon or Ricky Nelson dress up in grass skirts: Ricky
even is in full uniform when he sings (no guitar as on the poster but
piano accompaniment). Some Like It Hot 2 it ain't...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15636700/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mfurman11</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
this is a fun, wholesome movie suitable for all ages. Lemmon is
captivating, as always and Ricky Nelson does just fine. actually, this
is really a tailor made role for nelson. the young handsome, slightly
misguided, yet sincere officer who admits past failures and looks
forward to proving himself in the eyes of his superior, Lemmon. the
move has a touch of romance, a bit of action and plenty of laughs and
wholesome fun. check it out. i'll bet you'll be rooting for this bunch
of misfits just like i was. and Clayton Trap, i have no opinion on you
as a person, though i do have a great sympathy for that stick that's
stuck up your....
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15636700/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mfurman11</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
this is a fun, wholesome movie suitable for all ages. Lemmon is
captivating, as always and Ricky Nelson does just fine. actually, this
is really a tailor made role for nelson. the young handsome, slightly
misguided, yet sincere officer who admits past failures and looks
forward to proving himself in the eyes of his superior, Lemmon. the
move has a touch of romance, a bit of action and plenty of laughs and
wholesome fun. check it out. i'll bet you'll be rooting for this bunch
of misfits just like i was. and Clayton Trap, i have no opinion on you
as a person, though i do have a great sympathy for that stick that's
stuck up your....
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15636700/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mfurman11</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>