<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>L'ultima preda del vampiro</original_title><alt_title>Des filles pour un vampire</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Piero Regnoli</director><producer>Nord Film Italiana</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
Five beautiful showgirls are trapped by a storm and find refuge in a creepy old castle. The owner of the castle, a strange nobleman, has a secret laboratory in the basement and has his own plans for the girls.
</synopsis><actor>Walter Brandi</actor><actor>Lyla Rocco</actor><actor>Maria Giovannini</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0867063/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>FilmFlaneur</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Ragnoli's film focuses on the travails of a group of five dance hall girls
and their manager who, after defaulting on a hotel bill, find themselves
bumping through unfamiliar countryside at night looking for late
accommodation. Ignoring the warnings of a local, they continue along a
side
road to the castle of a mysterious Count Kernassy (Walter Brandi), where
one
of the girls, Vera experiences strong feelings of déjà vu. At first
treated
with coldness, it soon appears that the beautiful-yet-mopey Vera bears a
startling resemblance to one of Count Kernassy's ancestors, Margherita.
Ominously, the Count has an infatuation with this long-dead beauty. As
sudden storms wash out bridges behind them, the troupe are obliged to
spend
more than one night at the castle and, despite warnings, venture out of
the
their rooms at night...A minor camp item with some historical interest today, The Playgirls And
The
Vampire first saw light of day on the continent as L'ultima preda del
vampiro (trans: The Vampire's Final Prey), an Italian attempt to
capitalise
on the vogue for the contemporary Hammer product with a suitably spiced-up
Euro version. Adding lashings of female titillation in a way which was
unthinkable to the Anglo Saxon market (the film includes a brief topless
shot), director Piero Ragnoli made up a package which was both more
lascivious than that produced by the studio at Bray, and one to which
critical opinion has been less kind. Predictably, the heady cocktail was a
commercial success at the time, and some commentators have since seen the
results as anticipating the sexy vampire cinema of Jean Rollin a few years
later, although the sheen of erotic sophistication brought by the French
auteur is conspicuously missing here. American producer Richard Gordon,
sensing money from the exploitation market, promptly picked up the English
language rights to the original film, did a rush-dubbing job and re-titled
it with an eye on maximum marquee appeal. (He also prepared a cut print
for
those areas in which censorship was more squeamish, under the title of
Curse
Of The Vampire - a version that by all accounts approached the
incoherent).While the beginning of this version of the film, which features a long
tracking shot from a dungeon window to a stone sarcophagus and an
emerging,
spidery hand, momentarily recalls some of the splendours of such films as
Bava's Mask Of The Demon (aka: La Maschera del demonio, 1960), such
atmospherics are rarely repeated. The most effective moment occurs during
the big burial scene later, where Aldo Greci's camera performs a
360-degree
pan around the faces of the mourners from a low angle. Here the
combination
of a daring, continuous shot, allied with the distortions of a wide-angle
lens produces the sense of dread a film like this so badly needs.
Elsewhere
the cinematography is more careless, with at least one scene suffering
from
a distracting focus problem, and the sparse interiors of the Count's
castle
being lit without subtlety. Unfortunately, the plot hardly distracts one
from such shortcomings. Containing more holes than a ghoul's winding
sheet,
in execution it only emphases that for the most part Ragnoli's technical
competence is mediocre. Given the electric possibilities which exist when
sex and horror are combined, his film rarely aspires to the erotic, even
though the glamorous playgirls are frequently to be seen wandering through
chilly grounds and corridors, clad in nothing but their nighties.What makes the film enjoyable is the passing campness of it all, the
ineptness of the characters and the ludicrousness of some of the dialogue.
The girls form part of a truly terrible dance troupe: when, after a
tragedy,
they gather to lose themselves in a rehearsal ("the girls have been very
upset, and this is the only way to make them stop worrying about it" we
are
assured) and one performs a striptease, their lack of professionalism and
poise in ensemble is laughable. Their manager, Lucas, (Alfredo Rizzo) is a
crabby, cynical showman who is at least a more believable stereotype than
the dull vampire fodder he escorts. In one of the more amusing moments of
the film, we see him snuggling down in his room with a girlie magazine
before being confronted by a nude, newly dead girl. Here his mugging is
entertaining and the often self-conscious dialogue, which is a feature of
the film, doesn't intrude. Elsewhere the non-sequiturs can be amazing ("I
just don't understand it"/ "What don't you understand?"/ "Nothing, nothing
at all" is one worthy of Ed Wood). As various mysterious events unfold,
such
conversations contribute to an atmosphere that can be just as bewildering
to
the audience as to the principals. Supporting characters, such as the
groundskeeper, the limping Zoltan (probably Antoine Nicos), and the
housekeeper (Marisa Quattrini) remain woefully undeveloped which given the
nature of the genre, where every servant is a satanic stooge it seems, is
surprising. One especially regrets the waste of the housekeeper. A demonic
Mrs Danvers would have been a useful bonus in taking up some of the
dramatic
slack.As "one of the first horror films from any country to mix Gothic horror
and
explicit eroticism," the film is a slight genre landmark. Perhaps a
director
with a greater sense of visual style would have made more of the
opportunity, but the result is still watchable, if a little slow. For
those
who enjoy continental horror from this time - the start of a classic
production period, which until recently has been hard to see - this is
worth
seeking out, if not essential viewing. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0789991/comments</url><from>from Minneapolis, MN</from><name> (monsterhead_x@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

PLAYGIRLS AND THE VAMPIRE is a so-so early Italian horror movie that is
good
enough to hold an average euro-horror film buffs attention.  Nice music,
great looking (and occasionally, scantilly clad) go-go dancers, and not to
mention an oddly unique final death scene.Overall, a nice addition to any obscure movie collection, that will
probably
merit more than one viewing.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0812757/comments</url><from>from Haddonfield, IL</from><name>GroovyDoom</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
A group of five "showgirls" of varying curvaceousness, along with their
manager and bus driver, find themselves in the proverbial Gothic horror
movie circumstances: their bus, traveling through a rural area, is
forced off the road by a storm, so naturally the thing to do is to take
refuge in the spooky old castle that's just up the road, over a rickety
bridge. The storm is apparently pretty bad, although we don't ever see
any evidence of it, and it looks pretty sunny out during the outdoors
scenes. The castle itself contains a few servants and a lone
nobleman...oh, and there's also a vampire in the basement.Our main showgirl, Vera, is a dead ringer for the nobleman's long-dead
ancestor, the wife of the long-dead vampire, so she's the main
chica-in-trouble, but there's not much going on that's of interest. The
story is very silly, and this movie is of note today simply because it
features a great deal of scantily clad women on hand, as well as a
short topless scene. The photography is interesting, and the sets
really get some atmosphere going. I'm a sucker for haunted castle
stories with plenty of secret passageway action.But the hoary aspects of this story were generally of the Ed Wood
variety. The film is very campy, and cannot be taken seriously in any
way. Ultimately this comes off as too jokey to be a stellar example of
an atmospheric Italian "scares &amp; nudity" film, even if it was one of
the first.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5971012/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ferbs54</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"The Playgirls and the Vampire," an odd Italian amalgam of
sexploitation and Gothic horror, was originally released in 1960 under
the perhaps more fitting title "The Last Prey of the Vampire." The five
gals who are forced to spend the night at the creepy castle of Count
Gabor Kernassy, along with their manager and bus driver/pianist, are
more showgirls than playgirls (and, judging by a few of their dance
routines, bargain-basement showgirls at that!), and the "v" word,
strangely enough, is never uttered by anyone during the course of the
entire film...even when the 200-year-old, bloodsucking ancestor of
Kernassy is revealed to be a resident of the castle crypts. The
picture's scares are few, perhaps nonexistent, and the sex elements,
naturally, are very tame by today's standards (a brief topless moment,
a few peeks through a filmy negligee, and one striptease down to her
scanties by one of the gals). Indeed, I'm hard pressed to put my finger
on just what I found so likable about this film. Perhaps it is the
moldering look of the castle crypts, or the overwrought and oftentimes
oddball musical score of Aldo Piga. Director Piero Regnoli does a
competent job, sometimes even contributing some striking visual
flourishes (such as that 360-degree pan during a funeral); Walter
Brandi, in his dual role of the count and the aged neck nosher, is
pretty decent (although his vampire is quite lame looking); and Lyla
Rocco is strangely interesting as she somnambulates through her role of
Vera, one of the "playgirls" for whom the castle holds a special
attachment. Ultimately, though, the film is a real head scratcher, with
some glaring plot holes (can anyone tell me why Vera herself does not
become a vampire after having her neck noshed on?) and very illogical
actions on the part of the quintet. The picture is a bona fide
curiosity, to be sure, but an atmospheric one, at least. Just don't go
in expecting anything on the order of Mario Bava's "Black Sunday,"
which came out that same year....
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0414028/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, Canada</from><name>LJ27</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
*POSSIBLE SPOILER AHEAD* I watched this movie once a long time ago and
it is passable entertainment for one viewing I would say. The women in
it are very hot but I suspect it was made by the same people who made
SLAUGHTER OF THE VAMPIRES since it contains drawings with dissolves
between them to depict the climactic disintegration of the vampire. I
know make-up solutions to such technical problems are challenging but I
think someone with some imagination and inventiveness could have come
up with something better than what's on display here. I seem to recall
it was well-shot and the castle sets looked nice. As is the case with
many European horror films from the 1960s, it can be more than a little
bit dull at times. I expected to at least see some fun bargain-basement
special effects or make-up though. I found this one disappointing. I
guess if you want to find that though, it's best to stick with the
"brand name" horror specialists of the time, Mario Bava and Antonio
Margharetti. Either of them could have made something better out of
this same script.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4888011/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon, USA</from><name>Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
OK, we've probably all figured out by now that any exploitation film
from the early '60s (in fact, possibly from any era) has to feature a
bunch of hot babes. You'd better believe that "L'ultima preda del
vampiro" (called "The Playgirls and the Vampire" in English) has some!
Featuring a group of models having to spend a few nights in a castle
where a vampire apparently lived, the movie doesn't disappoint one bit.
To be certain, after seeing that one scene with Katia, I would consider
it an honor to have her suck my blood! Anyway, maybe this is the sort
of movie that can only appeal to teenage boys, but it's worth seeing.Hot Italian babes. YEAH!!!!!!!!!!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
- After running out on an unpaid hotel bill, a bus carrying five
showgirls, their manager, and a driver becomes stranded because of bad
weather. They seek shelter in a nearby castle (Is it a European custom
to ask any stranger with a spooky castle if you can spend the night
when you're stranded?). At first, the owner, Count Gabor Kernassy, is
reluctant to let them stay, but eventually changes his mind after
noting that one of the girls looks like a dead relative. During dinner,
the Count tells his guests that they must remain in their rooms at
night. Unfortunately for Playgirl Katia, she didn't listen and begins
exploring (What a shocker!) the castle after everyone has gone to bed.
The next morning, her dead body is found on the castle's grounds. Was
it an accident or was she murdered? And who else will die in Castle
Kernassy? - Let's get this out of the way up-front, The Playgirls and the Vampire
is remembered for one thing - it was one of the first Italian horror
movies (if not the very first) to mix nudity with horror. As a
curiosity piece, it's interesting, but it's hardly the basis for a good
movie. If you're interested in a slow moving Italian Gothic horror,
there are far better movies to be found than this one. The Playgirls
and the Vampire moves too slowly for even the most patient and
disciplined fan. The first 3/4 can best be described as drudgery.- The American title is a bit misleading. It suggests that the movie's
plot is about a group of scantily clad women being terrorized by a
vampire. Let's see, one woman is bitten and the vampire is one of the
least threatening I've ever seen. Walter Brandi plays the vampire (and
the Count) and his performance is best described as stiff. He acts like
his arms might fall off if he moves too quickly. The Playgirls in the
title are the most untalented group of showgirls ever assembled. And
the emotions they feel for their fallen comrade consist of rehearsing
their sad dance routine within minutes of the funeral.- The movie does pick-up the pace and become fairly entertaining for
the last 1/4 of the running time. The underground passages are creepy
and provide the only atmosphere to be found. The final fight between
the two vampires is enjoyable in a campy/cheesy sort of way. This
portion of the movie saves it from becoming a total waste of time.- If any of this sounds interesting, I recommend watching Bloody Pit of
Horror instead. The plots are almost identical (just replace a
homicidal lunatic for the vampire), but Bloody Pit of Horror is so much
more fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Five show girls, their manager and his assistant end up at a secluded
castle when they are forced to take a detour when the road is washed
out. At the castle they are warned to stay in their rooms during the
night, but one of the girls wanders out and falls to her death.
Meanwhile one of the other other girls, who look is exactly like an
ancestor, is wooed by the Count who owns the place. She is rightly
confused when a more demonic twin of the Count shows up and tries to do
her harm. Notorious horror film was once shown at adults only
screenings because of the hints of female flesh, but is now quite tame.
A good little Euro shocker this is quite better than its reputation and
its lurid title suggest thanks to some good performances and the
fantastic black and white photography which sets the mood early. Its
the sort of horror movie that would be perfect on a dark and stormy
movie night on the couch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This was one of 3 popular Italian films dealing with bloodsuckers (all
starring the brooding-but-bland Walter Brandi) from the county's
initial Gothic Horror outburst. Some years back, I had watched (and was
not exactly impressed by) Renato Polselli's THE VAMPIRE AND THE
BALLERINA (1960) – having now caught up with the other two in quick
succession, I can see that their reputation has more to do with
nostalgia than anything else…or, if you like, for providing a quaint
alternative to the contemporaneous Mexican/Hammer model!As can be gleaned from the title, this sees a group of entertainers
(incidentally, their sleazy yet awkwardly-choreographed routines – and
especially the taskmaster's own over-eagerness – are positively
embarrassing to watch!) stranded on a stormy night and who manage to
find shelter in a remote ancient castle (despite being specifically
told not to go there!). Unsurprisingly, one of the many dancers in the
troupe proves to be a dead-ringer for the host (Brandi)'s long-lost
love!; likewise, while they are warned not to wander about at night,
the liveliest lady among them disobeys orders and (apparently) pays the
price with her life! However, since it transpires that she was bitten
by a vampire, the girl is soon seeking her own victims – and she
settles upon the comic-relief manager (played by Alfredo Rizzo, later
director of the even worse THE BLOODSUCKER LEADS THE DANCE [1975],
which is actually a period Giallo!) who used to give her a hard time.
Though she fumbles the attempt, the scene is a striking one because she
turns up completely naked before him and, in fact, stays that way for
the rest of the duration (though, of course, this being the early 1960s
still, we are actually shown very little except brief glimpses of her
breasts)! As for Brandi, it is eventually revealed that he plays two roles: the
afore-mentioned aristocrat/castle owner and the rampaging vampire
(presumably his revived ancestor) However, the former also dabbles in
Science in an effort to cure the latter of his curse! The film
definitely scores a few points on atmosphere (particularly the very
first wraith-like appearance of the bloodsucker, predating by two years
Herk Harvey's in his own CARNIVAL OF SOULS, hiding from the heroine's
sight by the cemetery) and the climax – with the vampire first bloodily
disposing of the jealous undead dancer and, then, the Brandis facing it
off in the family crypt (where the tombs are adorned by a life-size
engraving of their respective occupants!).Though, at one point, the leading-lady is herself 'infected', there is
the expected happy ending: she leaves with the troupe, who had
conveniently exited the picture during its last act, until it is time
for the hero (needless to say, the two have fallen for one another) to
join her. For the record, director Regnoli was more usually credited as
scriptwriter but, recently, I did catch a not-too-bad noir of his (with
mild horror trimmings) from the same year i.e. I'LL SEE YOU IN HELL.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2171244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lastliberal</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
You are lost on a lonely Italian road. A storm is coming up. There is
no motel around. You spot a castle. Stay away, you dolt! Sleep in the
car. Do not enter the creepy castle.Alas, our group does not heed the warning and end up in a castle. The
owner, Count Gabor Kernassy (Walter Brandi), tries to shoo them away,
but there seems to be a connection with one named Vera (Lila Rocco).
She even knows where the smokes are kept, even though she has never
been there.Despite warnings, one of the girls (Maria Giovannini) goes wandering
and surprise, she's found dead the next day. I guess the story would
have ended too soon if they all obeyed the Count.There was not a lot of blood in this early Italian classic, and there
was only a brief flash of nudity. The girls did, however, do a lot of
running around in their see-through nighties. I always though castles
were cold and damp. I guess this one had central heat.For true vampire aficionados only.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2171244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lastliberal</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
You are lost on a lonely Italian road. A storm is coming up. There is
no motel around. You spot a castle. Stay away, you dolt! Sleep in the
car. Do not enter the creepy castle.Alas, our group does not heed the warning and end up in a castle. The
owner, Count Gabor Kernassy (Walter Brandi), tries to shoo them away,
but there seems to be a connection with one named Vera (Lila Rocco).
She even knows where the smokes are kept, even though she has never
been there.Despite warnings, one of the girls (Maria Giovannini) goes wandering
and surprise, she's found dead the next day. I guess the story would
have ended too soon if they all obeyed the Count.There was not a lot of blood in this early Italian classic, and there
was only a brief flash of nudity. The girls did, however, do a lot of
running around in their see-through nighties. I always though castles
were cold and damp. I guess this one had central heat.For true vampire aficionados only.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2171244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lastliberal</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>