<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Sundowners</original_title><alt_title>Horizons sans frontières</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Fred Zinnemann</director><producer>Warner Bros.</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
In the Australian Outback, the Carmody family--Paddy, Ida and their teenage son Sean--are sheep drovers...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Deborah Kerr</actor><actor>Robert Mitchum</actor><actor>Peter Ustinov</actor><rt_rating>6.9/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>78</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Frequently slow, solemn and simplistic, the films of Fred Zinneman are
the work of a director who appears to have equated artistry with
neatness, objectivity with aloofness, and significance with decorative,
humorless reverence… "The Sundowners" was perhaps the best 'Australian' film made up to that
time, and was, incidentally, a perceptive study of a marriage: Deborah
Kerr was the wife who wanted to settle down, and Robert Mitchum the
husband who didn't… It reveals much about their life-style and the land
in which they live… Their good teenaged son Sean (Michael Anderson Jr.)
explains the meaning of a sundowner as someone whose home is wherever
he happens to be when the sun goes down…So Paddy (Mitchum) and Ida (Kerr) are a warm and well-adjusted couple
with one grown son, except for one argument—the struggle between his
love of being a wanderer and her fundamental desire for the stability
of a home… Paddy was a man who couldn't settle in one place… For him,
most places were fit only for arrivals and departures… The film—which constantly endeavored to show the Australian woman's
compassion for the problems of women in a big male society—is also a
happy celebration with other notable participants being Glynis Johns as
an awfully pleasant barmaid-innkeeper who loves men's company and knows
how to deal with them; Peter Ustinov as an educated but slightly
mysterious Englishman, a likable drifter, a kind of an elderly turtle
who wears a nautical cap, with wealth of experience, but not much of a
mind to make use of it…This turtle signs on as a drover with Paddy,
apparently not so much for a job but for something to pass the time… Outstanding is a scene in which Ida, as a woman with no makeup, sitting
on the wagon, spots in the window of a stationary train a well-dressed
woman who obviously has all the things she doesn't... They look at each
other for an instance as the rich woman applies powder to her face… Ida
gently lifts her fingers over her cheeks… They stare at each other and
we rapidly notice Ida's thoughts…"The Sundowners" is one of the very best of Mitchum's films… In the pub
sequence, he is at his best when he sings "Botany Bay" and "Lime Juice
Tub." Deborah Kerr gave the role both a touch of delicacy and a touch of
sensuality… She wins, for her impressive performance, her sixth and
last Oscar nomination… The motion picture, splendidly photographed in Technicolor and with a
nice atmospheric music, contains fires in the dry forests, shearing
contests, fist-fights, the Aussie's love of beer, a game of two-up, a
big race meeting, much of the beautiful Australian landscape and the
life on sheep farming stations…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0314647/comments</url><from/><name>anonymous</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Set in Australia in the 1920s,this wonderful movie tells the story of
sheepdrover Mitchum, wife Kerr and son Anderson, drifting through the
Australian wilderness,never settling down.Tired of constantly being on the
move Kerr wants
a home for her family,but Mitchum is insensitive to his
family's
wishes.Deborah Kerr gives a fantastic performance that brings to life even the
inner emotions of her character.She's never been better.Robert Mitchum is
very believable in his assignment.It's perhaps one of his most complex
roles.Also Peter Ustinov scores a triumph:A man too irresponsible to have a
family of his own,and therefore clings to Mitchum and Kerr's
family.
The story isn't much on paper,but Fred Zinnemann's imaginative direction
gives the incidents the needed emotions.
Beautiful cinematography and sock performances from the rest of the cast
makes this a movie you shouldn't miss. 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1679475/comments</url><from>from Van Buren, Arkansas</from><name>krorie</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
For such a gifted actor as Robert Mitchum to go unrecognized by The
Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences is a shame and makes one
glad that George C. Scott did what he did in refusing to receive the
Oscar for his amazing work in "Patton." I don't want to mention Marlon
Brando because I'm still not certain what he was up to. He seemed to
want attention more than to make a statement when he flaunted the
Academy. Added to this shame is the same Academy virtually ignoring
Mitchum's co-star in this movie Deborah Kerr, also deserving of more
formal recognition for her contributions to the Hollywood dream
machine. Anyone who has any doubt about the outstanding acting
abilities of these two stars needs only watch "The Sundowners" to see
where I'm coming from. The rest of the cast in "The Sundowners" add to
the overall effectiveness of the movie, especially the brilliance of
Peter Ustinov.There is really not much of a story. The film is more of a character
study of a vagabond with a wife and a son who is trying to make a
living as a sheep drover in the outback of Australia. He encounters a
rather mysterious man Rupert Venneker (Ustinov) who becomes his hired
hand to help with the sheep. Paddy Carmody (Mitchum) is very happy with
this hand to mouth existence, living in a tent or sleeping out amongst
the stars, keeping a little change in a jar, but his wife and son
prefer a more settled existence, dreaming of owning their own ranch.
Director Fred Zinnemann captures the essence of vagabond life down
under filming on location in Australia, showing the exotic wild life in
all its beauty and spender. Technicolor and wide-screen heighten the
viewers enjoyment of this tale of dreams fulfilled and unfulfilled in a
land that is still somewhat mysterious to the average American.Of special note is the Australian music used by Zinnemann. In the first
pub scene Mitchum bellows out in a drunken Aussie accent one of John
Ford's favorites, "Wild Colonial Boy," but then sings a ballad that is
seldom heard on the big screen, "Botany Bay," about the infamous penal
colony from which modern Australia sprang. The versatile Robert Mitchum
was also a singer and songwriter. He helped write the music of his
production of "Thunder Road" and even had somewhat of a hit recording
of the title song in 1958. Rupert Venneker (Ustinov) makes fun of
Paddy's voice in "The Sundowners," but actually it wasn't bad.This is a rather long film, over two hours, but a highly enjoyable one.
I first saw it on the big screen when I was a senior in high school. It
was one of those flicks that stays with a person. I've had the pleasure
of seeing it a few more times since. It is still as fresh and as good
as when first released.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Robert Mitchum had one undeniable talent as an actor, his phenomenal
ability to pick up and use any kind of accent or dialect. I can't think
of another actor who could have so convincingly played a New England
hood in The Friends of Eddie Coyle, native Irish in Ryan's Daughter and
A Terrible Beauty, and pure Australian in The Sundowners. Although the
rest of the cast is great, it's his performance that pivots the whole
film. The movie itself is amazing in that the characters created are so
engaging that even though the film really has no plot, just a series of
connected wanderings, you enjoy it nevertheless. The film ending is
also offbeat. Normally you would think that Deborah Kerr would win out
in her desire to settle down on a farm. But unusual for Hollywood she
gives in to Mitchum's wanderlust. In their travels herding sheep through rural Australia of the 1920s
these people, hardworking and living close to the poverty line look
like their lives are fun. Like Mitchum's Paddy Carmody says he has no
worries and no ulcers because he doesn't own any property or has any
money in the bank. A whole lot like the real Mitchum in his Kerouac
like youth. It's what makes this film just good fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0204777/comments</url><from/><name>Strombol</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

It's a real joy just to watch this movie. It's a movie where the characters
really seem to come to life and inhabit the world which is presented to us
by director Fred Zinnemann. Even though the movie is basically about the
strong ties that keep a family together during changing times, he never lets
it get soppy. Robert Mitchum and Deborah Kerr play an Australian couple who
travel the around Australia, pick up jobs like cattle-driving and
sheep-shearing where they can, and never stay in place for too long. Michael
Anderson, Jr. plays their 16-year-old son, who begins to yearn for a steady
home and station in life. There are so many great things in the movie: the
photography, the way the story unfolds in an amusingly rambling pace, etc.
But the best has to be the cast. The Sundowners is probably Deborah Kerr's
least glamorous role and yet she has never been more attractive and
appealing than here. Perhaps it took a more gritty setting to really bring
her beauty to the surface. She seems less weighed down here than in other
roles. Robert Mitchum is a big hunk of tasteful testosterone. A
beer-drinking man's man who gets into fights but who nevertheless is
completely faithful to his family. Michael Anderson, Jr. is great at being
youthfully sunny and yet awkwardly self-conscious at the same time. The
movie has a truly great scene where the strong Mitchum faces off against a
frail-looking old man in a sheep-shearing contest and is surprisingly pushed
way beyond his physical limits. This dream of a movie also stars Peter
Ustinov and Glynis Johns in memorable roles. **** out of
****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0644657/comments</url><from>from Nagoya, Japan</from><name>galaxywest</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I have a few "special" movies. This is one of them. It's about people
needing people---like "Breakfast at Tiffanys." Can you imagine two more
different movies. But, the theme is the same, really. We need each other.
This movie is 100% honest. No gimmicks. Only one in a thousand movies can
claim that. You can have your "Citizen Kane" or your "Casablanca." I'll take
this movie. In a heartbeat. A wonderful story, a wonderful director, real
people. Honesty. Every inch of the movie is a joy. It's the kind of movie I
can watch over and over. It's a love story, really, isn't it. But, it's a
love story of two people who have been married a long time. How rare is
that. And, a story of a wonderful culture. And, the music is quite
beautiful, I think. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

"The Sundowners" was a favourite movie of mine at the time of its initial
release in 1960,and watching it again recently it still came across as a an
engaging and pleasant little movie but one that perhaps has lost something
of its impact with the passing years,ones in which Australian movies and
actors have come to the fore internationally.In 1960 it was considered
necessary to import two Hollywood names to give  world wide box office
appeal,something not necessary today with performers like Russell Crowe and
Cate Blanchett.(Of the egregious,smarmy self -centred Anglophobe Mr Gibson I
will remain silent)
Sundowners are itinerants ,moving from place to place in a small wagon
picking up work on an as and when basis.The Carmody family-Paddy,Ida and
teenage son Sean -are one such but while Paddy is content with the life the
others are keen to put down roots and buy a farm.
The picaresque tale tells of how the family as they drift across Australia
finding work at a sheep station,becoming race horse owners etc gradually
resolve their conflicts
En route they meet a nomadic upper class Englishman,played as well as ever
by Ustinov who acts as a kind of comic relief as he dispenses well honed
epigrams
The central section dealing with life on the sheep ranch is the best with
some richly comic scenes including a shearing contest and some bar room
scenes straight out of John FordThe accents of Kerr and Mitchum are not secure or convincing but they carry
the roles through sheer star power and their are strong contributions fron
Glynis Johns and John MeillonStill enjoyable but a remake with indigenous actors would be an interesting
idea
Still,all in all a bitter-sweet little gem of a movie I am glad I saw it
again
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0307374/comments</url><from/><name>Robert D. Ruplenas</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

First of all, this is one of the most gorgeous films to look at that I have
ever seen. Although I can't at this point identify the processing, I suspect
Cinemascope, which produced results that, in films of 40- or 50-year
vintage, are superior to the best of today's cheaper, inferior techniques.
The brilliant color, combined with the superb cinematography of the grandeur
of the Australian outback. make the movie a big piece of eye candy. The
performances, too, are first-rate, from a wonderful cast (Mitchum, Kerr,
Ustinov, Glynis Johns - who could ask for better?), and the story is a
warmly human one which draws us in. However, having said that, and having
enjoyed the movie immensely, one doesn't feel the desire to see it again, as
one does with similar movies that have a more deeply textured story, e.g.
The Quiet Man. I think it is just that the story, though interesting on a
superficial level, does not have the depth or complexity to make the film a
'keeper'. However, the Australian Tourist Bureau should be eternally
grateful. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2030420/comments</url><from/><name>perfectbond</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Anyone who enjoys the tales of the pioneers' trials to carve a nation out
of
the wilderness will enjoy the The Sundowners. The cast as would be
expected
is superb. It's a treat to see quintessential American
tough-guy-with-a-soft-spot Robert Mitchum, one of my all-time favorite
actors, pull of an Aussie accent. Deborah Kerr as the long-suffering but
loyal wife and devoted mother is also worthy of high praise. Peter
Ustinov
and his English accent provide great comic relief. All in all, very good
entertainment and insight into a lifestyle not familiar to the general
American public, 7/10. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This was a unique western in that (1) there are no villains; (2) no
gunfighters and gunfight and (3) only one man is shot in the whole
film.Most of it is a simple story of "Sundowners:" a group of migrant-type
workers who go from job to job - in this case as "sheep drovers." These
workers never have a permanent place to call home.In this particular story, the wife (Deborah Kerr) and their teenage boy
(Michael Anderson Jr.) want a home while the husband (Robert Mitchum)
doesn't want to settle down in one place. It may have American actors
but the scene is Australia. I found a number of the accents hard to
decipher. Peter Ustinov, Glynis Johns and Dina Merrill all add to this
impressive cast, which provides a lesson in solid acting. Ustinov's
character adds humor to the film, and the scenery is nice to ogle.You'd think with all these positive points I would rate this film
higher, but something was missing, perhaps a little excitement. This is
too low-key. The ending was kind of strange: not a a happy one but not
unhappy either.Yeah, it's a nice family story but not one I would go out of my way to
watch again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This was a unique western in that (1) there are no villains; (2) no
gunfighters and gunfight and (3) only one man is shot in the whole
film.Most of it is a simple story of "Sundowners:" a group of migrant-type
workers who go from job to job - in this case as "sheep drovers." These
workers never have a permanent place to call home.In this particular story, the wife (Deborah Kerr) and their teenage boy
(Michael Anderson Jr.) want a home while the husband (Robert Mitchum)
doesn't want to settle down in one place. It may have American actors
but the scene is Australia. I found a number of the accents hard to
decipher. Peter Ustinov, Glynis Johns and Dina Merrill all add to this
impressive cast, which provides a lesson in solid acting. Ustinov's
character adds humor to the film, and the scenery is nice to ogle.You'd think with all these positive points I would rate this film
higher, but something was missing, perhaps a little excitement. This is
too low-key. The ending was kind of strange: not a a happy one but not
unhappy either.Yeah, it's a nice family story but not one I would go out of my way to
watch again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/paul-brenner/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/The-Sundowners /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1804056</url><name>Paul Brenner</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>an enough enjoyable diversion</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-nusair/</url><url>http://www.reelfilm.com/fredzinn.htm#sundown /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1577151</url><name>David Nusair</name><from>Reel Film Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>...the film's lack of plot never becomes as pronounced as one might've feared...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/sundowners-the-3/ /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1560715</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>This sprawling, often boring saga of Aussie nomads in the 1920s is directed by Zinnemann with his customary tamed discipline and human realism, elevated by the solid ensemble.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/trevor-johnston/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/75627/the_sundowners.html /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1515048</url><name>Trevor Johnston</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Zinnemann's customary care for detail pays occasional dividends, but the film goes on rather too long.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?id=22341&amp;sourcetype=M /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1179788</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
4.5/5
					</rating><comment>A splendid, sprawling saga of Australia.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=108887 /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1146287</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>Overblown, but resolutely attractive star vehicle.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/15779_SUNDOWNERS.html /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=18656</url><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>A touching Fred Zinnemann movie.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/robin-clifford/</url><url>/m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1339269</url><name>Robin Clifford</name><from>Reeling Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1190497</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9401E3DF1630EF3ABC4153DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1020479-sundowners/comments.php?reviewid=1388496</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>What is nice about these people and valid about this film, is that they have an abundance of freshness, openness and vitality.</comment></review></movie>