<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Wild Ride</original_title><imdb_rating>4.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Harvey Berman</director><producer>Harvey Berman Productions</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A rebellious punk of the beat generation spends his days as an amateur dirt track driver in between partying and troublemaking...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jack Nicholson</actor><actor>Georgianna Carter</actor><actor>Robert Bean</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3672054/comments</url><from>from us</from><name>clayzar</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The Wild Ride is the original (B&amp;W) non-modified version. I have
watched it several times and believe it is one of the best cult
classics available. "Velocity" however, is a butchered color version
that splices in new scenes lacking in any sort of continuity and
ultimately destroying the mystique and integrity of the original film.
Whoever had the idea for Velocity needs to be shot in the head because
they turned a truly beautiful virgin classic film into a cheap
prostitute with too much makeup. This is a true testament to the "less
is more" adage. If you get to view both films you will see the ultimate
travesty of how a great film was destroyed by a greed driven marketing
attempt to update a true cult classic. In summary.... "The Wild Ride"
GOOD............."Velocity" BAAADDDD!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1453055/comments</url><from>from NYC</from><name> (stevenfallonnyc@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This may be my favorite "JD" flick. Nicholson is great as Johnny, the kid
who constantly gets into trouble, and who is the "big man" of his gang of
troublemakers. Of course there's one guy in the group who is getting a bit
tired of Johnny being the leader (especially since his girl seems to be
falling for Johnny) but he is still too scared of Johnny to do anything
about it. Johnny does have a friend he is a little soft with, Dave, who is getting on
Johnny's nerves still because he is dating a "lame chick." But Johnny always
defends Dave to the other gang members, even when Dave loses a game of
"chicken" with an oncoming truck.Johnny definitely has attitude, like with a cop:
Cop (getting a folder on Johnny): Here's your record.
Johnny: Did I make a record?Or when Johnny is buying booze...
Clerk: Do you have ID?
Johnny: Yeah.
Clerk: May I see it?
Johnny: No. Virtually every single line in this film has some kind of "hip slang" of the
times in it, which makes it non-stop fun and absolutely hilarious. You have
to pay attention all the way through as not to miss another classic line.Nicholson is a complete blast to watch. These are the kind of JD films that
are worth viewing, not overrated stuff like "Rebel Without A Cause."

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Sure, the first reason to see The Wild Ride (or, unfortunately as it
sounds, the 're-cut' Velocity which for some insane reasons extends the
story) is for Jack Nicholson. It's arguably his very first 'bad-boy'
role in a career with more than enough to go around. He's still got a
long way to go from here, but it's fun seeing him go practically method
about his character Johnny (apparently Nicholson just started with
Martin Landau at the time as his teacher), as he tries to sway Robert
Bean's Dave from going the not-hip route with a girl who isn't part of
'their scene' as it were. There's tension, there's some fall-out, and
in the end there's some overly high pitched melodrama following a chase
down a road. Nearly embarrassing to admit it, but for those who will
seek out the movie for that reason, as I did, it's not that bad (as in
*as bad* as some of his other B-movie work like The Terror and Rebel
Rousers).Hell, I'll even give one-time-only director Harvey Berman some credit:
for a picture that's main dramatic thrust is dictated mostly by the
same beef between Biff and the McFly's in the Back to the Future movies
("What's wrong? Chicken?" "Nobody calls me chicken!"), the Wild Ride
does provide the cheapest thrills necessary with a picture that
(thankfully) doesn't even run an hour's length of time. It gives a
halfway decent race-car sequence, and some nifty music in the end
climax (if not, of course, throughout). There's even an oddly
coincidental opening bit to the movie with that of Breathless, also
released in 1960, with a rebel and a cop on his trail (albeit this on
takes itself seriously, while Godard's parody).It's a silly bit of teens-and-hot-rods exploitation that is still
riding out whatever fuel is left from the 50s via the Wild One and
James Dean. It's tender moments are like tender cuts of lamb, and its
dialog is as pulpy as a moldy orange. And shame on me, perhaps, for
almost liking this diddle of a B-movie; at the least it features
something I've never seen before in another movie I can think of, which
is a guy working at a liquor store asking if the young man Johnny has
ID, he says yes, guy asks to see it, and Johnny says a simple 'No.'
5.5/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1594948/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>JumeirahSun</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I picked this movie up cheap out of a bargain bin. It is a double
feature disc with "The Little Shop of Horrors." When I started watching
it I was shocked to find that "Velocity," which I knew was circa 1960,
started off with a relatively new-looking scene of kids driving
dangerously. It seems that Vina Distributor (who put out this double
feature edition) or somebody decided to "update" the old teen flick
with some footage of more relevant "street punks." The bad "modern" teen meets a dude in a bar who looks a little like
Jack Nicholson but doesn't sound anything like him (I guess Jack has
better things to do these days, unlike these cutters) who tells him the
story of his young life. THEN we get into "Velocity," which is all that
the other reviews here promised.Jack is so young that one might not recognize him at first. This was
only his second role and he was 23 years old in 1960. It is pretty
funny and I gave it two stars for the yuks, but it is atrociously
dated. The version I have is colorized. I see on IMDb that "Velocity" is the video title and "The Wild Ride"
was the original name of the film. Maybe it was renamed "Velocity"
after the bizarre framing segments were added.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0009794/comments</url><from>from Grand Rapids, MI</from><name>MerleB (merleb@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

Has to be one of the worst movies of all time. Only partially redeemed by
Nicholson and the hot rod roadster driven by one of his gang members and
the
"hipster" dialogue that is so laughable. The dirt track race is the
lamest
movie race ever put to film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12756395/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rooster_davis</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Okay, this is not classic film-making. It has its moments though. Jack
Nicholson is about as young here as I can recall seeing him - almost
young enough to pull off the teenage-or-just-past delinquent role he
plays. The dialog is pretty full of then-current clichés and words, so
that part can be a little bit amusing. There isn't a whole heck of a
lot to say about this movie, either you like late 50's teen/delinquent
movies or you don't. I kinda like the '57 Ford convertible Nicholson
drives in this movie. I guess they made tons of this kind of movie back
in the day, because kids had little to do for evening entertainment
other than to go to the drive- in week after week, and the theaters
needed fresh fodder to keep the teens showing up. Well, it's a period
piece, don't watch it for any great entertainment value, just watch it
to see a somewhat exaggerated view of what life was like back when and
let it go at that.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This low-budget flick will probably be of interest only to Jack
Nicholson fans. This early role for the emerging star with the radiant
smile has Jack a hot-rodding beat generation Jekyll-Hyde duality of
character that defies everything and everyone on and off the road.
Johnny Varron(Nicholson)is a dirt track driver that has a need for
speed, buys his friends and ends up a cop killer. After serving fifteen
years in the pen, he returns as the mechanic for a mirror image of
himself. Lot of beatnik lingo and seems totally filmed outdoors.
Directed by Harvey Berman. Also in the cast: Georgianna Carter, Robert
Bean, Judith Tresize, Carol Bigby and John Bologni.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
This is an exploitation flick meant to entertain and perhaps teach us
about the dangers of angry young beatniks with fast cars. Jack
Nicholson stars as a larger than life punk who has a group of loyal
young idiots who follow him with almost cult-like devotion. And, when
one of the members DOESN'T, it ultimately spells disaster."The Wild Ride" was very low budget throughout and looks it. Aside from
a very good performance by Nicholson as an angry jerk, the rest of the
cast are uniformly bland. Also the story suffers because it is neither
florid and 'racy' enough to be salacious nor is it ever especially
believable. So, if you are a bad movie fan, it's just not bad enough to
be especially entertaining and everyone else would just be pretty bored
by it. But, on the positive side, it's not an embarrassment for
Nicholson or any of the rest of the cast to be in this rather limp
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8239592/comments</url><from>from The Last New Jersey Drive-In on the Left</from><name>Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Evil, arrogant, and amoral devil-may-care hot-rod hellion Johnny Varron
(an incredibly young Jack Nicholson in fine snotty form) kills a cop
and hassles his nice guy best buddy Dave (likable Robert Bean) because
he disapproves of Dave's sweet new girlfriend Nancy (fetching blonde
Georgianna Carter). Director Harvey Berman relates the engrossing story
at a steady pace, soaks up the whole teen rebel scene with considerable
aplomb (besides the expected lively and exciting vehicular carnage, we
also get some cool dancing, lots of hysterically dated hepcat slang,
and a rousing rough'n'tumble fistfight), and ensures that there are no
dreary lulls throughout the tight 60 minute running time. Moreover,
it's a total treat to watch a pre-stardom Nicholson play a blithely
cocky and wicked adolescent bad egg with obvious lip-smacking relish.
Taylor Sloan's crisp black and white cinematography gives the picture
an attractive sharp look. The swinging bebop jazz score does the groovy
trick. The tragic bummer ending packs a pretty strong punch as well. A
nifty little quickie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3434838/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rixrex</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Jack Nicholson has done better and most likely not done worse.He's a punky teen hot-rodder exhibiting all the characteristics of a
1959-1960 juvenile delinquent. He's sore at his best buddy for hooking
up with a girl who's not into the beatnik punk-kid scene and not eager
to let her new guy stay this course to disaster. Best buddy is waffling
between going straight and staying with the witless crowd. Nicholson
exhibits a weird sort of subconsciously gay relationship with best
buddy by trying to place a wedge between the gal and the pal.Ending is totally out of context with the morals of this leader of the
pack, but necessary for the film to have sociological value. Lots of
fun to watch just for the wild slang.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3434838/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rixrex</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Jack Nicholson has done better and most likely not done worse.He's a punky teen hot-rodder exhibiting all the characteristics of a
1959-1960 juvenile delinquent. He's sore at his best buddy for hooking
up with a girl who's not into the beatnik punk-kid scene and not eager
to let her new guy stay this course to disaster. Best buddy is waffling
between going straight and staying with the witless crowd. Nicholson
exhibits a weird sort of subconsciously gay relationship with best
buddy by trying to place a wedge between the gal and the pal.Ending is totally out of context with the morals of this leader of the
pack, but necessary for the film to have sociological value. Lots of
fun to watch just for the wild slang.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3434838/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rixrex</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>