<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Esther and the King</original_title><alt_title>Esther et le roi</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>USA</country><director>Raoul Walsh</director><producer>Galatea Film</producer><producer>Titanus</producer><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis/><actor>Joan Collins</actor><actor>Richard Egan</actor><actor>Denis O'Dea</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2955724/comments</url><from>from Tunbridge Wells, England</from><name>James Hitchcock</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film shortly after seeing "Spartacus", which probably meant
that it was not seen to its best advantage. Although both films date
from the same year, and although both fall within the same tradition of
the historic/Biblical epic, they are very different in terms of
quality. Whereas "Spartacus" is perhaps the greatest epic ever made,
"Esther and the King" is very much from the bargain-basement end of the
market.Like a number of other bargain-basement epics ("Samson and Delilah",
"Salome" and "Solomon and Sheba" all come to mind), "Esther" is an odd
mixture of godliness and sexiness. Films of this nature generally
preached a vaguely Christian message (in this case that religious
toleration is preferable to sectarian genocide) but in order to get
that message across the producers seemed to find it necessary to show
as much female flesh as the censors of the day would permit, with
nubile slave-girls and scantily-dressed dancers much in evidence. The
Bible tells us that Queen Vashti incurred the displeasure of her
husband King Ahasuerus because she refused his command to appear in the
palace "to shew the people and the princes her beauty". In this film,
however, Vashti is guilty of quite the opposite offence, namely that of
showing the people and the princes more of her beauty than she ought to
by doing a striptease down to her panties in the royal hall.There is, moreover, a good deal of male flesh on view as well as
female. The main qualification for the male lead in this type of epic
was a pair of muscular legs that would look good in a short kilt or
tunic. (Acting ability was very much a secondary consideration). This
convention is adhered to here; although the ancient Persians, unlike
the Greeks, Romans or Egyptians, preferred to wear trousers, Richard
Egan as Ahasuerus still dresses Roman-style, as do Sergio Fantoni as
the main villain Haman and Richard Battaglia as the secondary hero
Simon. (Simon is an invented character not found in the Biblical
account, Esther's sweetheart before she is chosen as the King's second
wife).The one person who is exempt from the need to strip down to the bare
essentials is, surprisingly enough, Joan Collins, strikingly attractive
in this film but covered up throughout. I say "surprisingly" because
since "The Bitch" and "Dynasty" the popular perception is that she was
a one-trick pony, an actress who specialised in playing sultry
villainesses and little else. There was, however, more to her than
that. Although she did play a villainess in her earlier epic "Land of
the Pharaohs", she was a versatile actress during her time as a
Hollywood star and was quite as much at home playing virtuous heroines.
(In "Sea Wife" she even played a nun). Here she plays Esther as an
innocent girl-next-door suddenly, and unexpectedly, raised to royal
status, and is probably the best actor on display.As with many epics, liberties are taken with history. Much of the plot
turns upon a coming war between the Persians and the Greeks under "that
young Macedonian upstart Alexander". The Biblical Ahasuerus is normally
identified by historians with the Persian King Xerxes I, who reigned
from 485 to 465 BC, well before the time of Alexander (356-323 BC).
When war comes in the film, the Persians defeat the Greeks, whereas
Alexander was in fact victorious in his war against Persia. In order to
strengthen the religious tone of the film, a contrast is made between
the monotheistic Jews and supposedly polytheistic Persians; in reality
the state religion of Persia at this time was Zoroastrianism, a
religion which only recognised one god, Ahura Mazda. The film's main weakness, however, is not its departures from both the
Biblical version of the story or from historical fact, something that
could be forgiven if the resulting film was artistically satisfying.
The main problem is that I found it impossible to believe in either the
characters or the story. With the exception of Denis O'Dea as Esther's
wise old uncle Mordecai, all the male stars are either wooden or hammy,
and with the exception of Collins herself the female ones are just
twentieth-century glamour girls transported back in time, with no real
function other than to look decorative. The dialogue often sounds
stilted, sometimes deliberately so, and this has the effect of
distancing the film even further from reality. It may be a fantasy of
the ancient world rather than an attempt to recreate that world
accurately, but even a fantasy needs to be populated by characters who
bear some resemblance to flesh-and-blood human beings. Apart from
Collins and O'Dea, that resemblance is all too often lacking. 5/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0638989/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>lora64</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Amidst the wars, pageantry, violence and mayhem, not to mention palace
intrigues, is a touching story of Esther's growing love for the king,
played
by Richard Egan, one handsome fellow, I must admit. In many of the quieter
scenes the lovely music adds much to the atmosphere, evoking gentler moods
and feelings. As well, I've always admired Denis O'Dea whatever role he
played, and here as the steadfast Mordecai he gives a fine performance as
usual. I like the sincerity of the actors, and an innocent portrayal of
Esther by Joan Collins is so refreshing. The pace of the story is steady
throughout so that one doesn't feel slowed down. Most action episodes are
fierce enough for me, thank you, as some violence is inevitable in movies
such as this. All in all it's a good movie that I personally
cherish.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1086394/comments</url><from>from Baltimore, Maryland</from><name>heliopause</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Like other Italian works of this era, underappreciated and cynically
criticized for what it is not, this is a work of art, beautifully woven
together in music, mood, and cinematography leaving the viewer in the end
fulfilled in the desire to escape from the modern world into a place
inaccessible, and, yes, surrealistic.The music, written by the Italian master Francesco Lavagnino, one of the
great movie music composers of the 20th century, commands the mood of each
scene and spans the range of moods in the work, from the march of soldiers
to the Queen in the flower garden to her love scene with the King to the
mystic mood in the ruins where Simon hides.  It is a fine piece of
composition.The words in the script are, in some scenes, not meant to be ordinary
conversation, but rather noble thoughts, royal council, and human
aspirations, and thus are written and delivered as such.  When mental
burdens weigh heavily on the King, he is told by his friend Mordecai that
"... by lifting the burdens of others one can lift one's own burden ... "
Such thoughts are actually quite profound, that in some cases depressed
moods arise from self-centered thinking and self-victimization, and that
by
helping others in a selfless way one can relieve one's own burdens.  In
the
garden, Mordecai councils Esther that " .. the King is attracted to her
sense of justice and loyalty, the same qualities that bind her still to
Simon, her previous love, and that may turn the King against her in
jealousy..."The cinematography in the scene of the death of Simon, where the camera
rises above Simon and the queen to the Star of David, which then appears
on
the wall of the next scene, is very well done.  In another scene, the King
is asked whom he had chosen to be his queen, and as he replies "A girl
named
Esther", the camera pans past the concerned face of Haman to reveal the
quite different satisfied expression of Mordecai.There is much to appreciate in the music, words, and visual presentation
of
this work.  Of course this is not meant to be a documentary, a faithful
retelling of an ancient story.  Criticism should be directed at how it
fails
in its own intent as a melancholic, romantic, and introspective fantasy,
rather than based on the viewer's expectations.  If my understanding of
its
intent is near the mark, then my conclusion is that this work, like the
Raoul Walsh epic The Big Trail made 30 years earlier, succeeds very
well.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
There isn't a whole lot to distinguish this middling biblical epic from
the sea of others that came out in the mid-50's and early 60's, but it
offers a certain degree of entertainment. Egan (decidedly miscast)
plays the King of Persia (with Brillcremed hair and a standard American
accent) who returns from a long battle to find that his wife has been
enjoying the services of one or more of his men. He excuses himself
from her and sets out to find a new virgin bride, choosing from all the
maidens in his kingdom. Virginal Jewess Collins (yes...that's right) is
the title character. She is snatched away mere moments before becoming
wed to Battaglia and is taken to the palace to be groomed for the
selection process. Once there, she is protected by her uncle O'Dea (who
entreats her to hide her Jewish heritage) and is targeted by Fantoni
who is Egan's right-hand man. Fantoni has another lady in mind for the
throne so he can use her to his own ends of taking over the kingdom.
Eventually, Collins realizes that she and only she can spare her people
from destruction and she decides to leave behind her dreams of a life
with Battaglia and pursue Egan. Egan, still in very good shape
physically, makes a handsome king and gives an okay performance. He is
just patently contemporary in his look and delivery. Collins is very
attractive throughout (complete with heavy bouffant 60's hair!) and
does an adequate job as well, but is always more interesting as a
villainess than as a docile young maiden. O'Dea lends able support as
her wise and stalwart uncle. It would be difficult to summon up a more
virile, hirsute, hunk of man than Battaglia as Collin's abandoned
lover. Seeing him, one can understand the torment she had at having to
turn her back on her past and move on. The location work, fancy sets,
pageantry and gauzy costumes keep this from being too dull, but there
is an awful lot of chatter and hand-wringing in between the action
sequences. Stay awake for the scene in which Egan gifts Collins with a
tiger cub and then immediately steps over to a lyre and plunks out what
sounds like the opening strains of "Born Free"! As expected,
considerable liberties have been taken with the original story, yet it
doesn't result in that much more spectacular a film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Esther and the King may appear unusual if you take a look at the usual
things I write about. But because Mario Bava was so heavily involved
with the film, I just had to give it a go. While the visuals may not be
as vivid and exaggerated as some of the films he had more control over,
you can see his influences if you look closely. There are several
scenes that demonstrate Bava's use of color. One very brief scene early
in the film shows the palace guards turning a wheel to close the gates.
This scene that lasts less than 10 seconds is lit in very dramatic
style with a wash of green and red. It's trademark Bava.As for the film, I really didn't expect to enjoy it as much as I did.
Oh, it's not great by any stretch of the imagination. Esther and the
King was part of the flood of Biblical epics that were made in the late
50s to early 60s. Actually, Esther and the King should be called a
mini-epic. It's not as sprawling or grand as the big budgeted Hollywood
epics. The sets look cheap in comparison and there are no great action
sequences. The first half of the film drags by at a snails pace. The
final thirty minutes do provide a little suspense and save Esther and
the King from becoming a total waste of time. I'm not even going to
discuss how well the film follows the Biblical story as that's a topic
best covered elsewhere.I've never cared for Joan Collins, but here she's quite good. I found
myself believing in her character and rooting her on. Another standout
to me is Sergio Fantoni as the evil Haman. The man plays a bad guy to
perfection. The rest of the cast is serviceable but not spectacular.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1869359/comments</url><from>from New York City</from><name>gazebo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a good looking movie, too bad it is so mediocre.  Joan Collins is
beautiful and her acting is okay, but it can't save this movie.  The other
actors were okay too.  This movie was hampered by the campy dialogue and a
mediocre script.  I was unhappy that partway through the movie, the story
veers away from the traditional bible story of Queen Esther.  I heard that
this movie is one of Joan Collins' least favorite movies, and I understand
why now.  Somehow, if the writer of this movie had gone the traditional
route of Queen Esther accusing Haman at the banquet, there would be the much
needed drama and excitement.However, if anyone has a hankering to see a real campy film filled with
pretty people, pretty clothes and silly dialogue, this is
it!I give this movie a "D".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2382545/comments</url><from>from Regina, Saskatchewan, Canada</from><name>L. Denis Brown (ldbrown1@shaw.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I have long found it difficult to remember any of the distinctive
features of this particular film which was released in 1960 towards the
end of a decade that featured numerous similar biblical epics. Checking
a dozen of these at random one probable reason for this quickly became
clear - Esther and the King had the lowest weighted rating among IMDb
users. However it has been featured as a home video on several DVD's
whilst many of its contemporaries from the same period have never seen
a DVD release (except perhaps in the form of Asiatic copies), and this
made me feel it might be worth watching again. On doing so, my first
reaction was a better appreciation of how good an actress Joan Collins
used to be. Sibling loyalty in playing many almost unplayable parts
from her sisters rather trashy novels was probably very commendable,
but must have lost her many fans from those who did not remember how
well she could also play other types of part. But I also quickly became
aware of the many deficiencies in this film. The dialogue was very
artificial, and the architecture and costumes seemed more improbable
than usual. Its historical period, a few centuries before the Christian
era, was one where there were beautiful fabrics but few fashion
designers, and no images from the period which I have seen in museums
had prepared me for costumes which all so effectively emphasised the
female bust - or for such a variety of western style coiffures.
Similarly the male costumes were more reminiscent of a cross between
colourful academic robes and casually decorative dressing gowns. No
doubt there are experts who can tell us what we could expect from the
architecture of the period, particularly that to be met with in Royal
palaces, but somehow the palace in this film was too reminiscent of
Hollywood style homes. The lighting in the copy I saw (which may not
have done justice to the original film) seemed quite inadequate. Both
still art and cinematography frequently make very effective use of spot
lighting, the shaft of sunlight or the single candle close under the
chin, to provide both mood and atmosphere for a scene, but when this is
repeated continuously throughout a full length film, with everything
else frequently disappearing into a gloomy background it can become
very monotonous to watch. This was one of the early films in which
Mario Bava learned his trade, his later ones show his ultimate mastery
of graphic imaging to better advantage. I do not concur with the
criticisms that early scenes were slow with insufficient action - these
scenes provided essential character development whilst action scenes
generally provide very little except a touch of the spice that should
always be used with great restraint. But the action when it finally
took place was largely at night, and groups of armed men with their
swords flashing and clashing, barely glimpsed through the enveloping
darkness, contributed nothing towards carrying the story onwards. This
contrasted very poorly with "Sodom and Gomorrah" - a longer film that
also only featured one battle, but a lengthy one which Robert Aldrich
shot sequentially in daylight so that viewers could understand the
tactics adopted by both sides and follow the ebb and flow of fortune
right through.The brief critique above is probably sufficient to explain the poor
IMDb User ratings for this film, but I must acknowledge that I enjoyed
re-watching it very much more than I had expected to, and after all
personal enjoyment is the reason for watching this type of film. I do
not find it easy to understand what so much attracted me to the film
but a partial explanation was certainly the acting (despite the poor
dialogue that was imposed upon the cast by their filmscript). Apart
from Joan Collins as Esther, Daniela Rocca gave a fine performance as
Queen Vashti (as well as what may be the nearest to a striptease to
have ever been featured in a film produced under the Hayes code. One
may wonder what that of Rita Hayworth in "Salome" would have been like
if she had been allowed to finish it and not interrupted by the arrival
of John the Baptist's head on a platter, but as things stand the palm
has to be awarded to Daniela Rocci. She probably only got away with it
because the Queen paid for her folly with her life a few sequences
later in true Hayes Code style) On the male side Richard Egan provides
a commanding and sympathetic portrait of King Ahasuerus but the honours
are shared by Denis o'Dea as the wise and discrete elder statesman
Mordecai and Sergio Fantoni who plays Haman brilliantly, always showing
a smiling face to the world and displaying complete self- confidence
that he is clever enough to achieve his goal whatever minor obstacles
crop up en- route. Rick Battaglia as Simon - a non-biblical character -
also plays his part extremely well.Ultimately however the whole is often greater than the parts, and this
seems to be particularly true here. Hollywood-Italian Sword and Sandals
epics almost always have a very fine musical score carefully integrated
with a deliberately rather poetic (or even Shakespearean dialogue), and
with both the lighting and cinematography, that enables them to capture
a mood of relaxation and fantasy. Even children's films such as
"Hercules, Samson and Ulysses" which initially seem totally laughable
still have something of this quality. Surrender yourself to the mood
and forget reality for a few brief hours, and you may find this is one
of the films that still has a lot to offer. Rating it is not easy.
Based on its technical failings and inadequacies my rating would
probably be 5, but I have preferred to rate it on the cinematographic
experience it provided for me and have rated it at 7.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3607375/comments</url><from>from California, USA</from><name>siameseoverlord (siameseoverlord@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I just got finished seeing this historical drama. As a religious Jew, I
wondered how the story would be played out on the big screen. I enjoyed
it very much, even though it has a lot of "historical liberties".
Overall, its a pretty good version of the Book of Esther, and while not
as big an epic as The Ten Commandments, it still adds in a little
"extra" drama to keep the non-Jewish audience interested. While not
exactly what happened, most of the story is accurate.Joan Collins is very beautiful, and gives a believable performance as
Esther, and Dennis O'Dea is excellent as Mordcai. The Actors playing
King Ahaserous, and Prince Haman, were just a little too clean-shaven
and handsome; but that's Hollywood! I will probably watch it again, before I un-tivo it...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
1960's Esther and the King may well be the very worst of 20th Century
Fox's CinemaScope Biblical epics, but even in its tax shelter
production line way it soars head-and-shoulders over One Night with the
King. There's certainly talent behind the camera – Raoul Walsh
directing, producing and co-writing, Francesco Lavagnino scoring and
Mario Bava director of photography – yet despite the Hollywood talent
it plays like any one of a dozen Italian sword-and-sandals saga (the
film was shot in Italy with an Italian crew). Part of it is the film's
look, but a big part of it is the way it sounds: with only three of the
leads seeming to use their own voices, most of the Italian cast either
can't pronounce any but the most basic English words or are dubbed by
the same people who'd go from dubbing Steve Reeves movies to every
other paella Western you've ever seen. Mind you, Richard Egan
mispronounces a lot of his dialogue and he's American, so has no
excuse. Yet while he's pretty woefully inadequate at anything that
requires acting or much more than standing looking confident in a
Charles Atlas advert kind of way, there's something about how bad he is
that makes it just impossible to dislike him. If anything you feel
sorry for him being planted in a job he's so clearly not up to while
admiring his determination to give it a try anyway. Luckily, Joan
Collins' Esther is pretty good and the story is strong enough to
survive direlogue like "You've plundered your last helpless village!"
even if the film is more functional than inspirational.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Much like another feminist and contemporaneous Biblical epic i.e Henry
Koster's THE STORY OF RUTH (1960), this turns out to be more enjoyable
and even compelling than one expects it to be. Actually, although I was
aware of Mario Bava's engagement as a cinematographer here, it had not
occurred to me that he was also a co-director (which prompted this
unforeseen revisit from yours truly – a few weeks after Good Friday
which would have been the ideal time for it). As was often the case
with such U.S./Italian co-productions, a Hollywood veteran 'supervised'
the production actually helmed by an Italian craftsman; in Bava's case,
he had already collaborated with Jacques Tourneur on THE GIANT OF
MARATHON (1959) and would do so again with Henry Levin on THE WONDERS
OF ALADDIN (1961; see my review above). However, when it comes to
ESTHER AND THE KING, it seems that Raoul Walsh's involvement was much
more hands on since, atypically for him at the twilight of his
impressive career, he was also the producer and co-screenwriter of the
film! Joan Collins and Richard Egan ably portray the titular roles of
the Hebrew maiden and the Persian King and the cast list is peppered
with recognizable faces that add appeal to the alternately solemn and
campy proceedings: Denis O'Dea (in his last screen appearance as
Collins' uncle and Egan's trusted counselor), Rik Battaglia (as
Collins' embittered fiancé and Egan's former friend), Sergio Fantoni
(clearly enjoying himself a great deal as the film's leering villain),
Daniela Rocca (as Egan's nymphomaniac wife – the dance sequence ending
with her topless has to be seen to be believed), Rosalba Neri (as
Fantoni's ambitious but ill-fated mistress), Gabriele Tinti (as
Battaglia's pal) and Folco Lulli (regrettably wasted in a throwaway
cameo towards the end of the film). While the few scattered fight
sequences are not particularly vivid or exciting, another element I
enjoyed was the equally rousing and lovely music score that is here
credited to Angelo Francesco Lavagnino (a peplum veteran) and Roberto
Nicolosi (a Bava regular).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Much like another feminist and contemporaneous Biblical epic i.e Henry
Koster's THE STORY OF RUTH (1960), this turns out to be more enjoyable
and even compelling than one expects it to be. Actually, although I was
aware of Mario Bava's engagement as a cinematographer here, it had not
occurred to me that he was also a co-director (which prompted this
unforeseen revisit from yours truly – a few weeks after Good Friday
which would have been the ideal time for it). As was often the case
with such U.S./Italian co-productions, a Hollywood veteran 'supervised'
the production actually helmed by an Italian craftsman; in Bava's case,
he had already collaborated with Jacques Tourneur on THE GIANT OF
MARATHON (1959) and would do so again with Henry Levin on THE WONDERS
OF ALADDIN (1961; see my review above). However, when it comes to
ESTHER AND THE KING, it seems that Raoul Walsh's involvement was much
more hands on since, atypically for him at the twilight of his
impressive career, he was also the producer and co-screenwriter of the
film! Joan Collins and Richard Egan ably portray the titular roles of
the Hebrew maiden and the Persian King and the cast list is peppered
with recognizable faces that add appeal to the alternately solemn and
campy proceedings: Denis O'Dea (in his last screen appearance as
Collins' uncle and Egan's trusted counselor), Rik Battaglia (as
Collins' embittered fiancé and Egan's former friend), Sergio Fantoni
(clearly enjoying himself a great deal as the film's leering villain),
Daniela Rocca (as Egan's nymphomaniac wife – the dance sequence ending
with her topless has to be seen to be believed), Rosalba Neri (as
Fantoni's ambitious but ill-fated mistress), Gabriele Tinti (as
Battaglia's pal) and Folco Lulli (regrettably wasted in a throwaway
cameo towards the end of the film). While the few scattered fight
sequences are not particularly vivid or exciting, another element I
enjoyed was the equally rousing and lovely music score that is here
credited to Angelo Francesco Lavagnino (a peplum veteran) and Roberto
Nicolosi (a Bava regular).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/walsh.htm#Esther /m/esther_and_the_king/comments.php?reviewid=1396712</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>One of the best Biblical films, moving and trenchant.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/esther_and_the_king/comments.php?reviewid=1403356</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9A03EED9173CEF3ABC4152DFB767838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/esther_and_the_king/comments.php?reviewid=1389128</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/20131_ESTHER_AND_THE_KING.html /m/esther_and_the_king/comments.php?reviewid=211409</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>