<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Elmer Gantry</original_title><alt_title>Elmer Gantry, le charlatan</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Richard Brooks</director><producer>Elmer Gantry Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Elmer Gantry is a fast talking, hard drinking traveling salesman who always has a risqué story and a hip flask to entertain cronies and customers alike...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Burt Lancaster</actor><actor>Jean Simmons</actor><actor>Arthur Kennedy</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Elmer Gantry the novel came out in 1925 and it took 35 years to get it
to the screen. But it certainly was worth the wait. The movie provided
Burt Lancaster, Shirley Jones, and Richard Brooks all with Oscars and
it has become a classic. But we sure view it differently 80 years after
the book and 55 years after the movie debuted.Inherit the Wind and Elmer Gantry came out in the same year and both
were set in the Twenties. Both dealt with fundamentalist religion and
the power it held. Both films got Oscar nominated for best film and for
Best Actor for it's first billed male player.In 1960 when you saw both films they were viewed as tales of a bygone
era. Evangelists like Elmer Gantry and Sister Sharon Falconer have the
kind of power that thankfully we don't give the fundamentalist
community now. Even seeing film clips of Billy Sunday and Aimee Semple
McPherson, they seemed quaint and old fashioned. Fortunately we'd
outgrown the nonsense of that era.But Sinclair Lewis proved to be a prophet. No one could ever have
dreamed in 1960 that fundamentalist Christians would have the political
power they do today. What Lewis if he were alive today would do with
Pat Robertson, Jerry Falwell, John Hagee and the rest of that crowd
would really be something. Elmer Gantry is alive and well. Some might
even call it a resurrection.And Elmer's a part that comes once in a lifetime to a player. Liar,
conman, womanizer and likable on top. You've got to be a real extrovert
to play that part. So Richard Brooks got perhaps one of the biggest
extroverts ever to hit Hollywood.Burt Lancaster was born to play Gantry, in fact he'd had something of a
dress rehearsal in the part in The Rainmaker. During those sermon
scenes, some of which are taken from Billy Sunday's actual sermons, you
know he's giving out with nonsense and you still get taken in by his
charm. Note the relationship between Lancaster and agnostic reporter
Arthur Kennedy. Kennedy knows he's a conman, but still they get along
just great.It was a shame that Jean Simmons was neglected by the Academy for her
portrayal of Sharon Falconer. Sharon is a true believer, but she's also
a romantic as the real Aimee Semple McPherson was. And the woman had
needs which Elmer is only too glad to fulfill.The real Aimee was also an outrageous character herself, but I believe
a decent soul at heart. During the Depression, her tabernacle set up a
soup kitchen that fed thousands. In fact Anthony Quinn, growing up in
Los Angeles at the time, recalled in his memoirs working for his and
his family's supper as a volunteer there. Quinn had nothing but praise
for Aimee, she was the difference in whether his family ate or not on
many a day.Shirley Jones got a career salvation with her Oscar winning role as
Lulu Baines, prostitute who's out for vengeance. A fine singer, she
came along unfortunately when musicals were winding down. That Oscar
for Best Supporting Actress insured a continuing career for her.Arthur Kennedy as the investigative reporter is whose perspective we
view the film from. He'd had five trips to the Oscar World Series
without a victory, might have been nice if this one had been a sixth.
His is the voice of reason, of true compassion, of truth in fact the
voice of Sinclair Lewis himself.Another of Sinclair Lewis's great characters, George F. Babbitt, makes
an appearance. Edward Andrews got probably his career part as Babbitt,
hypocritical businessman to the max. He was as born to play Babbitt as
Lancaster was to play Gantry. He could also have been given an Oscar
nomination.Elmer Gantry is a great film, a prophetic film, proving it sure can
happen here.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3533592/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Clark Richards</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
And there was light---9/10.All you need to know about the character of Elmer Gantry is neatly
summed up in the first 10 minutes of the film. The film opens as we see
Gantry holding court around a table in a bar, telling jokes and
anecdotes of sexual conquests one minute, and then the next minute is
helping out two wayward parishioners by passing the hat around the bar
and preaching in earnest the word of God. Lancaster plays out the
duality in the role of Gantry as everyman/ preacher brilliantly
throughout the film. We're witness to his meteoric rise within the
ranks of the religious road show, we see his stumbles within those
ranks and his eventual fall from popularity to an even more impossible
grace under fire (literally), but most importantly we see the ability
of his character to serve both his rise and fall in ways truly
unexpected. Gantry finds that there are many who will listen to him wax eloquent on
the bible. But when Gantry sees Sister Sharon Falconer (as played by
Jean Simmons) he forgets about getting closer to the lord and decides
to ingratiate himself into her 'inner circle'. Gantry can see that the
'old time religion show' is a soul saver on Sunday, but quite a
moneymaker on Monday. There are 'two very different' Gantry's, the one
who has a lifetime of sexual anecdotes and the other who's true love is
for the bible. What we are not in store for is the third Gantry; the
one in love with Elmer Gantry and his own voice. In any case, Gantry
sees a golden opportunity to satisfy all three Gantry's and he goes for
it. Through his ability to con and sweet talk his way to the top,
Gantry makes all of the right friends and maneuvers himself to a spot
underneath Sister Sharon Falconer. Gantry's fall comes in the form of Lulu Baines (as played by Shirley
Jones), a prostitute with a past history with Gantry. As Gantry's
popularity on the 'road show' circuit starts to hit its zenith, Baines
appears into Gantry's life once again as she sets up Gantry for
blackmail. How Gantry deals with Baines and the loss of trust from
Sister Sharon is one of the best moments from the film. And although
her time on screen doesn't come close to matching that of both
Lancaster and Simmons, it is the performance of Jones in one scene that
practically steals the show. Jones' speech to the ladies in the brothel
about Gantry "Ramming the fear of God so fast" into her was
exhilaratingly fun and mildly erotic. I would think it was largely this
scene that got her noticed by the Academy in 1960.However great Lancaster is as Gantry (Oscar winning performance) and
spectacular Jones is as Baines (another Oscar winner), let us not
forget how easy it would have been for this movie to have THREE Oscar
WINNERS!!! Yes, Jean Simmons was robbed by the Academy that year. I
think there are at least three reasons as to why Jean Simmons was not
given the Oscar that year. One is the brutally lame ending to the
movie. Sister Sharon is left to walk about the fiery inferno of her
newly built church, while everyone around her is knocking her to the
ground trying to escape. Sister Sharon is oblivious to human stampedes
and is more concerned in urging everyone to remain calm. A performance
that must not have been lost on John Landis when he made Kevin Bacon
reprise it in 'Animal House' some 18 years later (sans the fire). It
was a shame to see her babbling like an idiot while certain death
surrounded her. That's one reason, but the other two reasons are
probably more to the truth. You see, Jean Simmons wasn't the only
actress who can claim to have been robbed on Oscar night, so could
Shirley Maclaine. The Oscar could have gone to either one, but if it
had gone to Jean Simmons, The Academy would've had a hard time giving
any award to the 'The Apartment' or its director Billy Wilder. How
could 'Elmer Gantry' win three of the four main awards yet not walk
away with the Best Picture? It's also been said the Academy felt bad
for Elizabeth Taylor as she was not only recovering from the recent
death of her husband, Michael Todd, but also that she had just needed
an emergency tracheotomy only weeks before the awards. However, one
point should be clear, Elizabeth Taylor never should have won the Oscar
over the performances that year from Simmons or Maclaine.Another performer from the movie who gives a great performance is
Arthur Kennedy as Jim Lefferts. Lefferts is the skeptical newsman who
follows the 'road show' waiting to see a miracle or perhaps to see many
a false prophet fall. One scene that stands out is the scene where
Lefferts is dictating an article on the exploits of Lancaster and
Simmons' religious road show. While he is dictating he is also
absent-mindedly sharpening a pencil. As Lefferts comments become to
take on more of a cynical tone, the pencil in his hand also becomes
sharper. Once Lefferts is through with his thought, the pencil has been
sharpened to a fine point and his thoughts are ready for print. He
writes, "Is it a church, is it a religion or is it a circus sideshow
complete with freaks, magic and rabble rousing? This is a fine film with a slightly disappointing ending. I can't
accept that the errant fling of a cigarette can flash through the
heavens like a message from God, but if ever a bolt of lightning was
captured onto the silver screen, it was the bolt from Burt Lancaster as
Elmer Gantry. 9/10.Clark Richards
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4304070/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Billie</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"Elmer Gantry" is an amazing film that does not seem dated at all,
having lost none of its bite or appeal with the passing of time. Taken
from the classic Sinclair Lewis novel of the same name, director
Richard Brooks garnered an Oscar for Best Screenplay for his
adaptation, and Burt Lancaster won his sole Best Actor Oscar for his
performance as Elmer Gantry. Gantry is an over-the-top opportunistic
traveling salesman who teams up with evangelist Sister Sharon Falconer
(Jean Simmons) to promote religion in 1920's America. Gantry turns out
to be the perfect publicity compliment to Sister Sharon, who, unlike
him, is a true believer. Where she is quiet and gentle with her manner
of preaching, he is all fire and brimstone, literally throwing himself
about the audience and inflaming them into repentance.Burt Lancaster commands the screen: all flashing teeth, athletic
energy, charisma, and wild hair, using his own physical prowess to
great advantage. The angelic and lovely Jean Simmons, who had legions
of adoring male fans when she was in her ethereal prime, portrays
Sister Sharon (loosely based on a well-known real-life revivalist of
the early 1920's, Aimee Semple McPherson, about whom I'd heard from my
grandmother) in a manner reminiscent of her character in "Spartacus" -
she was the perfect choice for this role, as was Lancaster for his.Shirley Jones was awarded the Best Supporting Actress Oscar for her
lively portrayal of prostitute Lulu Bains, whose past history with
Gantry comes back to haunt him, with some of the best lines in the film
- gleefully laughing as she dances about a room full of her fellow
prostitutes, she recounts that "He rammed the fear of God into me so
fast I never heard my old man's footsteps!" Watching Burt Lancaster in
his prime use his athletic ability (he was a circus acrobat before he
became an actor) and physical grace helps make his performance truly
electrifying. And he also manages to believably evolve Elmer Gantry
from loud-mouthed salesman to a sympathetic and honest human being over
the course of the film.The top-notch supporting cast includes Arthur Kennedy, Patti Page, Dean
Jagger, and John McIntire.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
It took a long time before I watched this movie on VHS. I had boycotted
it for years, thinking it was too anti-Christian to support with my
money, either renting or buying it. Finally, in the summer of 2005 I
took a look after seeing several Burt Lancaster films and being
reminded how good an actor he was. Well, he didn't disappoint here,
either, with a fantastic performance as those of you who have seen this
already know. Lancaster is absolutely mesmerizing as "Elmer Gantry." At
times I wondered if he wasn't overacting, but his character called for
a very animated salesman-type person. So, I'll give him the credit and
assume he was just playing his role, not hamming it up too much as it
often appears."Gantry" gave the best speeches in this film and even though many
people think he was the charlatan all the way through, I disagree. I
think he had changed in the end. At any rate, Lancaster made him into a
believable person.He certainly was a lot more believable than Jean Simmons' female
evangelist, "Sister Sharon." Anyone who knows Scripture, knows that NO
evangelist - real or not - would say or do some of the things she
said-did in here. Nonetheless, Simmons gives just as riveting a
performance as Lancaster, her character just being lower-key than the
fiery "Gantry."The most shocking role to me was played by wholesome (can you say
"Oklahoma!"?) Shirley Jones, who only appears in the last part of this
long film but plays a memorable character: a hooker who had past
encounters with Elmer Gantry and now wants to expose him for the
womanizing heathen she thinks he is, and succeeds in doing so but is
ashamed of her actions in the end. Arthur Kennedy also is fascinating as the skeptical atheist-type
newspaper reporter who softens quite a bit at the end. Meanwhile, the
big-city businessman "George Babbitt" (Edward Andrews) was the only
really annoying and overblown character in the film and typical of what
Hollywood does today when they want to make a "relgious" person look
bad.I mention all these actors before remarking about the story because the
acting and the characters are what make this movie so well-done and
entertaining. As for the story, I don't believe this film is the
"expose" and critical critique of evangelists Liberal film critics
would have you believe. In fact, compared to filmmakers in the
following decade - the '70s - they were quite tolerant. "Sister Sharon"
was basically a sincere - if not misguided in spots - evangelist and a
Believer and so was "Elmer" as he says at the end of the film.Yes, there is some theology nonsense in here that simply isn't
Scriptural and there is an obvious Hollywood bias against evangelists,
but I expected far worse. To be fair, there were a lot of
Biblically-sound lines in this script, too. And - by the way - not all
evangelists are corrupt, despite what you see on film. (Don't hold your
breath waiting for Hollywood to do a bio on the most famous one of them
all: Billy Graham.)As a Christian, I still don't trust the intent of the filmmakers but I
found the film fascinating overall and think it's excellent work. I'm
glad I got the movie. Better late than never!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1683855/comments</url><from>from Derry, Ireland</from><name>Martin Bradley (MOscarbradley@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
For some reason Richard Brooks seemed to think of himself as the man
best suited to turning great novels and plays into films, but if the
results were at best entertaining ("The Brothers Karamazov", "Cat on a
hot tin roof") they tended to fall far short of the originals. If
"Elmer Gantry" worked better than most was largely due to Brooks
ability to tell a rattling good yarn at a cracking pace and to the
performances of a superb cast.Burt Lancaster seemed born to play the role of the lustful traveling
salesman whose desire for the Aimee Semple McPhearson-like Sister
Sharon turns him into a charismatic preacher, (his performance here is
a virtual reprise of his performance as Starbuck in "The Rainmaker" a
few years earlier). As Sharon, Jean Simmons gives a luminous
performance, all fragility and repressed sexuality and singer Shirley
Jones is a revelation as a trampy prostitute; (both she and Lancaster
were rewarded with Oscars). Not great then, but several cuts above what
it might have been.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1448185/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Igenlode Wordsmith</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This film is not only good; it misses being great by a narrow margin.
With a long line of charismatic cinematic rogues to his credit, Burt
Lancaster pulls off a barnstorming performance as Elmer Gantry, the
salesman turned opportunistic evangelist whose fast-talking pitch
scarcely slackens, off-stage or on. But for my money it is Jean
Simmonds, surely robbed of her own Oscar here, who has the most
impressive part.Her ethereal Sister Sharon is an idealist who truly believes in her
calling -- and is devastated when reporter Jim Lefferts calmly takes
her assumptions apart -- but she is more than just a plaster saint, let
alone the push-over Gantry initially counts upon. She has the logistics
of her operation at her fingertips, sees through Gantry's act at first
glance, and faces up to officialdom and blackmail alike with equal
courage. Simmonds performs with conviction in her varying role as
angelic preacher, self-possessed businesswoman, carefree girl and woman
in love, and it's unclear why it was co-star Shirley Jones who received
both Oscar nomination and award. As Lulu Baines, the girl whose
seduction and ruin caused Gantry's earlier expulsion from theological
college and whose reappearance threatens his newfound success, Jones
plays a pivotal part in the plot, and conveys the character's crucial
wavering between vengeance and sympathy for her lover; but I felt
Simmonds' was the greater challenge and the greater, unrecognised,
achievement.The filmed version is perhaps inevitably softened from the savage
satire of the book, presumably in quest of popular appeal; it certainly
succeeded so far as I was concerned. Lancaster's Gantry is a more
sympathetic and attractive character than the original. He uses his
huckster's tricks to sell religion, but at the heart of it he has a
genuine naive faith; he seduces Sister Sharon as he always intended,
but as far as he is capable he loves her and she redeems him. He uses
his rhetoric to undermine Jim Lefferts with his employer, just as the
reporter uses the logic of his own sharpened pencil to rip apart and
expose the revivalists' operation, and yet the two men share a mutual
knowledge and respect that verges on friendship.Ultimately, Gantry achieves a Christ-like moment of his own when he
endures humiliation at the hands of a vengeful mob as if in payment for
the disaster his actions have brought upon Sister Sharon, standing
mutely beneath the pelting filth with no move toward the self-defence,
both verbal and physical, in which he normally excels. And it is from
this spectacle -- admirably played by Lancaster in resignation as in
flamboyance -- that Lulu flees, unable to bear what she has brought
about.This is not, however, the story of Elmer Gantry's redemption, and it is
in the handling of the ending that in my view the film chiefly misses
greatness. The outcome, while perhaps deliberately ambiguous, is
confused.The plot mandates that Sister Sharon perish in the fire, but the
methods chosen to achieve this make both her and the scriptwriters
appear idiotic. The presentation of her attempts to prevent the
congregation leaving, in the face of what is here shown as clear and
present danger, and her own determination to remain, came across as
unmotivated and bizarre in a woman who has previously seemed realistic
and practical. In consequence the sequence drags out beyond the bounds
of plausibility, while the final shot of her miraculously white and
untouched among the flames is just tasteless.Rather than casting her as Joan of Arc, I feel it would have made more
sense to shorten the scene, indicating her human reluctance to abandon
her life's work if there is the faintest chance of saving it, having
her trampled by the crowd and then struck down by the falling beam that
as shot just misses her, and then, just as in the film, having the
floor give way beneath Gantry before he can reach her -- and using
*that* as the climax of the sequence. A couple of tiny changes to
existing material, 30 seconds or so of cuts, and the climax could have
been so much more coherent. It might even have served to redeem the
coda afterwards, where the lack of satisfactory resolution is I think
intentional...'Elmer Gantry' is intelligent, attractive, and -- at least to my mind
-- more subtle in its satire of hellfire evangelism than its source
material. Outstanding is the role of Jim Lefferts the cynic, who tags
along with the show in order to sell copy on its charades, but finds
himself touched by its purely human side; in many ways he represents
the modern audience, pre-empting our mockery and distaste and hence
preventing them from destroying the illusion. (It is a mark of the
film's sophistication that this character is presented neither as hero
nor killjoy villain.)The ending, however, isn't really up to the standards of the rest.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0270596/comments</url><from>from Indianapolis, IN</from><name>bongtalk</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The titular character starts out as a cynical small time hustler discovering
a good scam joining up with a traveling revival show, and casting his eye to
the charismatic and comely lady preacher leading it.What is really good is how the character develops, and gradually becomes a
good sincere Christian, which is best seen in his interaction with the
Shirley Jones character.She is a preacher's kid who was disowned by her father before the start of
the movie timeline after he caught Elmer "ramming the fear of god" into her.
She has since become a prostitute, and has the opportunity to repay Elmer's
earlier callous treatment.Oh, yes, I know these people, or at least watered down real life versions of
them.  This movie really gets at the charismatic Christianity of the
heartlands, and the strong sexual tensions running just beneath the surface.
Oh, I bet Jimmy Swaggart for one knew JUST what they were getting
at. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2171244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lastliberal</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Based on the muckraker Sinclair Lewis' novel, and superbly translated
to the screen by Richard Brooks (In Cold Blood , The Professionals, Cat
on a Hot Tin Roof), this story of huckster-ism by religion is a
masterpiece.Burt Lancaster player the greatest role of his career, getting his only
Oscar for his performance. Lancaster, so good in such films as From
Here to Eternity, Atlantic City, and Seven Days in May, was
spellbinding as the salesman for God.Shirley Jones (The Music Man, "The Patridge Family," was simply
delicious as Gantry's first conquest, and now a "five-buck hooker,"
that he left behind: "Oh, he gave me special instructions back of the
pulpit Christmas Eve. He got to howlin' "Repent! Repent!" and I got to
moanin' "Save me! Save me!" and the first thing I know he rammed the
fear of God into me so fast I never heard my old man's footsteps!" 1960
was a great year for movies, and this was certainly one of the best of
that year, and one of the best of all time. If you want to see real
acting, this film should be on your "must-see" list.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2366009/comments</url><from/><name>Danusha Goska (dgoska@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
In "Elmer Gantry," Burt Lancaster gives one of the all-time great
screen performances. Lancaster's performance is so rich, so real, that
the viewer knows this man, knows what Gantry smells like (sweat and eau
de cologne) and what he eats (big slabs of beef). I can't say I've ever
seen anything quite like it. Gantry's entire repertoire is performed
with encyclopedic thoroughness and accuracy. We see Gantry the
narcissistic conman, Gantry the philanthropist, Gantry the flamboyant
showman.Just when we think we've seen it all, just when we think we can write
Gantry off as a cross between a clown, a self-deceiver, and a blowhard,
the movie reveals another nuance in Gantry's soul – something we'd
never seen before, and yet realize is totally believable, and, in fact,
essential to understanding the man. Our views of the man change. We
can't help but love him.One such scene: almost 75 % of the way through the movie, in fact,
after a shorter and shallower movie would have ended, Gantry says to
another man, "Don't you know that that hurts?" in a voice we haven't
heard him use before. Lancaster is breathtaking in this, the film's
quietest line reading. Lancaster is so magnificent in this, his
Oscar-winning role, that you have to wonder if he is not calling on
much of his own character, as a charming, larger-than-life Hollywood
star, to play the charming, larger-than-life star of tent revivals.
IMDb trivia notes claim that Lancaster received a letter from a
childhood friend saying that Lancaster's performance as Elmer Gantry
reminded him of the Lancaster he remembered from real life.The rest of the cast is also superb. Jean Simmons is domineering,
spiritual, spooky, and lustful, by turns. Shirley Jones is
heartbreaking as a doomed woman. Arthur Kennedy is perfect as a
skeptical journalist. Dean Jagger perfectly times and pitches his
paternal air, his outrage, and his surprised forgiveness. Patti Page is
poignant as Sister Rachel. Edward Andrews is the embodiment of a
sanctimonious, ambitious, brothel owner.This film addressing religious corruption, lynch mob mentality, and
illicit sex was made under strict rules of censorship. There are no
four letter words, no naked breasts, no bleeding wounds. And yet this
film raised goose bumps in ways that more explicit movies only wish
they could. A crowd brays for blood; a man pulls a horse whip out of a
paper bag and cracks it. Refuse is thrown at a man, and what looks very
like maggots. A police officer arresting a prostitute says "You
wouldn't believe what I caught this one doing." A virgin is taken under
a building by a man who has practically hypnotized her. Wow! "Elmer
Gantry" is critical of Christian revival meetings that were popular in
the rural south and Midwest in the early decades of the twentieth
century. Its indirect targets were understood to be the historical
figures, Aimee Semple McPherson and Billy Sunday. Some Christians might
avoid the movie for this reason. That would be a mistake. The movie is
ultimately very charitable to all of its characters, even Babbit, the
brothel owner. Like Gantry himself, the film sees humanity in all its
beauty and ugliness, understands, and forgives. This is no black/white,
two-dimensional screed. It's a complex exploration of complex
behaviors, longings, needs, desires, ambitions. A woman can be a virgin
dedicated to God and also a lover who empties sand out of her
high-heeled shoe after a night of illicit passion on a beach. A villain
who contributed to the ruination of a young woman's life can redeem
himself through application of biblical concepts of humility and
forgiveness.Too, the flimflamming "Elmer Gantry" skewers is not limited to
churches. There is a charming narcissist of uncertain background on the
world stage today who, like Gantry, attracts chanting crowds, causes
women to faint and men to believe in a national renaissance. This
particular charismatic public speaker is not a religious leader, but a
candidate for the presidency. The speaker who wows crowds, the crowds
who yearn to surrender themselves to a putative messiah, are forever
with us. That being the case, "Elmer Gantry" is a film that will never
lose its relevance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
From the exceptionally talented pen of noted author Sinclair Lewis
comes this entertaining story of a fast-talking, yarn-spinning vacuum
salesman with the natural gift of persuasion. In his ever lustful
sights is a voluptuous female preacher. In order to conquer her, he
must use his extensive repertoire of biblical quips, quotes and bawdy
antidotes. Within the sphere of a traveling troupe of bible beating,
evangelicals on a religious crusade, the author's hero, one Elmer
Gantry (supurbly played by Oscar wining Burt Lancaster) is as energetic
as his tales. Although it's difficult to know if Gantry's spiritual
motivation is genuine or merely a ploy, throughout the film, one is
kept guessing. The target of his earthly desires is Beautiful Sister
Sharon Falconer (Jean Simmons) a sincere, but fallible woman out to
build a ministry. A serious obstacle to her goal is Gantry, but more so
is the cautionary and caustic pen of Jim Lefferts (Arthur Kennedy), a
Pulitzer Prize winning journalist who questions the personal and
financial motives of her entourage. Her main supporter is worldly
William Morgan (Dean Jagger) who believes in Falconer, and sees Gantry
and Lefferts for the opportunistic impediments they are. The film is a
triumph for Lancaster and Kennedy and for all those who wish to visit a
confusing period of Americanna, when the word of God was infected by
preachers, pushers and spiritual leeches. ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
From the exceptionally talented pen of noted author Sinclair Lewis
comes this entertaining story of a fast-talking, yarn-spinning vacuum
salesman with the natural gift of persuasion. In his ever lustful
sights is a voluptuous female preacher. In order to conquer her, he
must use his extensive repertoire of biblical quips, quotes and bawdy
antidotes. Within the sphere of a traveling troupe of bible beating,
evangelicals on a religious crusade, the author's hero, one Elmer
Gantry (supurbly played by Oscar wining Burt Lancaster) is as energetic
as his tales. Although it's difficult to know if Gantry's spiritual
motivation is genuine or merely a ploy, throughout the film, one is
kept guessing. The target of his earthly desires is Beautiful Sister
Sharon Falconer (Jean Simmons) a sincere, but fallible woman out to
build a ministry. A serious obstacle to her goal is Gantry, but more so
is the cautionary and caustic pen of Jim Lefferts (Arthur Kennedy), a
Pulitzer Prize winning journalist who questions the personal and
financial motives of her entourage. Her main supporter is worldly
William Morgan (Dean Jagger) who believes in Falconer, and sees Gantry
and Lefferts for the opportunistic impediments they are. The film is a
triumph for Lancaster and Kennedy and for all those who wish to visit a
confusing period of Americanna, when the word of God was infected by
preachers, pushers and spiritual leeches. ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>