<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Bellboy</original_title><alt_title>Le dingue du Palace</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Jerry Lewis</director><producer>Jerry Lewis Pictures</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
In Miami Beach, the mute bellboy Stanley works at the luxurious Fontainebleau Hotel. In spite of being a serviceable and friendly employee, the clumsy Stanley gets successively into trouble with his mistakes.
</synopsis><actor>Jerry Lewis</actor><actor>Alex Gerry</actor><actor>Bob Clayton</actor><rt_rating>6.9/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>67</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0724253/comments</url><from>from Warminster, PA</from><name>robeykr</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
No Plot -- The film starts with this proclamation. This film is
definitely one of Jerry Lewis' best of his carrier. Filmed during the
height of his movie output in the 1960's, this film is comedy unto its
own sake. The gags just don't stop -- you aren't given a moment to
relax, because it's all so funny, you can't stop laughing. The NO PLOT
aspect only helps, as the audience is free to concentrate on the
moment. I still burst into laughter when the hotel manager is called by
the airport to inform him 'HE WHAT!?' Yes, this film is dated by
today's standard, but that should come as no surprise. This film was
the product of a different era -- and a different society. The change
in our society was what made him decide to briefly retire from film in
the '70s. The standards of humor just changed. And performers had to
change with it. But film is permanent. It is set in celluloid. It can
be re-edited, but what would be the point? For anyone who can
appreciate 'the artist' for his art, this film still can be enjoyed.
For anyone who can look at past films for nostalgia, this film can be
enjoyed. It's called comedy -- 'nuff said.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2126532/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Meg H</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie is one of my all time favorites! Every time I see it I catch
something new I hadn't seen before, and, even after watching it so many
times, it never ceases to set me into a fit of laughter! Future viewers:
Ignore all that junk about it being dated, etc.! Watch this movie and
decide
for yourself- JL is awesome, and you WON'T be disappointed!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0167255/comments</url><from>from Fribourg, Switzerland</from><name>Sergeiii</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

It is with productions like "The Bellboy" that Jerry Lewis earned more and
more hostility in the States and made his eventual reputation in Europe
(i.e
France, of course). This movie is stuck in a continental divide, but also
in
a temporal one. I have no idea whether Lewis did actually grasp the ideas
of
surrealism or the absurd movement at the time, but it looks pretty much
so.
The man somehow managed to mix his usual desperately anarchic slapstick
routines with a very clear sense of not making the innate tragedy of the
matter an issue at all - only to disclaim at the end that the character
shown in the picture might be your neigbour. The achievement here is that
Lewis behaves like a lost circus clown throughout the major feature film -
never allowing himself to get halfway sentimental or plot-oriented. He is
illogic, destructive and spastic; and he makes the whole movie obey his
zany
rules, thus saving the Sennett/Roach school into a time when people were
heavily reflecting on the opportunities of physical humour. Maybe it took
the MelBrookses, the Abraham-Zuckers and the Farrellys to make that kind
of
unromantic comedy truly popular again way later, but here's someone who
tried in 1960. Today, it looks like Jim Carrey taking over a Bunuel
movie -
and that's as silly as it gets.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0222418/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Jerry Lewis produced, wrote and directed The Bellboy in 1960, in four
weeks at the Fountainbleau Hotel in Miami Beach, where he was
performing at the time.The movie has no plot, it just shows us Stanley
the bellboy getting in many hilarious situations.Stanley doesn't speak,
he doesn't say a word until at the end of the movie.Lewis shows us some
incredible silent comedy, great physical comedy in a way only Jerry can
do.And what he does with his face! Marvelous, just marvelous! In this
movie Jerry makes also a visit as himself.You can't help yourself
laughing when the star arrives with a whole bunch of people.An other
great comedian, Milton Berle can be seen there.And Stan Laurel.Well,
not quite.Jerry wanted Stan to be in the movie, he sent him the script
and Stan did make a few minor changes to it.He deleted one entire scene
because it was too mean-spirited.So Stan did have something to do with
the picture, but he wasn't seen in it.That's too bad, since Mr Laurel
is also one of my favorite comics.But there is Bill Richmond as Stan
Laurel look-alike.Mr Lewis will receive next September the Governors
award for his charity work.He is the chairman of Muscular Dystrophy
Association.Good for you, Jerry!You do deserve all the best in the
world.I bought the DVD yesterday and I sure am glad I did.It may not be
the most traditional Jerry Lewis movie, but it still works, works like
a charm.After 45 years it still does.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1305790/comments</url><from>from North</from><name>matthank</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie is solid gags.  No plot and JL is very open about that....only
gags or what they used to call 'blackouts'.
I have simply never laughed so hard as when I watched this movie.  But as
for the scene where he loses it by the elevators, you may or may not like
it
(French?) but it nearly caused me to have an early death.
Tape it, rent it or buy it, but if you have come this far, watch
it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1578983/comments</url><from>from St Catharines, Ontario</from><name>ajohns1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This movie is hilarious I like every little sketch there is some more
than
others but this is still a very funny especially in the limited time
Jerry
Lewis had and the limited money. I couldn't expect more from this movie
the
I'm told it was made because Jerry Lewis wouldn't let Cinderfella out
until
Christmas So he made this little movie too. And I'm very happy that he
did
9/10.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Jerry Lewis wrote, produced, directed, and stars in this collection of
skits centering around a put-upon bellhop at a Miami Beach hotel.
Having just completed "Cinderfella" for a mid-year release, Lewis
suggested to Paramount Pictures they hold off showing that film until
Christmas and gave them this one in its place (put together in
near-record time). Short and relatively painless, the film benefits
from Haskell Boggs' sharp black-and-white cinematography, Walter
Scharf's bright score, and of course the snazzy locale. Lewis, making
his directorial debut, smoothly segues from one sight-gag to the next,
and his low-key performance is actually one of his best. **1/2 from
****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
In Miami Beach, the mute bellboy Stanley (Jerry Lewis) works at the
luxurious Fontainebleau Hotel. In spite of being a serviceable and
friendly employee, the clumsy Stanley gets successively into trouble
with his mistakes."The Bellboy" is a silly collection of gags written, produced and
directed by the lead star Jerry Lewis. There are some funny and
non-sense jokes, like for example when Stanley meets the guest Jerry
Lewis or when he removes the engine of a Volkswagen, and a great homage
to Stan Laurel. My vote is five.Title (Brazil): "O Mensageiro Trapalhão" ("The Clumsy Bellboy")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1181624/comments</url><from>from new jersey</from><name>MHochee</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Out of the Jerry Lewis movies I have seen, this is his best in my opinion.
Excellent slapstick and sight gags. This movie will NEVER BE DATED. My
favorite bit is where he has to answer the phones although there are many
other great ones. GRADE: B+
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"The Bellboy" unapologetically states in an introductory scene that it
has no plot or story and is made purely for fun. "The Bellboy" really
is seventy minutes of nothing but sight gags, some hilarious, some
clever, and some disappointing."The Bellboy" was Jerry Lewis' first film as director and is just as
divisive as you would expect it to be, with some consistently claiming
it is one of the great physical comedies, up there with Tati et al and
others reacting to it the way one is sadly expected to react to a Jerry
Lewis comedy nowadays. I personally think "The Bellboy" displays a lot
of talent from Lewis as director, with some attempts at surrealism
being surprisingly successful. Lewis also works the sight gags into the
film beautifully, not ignoring one inch of the frame when composing the
gags, one of the many reasons I suspect I hated this film when I first
saw it on VHS.Still, "The Bellboy" is far from Lewis' funniest or best film (see an
unfairly maligned favorite of mine, "The Disorderly Orderly" for the
former, and "The Nutty Professor" for the latter) and has its fair
share of misses as well as hits with the gags. In addition the lack of
structure the film has is occasionally distracting.I won't comment on Lewis as a person or on his personal beliefs, but he
makes me laugh which is really what matters in a filmmaker. Moreover,
"The Bellboy" is surprisingly well-directed and more inventive than you
might expect, but I'll leave it to the Europeans to explain to you why
it's a great film as opposed to a good one, because I can't see the
reason in that.7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"The Bellboy" unapologetically states in an introductory scene that it
has no plot or story and is made purely for fun. "The Bellboy" really
is seventy minutes of nothing but sight gags, some hilarious, some
clever, and some disappointing."The Bellboy" was Jerry Lewis' first film as director and is just as
divisive as you would expect it to be, with some consistently claiming
it is one of the great physical comedies, up there with Tati et al and
others reacting to it the way one is sadly expected to react to a Jerry
Lewis comedy nowadays. I personally think "The Bellboy" displays a lot
of talent from Lewis as director, with some attempts at surrealism
being surprisingly successful. Lewis also works the sight gags into the
film beautifully, not ignoring one inch of the frame when composing the
gags, one of the many reasons I suspect I hated this film when I first
saw it on VHS.Still, "The Bellboy" is far from Lewis' funniest or best film (see an
unfairly maligned favorite of mine, "The Disorderly Orderly" for the
former, and "The Nutty Professor" for the latter) and has its fair
share of misses as well as hits with the gags. In addition the lack of
structure the film has is occasionally distracting.I won't comment on Lewis as a person or on his personal beliefs, but he
makes me laugh which is really what matters in a filmmaker. Moreover,
"The Bellboy" is surprisingly well-directed and more inventive than you
might expect, but I'll leave it to the Europeans to explain to you why
it's a great film as opposed to a good one, because I can't see the
reason in that.7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1533983</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Dispatch-Tribune Newspapers</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>For my meager money, Jerry Lewis' best &amp; one of funniest all-time comedies.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/bellboy.htm /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1471799</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>Jerry at his rawest and most creative.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eric-henderson/</url><url>http://www.slantmagazine.com/film/film_review.asp?ID=1292 /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1327184</url><name>Eric Henderson</name><from>Slant Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>The Bellboy is nearly silent, in what could easily be taken as a nod toward French comedy titan Jacques Tati.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1222905</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>One of Lewis' more successful outings.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1408482</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1348466</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/randy-shulman/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1335042</url><name>Randy Shulman</name><from>Metro Weekly (Washington, DC)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1301580</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-szymanski/</url><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1172500</url><name>Michael Szymanski</name><from>Zap2it.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117788970.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1735777</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/67577/the_bellboy.html /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1475047</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eugene-archer/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9907E7DF103EEF3ABC4951DFB166838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1389340</url><name>Eugene Archer</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>/m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1364721</url><from>Hollywood Reporter</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/bellboy.shtml /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1329159</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=100993 /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1148850</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/12802_BELLBOY.html /m/bellboy/comments.php?reviewid=1891</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>