<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Seven Thieves</original_title><imdb_rating>6.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Henry Hathaway</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A discredited professor and a sophisticated thief decide to join together and pick a team to pull off one last job--the casino vault in Monte Carlo.
</synopsis><actor>Edward G. Robinson</actor><actor>Rod Steiger</actor><actor>Joan Collins</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1259663/comments</url><from>from Atlantic Coast, USA</from><name>pro_crustes</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Remember "Mission: Impossible"?  The TV series, not the movie.  It was
always fun to watch the team pull off one of their stunts, because they
balanced their Rube Goldberg concepts with NASA-quality planning.  This
movie is cut from the same cloth.  It's about a casino robbery engineered
during one of the gambling hall's biggest celebrations.  The eponymous
crooks must work in synchronized unison to fulfill their plan.  Unlike the
MI series, though, they aren't all quite equally devoted to their mission
or, at least not to their particular roles within it.  Still, they have a
clever series of steps that get more interesting to watch, even as it seems
increasingly likely that the plan will succeed.Along the way, there are some interesting mixtures of personality types,
some mysterious backgrounds waiting to be uncovered, and a degree of
slipperiness that make it hard to be sure just who we should be rooting for.
 Indeed, part of the charm of this film is that there are _no_ "good guys,"
yet we want the thieves to get away with their crime.A nifty, thoughtful piece, with little action and no sfx (in the current
sense, anyway).  An added plus for some of us is a pair of fairly sexy dance
numbers a 27-year-old Joan Collins does "nearly naked," as her character
puts it.  She was at her physical prime in this film, but don't
underestimate her acting ability.  She carries the sole female role with
every bit as much mastery as Wallach, Steiger, and the oddly endearing
Edward G. Robinson carry theirs.  John Beradino (the original "Dr. Hardy" of
TV's "General Hospital") has a small role, and Marcel Hillaire appears as
more or less the same character he would play dozens of times in TV guest
spots for the next few years.7/10, recommended if you've had your fill of explosions, CGI, or Tom
Cruise.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Usually films located on a place as lovely as the French Riviera,
especially Monte Carlo get the full technicolor treatment like To Catch
a Thief. But in Seven Thieves director Henry Hathaway opted for black
and white because this is a noir and the key here is the plot of the
caper and the relationships of the characters.Expatriate American academician Edward G. Robinson calls on a young
protégé Rod Steiger to come over from America to help him heist a
casino in Monte Carlo. He's recruited a gang and needs someone he can
trust to keep them in line.Robinson's role is similar to that of Sam Jaffe in The Asphalt Jungle
and Steiger it seems is his Sterling Hayden.That's how it seems at the start, but there's a whole lot more going on
here as the characters reveal themselves bit by bit during the planning
and execution of the caper.Coincidentally in the same year another caper film, Ocean's 11 about
robbing casinos also came out. But this is definitely not as
lighthearted as that Ratpack romp.What to watch for is the relationships between Robinson and Steiger and
between Steiger, Joan Collins and Eli Wallach.Nicely done little noir classic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0208117/comments</url><from>from NY, NY</from><name>aromatic-2 (aromatic@ivillage.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Seven Thieves is an intricately plotted and well acted caper yarn.   It
combines beautiful Monte Carlo setting with seven distinct characterization.
 A host of international professionals are on hand including Edward G.
Robinson, Eli Wallach, Sebastian Cabot, Alexander Scourby, Berry Kroger,
Marcel Hillaire, John Berardino, and most of all, Joan Collins and Rod
Steiger.  Collins, generally not one of my favorites,  gives a marvelous performance,
surprisingly reminiscent of Sophia Loren.  Steiger starts the movie off
being belligerent and one-note, so much so, that I wasn't certain I would
continue watching.  But, soon we gradually see why Edward G. wants him on
his team so badly. Next, things get very taut and laced with whimsy and dry
humor.If you enjoy caper films that make you think, watch this
one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Edward G. Robinson has planned the perfect crime in "Seven Thieves," a
1960 black and white film also starring Rod Steiger, Joan Collins, Eli
Wallach, Alexander Scourby, Michael Dante, Marcel Hillaire, and
Sebastian Cabot. The film is set in Monte Carlo where Theo Wilkins
(Robinson) has arranged to meet Paul Mason (Rod Steiger) to ask him to
join in the plot. Wilkins is a former scientist who lost his
credibility after commission of some sort of crime, but we don't know
what it is; Mason has just finished three years in jail. The crime
concerns the theft of 4 million francs from a casino and will involve a
total of 7 people - a dancer (Collins), her friend (Wallach), her
married boyfriend (Scourby), and a safe cracker (Dante).Directed by Henry Hathaway, this is an interesting drama that moves
somewhat slowly and might have been better. It has a couple of twists
at the end that are interesting, and there is quite a bit of tension
and suspense for the audience throughout.The performances are excellent. Robinson gives a sympathetic portrayal
of an old man looking for his last shot; Steiger gives a subdued (!)
performance, his character being quietly threatening instead of
screaming his guts out - good choice. Someone commented on this site
that Joan Collins looks the same today as she did in this film 45 years
ago - actually, it's kind of true. The only difference is that she wore
less makeup then. Her figure is amazing, and she gives a wonderful
performance as an unhappy, hard woman who has much compassion
underneath. Eli Wallach does a great job as a nervous wreck."Seven Thieves" holds your attention. Strangely this is around the time
of "Ocean's 11" where the touch is much lighter. This is a very
dramatic story. It's not the greatest but worth checking out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1019294/comments</url><from>from Ottawa, Ontario, Canada</from><name> (bsmith5552@rogers.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

"Seven Thieves" is an average but interesting little "rob the casino"
caper, raised a level by the quality of the acting.Edward G. Robinson stars as "the professor" who masterminds a plot to rob
a
Monte Carlo casino. For Robinson, this represents his one last chance to
make a major score before he cashes in. Rod Steiger plays on old
acquaintance from the States whom Robinson tries to recruit in order to
complete his team. Joan Collins, looking gorgeous, is the femme fatale and
Eli Wallach as Poncho the Sax playing member of the group. Michael Dante,
Alexander Scourby and Berry Kroeger round out the rest of the "Seven
Thieves". Sebastian Cabot also appears as the casino director.Robinson in what amounts to a supporting role, is excellent as always.
Steiger's method acting seems a little misplaced here, however under Henry
Hathaway's direction, he does deliver a good performance. Collins was never
more beautiful and performs a couple of provocative (for 1960) dances in a
cabaret with Wallach."Seven Thieves" is always interesting but contains little in the way of
physical action. There are a couple of surprises as well, but I thought the
ending was a bit of a let down. Nevertheless, It is still an interesting
film to watch if only see the performances of the stellar
cast.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0850869/comments</url><from>from Chicago, Illinois, United States</from><name>John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
It seems like only yesterday that the gang and myself went to see this
SEVEN THIEVES picture. It was playing at our local movie show,The Ogden
Theatre at 63rd &amp; Marshfield, here in Chicago. It was a Double Feature
with THE PURPLE GANG, a production from Allied Artists (formerly known
as Monogram Pictures, a long time resident of Hollywood's Poverty Row.The advertising stated that it starred "........Edward
G.Robinson(Little Ceasar) and Rod Steiger(Al Capone)." Gangster films
were enjoying a renewed popularity at that time. AL CAPONE was released
the prior year and did okay at the Box Office. Desilu Playhouse had
aired the two part "THE UNTOUCHABLES", which led to the weekly series.Well, my 13 year old mind thought that we were seeing something that
would be like 'Little Ceasar Meets Al Capone!" We all left the show
giving the 'thumbs up' to THE PURPLE GANG, but not really caring for
SEVEN THIEVES. Small wonder, when a bunch of kids see a picture like
this that will have a lot of material that was really "TWA"(over our
heads).Well, only a few months ago this former guttersnipe saw SEVEN THIEVES
again. This time I understood it, I think.Billed as "The Robbery That Rocked Monte Carlo!" It is a caper film,
and a very good one at that. It has a fine cast, in addition to Mr.
Robinson and Mr. Steiger, Joan Collins, Elli Wallach, Sebastian Cabot,
Alexander Scourby, et al.Anyone would enjoy this film. It's well worth seeing, and our old gang
would heartily agree.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10348034/comments</url><from>from Claremont, USA</from><name>dougdoepke</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
A so-so caper movie that somehow fails to take off despite a veteran
cast and director. There's lots of casino glitz, a sexy Joan Collins,
and an inherently suspenseful premise, but the elements never really
come together. I agree with the reviewer who thinks Steiger miscast.
His is the central role. Yet he's so humorless, his enforcer-leader
fails to generate needed sympathy for the caper (I gather director
Hathaway was also unhappy with the grimness). In fact, with Robinson's
exception, none of the characters is particularly likable. As a result,
viewers are not encouraged to engage with the caper, but instead to
simply observe it. At the same time, ace director Hathaway films in
uncharacteristically impersonal, uncompelling fashion.Nonetheless, the movie does have its moments. There's genuine tension
when the Duc (Hillaire) tries to get Melanie (Collins) evicted from the
casino, spoiling the heist. Instead, Melanie does some fast thinking
and hangs in there. Then there's the very human last- minute-jitters
that threaten to undo the elaborate scheme. But these moments of
tension tend to remain isolated instead of tightening into a
suspenseful whole, a failing perhaps of the screenplay.I think there's a reason these heist films were popular during the
law-and-order 1950's. The best ones-- The Asphalt Jungle (1950), The
Killing (1956)— humanize crime in ways crime features to that point
don't. Unlike most crime dramas of the period, ordinary people are seen
as able to pool their talents into a cleverly profitable undertaking,
at the same time, being daring enough to take big risks for big gains. Such qualities mirror the kind of commercial initiative ordinarily
lauded by popular culture. Of course, heists are also criminal
enterprises, but except for the key factor of legality, they show off
the combined skills of ordinary people acting in effective and
sympathetic light. And just as importantly, as long as it's only a bank
or racetrack or casino that gets victimized, well, they can likely
afford it. Without that key consideration of who's harmed, the ending
of this film would be more morally questionable than it is.Anyhow, the movie's passable entertainment, and if it fails to scale
the caper film heights, at least there are compensations.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The plot of Seven Thieves is similar in many respects to the dozens of
other heist movies made in the 50s and 60s. Edward G. Robinson plays
the kindly, but discredited professor who has put together a plan to
rob a Monte Carlo casino much as he would put together an experiment to
mix two chemicals. He assembles his team and they get to work planning
and rehearsing their roles for the big heist. It will require timing,
precision, and a good head if something should go wrong. If one member
fails to perform, it will mean certain disaster for the rest. But can
these seven really just walk out of a casino with $4 million in French
francs? Seven Thieves is a nice, enjoyable heist film. It's certainly not as
good as it could have been, but it is entertaining with a few tense
moments along the way. The film has an incredible look that far exceeds
its budget. The cinematography and lighting are solid. The set
decoration is a real standout. The locations and sets fit the film
perfectly. Combine all of these elements and you've got one very nice
looking movie. In short, Seven Thieves looks stunning. And speaking of
stunning, there's Joan Collins. While everyone in the film gives a good
performance, none of her male co-stars can hope to compete with her.
She steals every scene in which she appears. And what a knockout! Those
dance numbers are a highlight for me. I don't know why it took me so
long to discover Ms. Collins, but I'm a fan now.But, as is almost always the case, the movie isn't perfect. As I said,
Seven Thieves is not as good as it could have been. Even though there
were a number of things that bothered me, I'll limit this to two key
weaknesses I saw in the film. First, there's a twist near the end of
Seven Thieves involving Rod Steiger's character that is completely
unnecessary. Its only purpose seems to have been to create some overly
artificial sentimentality. The movie didn't need it. Second, and most
importantly, I have a big problem is Rod Steiger himself. Don't
misunderstand – he gives a solid (and surprisingly understated)
performance, but he's terribly miscast in Seven Thieves. He just
doesn't look the part he's asked to play here. And he seems so terribly
serious throughout. The role seems to have called for a different sort
of actor with a more natural sense of humor.In the end, the good outweighed the negative and I really enjoyed
watching Seven Thieves. And I've come full-circle on Joan Collins. I
can't wait to discover more of her early work. For what it's worth,
I'll rate this one a 7/10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6815914/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gelalema</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This film about a heist of a casino in Monte Carlo is graced by three
giants of the film industry, Edward G. Robinson, Rod Steiger, and Eli
Wallach. Steiger in particular gives his multi-faceted performance
superb shading and sensitivity in the development of his relationship
with Edward G. Robinson, whose performance, as always, is stellar. Rod
Steiger is incapable of giving a bad performance, but his touching
reactions when the character played by Robinson dies at the end of the
heist is one of the best portrayals you will ever see an actor give in
any film. Joan Collins part is a bit overdrawn, especially with the
unnecessary exposition at the beginning where she dances at the strip
joint, but her participation later lends gravitas and poignancy to the
dramatic line. See this film for the performances of Steiger, Wallach
and Robinson if for no other reason. I have watched it five times and
never miss it when it is shown on TV. The power and pathos of Steiger's
performance make it work the watching, time and again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
THE SONS OF KATIE ELDER director Henry Hathaway made just about every
kind of movie during his long career that spanned from the 1932 western
WHEN THE WEST WAS YOUNG to the 1974 blaxploitation thriller SUPER DUDE.
This above-average 1960 casino crime caper came out several months
before the Frank Sinatra &amp; Dean Martin epic OCEANS ELEVEN. The Hathaway
takes place in France instead of Las Vegas and concerns an elderly
ex-con, Professor Theo Wilkins (Edward G. Robinson of LITTLE CAESAR),
who wants to make the world gasp for one last time. He has orchestrated
a highly complex robbery at a Monte Carlo casino that will net some 4
million dollars in French money. He entices an old and dear friend,
Paul Mason (Rod Steiger of DUCK YOU SUCKER), as the man who ramrods the
operation. Paul straightens out everybody on the crew that he has the
final word in everything. He also checks them out and tests them so he
can be sure that they are reliable in a tight spot. One of the
conspirators is a gorgeous stripper, Melanie (Joan Collins of LAND OF
THE PHARAOHS), who strings along a timid, uptight casino secretary
Raymond Le May (Alexander Scourby of THE BIG HEAT) to help them obtain
invitations to an exclusive party the same night they plan to pull the
robbery. They also enlist the aid of a safer cracker, Louis Antonizzi
(Michael Dante of RAINTREE COUNTY), and Poncho (Eli Wallach of BABY
DOLL) who is supposed to impersonate a wealthy baron. The night of the
heist, Poncho fakes a heart attack so they can have an ambulance
arrive. The ambulance is being driven by another conspirator Hugo
Baumer (Berry Kroeger of Hitler) who handles the automobiles that they
use for the robbery. Remember, back in 1960 when this movie was
produced, the Production Code Administration still had enough clout to
censor movies and they were not about to let these talented thieves get
away with their crime. The way that Hathaway and scenarist Sydney Boehm
work things out is not entirely satisfactory but it does make for a
better ending that all of them being nabbed by French authorities.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
THE SONS OF KATIE ELDER director Henry Hathaway made just about every
kind of movie during his long career that spanned from the 1932 western
WHEN THE WEST WAS YOUNG to the 1974 blaxploitation thriller SUPER DUDE.
This above-average 1960 casino crime caper came out several months
before the Frank Sinatra &amp; Dean Martin epic OCEANS ELEVEN. The Hathaway
takes place in France instead of Las Vegas and concerns an elderly
ex-con, Professor Theo Wilkins (Edward G. Robinson of LITTLE CAESAR),
who wants to make the world gasp for one last time. He has orchestrated
a highly complex robbery at a Monte Carlo casino that will net some 4
million dollars in French money. He entices an old and dear friend,
Paul Mason (Rod Steiger of DUCK YOU SUCKER), as the man who ramrods the
operation. Paul straightens out everybody on the crew that he has the
final word in everything. He also checks them out and tests them so he
can be sure that they are reliable in a tight spot. One of the
conspirators is a gorgeous stripper, Melanie (Joan Collins of LAND OF
THE PHARAOHS), who strings along a timid, uptight casino secretary
Raymond Le May (Alexander Scourby of THE BIG HEAT) to help them obtain
invitations to an exclusive party the same night they plan to pull the
robbery. They also enlist the aid of a safer cracker, Louis Antonizzi
(Michael Dante of RAINTREE COUNTY), and Poncho (Eli Wallach of BABY
DOLL) who is supposed to impersonate a wealthy baron. The night of the
heist, Poncho fakes a heart attack so they can have an ambulance
arrive. The ambulance is being driven by another conspirator Hugo
Baumer (Berry Kroeger of Hitler) who handles the automobiles that they
use for the robbery. Remember, back in 1960 when this movie was
produced, the Production Code Administration still had enough clout to
censor movies and they were not about to let these talented thieves get
away with their crime. The way that Hathaway and scenarist Sydney Boehm
work things out is not entirely satisfactory but it does make for a
better ending that all of them being nabbed by French authorities.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dan-jardine/</url><url>http://apolloguide.com/mov_revtemp.asp?CID=5536 /m/seven_thieves/comments.php?reviewid=1655313</url><name>Dan Jardine</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
61/100
					</rating><comment>Despite some interesting individual moments, when taken as a whole, Seven Thieves is an uneven and (most damning) an uneventful mess.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/seventhieves.htm /m/seven_thieves/comments.php?reviewid=1271460</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Routine caper about a casino heist in the French Riviera.</comment></review></movie>