<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ice Palace</original_title><alt_title>Les aventuriers</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Vincent Sherman</director><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
At the end of World War I, Zeb Kennedy, a canner, and Thor Storm, a fishing boat captain, set up a fish...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Richard Burton</actor><actor>Robert Ryan</actor><actor>Martha Hyer</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10408116/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>jpdoherty</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
ICE PALACE was a failed 1960 Warner Bros. minor blockbuster! Rather
poorly adapted for the screen by Harry Kleiner from the best selling
novel by Edna Ferber it was stodgily directed by Vincent Sherman on one
of his off days! This would-be sprawling saga about Alaska statehood
and the feud between two men in the fisheries industry did however have
rich colour Cinematography by Joseph Biroc and a magnificent score by
the studio's legendary Max Steiner!The picture, set in Alaska just after WW1, turned out to be a wearisome
143 minute soap opera! Like most Ferber stories, which tend to be
overlong and tediously generational, ICE PALACE as a film suffers from
an unremarkable screenplay, flabby direction and most importantly an
unimpressive cast. Firstly, Richard Burton as the main protagonist is
wholly wrong for the part! His "just mustered out regular U.S. soldier"
character is simply at odds with Burton's own personality! His stern
Englishness (does he ever smile) renders his playing totally
unconvincing! You keep waiting for the actor to break into a reading
from "Richard The 3rd" or use something from "Romeo &amp; Juliet" in the
love scenes! Secondly, Robert Ryan, in one of his rare sympathetic
roles and sporting the colourful name of Thor Storm, isn't much better!
He just doesn't suit the part of a bible quoting goody-two-shoes
moralist! And the female lead has to be the casting director's idea of
being humorous! Carolyn Jones - a second rate actress of little account
- is amazingly cast here as the object of desire for both Burton and
Ryan! Miss Jones - trying to look and act like Bette Davis - never
struck me as the ideal woman that could set a fire alight in a man -
let alone two! But I guess that's life.... in the movies anyhow! C'est
La Vie!!The best thing about this near Turkey is Max Steiner's wonderful music!
This was the composer's fourth score for a Ferber story following
"Cimarron" (1931), "Saratoga Trunk" (1946) and "So Big" (1953). The
composer's magnificent Anthem-like main theme for ICE PALACE - first
heard over the titles - was purposely based on "Maryland My Maryland"
and was once considered by Alaska for its state song. After the main
title it segues into the music for the Prologue which can be heard
under the splendid on-screen poem "Alaska" by Robert W.
Service.............Wild And Wide Are My BordersStern As Death Is my Sway,And I Wait For The Men Who Will Win meAnd I Will Not Be Won In A Day,And I Will Not Be Won By WeaklingsSubtle, Soft And Mild,But By Men With The Hearts Of VikingsAnd The Simple Faith Of A Child. The score also boasts two beautiful love themes and a haunting Eskimo
cue where the intuitive composer conveys a compelling ethnic
impression. Also heard are exciting variations on the main theme for a
montage of some fishing sequences and a terrific frenetic cue for a
dog-sled as it races across a snow covered landscape.ICE PALACE never made the grade as even a competent movie! It could
have been and should have been a whole lot better. If it is worth
anything it is for Steiner's music! The esteemed composer once said
that great music could never save a movie. In the case of ICE PALACE he
was right on the button!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7059410/comments</url><from>from Serbia</from><name>fedor8 (fedor8@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Without any doubt one of the corniest, most idiotic dramas of all time.
Based on a "novel" by one of those dim-witted and talentless 5-dime
soap-opera female writers, it lives "up" to its expectations, and then
some: this film is a laugh-a-minute drama which easily qualifies for a
"Mystery Science Theater 3000" treatment. The dialog, the story, the
characters, the plot-twists, the plot-devices, and the unintentionally
comical dramatic soundtrack all combine to form a movie that has to be
seen to be believed. The sheer imbecility of it all is a joy. Ed Wood
would have been proud had he made it.Where should I even begin? Here goes, in no particular order: 1)
Burton's and Ryan's granddaughter (how poetic) is quarter Eskimo, but
what about those blond, Swedish looks? 2) Her Eskimo Daddy is basically
a white college type with dark oil smeared onto his face, 3) His fight
with the bear is a comedic highlight; watch how he goes at the bear
(and why isn't it a white i.e. polar bear?) with just a knife, and how
little he is hurt when the bear slaps him, 4) the moment Ryan's son was
born it became so damn obvious that he would grow up and fall in love
with Burton's daughter, and that way set the stage for a lame
re-re-re-re-re-hash of "Romeo &amp; Juliet", 5) the re-re-re-re-re-re-hash
not only ends tragically - it ends so ULTRA-tragically that I had to
laugh out loud! Romeo gets killed by a bear, while Juliet dies at the
same time at childbirth, 6) By the way, Juliet is woman no.2 to die at
childbirth in this movie; it seems that in the early Alaskan days
babies tended to plop out of the womb at the most inconvenient times,
and there was nobody in sight anywhere to help; plus it was a
convenient way to get rid of two mothers so that Jones can be their
reserve-mommy, 7) and as if the totally over-the-top deaths of Romeo
and Juliet weren't enough, only (movie-)minutes before their doom
Burton's wife dies of a heart-attack; them corpses, they just kept
a-pilin' in the middle section (and them plot-devices, they started
a-getting' dumber and dumber), 8) since Burton made it as a successful
capitalist, it was only fair that his arch-enemy, Ryan the fisherman,
makes it as a politician: this is rather hilarious, too, 9) Burton's
rich daughter (Juliet) decides to run away from home to Romeo's Eskimo
village and she is happy there! 10) Baccus's son is born BEFORE Juliet
yet I had the strange impression that Juliet was a cool 5 years older,
11) one of the idiotic highlights is "Star Trek"'s Zulu (Takei; in a
wonderfully bad performance) trying to find a doctor for Burton's
expecting wife, but managing only to find Jones, whom the former can't
stand - how poetic! 12) in the first scenes showing Romeo's and
Juliet's daughter (let's just call her Lovechild) the movie almost
becomes a sit-com, with Burton and Ryan being both Granddaddies to her
but also arch-enemies, and Lovechild being in the middle, but 13) then
suddenly the movie starts getting overly dramatic and soppy yet, yet,
yet again! 14) Burton saves Ryan's life at the end - how CORNY! 15) a
highlight in the last half-hour (which tends to get dull) is
undoubtedly Burton losing his cool at a political hearing and wanting
to have a punch-up with Ryan! It strikes me as the height of hypocrisy
and irony that a movie which takes such a righteous stance against
racism casts all-white actors to play half- or quarter- Eskimos. Were
they afraid that we wouldn't like Eskimo-looking Eskimos as much as
Eskimos who look like they graduated from Yale? Talk about left-wing
Hollywood's double-standards! I can't imagine how the actors must have
felt uttering so many idiotic lines. There are a number of moments of
campy preaches and pathetic moralizing which are only good enough for
5-dime soap-operas and retards. The fact that this dumb tale is
supposed to be an epic only makes it sillier. And how about Jones's bad
looks: this bug-eyed actress, who looks at least ten years older than
she really is, is the focal point of the two lead studs. But perhaps
that was - as Takei found out one day (in one scene) - the result of
her being the only woman in town.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Another cinematic weakness of mine has been the filming of Edna
Ferber's stories. Here work adapts so well to the cinema I think it's
impossible to make a bad movie of her work. Ice Palace is always given short shrift when it is viewed in comparison
to Showboat, Cimarron, and most importantly Giant. Actually it is Giant
that Ice Palace seems to have the most in common with. Two men grow
wealthier during the history of the area's growth and are changed by
their love for the same woman. Carolyn Jones had quite an effect on the
two men panting after her, the same as Elizabeth Taylor did to Rock
Hudson and James Dean.I viewed Ice Palace again after seeing it many years ago and it is as
good as I remembered it the first time. Two fine portrayals of rival
empire builders are given by Richard Burton and Robert Ryan. You can
feel the hatred they have for each other come crackling right out of
the TV screen as on the big screen. Carolyn Jones as she ages from
comely young Scotch lassie to matronly spinster because she won't
commit to either man, makes you forget her as Morticia Adams.If Ice Palace has a weakness it's in the direction. I think if George
Stevens had done this one it would have been a cinema classic like
Giant is. Still Ice Palace is a fine film that is often overlooked in
retrospectives of either Richard Burton or Robert Ryan.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur23401959/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>williwaw</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I like this movie due to the fact it celebrates the statehood of Alaska
and it features Richard Burton pre Cleopatra when he was a solid
journeyman Actor before all the hype of the Taylor/Burton affair.
Vincent Sherman who made many fine films at Warner Bros. directs this
film and it is a very easy going picture with great photography.
Sherman did fine work at WB (and is noted for his relationships -at
different times with feuding divas Joan Crawford and the Queen of the
Lot Bette Davis)Am also a fan of the Warner Bros stock company of the 1960's and
several players of that group are cast here including the fine actor
Ray Danton, and the lovely Diane McBain. Both Danton and McBain were
groomed for stardom and Warners kept both busy in both movies and TV.
(Warners would shunt their stock players between various TV shows and
movies filming on the lot. There is a great picture which I wish
someone would find that showed J L Warner with the dozens of players
under contract at the time shot on the back lot: Troy Donahue, Connie
Stevens, Edd Byrnes, Roger Smith, Peter Brown, Chad Everett, Dorothy
Provine, Tony Eisley, Gary Vinson, Diane McBain, Ty Hardin et
al...names that conjure up wonderful memories of a bygone era)Is "Ice Palace" a great movie? no! Is it enjoyable to watch? Yes!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a surprisingly little known generational saga based on a novel
by Edna Ferber (who also penned "Cimarron".) It spans about 45 years in
the lives of a trio of entrepreneurs in Alaska. Burton plays an ex-WWI
soldier who isn't given his old job back as the war ends. He makes his
way to Alaska where he (after some plot complications) meets up with
fisherman Ryan and Ryan's fiancée Jones. From here, the story follows
their many trials and tribulations leading up to the statehood of
Alaska. There is a TON of story to be told in this film and, though it
is long, most vignettes only get touched on and many characters come
and go and age so quickly it's sometimes head-spinning. Burton is a
thoroughly unsympathetic lead character. All he does is brood and
bellow. Ryan is less grating at first, but soon joins in. Jones, though
solid, seems to be channelling Bette Davis half the time and her
long-suffering role is one like Ms. Davis might have essayed back in
her prime at Warner Brothers. Hyer, in a thankless role, pretty much
models some nice suits before her big (and hilarious) scene involving a
heart attack. Backus does okay as Burton's sidekick. One shocker is
witnessing the well-spoken Takei portraying a demeaning,
pigeon-English, Chinese servant complete with all the stereotypical
traits and insulting "comic relief". It is odd to see Burton sharing
screen time with "Mr. Howell" and "Mr. Sulu"! Knight barely appears at
all. McBain comes along toward the end to provide a welcome dose of
spark and sex appeal. The film is not exactly good, but it is
watchable. Several scenes are marred by tacky effects like plastic snow
and rear-projection (and in one howler of a scene, an attack by a man
in a bear suit!) Also, Burton, who was twelve years YOUNGER than
Backus, ages and ages while Backus just goes a little gray. He passes
Backus up! Max Steiner provides some nice music. One scene, which seems
daring for the time, involves two Eskimo women getting naked under some
furs to thaw out a frozen traveller.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1720516/comments</url><from>from Fort Worth, Texas</from><name>pv71989</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I know it sounds like a contradiction, but "Ice Palace" suffers from a long
running time while the movie's scenes are too brief to offer anything
substantial.
   Based on a novel by Edna Ferber (who also wrote the best-selling novels
Show Boat, Cimarron and Giant, all of which became classic, award-winning
films), the movie deals with an almost life-long rivalry between Zeb Kennedy
(Richard Burton) and Thor Storm (Robert Ryan) in the wilds of a still
territorial Alaska.
   Zeb is a WWI veteran who comes back home to Seattle to find he can't get
a job, thanks to local packers who see him as a troublemaker because he
dances to his own tune and not theirs. He heads to Alaska aboard a
freighter, along with a bunch of Chinese workers (he meets the character of
Wang (George Takei in a demeaning role of a pidgen-English speaking role of
comic relief).
   Zeb meets Thor (Robert Ryan), a local fisherman in the town of Banarov
when he is beaten up by local cannery workers and thrown into the bay after
stepping in to defend Wang, who's being threatened.
   Not to belabor a point, but Thor and Zeb become friends and conspire to
open a rival cannery in Banarov to avoid having to grovel at the feet of the
big cannery across the bay. Zeb then meets Bridie Ballantyne (Carolyn
Jones), who is Thor's woman and business partner. He falls for her, makes
her fall for him, then realizes it's wrong and decides to leave Baranov.
Thor, unknowing of all this, gets him to set up financing in Seattle for the
cannery.
   Zeb does this by marrying Dorothy (Martha Hyer) to get her father to back
the cannery, thanks to some advice from best friend and future business
partner Dave Husack (a pre-Gilligan's Island Jim Backus). Anyway, when Zeb,
Bridie, Thor and Dorothy all meet up, it's like that song where Chicago says
to look away. The jig is up and sets the tension for the rest of the
movie.
   Zeb becomes a tyrant, in league with other big packers, while Thor
becomes a protector of Alaska, seeking statehood so that federal laws can
come in and stop Zeb, called "Czar" Kennedy by the locals.
   The problems with the movie deal mostly with the length of the novel,
which rivaled "Giant." Whereas "Giant" and "Cimarron" dispensed with huge
chunks of the books to avoid boring and losing audiences, "Ice Palace" tries
to touch on all of the story. This leaves quick scenes that jump and leave
the rest of us behind. 
   Characters aren't allowed to develop fully. For instance, Zeb defends
Wang and then, feeling guilty about Bridie, decides to leave well enough
alone. A moment later, he's a cruel, callous tyrant who calls Eskimo kids
"half-breeds" and mistreats his wife, Dorothy (Diane McBain in a wasted
role). 
   The costumers and set designers do a marvelous job of advancing Baranov
year by year and a little make-up does wonders to make Burton et al age with
the times (although Jim Backus, who was 14 years older than Burton, seemed
to just let the Just for Men wear off).
   In no short time, we're introduced to Chris, Thor's son by his Eskimo
wife (Dorcas Brower, a gorgeous woman who's character is barely touched upon
because she conveniently dies off-screen in childbirth). Grace, Zeb and
Dorothy's daughter is seen briefly as a little girl and then as a teenager
who elopes with Chris. By this time, Zeb is a shell of a husband and Thor
spends his every waking moment railing against Zeb like George Bush against
Saddam Hussein.
   Then, suddenly, Grace is pregnant and she and Chris are flying across the
frozen tundra on a three-week journey via dog sled to the nearest town so
she can give birth (don't ask). They get lost and Thor and Zeb come to the
rescue. Great drama until the scene with Chris fighting a man in a bear suit
(watch how the bear throws Chris to the ground, then hams it up in a death
scene; it's unintentionally hilarious).
   No doubt, the movie has a great cast, but most of the roles are
underdeveloped and a few are totally out of place. George Takei's voice-over
work on the English version of "Rodan" must have seemed a godsend compared
to the simpering man-servant Wang. Kar Swenson as the full-blooded Irish
father of Bridie is a hoot. Swenson is best known as lumber mill owner Lars
Hanson of "Little House on the Prairie" and his Scandinavian accent
massacres his attempts at speaking with an Irish brogue.
   Bridie is also wasted. She's supposed to be the object of love for Thor
and Zeb, yet she marries neither, tries to help Thor raise his son, but is
rarely shown in the same space as the boy. As she ages, she begins to
resemble Bette Davis (it's hard to imagine her later role as Morticia
Addams). It's become more and more difficult to believe she can still harbor
any love or like for Thor or Zeb, both of whom lose audience sympathy by
being total jackasses.
   Of course, all would seem to come together in the end, despite a
despicable plot by Zeb and Dave's son, Bay (Ray Danton), to use his
granddaughter Christine (Shirley Knight in another wasted role). But even
this is left flapping in the breeze, literally, when Thor and a local pilot
do the cliche "small plane in a snow storm hitting a glacier" plot twist.
You can guess what happens next, which leaves you feeling cheated.   "Ice Palace" plays out more like the pilot for a TV show, where you hope
unresolved issues will be answered. Actually, it probably should have been
made into a TV show a la "Peyton Place" where the whole story line could
have been given its proper due.
   All in all, it's an interesting little film to watch if you happen to be
the kind of person who doesn't hit the "pause" button when the phone rings
or the doorbell rings in the middle of the viewing. If you miss a scene,
don't worry. You'll be just as confused as if you had watched
it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I can't believe this movie has a rating as high as it does! This is an
absolutely awful "epic" film that is about as dull and poorly made "big
picture" as you'll find. To put this in perspective, this came out just
a few years after GIANT and seems to be a similar-type movie (having
been written by the same person, by the way) but it's set in Alaska
instead of Texas. And,...in addition, it is chock full of histrionics
and soap opera elements.My biggest complaint is actually the music. This is an odd thing to
complain about, but throughout the movie incredibly loud and flamboyant
music occurs in the most mundane moments! For example, when people are
out catching salmon in fishing boats, you are assaulted by loud
classical-style music! Again and again, the lousy musical score
dominates and overwhelms. A lot of the time, it simply would have been
better with no music instead of the brash music they used.Secondly, no one in particular is very likable or interesting. At
first, Richard Burton seems interesting and pretty likable, but soon he
becomes and unreasoning money-crazed robot instead of a real human
being. So, in effect, he's a caricature of a person--completely
one-dimensional and fake. His kid and later grandkid MIGHT be
interesting, but their characters really are never developed--they're
more like a part of the set or a plot device. Despite Robert Ryan's
character being a little less repellent and wooden, he isn't a BIG
improvement, either. Of the three leads, Carolyn Jones probably comes
off best.Thirdly, George Takei (yes, from STAR TREK) plays the role of a very
stereotypical Chinese lackey. Considering how broad and insulting the
character was, I feel sorry for him having to take such a demeaning
role. Plus, he's Japanese--this just isn't the same as Chinese! Why not
get a real honest-to-goodness Chinese guy who can act like he's not an
idiot to play the part?Fourthly, I hated the scene involving the fight between Thor's son and
the bear. In the distant shots it's obviously a real bear. But in the
close shots it's also obviously a guy in a bear suit! It's so obvious
that it looks like something you'd see in a 3 Stooges short, not an
expensive epic.And finally, the film is just uninteresting. The movie seemed like it
was 4 hours long, but it wasn't. It's just that a guy making money by
operating a fish cannery just isn't compelling.So in conclusion, the movie stinks. It's BIG and SWEEPING and has some
nice cinematography, but that's all!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8977071/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>drystyx</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This is one of those grandiose movies in which everyone is destined to
be a governor or some such character. So, this isn't a movie that you
take too seriously. It is a movie which depends on characters to keep
you interested. Two friends, played by screen legends Richard Burton
and Robert Ryan, go through ups and downs, and a big feud that
culminates through the generations. The story itself isn't too bad. It
gets a bit too grandiose for some people, and possibly not enough for
others. At the time, Burton was considered the great actor, and Ryan
was considered a Western actor. But now both are regarded as
superstars. And this is a pretty star studded cast. And it isn't a
boring story. There are assets to this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12846507/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lairdjs</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is one of the great movies ever made. I really would love to own
it on DVD. I have it on VHS, but the color is fading. Do you know when
it will come out on DVD. I recommend this movie to all ages.Anyone who
is interested in the history and stories of Alaska will enjoy the
story. The actors are Robert Ryan, who is great, Richard Burton, who is
always very good, and Carolyn Jones and Marther Hyer who portray their
parts perfectly. You are in for a real treat, so grab your popcorn,
something to drink, set back and enjoy a great movie, full of
entertainment and good acting. To bad that Hollywood does not put out
this kind of movies anymore. An era has pasted and that is too bad.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0725998/comments</url><from>from Mount Vernon Missouri</from><name>enlewellyn</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

The growing tension between Richard Burton and Robert Ryan is amazing.
Both
actors were as serious, driven, righteous (in their own minds), and caring
as the other. All performances were believable and interesting. The change
from generations to generation was seamless. And character change melded
nicely with Ryan and Burton. Carolyn Jones however did not impress me as
much as she did in the beginning. She somehow lost her luster as the film
seemed to continue without her. Strangely this also was her role through
the
duration of the film.  And I felt she seemed to be going through the
motions
towards the end. Just my opinion. I also found the characters of
Christopher
and Grace charming at first and utterly brainless towards the end. You
have
to see it and the circumstances to believe it. The innocent bliss that
leads
them throughout the film culminates.
To mention Jim Buckus, his performance was quite an agitation to most
every
event in the film due to his characters business interests. Believable
even
if you still see him as Mr Howell! LOL! Four years later, character
development, who can say,
Recommended if you looking for a (mini) epic that might just keep your
interest.I'm keeping my copy!Otherwise outstanding performances
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0725998/comments</url><from>from Mount Vernon Missouri</from><name>enlewellyn</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

The growing tension between Richard Burton and Robert Ryan is amazing.
Both
actors were as serious, driven, righteous (in their own minds), and caring
as the other. All performances were believable and interesting. The change
from generations to generation was seamless. And character change melded
nicely with Ryan and Burton. Carolyn Jones however did not impress me as
much as she did in the beginning. She somehow lost her luster as the film
seemed to continue without her. Strangely this also was her role through
the
duration of the film.  And I felt she seemed to be going through the
motions
towards the end. Just my opinion. I also found the characters of
Christopher
and Grace charming at first and utterly brainless towards the end. You
have
to see it and the circumstances to believe it. The innocent bliss that
leads
them throughout the film culminates.
To mention Jim Buckus, his performance was quite an agitation to most
every
event in the film due to his characters business interests. Believable
even
if you still see him as Mr Howell! LOL! Four years later, character
development, who can say,
Recommended if you looking for a (mini) epic that might just keep your
interest.I'm keeping my copy!Otherwise outstanding performances
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0725998/comments</url><from>from Mount Vernon Missouri</from><name>enlewellyn</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>