<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>BUtterfield 8</original_title><alt_title>La Vénus au vison</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Daniel Mann</director><producer>Afton-Linebrook</producer><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
The romantic life of a fashionable Manhattan beauty who's part model, part call-girl--and all man-trap.
</synopsis><actor>Elizabeth Taylor</actor><actor>Laurence Harvey</actor><actor>Eddie Fisher</actor><rt_rating>5.7/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>47</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1592694/comments</url><from>from Biloxi, Mississippi</from><name>gftbiloxi (gftbiloxi@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
In the normal scheme of things, lofty MGM wouldn't have touched John
O'Hara's novel with a ten foot pole--but shortly before her contract
was to end, MGM star Elizabeth Taylor besmirched her image by running
off with Debbie Reynolds' husband Eddie Fisher. With her reputation in
shreds and one foot outside the studio gate any way, MGM decided to
capitalize on the bad press by casting Taylor as BUTTERFIELD 8's
bad-girl-from-hell... and then, to add insult to injury, tucked Eddie
Fisher into a supporting role and cast Debbie Reynolds look-alike Susan
Oliver in the role of Eddie's girl friend, who feels threatened by
Liz's manhungry ways. Liz fought the project tooth and nail, but MGM
was adamant: she owed them another film, and she wasn't leaving until
she made it.BUTTERFIELD 8 is the story of Gloria Wandrous (Taylor), a
hard-drinking, sexed-up, bed-hopping dress model who gets her kicks by
seducing and then dumping men according to whim--until she encounters
an unhappily married man just as hard and disillusioned as she in
Weston Liggett (Laurence Harvey.) Although the production code was
still somewhat in force, it had loosened up quite a bit since the days
of NATIONAL VELVET, and while scenes stop short at the bedroom door
they have plenty of sizzle while they walk up to it; moreover, every
one in the film talks about sex so much you'd think it had just been
invented. Taylor is on record saying that she considers the film a
piece of trash, and she swears she has never actually seen it, that she
would rather die than ever see it.But something weird happened as the camera rolled. Taylor, doubtlessly
driven by her fury at having to do the movie, gives a throw-away,
over-the-top performance--but perversely, this is precisely what the
role requires, and her performance was successful enough to earn her an
Oscar. The supporting cast follows her lead, all of them performing in
broad colors and bigger-than-life emotions, and again they too are
quite successful, with Laurence Harvey and Dina Merrill (as his long
suffering wife) particularly effective. Ultimately, of course,
Elizabeth Taylor is quite right when she says the film is a piece of
trash. But it is the best kind of trash because it is so completely
trashy: BUTTERFIELD 8 doesn't just dive into the trash pile, it wallows
in it with considerable conviction. Modern films of the same type may
show more skin and more sex, but for sheer authority BUTTERFIELD 8
remains a standard against which most of them pale. Not every one will
like it, but I recommend it all the same.Gary F. Taylor, aka GFT, Amazon Reviewer
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
On the surface, Taylor was all sex and devil-may-care… Everything in
her was struggling toward respectability… She never gave up trying…The
film concerns her fashionable life which is part model, part
call-girl—and all man-trap… Her performance is one of her best and was
nominated for her third Academy Award… Her remarkable scene is her confession to Eddie Fisher about how she
got started in the life: she was seduced by a house guest when she was
thirteen, and she liked it! She has always 'liked' it! Emotionally, she
dominates the screen at this moment and her serious attitude simply
fills it up… Filmed in and around New York, "Butterfield 8" is an intimate portrait
of a tormented woman daringly beautiful and sexy…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0397955/comments</url><from>from Morristown, NJ</from><name>Eric-62-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Elizabeth Taylor hated making this movie (forced on her by MGM to fulfill
the last part of her contract with the studio dating back to her days as a
child star), and she hates it still.    But whereas a lesser performer would
have channeled that hatred into not trying at all on screen, La Liz instead
channeled her hatred of the project by playing her part of call-girl Gloria
Wandrous to the hilt, and in the process richly earned her first Academy
Award (it is a far better performance than Shirley MacLaine's in "The
Apartment", her chief competition that year).    The story is cheap soap
opera that really makes one snicker today when you see how they had to dance
around the Production Code restraints of the day like never before, but
watching La Liz in action is spellbinding.   No other part reveals how in
her prime she was the total picture of stunning beauty *and* a talented,
gifted actress to boot.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
John O'Hara's novel was way ahead of its time. Daniel Mann's
"Butterfield 8" was a film that capitalized on the lurid aspects of the
book, but actually was turned into a soap opera. By today's standards
it looks kind of ridiculous, but of course, it was meant to reflect the
period of the late fifties in which the action is set.Elizabeth Taylor was at the height of her beauty when the movie was
shot. She comes out as the gorgeous creature she was in this vehicle
that won her the Oscar that she should have received for other films,
notably "Suddenly, Last Summer".The film will entertain whoever hasn't seen it before. It's obvious Ms.
Taylor and her co-star, Lawrence Harvey, had no chemistry whatsoever,
as it shows in the film. What was shocking then wouldn't raise an
eyebrow now. In the supporting cast, Mildred Dunnock, Betty Field, Dina
Merrill give good performances.Watch this film as curiosity piece to see some of the New York of that
era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4697955/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (style@austinchronicle.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"She's catnip to every cat in town," a bartender says of Gloria
Wandrous, call girl and Party Girl #1, who is boozing it up, surrounded
by a dozen men. Waking up in Wes Liggett's (Harvey) Fifth Avenue
penthouse, she discovers he's left her a wad of money and a note
saying, "Is $250 enough?" She hurls the money away, scrawling "No Sale"
on the mirror with her lipstick. But she seems to forget that she is a
call girl, and call girls accept money for services rendered.
Unfortunately, Gloria is in love with Liggett, her "john", but he is
married to someone else – a society matron poorly played by the cold,
patrician beauty, Dina Merrill. As Gloria is leaving, she steals
Ligget's wife's $7000 fur coat and starts all kinds of trouble. It
certainly would have caused trouble today – the entire film is a PETA
nightmare, as Gloria can be clocked wearing suede, lynx, coyote, mink,
sable, beaver, and something that looks like skunk. The whole movie has
Liz in her last fading bloom of youth, girded-to-the-gills and at the
peak of her "eyebrows-of-death" period. Her Gloria-ously voluptuous
figure is beginning to bulge and sag, but she is decked out to the
nines in drop-dead stylish early-60s glamour. At the time, Liz and
Jackie Kennedy were neck-and-neck in the glamour department, and the
Jackie look is unmistakably present in Liz's styling. Though Jackie's
never would be, Liz's cleavage is on abundant display. Cleavage was
such a powerful metaphor for sex, then – a set-piece whose
effectiveness would be impossible now (you practically have to show
actors rutting on the floor to satisfy the modern taste). Liz was also
at the peak of her Eddie Fisher period - playing a harlot on screen
after stealing Fisher away from his real-life wife, Debbie Reynolds,
only added to Liz's plummeting reputation. Fisher plays Gloria's friend
who loves her but is not taken seriously by her. He's such a drip on
screen, that you can't help wondering how in real life this guy managed
to attract one of the most glamorous women in the world. The suave and
very continental Harvey is equally dull, especially as he commandeers
that last 20 minutes of the film. The part of Gloria won an Oscar for
Liz Taylor – mysteriously, since the work is far inferior to many of
Liz's previous films. Liz has proclaimed that this is the least
favorite film she ever made – she was simply fulfilling the
requirements of her contract. But when Liz is good, she's very, very
good, but when she's bad, she gives it all she's got. Director Daniel
Mann definitely had a way with leading-ladies. In addition to guiding
Liz towards her Oscar, he did the same for Shirley Booth in *Come Back,
Little Sheba* and Anna Magnani in *The Rose Tattoo*. Also directing
Susan Hayward in *I'll Cry Tomorrow*, Mann certainly excels in these
heavy-handed soapers. Based on the racy John O'Hara novel, the dialogue
is dreadful. At one point Gloria tells her shrink, "I don't need you
any more. I have no problems. I'm in love," as well as, "Someday Wes is
going to find himself, and I want to be there." The script was so bad
we veered off into a conversation about the yogurt shop murders, and
missed a scene full of lots of drinking, ultimatums and arched
eyebrows, but we were riveted to the screen as Gloria is screaming,
"Mama, face it! I was the slut of all time!" But even when shrieking,
Liz is irresistible. And like Gloria says in the movie, "I loved it –
every awful moment of it, I loved!"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
It's recalled now for the star's performance, which netted her her
first Oscar. In 1960 the performance of Elizabeth Taylor as Gloria
Wondrous was considered a fine one for that up and coming actress, but
despite her acting performance most people then (and since) have
believed that it was not her sad portrayal of the self-destruction of a
beautiful call girl that merited the award, but that she was recovering
from a near fatal illness at the time. Taylor's performance was first
rate - probably the best reason today to see this film. Despite an
apparent hard shell she is quite vulnerable, and her tormented
relationship with socialite Laurence Harvey leads up to his degradation
and her demise. John O'Hara's novels are still in print. He was a master of American
idiom - the class and background of his characters could be seen by
reading their dialog. He had a great eye for details, and for social
class conflicts. This first comes out in his first novel "Appointment
In Samara", but it appears in "Butterfield 8" as well, where the class
problems that arise from Gloria's affair with Weston Liggett can be
called the tragedy of the purloined fur coat. Gloria, as the novel
opens, has had her one night stand with Liggett at his home, a ritzy
upper-east side apartment in Manhattan. She is unsatisfied with leaving
so soon, so she takes a fur coat out of the closet to cover herself in.
It is this theft that leads to the gradual revelation of the affair
with Liggett, and it's affects on Gloria, Liggett, her mother and
friend Steve (Eddie Fisher), and his wife (Dina Merrill) and their
family and friends. The coat symbolizes the sexual relationship that
Gloria threatens to take away from Emily Liggett, and how the social
order is shaken by the affair.O'Hara based the story on a tragedy that happened in the summer of 1931
in New York City and Long Island (and that also affected Boston). A
very beautiful young woman, Starr Faithful*, was found dead on the
beach at the city of Long Beach in Nassau County, New York. Starr was
soon revealed to have had a number of socially prominent acquaintances
(one is hard put to call them friends). She and her sister Tucker and
their mother and stepfather lived in Greenwich Village - their next
door neighbor was Mayor James J. Walker (to be fair to "Beau James", it
is not very likely that he ever really knew Starr and her family). She
did have a habit of popping up at parties all over the place (rumor put
her at a party to celebrate a Broadway production of Aristophanes'
Lysistrata thrown by Bennett Cerf, and in honor of the star of the
production Miriam Hopkins). She also slept around, one of her
boyfriends being a ship's doctor on an Atlantic liner. But finally, it
came out that in her youth she was sexually abused by Mr. Andrew J.
Peters, a former Mayor of Boston. Peters actually was a cousin by
marriage of Starr's mother. He continued seeing her as she grew up (she
was a minor when the relationship began), and paid the family large
sums to keep their mouths shut.None of this background is in the novel or film. The novel does have a
character (a respectable college professor) who has had a relationship
with Gloria and is coming to New York to pay her some extortion money,
but the tragedy of the Long Beach death is only approximated in the
novel (where Gloria drowns in a freak accident on an aging steamboat),
and is changed in the movie (I won't explain how). In any case the
death of Gloria is an accident in the novel and the movie - although
Gloria's final actions may have been based on a death wish. Was that what killed Starr Faithful? Actually, her last biographer
(Johnathan Goodman in "The Passing Of Starr Faithful") makes a case for
her being murdered by gangsters who were after important secrets she
might have had knowledge of. O'Hara would not have known of that
theory, but would have just worked on the general assumption that his
model committed suicide (which was accepted as likely in 1935, when the
novel was written). Gloria may be based on Starr, but their fates are
not quite the same even if their emotional problems seem very similar.(*For some reason the spelling of the last name of Starr is
consistently respelled incorrectly on this website - despite my
attempts to correct it - as "Faithful" with one "ell" at the end. It
has two "ells" at the end.)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0419478/comments</url><from>from NAS Ream Field</from><name>Ben Calmes</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Two beautiful unhappy people from opposite ends of Eisenhower era America
are drawn together by an obsessive love that ends in tragic consequences. 
Elizabeth Taylor won a Best Actress Oscar (after much better performances in
earlier pictures such as `Cat On A Hot Tin Roof') for her portrayal of
(shock!) call-girl Gloria Wandrous.  Laurence Harvey plays the john, Weston
Liggett, trapped in a stale marriage with his stoic wife Emily (Dina
Merrill, perfect as a blue-blooded blonde heiress).  Complementing the moody performances of Liz and Laurence Harvey are an
excellent Eddie Fisher as Gloria's long-suffering best friend and greatest
admirer Steve, Mildred Dunnock as poor Mrs. Wandrous, in complete denial of
her daughter's easy virtue, Betty Field as nosy neighbor Mrs. Fanny Barber,
and many others including Kay Medford as tragicomic motel matron,
Happy.Lurking behind the scenes of `Butterfield 8' are some very grown up issues
(particularly for its day) about infidelity, high class prostitution,
childhood sexual abuse, and the meaning of true commitment.  The dialogue by
John Michael Hayes (`Peyton Place,' `To Catch A Thief,' and `Rear Window",
among many credits) and Charles Schnee, is punchy and quick, and the movie
glows with luscious cinematography from Hollywood veteran Joseph Ruttenberg,
who got an Academy Award nomination for his efforts (he had previously won
four Oscars dating back to 1938).Although somewhat dated, it remains a thoughtful film (if you pay attention)
and a visual treat for any Liz fan.   Worth watching!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0386241/comments</url><from/><name>gridoon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When I started watching this film, I didn't know what to expect. At first it
seemed like a slick, empty showcase for Elizabeth Taylor's beauty. However,
it gradually turned into an involving (and extremely good-looking) little
drama. You may have heard that it is campy; that's not true, although there
is an unnecessary little speech by Harvey at the end. It's slickly produced,
well-paced, entertaining and has an excellent cast.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2250666/comments</url><from>from Hollywood, CA</from><name>singjohn</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
If dated 60's camp with sexual innuendo and great outfits for the
leading lady are your thing, then B8 will not disappoint. However
speaking as a fan of such fare, this film leaves me a bit cold. Its
camp moments and dialog are numerous enough, but B8 holds its best
shocker for the end. The film, like Liz's character is a big tease.
Taking small but well-placed stabs at sexual mores of the time period,
but never really going further. Add Laurence Harvey's womanizing
alcoholic, Dina Merrill as the waspy compliant wife, Eddie Fisher (La
Taylor's current hubby at the time) in the non-essential role as Liz's
pal, and Mildred Dunnock as Liz's annoying mother in denial, and you'll
be hard pressed to find a likable character. Liz herself did not
consider this her best performance. Shirley MacLaine called it "the
Oscar I lost to the tracheotomy" referring to Taylor's near death from
pneumonia complications in 1960. B8 (like other films that were based
on camp sex novels of the 60's) would make a great remake if it
remained set in the 60's but kept the shocks of the original book
intact. If you love Liz, chances are you'll love B8. If you're looking
for an accurate portrayal of O'Hara's landmark novel, this is not it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0091670/comments</url><from>from california</from><name>stills-6</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Taylor is tasty in this role, but is it the way she smokes or the way she
smokes? Much of this movie is cheap psychobabble, but Taylor smolders with a
raw sensuality that you would never guess she had in her. You knew she was
strong, beautiful, and flawed, but you never knew she could be all three and
still be able to act with that much cleavage.The unfortunate thing about this movie is that there are other people in it.
It's Taylor's movie, but somehow it gets mangled and it ends up being
Laurence Harvey's story. Who the Hell let the last twenty minutes of this
movie get through the production line? What a complete letdown. And
Bronislau Kaper's absolutely horrible musical score doesn't help matters. If
there was ever a movie that didn't need this kind of filler music, this is
it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0091670/comments</url><from>from california</from><name>stills-6</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Taylor is tasty in this role, but is it the way she smokes or the way she
smokes? Much of this movie is cheap psychobabble, but Taylor smolders with a
raw sensuality that you would never guess she had in her. You knew she was
strong, beautiful, and flawed, but you never knew she could be all three and
still be able to act with that much cleavage.The unfortunate thing about this movie is that there are other people in it.
It's Taylor's movie, but somehow it gets mangled and it ends up being
Laurence Harvey's story. Who the Hell let the last twenty minutes of this
movie get through the production line? What a complete letdown. And
Bronislau Kaper's absolutely horrible musical score doesn't help matters. If
there was ever a movie that didn't need this kind of filler music, this is
it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0091670/comments</url><from>from california</from><name>stills-6</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies.tvguide.com/butterfield-8/review/121844 /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1967595</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Glossy trash with the star at full throttle, it's the quintessental La Liz movie.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,874219,00.html /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1967594</url><from>TIME Magazine</from></reviewer><comment>A sleek and libidinous lingerie meller.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://www.chicagoreader.com/chicago/butterfield-8/Film?oid=1059716 /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1967592</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>It's just about as awful as you'd expect, despite the presence of two first-class screenwriter.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117789622.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1808157</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>Under director Daniel Mann's guidance it is an extremely sexy and intimate film, but the intimacy is only skin deep, the sex only a dominating behavior pattern.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/butterfield8.htm /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1731295</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>When viewed today it's a work of considerable dreck, it's badly dated and unappealing.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/butterfield-8-1960-2/ /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1612719</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>"Mama face it, I was the slut of all time," Liz Taylor's hooker confronts her mother, and that's pretty much sums up the nature of this glossy, trashy melodrama that Hollywood used to make until TV appropriated the genre.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/68662/butterfield_8.html /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1516399</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Once thought of as racy and adventurous in its treatment of sex, this turgid nonsense about a high-class whore with love in her heart has dated atrociously.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pete-vonder-haar/</url><url>/m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1450518</url><name>Pete Vonder Haar</name><from>Film Threat</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Mostly crap, but Elizabeth Taylor is hot</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C00E2DB1431EF3ABC4F52DFB767838B679EDE /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1389057</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>The dialogue is rough. Let's say O'Harrowing. And the ending is absurd. But so is most of it for that matter. It's the living it up that gets you in this film.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Butterfield-8 /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1209757</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>Taylor's heralded performance as the archetypal hooker ('the slut of all time!') with a heart of gold is a bit overrated.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=101679&amp;section=review /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1148025</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>Taylor won an Oscar for her role in this, but holds the movie in scant regard compared to the rest of her work. And with good reason.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movieline.standard8media.com/reviews/butterfield8.shtml /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=263520</url><from>Movieline</from></reviewer><comment>Though it's generally true that nothing dates faster than Hollywood's idea of what's daring, Butterfield 8 can be viewed as a fascinating artifact from the days when movie stars' offscreen myths were carefully woven into their on-screen roles.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/brian-webster/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=2487 /m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=239534</url><name>Brian Webster</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
79/100
					</rating><comment>Taylor deserves much of the credit for the movie's success, as she imbues Gloria with moxie and vulnerability at the same time.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>/m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1715847</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1428328</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=1309098</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-smith/</url><url>/m/butterfield_8/comments.php?reviewid=794920</url><name>Christopher Smith</name><from>Bangor Daily News (Maine)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>