<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Portrait in Black</original_title><alt_title>Meurtre sans faire-part</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Michael Gordon</director><producer>Ross Hunter Productions Inc.</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
After a married woman and her lover murder her cruel husband, they find themselves targeted by someone who is aware of their crime.
</synopsis><actor>Lana Turner</actor><actor>Anthony Quinn</actor><actor>Richard Basehart</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0158131/comments</url><from>from Atlanta, GA</from><name>Bacall-3</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This movie does not have a convoluted plot, no outrageous secrets that the
viewer is unaware of, just plain good murderous suspense.
Lana Turner is beautiful, and gives a flawlessly terse performance as the
wealthy heiress to be.Sandra Dee is very believable as her step-daughter, and
nemesis.
It was wonderful to see so many famous faces in this movie, which just
happened to air on a movie channel on a Sunday afternoon.
This is exactly what rainy-day entertainment should be, entertaining and
pleasant to view. Lana and Sandra play wealthy women, and their costumes and
home are a treat for the eyes.
Watch this, you will be entertained, although the plot is not
knee-deep.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0407671/comments</url><from>from Palm Springs, California, USA</from><name>Thad Taylor (psthad@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Poor Lana Turner is forced to wear Jean Louis gown after Jean Louis gown
in
this picture, a veritable sea of sequins.  To add insult to injury, she is
kept like a bird in a gilded cage in her magnificent Pacific Heights
mansion.  Her lover (Anthony Quinn) lives only a couple of blocks away,
but
in order to tryst with him, she must first go down to Union Square and
pretend to shop at the old I. Magnin store (now Macy's), then take a cab
back out to Divisadero - very inconvenient.
An uncommonly silly movie, but great set decoration and use of locations.
If you ever come to visit San Francisco, you can see the house that Lana,
Sandra and Lloyd lived in; it's at the corner of Broadway and Baker, just
about the ritziest neighborhood in town, natch....enjoy!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0738625/comments</url><from>from Alexandria, VA</from><name>dglink</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Adultery, murder, blackmail, and Lana Turner, what more could one ask
of a Ross Hunter production? Perhaps a good script, but that would
spoil the fun. "Portrait in Black" will have lovers of camp in stitches
at dialog that makes daytime soaps seem Shakespearean. The overwrought
emoting and melodramatic scenes are often unintentionally funny, and
the plot requires Olympian leaps to cross the credibility gaps.Lana is having an affair with Anthony Quinn, the doctor who is
attending her terminally ill husband, Lloyd Nolan, a shipping magnate.
Nolan's company, Cabot Lines, is evidently quite successful, because
Lana's daily expenditures on wardrobe, coiffures, and makeup would
likely sink a ship. The couple's palatial San Francisco home is a Ross
Hunter fantasy whose upkeep could sink yet another Cabot Line vessel.
Nolan's daughter from a first marriage, Sandra Dee, evidently has her
stepmother's taste in clothes and manicure, while the son from his
marriage to Lana has to make do with a toy airplane. Throw in a greedy
business associate played by Richard Basehart; Dee's suitor, John
Saxon; a chauffeur, Ray Walston; and a housekeeper, Anna May Wong; and
you have a delicious cast of potential suspects to populate an Agatha
Christie mystery. However, "Portrait in Black" is not a whodunit, but
rather a "who knows they dun it." Lana is the ultimate drama queen, and she is in peak form. She suffers,
she screams, she cries; she is the empress of high camp. Anthony Quinn,
who should have read the script before he signed the contract, plays
down to his part and seems to know he has had and will have better
parts. Sandra Dee appears to be studying for future Lana Turner roles,
while Walston and Wong play their parts with the necessary ambiguity to
keep viewers guessing their secrets.However, despite the overacting, bad writing, and soap opera direction,
"Portrait in Black" is great fun for those who love their melodramas
with big budgets and great style. Even the obligatory mirror smashing
has been incorporated. The movie is enormously entertaining for its
sometimes howlingly funny situations, absurd lines, and the sheer
pleasure of watching Lana looking and emoting at her best.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6096355/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mrsastor</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Portrait In Black is in many respects typical of the Ross Hunter films
that rejuvenated Lana Turner's later career. If you're a fan of the
genre, this one is quite entertaining, and in my opinion far superior
to the previous year's terrible remake of Imitation of Life.Portrait In Black brings us a torrid soap opera revolving around the
relationship between the wife of a wealthy shipping magnate, Sheila
Cabot, and her husband's physician, Dr. David Rivera. Unable to bear
having only a few stolen moments for the each other, they conspire to
murder Sheila's husband so they can be together. They subsequently find
themselves blackmailed and must determine who is the blackmailer and
how they will extricate themselves from this web of danger that
continues to keep them separated.As previous reviewers have pointed out, there are some rather silly
aspects to the story, but these again are typical of the genre. For
beginners, Sheila's husband Matt Cabot is said to have a hopeless
terminal illness and to have been ill for many months. Thus, their
motivation for murdering him is rather weak; he will soon die without
any malicious intent on their part. If they really could not bear the
wait, the idea proposed in the script, that they cannot just run away
together because Matt Cabot would ruin Dr. Rivera's career and he would
"never practice medicine again", is a rather unrealistic threat
(although admittedly common in soap opera land). Dr. Rivera's home
gives the impression he is already quite wealthy, it is not as though
these two would be condemned to a life of poverty and want. These plot
holes are exasperated by the poorly directed love scenes between David
and Sheila, which consist of much-overplayed melodramatic panting,
gasping, crying, and an inordinate and unnatural amount of chewing on
one another's hands. Secondly, there are a few script blunders that
could have been easily corrected. When Dr. Rivera requires Sheila to
drive, he puts her in the car and has to explain what the gas and brake
are for, yet in scene one we are told Sheila has been issued a
learner's permit by the Department of Motor Vehicles. A learner's
permit allows one to drive so long as another licensed driver is
present, and one would obviously have to have mastered the basics of
what makes the car go in order to be issued such a permit. The plot of
device that Sheila "doesn't drive" would have been far more believable
without the unnecessary learner's permit in the script. There are a
number of similar absent-minded script errors here.Having said that, one does not watch a period Ross Hunter soaper for
realism. One watches it for drama, and the lush and beautiful feel we
expect from Mr. Hunter. In this regard, Portrait does not disappoint.
Our setting is upper crust Nob Hill in San Francisco. The Cabot home,
with the exception of the library being inexplicably painted black, is
breathtaking. Lana Turner is stunning, and of course immaculately
outfitted in high class fashions, shoes, hats, furs, and jewels at all
times, as is Sandra Dee in her second role as Lana Turner's daughter
(well, step-daughter in this one). Drama abounds and the at times weak
script is handled expertly by the well seasoned cast, including Richard
Basehart, Ray Walston, Virginia Grey, Anna Mae Wong, and John Saxon.
While Anthony Quinn would have been ideally suited to his role of Dr.
David Rivera if the film had been made fifteen years earlier, he is so
badly addled by Michael Gordon's incompetent direction in this role it
makes him seem a bit past it (with the exception of Pillow Talk, none
of Mr. Gordon's films are particularly well directed).All things considered, this film easily meets its purpose, to entertain
and is fun to watch…if you can find it. It is not out on DVD, is no
longer available on VHS, and is seldom aired on television. But if you
get the chance, it's well worth a watch.UPDATE: This film was release on DVD in Jan 2008, and it looks great!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0689103/comments</url><from/><name>rbrb</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This film was released 40 years ago yet stands the test of time.The
music,costumes and sets are excellent, the acting lovable melodrama and the
real winner... in my view.... the lighting!Can you get an Oscar for that??The tale is of a repressed rich housewife conspiring with her doctor lover
to rid them of her invalid husband......and the spiders web which flows from
that....Great acting from all the cast---do not miss it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Ms. Turner, enjoying a career renaissance kicked off by the combination
of her Oscar-nominated role in "Peyton Place," the Stompanato murder
case and the extraordinary success of "Imitation of Life," reteamed
with producer Ross Hunter here as another well-to-do beauty suffering
great duress. She plays the wife of cantankerous Nolan (who was the
noble doctor in "Peyton Place"), a successful shipping magnate confined
to a mechanical bed. His inherent bitterness leads him to lash out at
Turner, who turns to his handsome doctor Quinn for comfort. When it
becomes clear that they can never truly be together as a couple, they
decide to relieve Nolan of his pain for good, but soon after they begin
to get letters that hint of blackmail. Before long, they are faced with
the prospect of committing a second murder in order to protect their
secret. Meanwhile, shifty Basehart is running the company and eyeing
Turner and Nolan's daughter Dee (who was Turner's daughter in
"Imitation of Life") is carrying on with low-rung tugboat owner Saxon.
Also, sneaky chauffeur Walston and vaguely threatening housekeeper Wong
lurk around every other corner. Turner looks terrific throughout most
of the film, being saddled with a couple of ugly hats here and there
(and :::gasp::: wearing one outfit twice!), but generally looking
fantastic. She was perfect at these types of glossy, over-the-top
melodramas and this is among the best. The story (riddled with
contrivance and preposterousness) reaches a fever pitch several times
and overwrought Lana is right there to help serve it up at its best.
Quinn seems a tad out of place, but it's nice to see him in a film from
this period that didn't have him playing an Indian, a slave, a
fisherman or some other type of earthy character. Basehart is
remarkably slimy, Dee a bit more mature than she had been in previous
films, yet still unable to shake off her squeaky-clean image and Saxon
gritting his teeth in outrage when he isn't trying to canoodle with
Dee. Walston gives an appropriately mysterious performance while silent
film legend Wong is mostly relegated to stern stares and curt comments.
Grey has a supporting role as Nolan's beleaguered secretary, while
fairly grating child actor Kohler plays Turner's inquisitive son. Based
on a short-running Broadway play from the 40's, but slathered over with
the customary Hunter lavishness, this slightly overlong film is a
glimmering camp hoot today. As if the overheated acting, silly script
and glitzy décor weren't enough, there is a deliriously insane Frank
Skinner score punctuating every "nuance" of the plot. At least there is
some very creative, for the time, lighting and camera-work in evidence,
giving the picture a nourish feel at times (which is quite an
accomplishment considering all the gloss in view.) Highlights of the
film include: Turner running open-armed to Quinn in his apartment,
Turner, decked out in a purposefully drab gown, watching Quinn enter
the house to kill Nolan, Turner running around the house and up and
down stairs in her snug skirt, turning off lights and panicking and,
most especially, Turner confessing that she can't drive and then being
forced to operate an unfamiliar car on the Pacific Coast Highway during
a hysterical rainstorm! Yes, it's basically her show all the way right
up to the closing frames.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The plot outline of PORTRAIT OF BLACK makes it sound like it would have
been a great '40s melodrama for someone like Barbara Stanwyck, who
might have given it the grittier touch it needs to succeed as a
suspenseful piece about blackmail and murder. But Ross Hunter has given
it a luxurious look, filling it with lavish sets and some stunning
costumes for LANA TURNER to wear as she and ANTHONY QUINN conspire to
kill her obnoxious husband LLOYD NOLAN.The cast too is full of glamorous Hollywood names--SANDRA DEE, JOHN
SAXON, RICHARD BASEHART, VIRGINIA GREY, RAY WALSTON and ANNA MAY WONG.
No expense has been spared to give the story whatever production values
Hunter could throw at it, including a score by Frank Skinner (who did
the music for Turner's MADAME X). But nothing hides the fact that it's just a routine tale of a plan to
commit the perfect murder that backfires in time for the sort of ending
Hollywood demanded for its killers, even if they were stars of Turner's
caliber.Lana did better work earlier in her career than she does here, but she
looks gorgeous and SANDRA DEE (as her step-daughter) gets to wear some
nifty outfits too. It's eye candy for Turner fans, but if it's solid
entertainment you're looking for, this is only passable. Even ANTHONY
QUINN looks a bit uncomfortable in his underwritten role.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0798804/comments</url><from>from cincinnati, ohio</from><name>verna55</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A beautiful, but faithless woman(Lana Turner) plots with her handsome, but
brooding doctor-lover(Anthony Quinn) to murder her sickly husband(Lloyd
Nolan). No, there's nothing overly fancy about this suspense melodrama, in
fact in content it's quite ordinary. But the movie is given Hollywood's
full
treatment with striking photography, splendid costuming and decor, and
good
performances by a capable cast. Trivia: this film reunited IMITATION OF
LIFE
producer Ross Hunter with that movie's stars Lana Turner and Sandra Dee.
Having played mother and daughter in that film, Turner and Dee are
stepmother and stepdaughter this time around.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2420383/comments</url><from>from Dallas, Texas</from><name>Lechuguilla</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Oh the heartache and troubles rich people suffer through. Take Sheila
Cabot (Lana Turner) for example, an attractive, middle-aged woman
married to a wealthy, but ailing, shipping tycoon, Matthew Cabot (Lloyd
Nolan). They live in a San Francisco mansion overlooking the Bay, and
have multiple servants. But Matthew is gruff, verbally abuses his wife,
and generally treats everyone like dirt. It's enough to make Sheila ...
well ... cry. Making matters infinitely worse, Sheila has a lover on
the side. And she's desperate to exchange the gruff hubby for the
lover. However will she manage?That's the setup for this melodrama-mystery combo, a story that
involves passion, suspicion, deception, and ultimately murder. The
film's easy to follow plot gets a needed boost when a card addressed to
Sheila arrives in the mail. All the card says is: "Congratulations on
the success of ..." That scene sends the plot hurling into mystery
territory. Who wrote the card, and why?The script's two main characters behave in ways that do not seem
credible, given their circumstances. And the idea that a grown woman
living in California has never learned to drive is a tad dubious.The film's overall look and feel is that of a typical 1950s melodrama.
Elegant, expensive clothes, dreamy violin background music, and
melodramatic acting conjure up visions of some sudsy 1950s film
directed by Douglas Sirk. I don't recall any scene in which Lana Turner
is not wearing an expensive dress and, in some scenes, a full-length
mink coat.Color cinematography is acceptable, if unremarkable. Casting favors
well-known actors. And they perform well enough. I was pleasantly
surprised by the performance of Sandra Dee.If you're looking for a believable story, look elsewhere. If you're
looking for a sudsy melodrama and/or mystery, "Portrait In Black" will
appeal. I could have done without the pretentious suds of these very
rich people. But the plot puzzle provided enough mystery to keep me
hooked.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is another one of my favorite camp movies, though I'm sure Ross
Hunter didn't intend that. It's an opulent, big budget soaper with Lana
Turner rich and glamorous in the lead, which guarantees us some nice
clothes anyway. Her husband is the sickly Lloyd Nolan, and his doctor
is Lana's boyfriend, played by Anthony Quinn. Quinn is just aching to
put an air bubble in that hypodermic and knock off Nolan. The next
thing you know, we're at Lloyd's funeral.Of course, as soon as she's a widow, Lana has another gentleman caller,
played by Richard Basehart, and she starts getting blackmail notes.
Someone knows that Lloyd had some help going into the great beyond.
Soon it's time for another murder...Portrait in Black has some really funny scenes and situations in it. My
favorite is when Lana's character, who never got her driver's license,
has to drive 25 miles on the Pacific Coast Highway in the rain. It's a
riot! John Saxon, Sandra Dee, Ray Walston, Anna Mae Wong, and Virginia
Gregg are along for support. Dee plays Turner's daughter, which is good
casting. If you like this kind of big-budget potboiler, don't miss
Portrait in Black.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is another one of my favorite camp movies, though I'm sure Ross
Hunter didn't intend that. It's an opulent, big budget soaper with Lana
Turner rich and glamorous in the lead, which guarantees us some nice
clothes anyway. Her husband is the sickly Lloyd Nolan, and his doctor
is Lana's boyfriend, played by Anthony Quinn. Quinn is just aching to
put an air bubble in that hypodermic and knock off Nolan. The next
thing you know, we're at Lloyd's funeral.Of course, as soon as she's a widow, Lana has another gentleman caller,
played by Richard Basehart, and she starts getting blackmail notes.
Someone knows that Lloyd had some help going into the great beyond.
Soon it's time for another murder...Portrait in Black has some really funny scenes and situations in it. My
favorite is when Lana's character, who never got her driver's license,
has to drive 25 miles on the Pacific Coast Highway in the rain. It's a
riot! John Saxon, Sandra Dee, Ray Walston, Anna Mae Wong, and Virginia
Gregg are along for support. Dee plays Turner's daughter, which is good
casting. If you like this kind of big-budget potboiler, don't miss
Portrait in Black.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>