<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La vérité</original_title><imdb_rating>7.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Henri-Georges Clouzot</director><producer>Han Productions</producer><producer>C.E.I.A.P.</producer><producer>Iéna Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Dominique Marceau is on trial for the murder of Gilbert Tellier. The counsels duel relentlessly, elaborating explanations for why the pretty...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Brigitte Bardot</actor><actor>Paul Meurisse</actor><actor>Charles Vanel</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Henri-Georges Clouzot—a director of the older generation—was known for
his uncompromising temperament, and, working together, he and Bardot
attempted to rid her of the two-dimensional image she had been saddled
with, as well as those two cumbersome initials which had come to
represent so much… Although the film was not Clouzot at his best, "La Vérité" kept its
promises in regard to Bardot the actress… Her innate talent was finally
recognized by the press in its entirety… Clouzot attempted in his film to contrast the unrelenting morality of
the French courts with the new, amoral life of youth; the truth,
Clouzot shows, becomes distorted through the legal process… Dominique
is the victim not only of her own self-indulgence but of a scheme of
values in which she has no place… Clouzot admired Bardot's acting capacity – "she has a very large
range," he said… "She can pass with ease from comedy to drama and even
to tragedy."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0917767/comments</url><from>from Belfast, N.I</from><name>Fiona-39</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a particularly interesting film in relation to Bardot's star
image.
It portrays her as a little slut (she's had sex before marriage - cue
shocked gasp from the courtroom) on trial for the murder of her lover. In
many ways, the film thus acts out what many in France would like to have
done - put BB on trial for her sexual promiscuity, her modernity, and her
'youthful' values. The film emphasises Bardot/ Dominique (the character is
effectively overshadowed by the star who plays her) as sexual, modern,
promiscious, flighty, idle, a spendthrift, all at odds with the uptight
bourgeois ruling class. The film is a fascinating glimpse into the values
that preoccupied the French bourgeoisie at the turn of the decade, with
its
emphasis on the students of the Latin Quarter as a drop out counter
culture
compared to the good youth learning traditional music at the
Conservatoire.
Not so much a generation clash, then, more one group rooted in tradition
versus another embracing modernity and new models of behaviour. The film
is
sometimes unwittingly hysterical as it has dated so much, and it does not
so
much end as fizzle out, but in its depiction of a youthful counter culture
it anticipates the events of May 1968 nearly a decade before they occur.
BB
may have lost the particular battle in this film, but she went on to win
the
war.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Here Brigitte Bardot strips bare and the precedent writer was
completely right;it's not Dominique who's judged ,but Bardot
herself.Never a character had been closer to the actress -I'm obviously
speaking of the public figure- than this victim.Because she's primarily
a victim : of a family who was dreaming of a good girl,respectful of
family values -see Marie -José Nat 's Annie ,the perfect sister ,the
"good" ,the earnest musician :she's so "straight"so
"holier-than-thou,that she's almost frightening-;of a society ,not
prepared to accept this new way of life,which predates the events of
MAY 1968 and woman's lib;and finally,and mainly ,of men:they,too, are
not prepared to accept the fact that a woman wants to live like .. a
man:Samy Frey,the well-respected and well-meaning young man is actually
a macho as well as a future mean bourgeois.The man who worked this miracle ( turning Bardot into a first -class
thespian) is none other than Henri-Georges Clouzot,one of the most
daring clever gifted directors France has ever known.It was probably a
hard time for him:he was about to become ill ,and that would prevent
him from making another movie before 1968 ("the prisoner" ,his final
achievement);besides the nouvelle vague on the rise dismissed Clouzot
as a man of of the past,one of those creeps who "did not live what he
was filming" (sic).Clouzot ,at his best, was better than 10 Chabrol ,20
Truffaut and 100 Godard ,but there's no accounting for tastes.Suffice
to say that Clouzot,during his relatively short career (20 years ,and
11 films) ,took more chances single-handedly than the three artists
mentioned above ,and his best works ("l'assassin habite au 21","le
corbeau","quai des orfèvres","Manon","les diaboliques" -which got more
praise abroad than in its native country- and "wages of fear" )are all
classics."la vérité" is a long flashback ,a giant jig-saw the pieces of which
will not completely put together at the end.The lovers of "les
diaboliques" will appreciate the duel Paul Meurisse /Charles Vanel.They
say HG Clouzot was very hard on his actors:but what filmography!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2317131/comments</url><from>from Frankfurt, Germany</from><name>Thorsten_B (thb8@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This comes as a surprise entry in Brigitte Bardots filmography. Surely
the blonde siren wasn't everybody's first chance for a female lead in a
Henri-Georges Clouzot film; then again, the role she is playing fits
perfectly. Dominique Marceau is a pretty young girl eager to leave her
parents home and live with her sister in Paris. Other than her,
Dominique is living out her lust for life, hanging around with friends,
with parties, drinking and casual affairs. By coincidence she
encounters her sisters fiancée, a very serious young musician.
Eventually they fall in love, but Dominique can't be faithful and
Gilbert (Sami Freys character) cannot adjust to her way of life. They
break up, reunite, and break up again – with Gilbert more and more
being ridiculed by her affairs with other men. On the other hand,
Dominique cannot let him go either, and when he suddenly loses all his
passion and returns to her sister, Dominique makes a decision. This is
all told in flashback sequences during the trial in which Dominique is
accused of Gilberts murder. The people participated in finding the
truth, Clouzot tells us, are incapable of leaving their personal
convictions and moral perspectives out of the court. Whatever the
verdict may be, Dominique won't leave as an innocent. - "La Verité" has
some memorable scenes, not least the one where Gilbert is conducting
Strawinskys "Oiseau de Feu" on television, which blends over to the
next scene while the music continues without a break. While being a
serious drama about passion and justice, Clouzots film still makes good
use of Bardots erotic energy – and yet there is never a moment where
the images make the story irrelevant.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0547823/comments</url><from>from Herzlya, Israel</from><name>dromasca</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
In Bernard Tavernier's film 'Laissez Passer' Henri-Georges Clouzot gets
indirectly a harsh treatment. He is one of these directors who
continued to work under the German occupation during WWII, and was
attacked for this attitude long time after. He was also a fine
director, classics like 'Quai d'Orfevres' and 'Diabolique' are among
the best works in French cinema until the emergence of the New Wave,
which displaced Clouzot.It is ironical that 'La Verite' was his last great film, and that the
New Wave exponents were so critical of him. The film contains in my
opinion in it many of the elements that were further taken over,
continued and amplified by Truffaut, Godard, et co. It is to some
extent a milestone at the border between the classic and the new French
cinema of the 60s. The subject itself speaks about the confrontation of
two generations. A young girl is brought to trial. She killed her lover
and the court needs to decide if this was an accident, or a passion
crime, or a calculated murder. The tribunal is composed of all that
represents the old generation - judges, lawyers, audience - all ready
to pass a moral judgment or maybe a lynch on the girl. She comes from a
different world, she belongs to a different generation, one that
refuses to complain to conventions, she speaks a different language,
listens to a different music, feels and loves differently. Today's
spectator cannot abstain from thinking about 1968, the year when than
generation took the streets in France and elsewhere, and changed
history. But the year is still 1960, and the verdict of the trial can
be only one.The intuition of Clouzot is ahead of time not only in what concerns the
historical judgment. It is also in the style of filming. Most of the
film is a court drama, in the American tradition of Kramer, just
translated in French. A few scenes however are filmed in the street,
part of the flashbacks that recall the story of the affair that ended
in tragedy. Well these scenes are for all practical purposed New Wave.
They do not only depict the Paris of the new generation, they are also
filmed in the style of the new generation of directors. Here Clouzot
bends graciously towards the young directors that will defame him.And of course, there is Brigitte Bardot. This is one of her best roles,
she plays the whole range of emotions she is capable of, is beautiful
and vulnerable, passionate and desperate. She attracts men, she
attracts the attention, she creates emotion. It is her against the
whole world, in a personal rebellion with no chance of success. With
this film she established herself as a serious actress, not only as a
popular star. It is her film to the same extent that it's Clouzot's and
it is one to remember.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0547823/comments</url><from>from Herzlya, Israel</from><name>dromasca</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
In Bernard Tavernier's film 'Laissez Passer' Henri-Georges Clouzot gets
indirectly a harsh treatment. He is one of these directors who
continued to work under the German occupation during WWII, and was
attacked for this attitude long time after. He was also a fine
director, classics like 'Quai d'Orfevres' and 'Diabolique' are among
the best works in French cinema until the emergence of the New Wave,
which displaced Clouzot.It is ironical that 'La Verite' was his last great film, and that the
New Wave exponents were so critical of him. The film contains in my
opinion in it many of the elements that were further taken over,
continued and amplified by Truffaut, Godard, et co. It is to some
extent a milestone at the border between the classic and the new French
cinema of the 60s. The subject itself speaks about the confrontation of
two generations. A young girl is brought to trial. She killed her lover
and the court needs to decide if this was an accident, or a passion
crime, or a calculated murder. The tribunal is composed of all that
represents the old generation - judges, lawyers, audience - all ready
to pass a moral judgment or maybe a lynch on the girl. She comes from a
different world, she belongs to a different generation, one that
refuses to complain to conventions, she speaks a different language,
listens to a different music, feels and loves differently. Today's
spectator cannot abstain from thinking about 1968, the year when than
generation took the streets in France and elsewhere, and changed
history. But the year is still 1960, and the verdict of the trial can
be only one.The intuition of Clouzot is ahead of time not only in what concerns the
historical judgment. It is also in the style of filming. Most of the
film is a court drama, in the American tradition of Kramer, just
translated in French. A few scenes however are filmed in the street,
part of the flashbacks that recall the story of the affair that ended
in tragedy. Well these scenes are for all practical purposed New Wave.
They do not only depict the Paris of the new generation, they are also
filmed in the style of the new generation of directors. Here Clouzot
bends graciously towards the young directors that will defame him.And of course, there is Brigitte Bardot. This is one of her best roles,
she plays the whole range of emotions she is capable of, is beautiful
and vulnerable, passionate and desperate. She attracts men, she
attracts the attention, she creates emotion. It is her against the
whole world, in a personal rebellion with no chance of success. With
this film she established herself as a serious actress, not only as a
popular star. It is her film to the same extent that it's Clouzot's and
it is one to remember.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>