<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Atomic Submarine</original_title><imdb_rating>4.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Spencer Gordon Bennet</director><producer>Gorham Productions</producer><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
Ships mysteriously disappear on route across the Arctic Sea, and a specially-equipped submarine is sent to investigate.
</synopsis><actor>Arthur Franz</actor><actor>Dick Foran</actor><actor>Brett Halsey</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1363171/comments</url><from>from nashville, tn</from><name>henri sauvage</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Something about this movie makes me believe it was inspired by some
article in an old Popular Science magazine about giant atomic-powered
cargo subs of the near future plying the short route to the Pacific
under the polar ice cap. (I must have missed that development while I
was commuting by hovercar to my all-plastic cabin in the mountains,
where a home breeder reactor supplies me with power too cheap to
meter.) The actors are (mostly) competent, with B-movie stalwart Arthur Franz
in the lead. The script is serviceable, containing some creepy moments
as well as an occasionally interesting clash of ideologies between
military tough guy Franz and the peacenik scientist son (Brett Halsey)
of his revered mentor. Though they despise each other at first, they
find they can agree on the need to kick some alien booty.The sfx team of Jack Rabin, Irving Block and Louis DeWitt collaborated
on quite a few low-budget sci-fi's in the 50's -- the most notable
example being "Kronos", with its bizarre, energy-sucking giant cubist
robot -- and manage to achieve a few interesting effects in this one,
too.The most unusual thing about this film is that I believe it's the first
sci-fi movie to use the concept of a "living" spaceship. And I'm
willing to bet money that the film's slime-dripping, tentacled alien
Cyclops is the direct inspiration for The Simpsons' Kang and Kodos.
Even the voice is similar.If you're willing to forgive its obvious limitations, "Atomic
Submarine" is an entertaining little low-budget romp.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0304471/comments</url><from>from Columbus, Georgia</from><name>teuthis (Teuthis@knology.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

"Atomic Submarine" has two things to recommend it to viewers. It is
adventure, with all sorts of dangerous situations, and a desperate battle
against an undersea alien. And, it is unintentionally funny. Not hilarious
mind you; but certainly funny enough for a few laughs as you enjoy its
clumsy attempts at plot, acting and logic. Still, I like it, and I always
watch it if it comes on cable. Its the adventure I guess. I get caught up in
the idea of the powerful submarine; the crew at odds with each other; the
"science-on-the-fly" they use to fight the monster. Its fun overall. I would
venture to say that it is one of the classics of the 50's-60's low budget
sci fi era.  This film is also notable for a brief appearance by Joi Lansing; the last,
and prettiest, of the Hollywood "blonde bombshells". It's certainly worth
watching if you're a guy, and a sci-fi fan.  With a little imagination,
"Atomic Submarine" is entertaining escapism. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The Atomic Submarine is atmospheric and creepy, especially when out in the
frozen wastes of the North Pole.A lot of stock footage didn't spoil my enjoyment, although we see
different
submarines.  Good performances from 50s B movie regulars like Arthur Franz
and Tom Conway keep the movie going.  The monster in the flying saucer has
to be seen to be believed.  Great stuff, considering the low
budget.Rating: 4 stars out of 5. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0043975/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ronnie</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Yet another interesting, small-budget, black-and-white thriller gem from
the
1950s. These pictures are being continually (and successfully) released to
DVD, much more than the genre films from the 1960s through 1990s. Why? In
these post Atomic, Cold War years, imagination ran rampant with so many
new
ideas that were fresh and innovative. They're charming in their antiquated
way. Using inexpensive special effects, with a generally serviceable,
attractive cast working with scripts that moved the action along, these
sci-fi drama infused sex (tame for the time) and violence with effective
results. "Atomic Submarine" tells the story of an alien spacecraft
destroying subs in the Arctic. When Arthur Franz finally meets the
creature,
a giant cyclopean octopus-style thing, it states (via telepathic
communication) "We finally meet face to face. Franz replies: "That's a
face?" Later Franz relates to extraordinarily handsome hunk Brett Halsey,
that he left his little black book on the alien spacecraft, which included
the number of buxom blonde (Joi Lansing) that he had a rendezvous with
earlier. Most enjoyable.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1908551/comments</url><from>from Newfoundland, Canada</from><name>Space_Mafune</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Which so many familiar Sci-Fi/Horror Genre faces in the cast and with a
really cool monster at the end, I feel this 1959 film is loads of fun to
watch. I recommend it mainly to those fans of 1950s/60s style Sci-Fi and
submarine adventure tales(such as IT CAME FROM BENEATH THE SEA, SUBMARINE
SEAHAWK, VOYAGE TO THE BOTTOM OF THE SEA, etc.).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0976573/comments</url><from>from Milwaukee, Wisconsin</from><name>davidemartin (davidemartin@cs.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

What a difference the three years separating ATOMIC SUBMARINE and
VOYAGE TO THE BOTTOM OF THE SEA made! Of course, Allen's much larger
budget sure helped too. Still, one can see The Tigershark as being the
direct parent of The Seaview.We have an advanced nuclear sub capable of firing missiles or torpedoes
and equipped with a secondary submarine. The Seaview originally carried
a small fleet of 2-man submersibles but they got eclipsed by the
flashier Flying Sub. And of course you have the senior officer, the
younger guy who actually handles the action scenes, and a couple
onboard scientists just for the heck of it. The plot itself is pretty much the model for many of the Voyages to the
Bottom of the Sea. The hidden mystery at the heart of an otherwise
normal mission, the unexpected monster.... Yeah, this could have been a
VOYAGE episode. And in fact, eventually IT WAS! VOYAGE did an episode
that adapted ATOMIC SUBMARINE pretty much straight, just changing the
sub, the crew names, and a few details (and ditching Joi Lansing's
character, alas!). While ATOMIC SUBMARINE does look frightfully low budget compared to
VOYAGE, let alone today's super-bloated budget busters, it works pretty
well for a product of its time. And the minimalist, barely illuminated
alien saucer interior is surprising effect. I know it creeped me out
when I first saw this late one night in '66!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7888206/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bobtheplanet</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
8 out of 10 for effort in the category of lo-budget Sci-Fi Tomfoolery.What can I say… old "B" grade sci-fi films from the 50's and 60's are
really fun to watch. This one is favorite of mine; I'll watch it over
and over again. Somehow these movies re-ignite childhood memories of
Saturday afternoons at the show or late night TV popcorn fests. Sure
they're stinkers, but the odor they emit is as evocative as an exotic
fragrance that stimulates half-forgotten memories. Lots of stock footage; voice-over narration; maps with squiggly chase
routes; a solid cast of character actors; cheap, but eerie and
imaginative effects… all earmarks of the trashy Drive-in and Matinée
fare. Remember "Double Features" or "Triple Features"? Movies like
"Atomic Submarine" were the Chinese takeout menu of the 50's cinema
scene – quick and filling, but not much else!If you like ATOMIC SUBMARINE, you'll also like KRONOS; IT, THE TERROR
FROM BEYOND SPACE; TARGET EARTH; THE CRAWLING EYE; FIEND WITHOUT A
FACE; I MARRIED A MONSTER FROM OUTER SPACE; THE BRAIN EATERS; THE CURSE
OF THE FLY along with many others too numerous to mention. All flawed
by their cheapness, but remembered for a few minutes of imaginative
storytelling.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0698446/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>Wilbur-10</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
'B' grade Sci-Fi which attains, for the first half at least, the
heights of a reasonable thriller, as a submarine is dispatched to the
arctic circle to investigate the cause of shipping accidents and
disappearances. While the effects are never up to much, the plot and script are more
than adequate. The climax of the film is a glorious return to B-movie
hokum as an underwater flying saucer is discovered to be the cause of
the problems. The scientists reason that the saucer returns to the pole
for magnetic energy and they decide to lie in wait in the sub to ram it
!! In doing this however, the sub becomes stuck in the saucer and some
crew members are dispatched to go inside the saucer and dislodge it.There is the usual character tension between the young inexperienced
scientist on the mission, and the older, wiser navy man, who just
happens to be friends with the younger man's father etc. etc. The
inside of the spaceship is a lesson in minimalism - simply illuminated
gangways in a sea of darkness. These scenes lead to the creature in the
saucer which is an octopus-type figure, with one huge eye on a stalk.
The creature speaks ( in Queens English ) through thought and turns out
to be looking for suitable planets as homes for its advanced race of
bug-eyed-hairy-octopi.Saucer is blasted by a ballistic missile, contradicting the 1950's
sci-fi theme of warning against the nuclear arms race. A difficult film
to dislike, but a few leagues below 'It Came from Beneath the Sea'.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2575838/comments</url><from>from sparks     nv</from><name>march9hare</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A series of unexplained maritime disasters (no, not necessarily this film)
prompts the US Government to dispatch its latest and greatest atomic sub
to
investigate and, if possible, neutralize whatever it finds - in this case,
a
malevolent monocular alien and his (it's?)
living UFO.  The cast consists of the usual characters: a
hard-nosed,
two-fisted manly man Executive Officer (played by Arthur Franz),
the
level-headed Captain (played by the barely seen Dick Foran), and the
vaguely
condescending scientist Sir Ian Hunt (played by the
for-once-in-his-life-sober
Tom Conway).  Rounding out the crew are: the crusty CPO, a couple of UDT
frogmen (you just KNOW they're gonna get snuffed),
a wonderfully discombobulated Sid Melton (a part he plays SO well),
a
snivelling antiwar oceanographer, and the jaw-droppingly gorgeous
girlfriend/flavor-of-the-week (played with impeccable style and subtlety
by
Joi Lansing, last of the Hollywood Blonde Bombshells.
Awright: so who cares if she can't act?).  Plotwise, the movie is very
similar to "Voyage to the Bottom of the Sea", except it's shot in
glorious black and white, with cheap sets, not-so-special
effects,
hambone acting, and models that, while very imaginative, look like models.
Some of the dialogue is pretty shaky too, especially the exchange between
Franz and the colossal, one-eyed alien.  Still, this movie has a certain
quaint quality about it, and remains one of our favorites.  It's one of
those "At least it's better than. . ." films.
Better than what?  Well, "Santa Claus Conquers The Martians", for
one;
"Murdercycle", for another.  Bottom line: it's a good rainy Saturday
popcorn
movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
**SPOLIERS** After some half dozen US Navy subs have been destroyed in
the Arctic Ocean within 200-from 87 to 90 degrees North latitude-miles
of the North Pole it's decided by the US Military to send it's most
advanced atomic submarine The "Tiger Shark" there to see what's causing
all this destruction.With Camdr. Reef Holloway, Arthur Franz, and his second in command
Capt. Dan Wendover, Dick Foran, put in charge of the nuclear sub "Tiger
Shark" in a top secret mission to the North Pole things get a bit
sticky when Dr.Carl Neilson joins the sub's crew. Despite his youth,
he's in his late 20's, Dr. Neilson is one of the top oceanographers in
the world. Dr. Neilson is also an unashamed peace-nick who had his old man, Reef's
mentor the top naval war tactician in Annapolis,and the person whom
Reef worshiped the very ground he walks on,end up hospitalized with a
career ending nervous breakdown! That resulted in Dr. Neilson
insinuating to the press that his father is a warmonger in his
obsession with the use of nuclear submarines- and their payload of
Polaris nuclear missiles-in the defense of freedom.This tension between Reef and Dr. Neilson goes on unabatedly during the
entire trip to the North Pole until it's realized that what's been
sinking US military vessels up there is a hostile 300 foot in diameter
flying saucer!This UFO identified as the Cyclops, because of its flashing blue light,
is using the magnetic pull of the earth, centered at the poles, to
regenerate itself with magnetic energy. At the same time the UFO in
order to keep it's existence secret zaps any ship or underwater sub
that's unfortunate enough to get in its way! It's also later found out straight from the UFO's pilot's-a hairy one
eyed alien- mouth, or subconscious, that it's planing to have it's
fellow one eyed monsters colonize the world and enslave the earth's
human population!It takes a while, with a number of the "Tiger Sharks" crew members
getting killed, to figure out how to handle this alien, or aliens, from
space. But later with the help of the now, he finally saw the light,
kill em first and don't ask questions later ex-pacifist Dr. Neilson the
human race in the end prevailed. The problem now, after destroying the Cyclops, is just how many more of
these one eyed monsters are still out there in space watching and
monitoring us! And also will we have the both strength and fortitude,
as well as the military hardware, to combat and defeat them in the not
so far off distance future?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
**SPOLIERS** After some half dozen US Navy subs have been destroyed in
the Arctic Ocean within 200-from 87 to 90 degrees North latitude-miles
of the North Pole it's decided by the US Military to send it's most
advanced atomic submarine The "Tiger Shark" there to see what's causing
all this destruction.With Camdr. Reef Holloway, Arthur Franz, and his second in command
Capt. Dan Wendover, Dick Foran, put in charge of the nuclear sub "Tiger
Shark" in a top secret mission to the North Pole things get a bit
sticky when Dr.Carl Neilson joins the sub's crew. Despite his youth,
he's in his late 20's, Dr. Neilson is one of the top oceanographers in
the world. Dr. Neilson is also an unashamed peace-nick who had his old man, Reef's
mentor the top naval war tactician in Annapolis,and the person whom
Reef worshiped the very ground he walks on,end up hospitalized with a
career ending nervous breakdown! That resulted in Dr. Neilson
insinuating to the press that his father is a warmonger in his
obsession with the use of nuclear submarines- and their payload of
Polaris nuclear missiles-in the defense of freedom.This tension between Reef and Dr. Neilson goes on unabatedly during the
entire trip to the North Pole until it's realized that what's been
sinking US military vessels up there is a hostile 300 foot in diameter
flying saucer!This UFO identified as the Cyclops, because of its flashing blue light,
is using the magnetic pull of the earth, centered at the poles, to
regenerate itself with magnetic energy. At the same time the UFO in
order to keep it's existence secret zaps any ship or underwater sub
that's unfortunate enough to get in its way! It's also later found out straight from the UFO's pilot's-a hairy one
eyed alien- mouth, or subconscious, that it's planing to have it's
fellow one eyed monsters colonize the world and enslave the earth's
human population!It takes a while, with a number of the "Tiger Sharks" crew members
getting killed, to figure out how to handle this alien, or aliens, from
space. But later with the help of the now, he finally saw the light,
kill em first and don't ask questions later ex-pacifist Dr. Neilson the
human race in the end prevailed. The problem now, after destroying the Cyclops, is just how many more of
these one eyed monsters are still out there in space watching and
monitoring us! And also will we have the both strength and fortitude,
as well as the military hardware, to combat and defeat them in the not
so far off distance future?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>