<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Alamo</original_title><alt_title>Alamo</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>John Wayne</director><producer>Alamo Company, The</producer><producer>Batjac Productions</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In 1836 General Santa Anna and the Mexican army is sweeping across Texas. To be able to stop him, General Sam Houston needs time to get his main force into shape...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>John Wayne</actor><actor>Richard Widmark</actor><actor>Laurence Harvey</actor><rt_rating>5.4/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>54</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
John Wayne's directorial tribute to the struggle for "The Alamo"
symbolized the spirit of resistance of a small group of determined
fighters for Texan independence from Mexico...Texans established a provisional government in 1835 and appointed Sam
Houston (Richard Boone) commander in chief of their army... There
followed a seesaw battle for control of San Antonio, including the
ill-advised defense of the Alamo by a force of fewer than 200 Texas
volunteers... General Antonio Lopez De Santa Anna was determined to
take this key location in order to impress upon the Texans the futility
of further resistance to Mexican ruler...After a 13-day siege, every fighting man perished under the onslaught
of 7,000 Mexican troops... Among the fallen defenders were Cols.
William B. Travis, James Bowie and the legendary Davy Crockett... Only
Mrs. Dickinson (Joan O'Brien), her little daughter and a black boy
survive to provide the eyewitness story of the Siege and the Battle of
the Alamo...John Wayne portrays Davy Crockett, a frontiersman and politician, who
saw the future of an independent Texas as his future and he loved a
good fight... Crockett and his brave combatants - the Tennesseans,
expert marksmen, held their position until death... Richard Widmark is cast as Colonel Jim Bowie, a reckless adventurer,
known for his famous 'Bowie knife'. Bowie has come to fight for Texas
independence with a small force of volunteers. He had strong personal
friction with Travis which threatens to develop into a private war...
The difference in their personalities resulted in the two men sharing a
somewhat antagonistic competition for command of the entire garrison...
On one point they did agree: "The Alamo" is the most important
stronghold of Texas... Laurence Harvey plays Colonel Travis, "the grand Canyon of Texas," who
arrives with 25 men to establish the first line of defense against
Santa Anna... Travis is a disciplinarian officer who commanded the
Texas defenders during the siege and battle of the Alamo, a genuine
hero who anticipated a battle to the death, a polite gentleman who gave
the men an opportunity to retreat with honor the ill-fated garrison but
explained how important their defense of the Alamo is... His appeal
from the Alamo of reinforcements becomes an American symbol of
unyielding courage, heroism and self-sacrifice... Travis high moment in
the film was when he fired his answer to Santa Anna with a cannon
blast: Victory or Death!With its seven Oscar nominations, including the Oscar-nominated hit
song "The Green Leaves of Summer" and a superb score written by Dmitri
Tiomkin and song-writer Paul Webster, and featuring some of the most
spectacular battle sequences ever seen, "The Alamo," - a sacrifice on
the altar of liberty - becomes the 'Battle Cry' that broke Santa Anna's
back...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0018365/comments</url><from>from Savannah, GA</from><name>Bob-45</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Corny? At times long-winded and stilted? Touching, poignant and
inspiring? John Wayne's "The Alamo" is all of these things; and, of
this, I'm certain John Wayne would agree. For, unlike the lessor men
who make up most of Wayne's critics, Wayne was fair. This is clear even
in "The Alamo," in his depiction of Santana's army. Wayne believed in
the basic nobility of men, much like those heroes depicted in "Rio
Bravo". That his life and memory is treated more like that of Marshal
Sam Kane's in the Wayne-despised "High Noon," or even in Wayne's own
"The Shootist" is testimony that Wayne HOPED men were better than they
are.I'd never seen the full-length version of "The Alamo" until it was
released on VHS in the early 90s. I realized then the greatest scene in
the movie is "The Birthday Party," which was cut from the general
release version of the film. NOTE: For those that don't remember,
during the 50s and 60s, Hollywood would release long, big budget movies
as reserved seat attractions. The film would show at a "roadshow"
theater for several months before general release. Since "roadshow"
theaters showed the movies only twice a day, running time was
restricted pretty much to the patience of audiences. However, when the
same film was shown general release, time restrictions became
important, so films were cut to maximize theater owner profits. It
still happens today, except now the "director's cut" reaches the home
audience via DVD. In any event, the short version of "The Alamo," while
impressive, is still a pale shadow of the Wayne's original cut. Most
importantly, to see "The Alamo" is to understand John Wayne as a man,
not an idol or actor. Wayne generously gave virtually all the big
scenes to his costars. Certainly, Lawrence Harvey, Richard Widmark, Ken
Curtis, Joan O'Brian and Richard Boone get better scenes. Also
certainly, Chill Wills, Jester Hairston (Jethro) Hank Worden (Parson)
and Veda Ann Borg (Blind Nell Robertson) have showier ones than Wayne.
The scenes between Wayne and Linda Crystal in the first hour seem out
of a different movie, though neither Wayne's nor Cristals are as big or
showy as the ones I've mentioned. One thing I hope to suffer again was
the "reunion" video attached to the VHS. The same old garbage about
Wayne not being able to direct actors (by his SON, no less), that he
really wasn't a very good director (Wayne's action scenes will match or
beat anybody's in Hollywood). Especially rude was Richard Widmark's
idea of impressing Wayne by insisting Wayne call him "Richard" and not
"Dick" during their first meeting. Widmark came across as a pompous
ass. However, the rudest cut was from Ken "Festis" Curtis. Curtis never
had a better, more respectful part in ANY movie, but he didn't miss an
opportunity to try to soil Wayne's memory.Forget that "The Alamo" is a topnotch, if not entirely historically
accurate historical western. Forget that Wayne directs action better
than his mentor, John Ford, or that Chill Wills got an Oscar
nomination, the only of his career, thanks to this "lousy
director/actor". Remember this, Wayne risked EVERYTHING on "The Alamo"
and lost. He was broke for years afterward. Wayne's continued success
on the "A" list was by no means assured. He was 54 years old and
raising a second family. Wayne had recently been swindled by a business
manager and recently lost a best friend to suicide (Grant Withers).
Wayne had to take a role in "The Alamo" to secure financing, and "The
Alamo" is probably STILL the biggest movie ever directed by one of its
stars. During filming, Wayne had to contend with interference from
mentor John Ford and a murder investigation of one of his actresses.
That same year Wayne's house was severely damaged by fire. Yet Wayne
took continued carping by lessor men, those "artists" in Hollywood who
ridiculed his acting and his directing. I'm sure they sneered in
satisfaction when "The Alamo" failed to break even. However, it's
reported the movie eventually made a small profit, probably part of it
through sale of "Alamo Village" in Bracketville, Texas.Wayne continued to make fine movies for sixteen more years after "The
Alamo." In 1969 he was finally awarded by his peers an Oscar for
"Rooster Cogburn." However, by then, Wayne had P.O.d them again with
"The Green Berets". War service or not, NOBODY can say the man ever ran
from a fight. I'm not sure I would have liked John Wayne had I known him. I'm not a
drinker and I'm not obsessively patriotic about this country,
particularly since we started picking fights in the Middle East.
However, as Wayne proved with Lawrence Harvey and Rock Hudson, Wayne
didn't have to agree with someone's lifestyle or even their personal
views to treat them with respect. I most certainly would respect him
better than the "friends" he gave jobs in "The Alamo;" at least, those
who slandered him.Oh, and by the way, "RICHARD Widmark never won an Oscar."I give "The Alamo" a solid 8.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3242428/comments</url><from>from West Sacramento, California</from><name>jckalar</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

John Wayne did an outstanding job on this film.  It was overlooked at the
Academy Awards and unjustifiably so.  It was beautiful, costumes were
outstanding and very true to type.  The actors were wonderful and I
believe
should have been more acknowledged for the great job they did in
protraying
those truly brave men at the Alamo!  I have this on DVD and watch it
probably at least twice a year.  The music, just to listen to the music,
is
an experience; beautiful and haunting.  The horses were beautiful, the
scenery was beautiful.  Everything about this movie was beautiful.  John
Wayne, an American institution, a lover of this country and a true patriot
deserved an academy award for directing this great film.  I cant say
enough
great things about it.  One of  my favorites of all
time!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0649119/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas, Nevada</from><name>Ben Burgraff (cariart)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Viewed as history, John Wayne's epic production of 'The Alamo' is as
full of holes as Swiss Cheese (the final battle actually lasted less
than an hour, in the pre-dawn darkness of March 6, 1836; current
scholarly consensus is that the historical Crockett attempted to
surrender, at the end of the furious onslaught, but was executed), but
just as Wayne mentor John Ford never let 'the facts' interfere with a
good story, first-time director Wayne wanted to tell a tale of
larger-than-life heroes, taking a stand for what was right, and being
willing to die for that cause. It was a firm belief in these truths
that pushed Wayne into investing over ten years of his life, and much
of his personal fortune, in telling this story, and 'The Alamo' was,
and is, a triumph.The film can really be broken into two distinct parts; the first part
introduces the characters, providing insights into their personalities,
and tells a melodramatic tale of a beautiful woman (the radiant Linda
Cristal), being forced into an unwilling relationship with an evil,
profiteering Texan, who is rescued by the plain-spoken and heroic Davy
Crockett, as portrayed by Wayne. The story bears similarities to 'The
Fighting Kentuckian', a Wayne vehicle of twelve years earlier. In this
version, however, Wayne doesn't 'win' the girl, but gives her a rather
preachy speech about patriotism, and doing what's right, and sends her
on her way.Despite a terrific fight scene between a bunch of the Texan's henchmen,
and Crockett and Jim Bowie (portrayed with easy charm by Richard
Widmark), this first part drags, a bit, and seems contrived to allow
Wayne to air his political beliefs. Bear with it, though, because when
the action moves to the mission/fortress of the Alamo, for the second
half of the film, Wayne's talents as a director truly shine.The story of the 13-day siege between the Alamo's 187 defenders, and
General Santa Anna's 6,000-man army, has NEVER been told on a grander
scale than in the John Wayne version, and the uncut edition of the film
is presented in a wide-screen format, which allows the viewer to really
share Wayne's vision. With a nod to the fact that the Mexico of today
is a staunch ally (several characters make a point of saying how
'proud' they are of the Mexicans, even as the two forces are killing
each other!), the story flows between exciting 'victories' (stealing
the cattle, spiking the Mexican cannons), and an understanding of the
inevitable conclusion (defined by Lawrence Harvey, as Travis, in the
memorable 'sword in the sand' scene). Harvey's Travis is the
best-realized of the film's many characters; he brings a humanity to
the complex, driven commander, growing from someone insensitive to
others, into a leader who earns everyone's respect.Wayne used thousands of Mexicans as extras in the film, which gives the
viewer a far greater sense of the magnitude of the siege than
Republic's 'The Last Command' or Disney's 'Davy Crockett' ever could.
The battles, particularly the final one, as row after row of Mexican
foot-soldiers overrun the pockets of defenders, are unforgettable! Each
character is allowed to die heroically, and is given a lingering moment
to make a final gesture (Travis breaks his sword over his knee as
Mexicans surge past, Bowie fires his unique gun, a brace of pistols,
and swings his famous knife, Crockett, bayoneted to a door, still
manages to pull free, and torch the magazine). The film's climax,
alone, would make the film a 'must' for any action fan.The cast includes many well-known character actors and long-time Wayne
friends, including Ken Curtis as Lt. Dickinson, Travis's adjutant;
Chill Wills as the most outspoken of Crockett's men; Guinn 'Big Boy'
Williams, Denver Pyle, Chuck Roberson, and many others, as defenders.
Wayne's son, Patrick, has a small but visible role as James Butler
Bonham, the famous Alamo dispatch rider, and his daughter Aissa plays
the Dickinson's child, Angelina.'The Alamo', for all it's faults, is a magnificent spectacle,
monumental in scope. It is a fitting tribute to it's star/director, and
an ESSENTIAL part of any John Wayne collection!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This grand, over blown piece of Hollywood historical fable making is
one the old Hollywood's last gasps. Its an old Hollywood star vehicle
done at the start of the modern film era. Its far from realistic, but
its a hell of a fun ride. In its full form its a grand epic that may
not be one of the greatest films ever made but certainly in the second
ring.When the film was originally released this ran well over three hours.
MGM wasn't thrilled, and hacked 40 minutes out of it for general
release, despite numerous Oscar noms. Much of the subtler shades to the
story went leaving a huge bloated and wrong headed tale of heroism at
the Alamo.I can't really recommend the shorter version because its not
very good. This is the version that was the only one you could see for
years and its colored many peoples feelings towards the film which is a
shame since its not a fair depiction of the events at the Alamo or the
intentions of John Wayne.The footage was thought lost until a print was discovered about ten or
fifteen years ago and released to video and laserdisc. To see the full
version is to have a night and day experience. Here in the full version
we have real characters and not cartoons. The events suddenly have a
weight missing from the shorter version. This is the version that
should be seen, however the current DVD release of the Alamo by MGM is,
the short release version of the film. That's a shame since since the
missing minutes are the difference between a 9 out of 10 and a 6 out of
10. If you can manage to see the full, uncut version do so, its worth the
investment of time and popcorn.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0793827/comments</url><from>from Northridge, Ca</from><name> (patrick.hunter@csun.edu)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I love this movie as much as anyone, but the recently released DVD is
inexplicably almost half an hour shorter than the version of this film that
has been in release on video and laserdisc for years.  Why, oh why MGM/UA
did this, I don't know, but I know I am not keeping my copy of it.  I got
worried when this new version didn't have an overture...but I can live
without that.  However, when Richard Widmark's first scene occurred and over
half of it was missing, I could only groan.  Shame on you MGM/UA.  This movie is more than a classic for a good many  of
us.  You should release the cut that you have been putting out for years
now, the one that is 3 hours, 10 mins.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7543312/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>farleyconsulting</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I have read many of the comments about this movie and have researched
the actual event as extensively as I can. I find it difficult to
understand how people could deem this movie categorically inaccurate in
any way. It is indisputable that no one really knows the exact way the
main characters died although Bowie in the infirmary with a bad leg is,
perhaps, the only clear inaccuracy. Susannah Dickinson (one of the 3
survivors) testified that she saw Crockett's body in the compound
within 20 minutes of the end of the battle with his "peculiar hat" next
to him. This makes it unlikely that he was lined up and executed. It is
also indisputable that these men could have run, but chose to stay,
clearly understanding their probable fate. Reading Travis' letter to
Houston just days before the final battle can leave no doubt of the
heroism of these men. Is it not, therefore, infinitely more believable
that perhaps Crockett did discuss the meaning of the word "Republic"
with Travis (possibly the most emotional scene in the movie)? John
Wayne researched the actual event and location meticulously. The actual
original plans of the mission were used to ensure the Alamo Village was
correct. Costumes were identical to those depicted in every book of
Mexican military history I have seen.I have seen "The Apartment"-winner of the 1960 best picture academy
award. Its clear that Groucho Marx and the rest of the voters made a
decision to scoff at Wayne in particular and patriotic historical epics
in general. For, in my opinion, "The Apartement" is inferior. The Alamo
should have won 5 Oscars (best score; best song "Green Leaves of
Summer"; best supporting actor-Chill Wills; best movie and best
sound).I also think Laurence Harvey should have been nominated for best
actor.I do agree with all of those that lament the deletion of certain scenes
from the DVD version. How could MGM leave out the scene of the 32
Tejanos arrival at the Alamo. It is central to the movie and the actual
historical event. The death of the Parson should also have been
included.It will always be one of my favorites.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7628463/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>patrickshaffer</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Majestic and poignant, a glorious and mighty epic that will last down
through the ages. Mr. Wayne never intended to make a documentary, but
rather as he said in many interviews at the time, that he considered it
one of the greatest stories of heroic American "folklore". Of course it
is based on one of the valiant battles ever fought on this planet, but
of course all that remains of that horrible slaughter, are letters,
accounts of survivors from both armies ( and yes, diaries that are very
likely accurate, if not totally honest, by participants). The point is
- anyone that makes a movie, book, article based on history - had
better have videotape or audio, to prove their accounts, or they will
be torn to shreds by the nitpickers, that weren't there but love to
complain, and not create. John Wayne wanted to preserve a moment of
human dignity and ferocious battle action, between 2 forces that were
destined to crash in this massacre. 1 side, the Alamo defenders, were
the vanguard of democracy that was spreading across the West, first
with mountain men and trappers, then the fighting pioneers that were
determined to continue to the Pacific, in the spirit of Daniel Boone
and Lewis and Clark. And the Mexican Army was defending it's land
against what it came to think, were pirates and invaders. Santa Anna
was a monstrous leader who lost so much that the young Mexican
Republic, barely had a chance to start, after getting the Spanish out
after hundreds of years. John Wayne bet everything on his values,
American values - instilled in him on the prairies of Iowa, where he
still heard cavalrymen and Union Army veterans, tell of a country they
helped build, and passed it on to young Marion Morrison, before his
family migrated to California, and his destiny to become one of the
great symbols of America. By getting into the movie business, and
studying at the elbow of the great rugged directors of the early years
- Walsh, Wellman, Hathaway, Hawks and the great poet of the Western
movie - John Ford. Who passed onto Duke the great motto - When the
legend becomes fact, film the legend. Which Wayne did in a gigantic
fashion, with "The Alamo". By hiring the very best composer of huge
western themes, mixed with stirring and heartfelt emotion -- Dimitri
Tiomkin, he assured audiences of rousing background to his great
cameraman, Bill Clothier's fabulous and stunning cinematography -- like
dropping back into history at such a pivotal moment. And if John
Wayne's effort was not flawless, step up and invest millions into your
own version of that timeless story. To say he had a ton of courage, is
an understatement, for those who can appreciate greatness, now luckily
available to us in DVD and tape forms, to pass on to our ancestors, the
work of a man dedicated, come hell or high water, to preserve his big,
bold monumental vision, for all generations to come. And for Americans,
and all freedom loving peoples - to respect and forever "REMEMBER THE
ALAMO".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1899800/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Swampthing316</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I have seen both the long Director's Cut and the short theatrical release.The Short version is the DVD release, which was ok, the film goes much
faster but it leaves many holes in the plot.The Long Version helps to fill in the plot holes, watch this version if
you
really like long films and are into history quite heavely, otherwise stick
with the short version if you just want entertainment value, plus it still
manages to keep your attention.This film is truly a masterpiece that will be enjoyed for Generations to
come.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1058916/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>DB (alembic)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I'll come clean.. I really liked this movie....
O.K there will be those who decry it for historical accuracy and some of the
liberties taken with the depiction of some of the characters etc...... but
at the end of the day this movie is entertainment and I have sure seen
movies a lot worse than this.
Likely if all the events and persons were accurately presented , the result
might well have been a boring lecture/travelogue.
Instead there is the "Duke" John Wayne in true John Wayne style and his able
cast giving us a rousing movie and with loosely enough facts to make it
believable.
Imagine the reaction of moviegoers of the day, if John Wayne was not the
larger than life John Wayne in turn playing the even more larger than life
Davy Crockett ! 
Movie-goers of the time who expected to see the style of John Wayne got
exactly that.
Likely in America where "remember the Alamo" is of much importance, any
movie-maker
would have his work cut out to please everyone - Wayne's effort should be
judged on the
attitudes of the time and his personal battle to get the movie made at
all.As purely entertainment in the western/action style this movie stacks
up.
There are those who mention the "slow" segments ... what do you want 167
minutes of
cannon fodder and gore ?
True the movie portrays events from the American viewpoint, yet Wayne does
pay homage
to the gallantry of the Mexican forces.The musical score is also very memorable with a haunting main
theme.Big mythical heroes, big scenes, and big fun .. enjoy .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1058916/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>DB (alembic)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I'll come clean.. I really liked this movie....
O.K there will be those who decry it for historical accuracy and some of the
liberties taken with the depiction of some of the characters etc...... but
at the end of the day this movie is entertainment and I have sure seen
movies a lot worse than this.
Likely if all the events and persons were accurately presented , the result
might well have been a boring lecture/travelogue.
Instead there is the "Duke" John Wayne in true John Wayne style and his able
cast giving us a rousing movie and with loosely enough facts to make it
believable.
Imagine the reaction of moviegoers of the day, if John Wayne was not the
larger than life John Wayne in turn playing the even more larger than life
Davy Crockett ! 
Movie-goers of the time who expected to see the style of John Wayne got
exactly that.
Likely in America where "remember the Alamo" is of much importance, any
movie-maker
would have his work cut out to please everyone - Wayne's effort should be
judged on the
attitudes of the time and his personal battle to get the movie made at
all.As purely entertainment in the western/action style this movie stacks
up.
There are those who mention the "slow" segments ... what do you want 167
minutes of
cannon fodder and gore ?
True the movie portrays events from the American viewpoint, yet Wayne does
pay homage
to the gallantry of the Mexican forces.The musical score is also very memorable with a haunting main
theme.Big mythical heroes, big scenes, and big fun .. enjoy .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1058916/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>DB (alembic)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/alamo-the-1960-1/ /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1601416</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Despite a banal and preachy script, full of speeches about religion and patriotism,the film has some good action sequences; overall, it's not worse than the 2004 remake starring Billy Bob Thornton.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/alamo1960.htm /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1442331</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Patriotic but inaccurate epic Western.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1332445</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Duke does Alamo redux. Heroic, overblown, speechy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/alamo60.shtml /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1273941</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>John Wayne doesn't appear for the first twenty minutes of The Alamo, his 1960 directorial debut, and that's a bad sign.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-a-nesbit/</url><url>http://oldschoolreviews.com/rev_60/alamo.htm /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1268268</url><name>John A. Nesbit</name><from>Old School Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
D+
					</rating><comment>Could Wayne have crafted a better film if he only tried his hand at directing, instead of putting on the hero's mantle as well? Doubtful.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1713388</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/s-james-wegg/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1470315</url><name>S. James Wegg</name><from>JWR</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/thomas-delapa/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1337371</url><name>Thomas Delapa</name><from>Boulder Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/The-Alamo-(1960) /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1273799</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1242027</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=833614</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/brian-j-arthurs/</url><url>/m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=798892</url><name>Brian J. Arthurs</name><from>Beach Reporter (Southern California)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-renshaw/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=2931 /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=194835</url><name>Scott Renshaw</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
68/100
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117796719.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1807152</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/77653/the_alamo.html /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1482430</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C02E7D91731EF3ABC4F51DFB667838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1389200</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/leonard-maltin/</url><url>http://leonardmaltin.com/picks.htm#alamo /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1270650</url><name>Leonard Maltin</name><from>Leonard Maltin's Picks</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=100290 /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=1172839</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/marjorie-baumgarten/</url><url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gbase/Guides/Film?Film=oid%3A142195 /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=850723</url><name>Marjorie Baumgarten</name><from>Austin Chronicle</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/urban-cinefile-critics/</url><url>http://www.urbancinefile.com.au/home/view.asp?a=2854&amp;s=Reviews /m/1000560-alamo/comments.php?reviewid=504</url><name>Urban Cinefile Critics</name><from>Urban Cinefile</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>