<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Please Don't Eat the Daisies</original_title><alt_title>Ne mangez pas les marguerites</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Charles Walters</director><producer>Euterpe</producer><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Family</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Drama critic Larry McKay, his wife Kay, and their four sons move from their crowded Manhattan apartment to an old house in the country...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Doris Day</actor><actor>David Niven</actor><actor>Janis Paige</actor><rt_rating>5.5/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>67</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1348556/comments</url><from>from Römerberg, Germany</from><name>foggyday</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

"Please don't eat the daisies" is one of my favorite movies of Doris Day.
In
opposite of her other Screwball-Comedies she shows us in this movie her
natural talent. She sings like in the most of her movies, but her song with
the children is made in an excellent way. Her Leading Man David Niven is
the
perfect partner for the lovely Ms Day. We can also see, that she is one of
the few real Hollywoods Ladies, who played with children. In ten movies she
plays a mother !!! This movie kept her at the top of the Box Office after
her sucess with Pillow Talk, which is the opposite to this one. Everybody
will enjoy this little cut comedy, which is really more than 'just one of
those films".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1592694/comments</url><from>from Biloxi, Mississippi</from><name>gftbiloxi (gftbiloxi@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Based on the popular book by Jean Kerr, PLEASE DON'T EAT THE DAISY is
probably the best of Doris Day's 1960s comedies--and it finds her
surprisingly paired with David Niven. While the two may seem an
unlikely couple, they have extremely good on-screen chemistry, and the
film neatly balances its story between the two stars so that neither
overshadows the other.Day plays Kate MacKay, mother of four hellions and the long suffering
wife of esoteric drama critic Larry MacKay (Niven.) With her husband
under siege by every actor, director, and producer in town, Kate
decides to move the family to a home in the country--and in the process
leaves her husband open to the temptations of Broadway star Deborah
Vaughn (Janis Paige.) Before too long, Larry's swelling ego threatens
their happy home.The cast is expert, with both Day and Niven extremely enjoyable and
Janis Paige memorable as the Broadway siren who attempts to lead Niven
astray; the supporting roles are also expertly handled by a cast that
includes Spring Byington. The script is witty with a dash of
sophisticated sparkle, and unlike most of Day's later comedies manages
to avoid the feel of frantic farce. A truly enjoyable outing; pure fun
all the way.Gary F. Taylor, aka GFT, Amazon Reviewer
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4955078/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>dencar_1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I have read so many negative comments about this movie and I don't know
why. It's fresh, funny, and very entertaining. David Niven is well cast
as the ambitious New York critic dreaming of higher social circles and
a house in the suburbs. The story is loosely based on the experiences
of author Jean Kerr as she juggled children and a profession. She was
also married to New York drama critic John Kerr.Janis Paige is a natural as the Broadway vixen with eyes for Niven. And
Richard Haydn is excellent as the urbane Broadway producer and agent
for Paige who sets out to settle the score with Niven after Niven's
negative theatrical review of his musical. Haydin devilishly tries to
let the air out of Niven's inflated ego by getting Day to stage one of
Niven's college theatrical stinkbombs, but Niven beats everyone to the
punch and admits to it in his column. As for Doris Day--she's colorful,
exuberant, and as appealing as ever. Besides the title song PLEASE
DON'T EAT THE DAISIES, she reprises one of her huge 1950's hits QUE,
SERA SERA in a quaint Italian restaurant to Niven.Perhaps the best scene in the movie is the confrontation between Day
and Niven when Niven learns that Haydn has tricked Day into using one
of his old college scripts for a church production. When Niven realizes
what is happening, he explodes and refuses to allow his play to be
produced. Day lays into Niven for his insensitive and self-centered
attitude--the result of his new-found celebrity as a New York drama
critic. The exchange between them in the school auditorium truly
showcases the polished side of Day's dramatic talent.PLEASE DON'T EAT THE DAISIES does not pretend to be anything more than
what it is: a light-hearted comedy about a wholesome family adjusting
to the country as children, mother-in-law, and New York social life
become gremlins working against a married couple's bliss. But DAISIES
is also an entertaining pastiche from an era when the worst things that
happened to a family meant scrambling for the right baby sitter and
dealing with the serendipity of transplanting to the suburbs. Dennis Caracciolo
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3263460/comments</url><from>from Aventura, Florida, USA</from><name>Tickerage</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I had to comment here because the other comment was so negative.  First,
you
have to like Doris Day to like this movie.  It is one of her best and
capturtes her in all of her best environs, as a mother, on the sidelines
of
fast lane society.  How can any true fan not love this movie?  She sings,
she dances, and she acts.Doris's interaction with the kids is what steals the show, she's so
natural
with them.  The musical numbers are light and fluffy, but that was what we
loved about her work!  Niven makes an unexpectedly good straight man and
counterpart for Doris who is all over the place.  It is also interresting
that Janis Page co-stars in this film as she was the top billed female in
Doris's first film, Romance on the High Seas.I think Page looks good as a blond and gives a great performance.  Spring
Byington is fantastic as the grandmother. The only walk-through
performance
is by Richard Haydn, who isnt too bad.Anyone who loves Doris Day will consider this one of their favorite
movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0650226/comments</url><from>from Universal City, TX</from><name> (michael.e.barrett@worldnet.att.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I've seen the screenwriter Isobel Lennart's name on a few standout films,
and she seems consistently to write about people who love and support each
other and give each other encouragement, and whose conficts arise from
this
very love and consideration for each other's feelings more than what they
want for themselves. I noticed this in the very underrated "It Happened in
Brooklyn" and "Fitzwilly" and again in this film."Daisies" isn't a slapstick family movie about the kids' antics but a
serious portrait of the marriage between Doris Day and David Niven and the
crisis over his career as a theatre critic (based on the reality of Mary
and
Walter Kerr). The central conflict is whether Niven, a frustrated
playwright
turned critic, is in danger of becoming a witty personality who skewers
others' works. The answer is: not really. His values are still solid but
he
has to prove it. Doris worries about him and has wanted them to leave NY
for
a suburb. They do move but it's a compromise for both--like marriage and
life.The script doesn't cut away after a punch line; it leaves characters to
deal
with the situation. Perfect example: restaurant scene where an actress who
feels insulted by a review slaps his face, humiliating him just as his
wife
walks in. If this were some stupid movie, he'd be spluttering while the
music razzed him and we faded out, or he'd promptly get in a new fight
with
his wife who wanted to know who was that woman slapping his face, or you
can
write it yourself. Instead, his wife grasps the situation perfectly and
sits
down to brazen out their lunch while smiling diners look on; they support
each other, share how angry they feel and go on with their lives as they
must. There's a wonderful lengthy scene where the situation turns into a
real argument in their apartment about his preferring to stay in NY,
admitting that it's nice for the first time to be a receiving some
attention
as a writer, it's what he's doing to support them, etc, while she sees her
dreams of the country and "saving" him recede from her, and it doesn't at
all sound like a contrived movie argument. They're not bickering for our
amusement, like Doris &amp; Rock. They have points of view that are slightly
but
significantly different, and best of all, the scene leaves them standing
there while it hangs in the air; they move apart and change the subject
before they go too far, having some breathing room as she goes into the
kitchen to make sandwiches and think, and then approaches it with fresh
psychology that concedes this and that and makes him concede the move to
the
country, and they both understand perfectly what's going on. I thought
"This
writer knows how civilized couples argue."I could also go on about the actress, essentially an "other woman" role
who
tries to vamp Niven and is initially presented as merely a bad actress.
She
comes across as a woman who frankly understands her world and isn't trying
to put something over on Niven that he's not smart enough to handle. He
admits to being flattered and even coming to like her, and that's it. How
well you can imagine another movie with the vixen laying traps for the
hapless guy and Doris stumbling across some info about them having lunch
and
getting jealous etc., but that's just not how Lennart handles it. Doris
doesn't worry about this individual but the general nature of her
husband's
new life, what it means for the family, and above all how it affects Niven
himself.I will repeat one exchange that probably comes from Mary Kerr's book. It
was
funny, but it's an example of what the screenplay really was NOT: a string
of zingers. They did keep dropping dry comments out of Kerr, but there was
more substance than that. So the whole family is looking at the house they
bought, which looks like the Addams Family's, and one kid says "It's like
out of Ivanhoe." Dad says "Oh, I'm afraid it's much older than that." Then
another kid says "Why is it so big?"  Doris says "Because we couldn't
afford
anything smaller."

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0605146/comments</url><from>from Northeastern Wisconsin</from><name>ipra</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Although made in 1960, this classic sampling of Doris Day fluff is more
a product of the 50s than the coming decade of the 60s. As ever, Miss
Day is gorgeous and perfectly turned out, this time the mother of four
small boys, an aspiring playwright overshadowed by her theater critic
husband, coping with a series of domestic crises while she attempts to
move her family from a city apartment to an improbably ramshackle
English-style country house. 'Improbable' is indeed the word for the
entire plot of this movie, but then probability was seldom the reason
we went to the movies in the 50s. Bouyed along by the bright force of
Miss Day's personality, the light touch and easy charm of David Niven,
and ably supported by Janice Paige, Spring Byington, and Richard Haydn,
this pic has all the bouncy sweetness and escapism her fans so
appreciate in Miss Day's work. So, if you are looking for a 2-hour time
trip to what seems like a kinder and gentler time, don't mind bumping
your nose against a few cultural idiosyncrasies of the 50s (and no Day
fan can avoid that), enjoy discovering some charming but forgotten
musical numbers, appreciate really great vintage clothes, and generally
believe it is hard for Miss Day to do any wrong, this seldom-mentioned
film is just the ticket!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10065125/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bj218</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This movie is a charming tale which I enjoy every time that I see it.
When drama critic Larry McKay, his wife Kay and their four boys move
from a crowded apartment in NewYork City to an old house in the country
Larry finds that a house undergoing (what one can only assume) a major
remodeling is to noisy to work in. So after he starts complaining Kay
decides that Larry is basically becoming a pain and so she sends him
off to live (for about a week) in a fancy hotel in the city until the
work on the house is completed. What follows is the portrayal of true
to life hilarity that we tend to see with children (because if you do
not specifically tell your child not to put a chair on his head-- he of
course will) after all boys will be boys and the true to life jealously
(between husband and wife) that results when living apart.Many eccentric wonderful lovable characters flow easily in and out of
the story making this a must see movie for old movie fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2375356/comments</url><from>from Norwalk, CT United States</from><name>Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
You're glad they made movies like "Please Don't Eat The Daisies"
alright, simply to prove there was a time people were more innocent.
Sitting through it is another matter.The central problem with "Please Don't Eat The Daisies" as it stands
today is that it suffers from a major case of indecision: Does it want
to be about a theater critic who gets a big head, or does it want to be
about a Manhattan mom with four sons who finds a new home in
Westchester County? Doris Day stars doing what she does best, throwing
off clever one-liners with a maternal glow, doing a little bit of
singing, and standing by her man, in this case David Niven as theater
critic Lawrence Mackay, who probably doesn't deserve her but as played
by the winning Niven keeps our sympathies enough to make us happy he
convinces her otherwise.Mackay is quite taken by his new role as the Frank Rich of Mayor
Wagner-era Broadway, but she's worried his becoming an influential
quipmeister has made him mean, a candidate for a ride on the
"down-a-lator" as expressed by a producer who used to be Mackay's
friend until one of Mackay's catty reviews sundered their relationship.
The producer, played by Richard Hadyn in much the same jaded manner he
brought to his impresario role in "The Sound Of Music" five years
later, accelerates Mackay's notoriety by having the starlet of his
latest play, "Mme. Fantan," slap Mackay across the face for the benefit
of a newspaper photographer after he disses her performance.There's a great idea for a story here, about a critic coming up against
the egos of himself and others, but unfortunately the result doesn't
give Day much to do. Niven is neither unfaithful to her nor really all
that nasty a critic. Instead of trying to make the story work better,
which admittedly would risk running against the grain of a Doris Day
comedy, the film throws in a subplot, about the couple and their four
sons moving up the Hudson River to the bucolic suburb of Hooton and the
resulting mild turmoil that causes. Thus, the entire second half of the
film feels as awkwardly tacked on as the musical numbers Day performs
in the final third of the programme.It's all rather stupid, yes, but winsome, too, in that nice way that
makes one nostalgic for the early 1960s. The scenery is attractively
shot. The supporting actors are fun. Of the Day numbers, one, "Any Way
The Wind Blows," is a terrific number with a busy bassline and some
nice dipping harmonies that recalls Elvis Presley's "King Creole,"
fetchingly performed by Day and members of the cast as the "Hooton
Holler Players." Never mind that groaner of a name, it's a good
routine. The other number, the title song sung by Day and a merry band
of children, should have been cut but for the fact it's a Doris Day
movie and a drippy song with a kiddie chorus was what her audience
wanted.The same can be said for the whole movie. "Please Don't Eat The
Daisies" is charming in a way films wouldn't dare be today. The
dialogue is unnaturally whipsmart Neil-Simonesque, even when it's Day
talking to one of her sons ("All he does is eat and sleep." "He's a
dog. What d'ya want from him, blank verse?"). The youngest boy is
clearly overdubbed by a woman with a cutesy voice, saying "Cokee Cola"
as he drops water bags on people in a way that's supposed to suggest
Tom Sawyer, not lawsuits. The dog jumps into Niven's arms at the sight
of a squirrel, and he raises his magnificent eyebrows as only David
Niven can at the idea of finding himself in a lightweight suburban
farce.Day makes you glad you stopped by, a suburbanite dream in her snug
Capri slacks who finds the humor in every scene. Limited, yes, but very
good in her genre, enough to make a film like this at least
intermittently entertaining. She and Niven do play very well off each
other. Like Michael E. Barrett wrote here in another review, the scene
of them in the restaurant together after Niven has had his face slapped
is a terrifically acted sequence, underplayed well by both stars.Unfortunately, the rest of film doesn't rise to that same level of
subtlety. Instead, she does her suburban mom thing while he plays the
non-vicious critic with a vicious reputation, until at the end we are
asked to pretend the twain come to meet and all is resolved. It
doesn't, but the nicest thing to be said for "Please Don't Eat The
Daisies" is that it's so genial it makes you willing to pretend
otherwise.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8123779/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>blackbritishbabe</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
i really like this film. unlike some other reviewers i think the
chemistry between niven and day is strong - they presented like a
genuine married couple. the script is versatile, witty on the one hand,
but also able to shift to the more dramatic. the argument between day
and niven as he reveals his desire for professional success is very
well done. niven himself was laugh out loud funny on many occasions,
and the portrayal of parenthoood was quite charming. the song at the
school doesn't do anything for me, so i tend to fast forward past that
scene. however that is a matter of personal preference: i enjoy doris
day as an actress much more than as a singer. it's an amusing, easy
going, light hearted film, perfect for afternoon viewing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Based on the best-selling novel by Jean Kerr, "Please Don't Eat the
Daisies" is the story of a New York City family, the Mackays - four
boys, a wife Kate (Doris Day) and her husband Larry (David Niven).
Suddenly, Larry finds success as a powerful theater critic, and Kate
wants to move out to the country, which was always their dream.
However, it's not really Larry's dream any longer. He's heady on New
York success and wants to be near Theater Row. Conflict comes with his
changing values.This is a nice story co-starring Spring Byington as Kate's mother and
Patsy Kelly as the family housekeeper. It doesn't compare with the
sparkling Doris-Rock comedies. I happen to like David Niven in the role
- he's what you would expect from a New York critic - above it all,
sophisticated, egotistical, well-educated but ultimately likable.Day is very good as always and gets to sing, but the whole thing is a
little too much. There aren't enough laughs to make it really funny.
The brightest part of the movie for me was Janis Paige as Deborah
Vaughn, an actress/singer decimated by Mackay in a review who then
becomes attracted to him. She looks gorgeous, she's sexy, and she
supplies the bite that the story needed more of. If the writers had
built up that part of the story, the movie might have turned out
better. The other part they could have built up is the awful play that
Larry wrote that ends up being produced by the local community theater.
Some scenes from that with Doris would have been great.Day, as it turned out, was at her best when Ross Hunter made her over
into a glamorous, sophisticated woman herself and teamed her up with
Rock Hudson and gave her glossy productions and great clothes. This
film was made was right at that transition. Day is a very vibrant
presence but she can't elevate this material to more than what it was -
a pleasant family comedy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Based on the best-selling novel by Jean Kerr, "Please Don't Eat the
Daisies" is the story of a New York City family, the Mackays - four
boys, a wife Kate (Doris Day) and her husband Larry (David Niven).
Suddenly, Larry finds success as a powerful theater critic, and Kate
wants to move out to the country, which was always their dream.
However, it's not really Larry's dream any longer. He's heady on New
York success and wants to be near Theater Row. Conflict comes with his
changing values.This is a nice story co-starring Spring Byington as Kate's mother and
Patsy Kelly as the family housekeeper. It doesn't compare with the
sparkling Doris-Rock comedies. I happen to like David Niven in the role
- he's what you would expect from a New York critic - above it all,
sophisticated, egotistical, well-educated but ultimately likable.Day is very good as always and gets to sing, but the whole thing is a
little too much. There aren't enough laughs to make it really funny.
The brightest part of the movie for me was Janis Paige as Deborah
Vaughn, an actress/singer decimated by Mackay in a review who then
becomes attracted to him. She looks gorgeous, she's sexy, and she
supplies the bite that the story needed more of. If the writers had
built up that part of the story, the movie might have turned out
better. The other part they could have built up is the awful play that
Larry wrote that ends up being produced by the local community theater.
Some scenes from that with Doris would have been great.Day, as it turned out, was at her best when Ross Hunter made her over
into a glamorous, sophisticated woman herself and teamed her up with
Rock Hudson and gave her glossy productions and great clothes. This
film was made was right at that transition. Day is a very vibrant
presence but she can't elevate this material to more than what it was -
a pleasant family comedy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=16179 /m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1922427</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>Doris Day's fluffy comedy, made at the height of her popularity, is based on Jean Kerr (married to film critic Walter Kerr), and co-stars a smooth David Niven as her husband.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1508718</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Enjoyable romantic comedy suffers from excess length.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Please-Dont-Eat-the-Daisies /m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1392968</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/5
					</rating><comment>Cute little flick, and it has absolutely nothing to do with daisies.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>http://www.dvdtown.com/review/pleasedonteatthedaisies/15886/2815/ /m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1379905</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/10
					</rating><comment>It's so ho-hum, it's hard to stay awake through it. And the title? One of the Mackay kids eats the daisies at the new house. Somehow, in the book that seemed a lot funnier.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1422810</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1393240</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794040.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1737236</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/71202/please_dont_eat_the_daisies.html /m/please_dont_eat_the_daisies/comments.php?reviewid=1480177</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>