<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Last Voyage</original_title><alt_title>Panique à bord</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Andrew L. Stone</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
After a boiler explosion aboard an aging ocean liner, a man struggles to free his injured wife from the wreckage of their cabin and ensure the safety of their four-year-old daughter as the ship begins to sink.
</synopsis><actor>Robert Stack</actor><actor>Dorothy Malone</actor><actor>George Sanders</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467875/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Angus T. Cat</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When I was small I saw a movie on TV with my grandfather that scared the
BEJEEPERS out of me: its images of a woman imprisoned by steel beams on
an
exploding, sinking ship have haunted me all these years. I was watching
TCM
today and when I saw the opening sequences of "The Last Voyage" I
recognised
it straight away as the movie with the poor lady trapped in the wrecked
liner. As an adult I found the movie suspenseful: no wonder it terrified
me
as a kid. Dorothy Malone's performance masterly captures the wife's
desperation, panic, and concern that her child and husband survive.
Robert
Stack makes the viewer feel the loyalty and drive that makes the husband
battle to save his wife against the odds. It was great to see a movie
from
my early childhood present a black character who is every inch a hero as
the
leading character, who fights to rescue the wife as much as her husband
does. The characters of the captain and the British main officer are
finely
drawn and the struggles of the officer to preserve the ship and take care
of
the passengers while the captain fails to grasp the seriousness of the
situation make an effective counterpart to the husband's attempts to free
his wife and daughter from the wreckage of their cabin. The overhead
shots
of the daughter perched on the edges of a hole ripped through several
decks
of the ship are horrifying and I'm sure they are responsible for my still
being scared of heights. This movie's style is matter of fact, complete
with
a historical-sounding narration, but this increases the impact of the
terror
of the wife and the growing desperation and frustration of the husband as
he
races to find someone who will help them. The engineer's outburst at the
captain reflects the growing tension that the film creates. This is not
just
another hokey disaster film in Technicolor - this is a film that shows
how
people facing danger and death keep their heads to honour their
relationships, professions and their humanity. An unforgettable film, and
one that puts the overblown special effects and underdeveloped
characterisations of Titanic to shame.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4012150/comments</url><from>from Moultrie, Georgia</from><name>Jcmdc</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Viewers of "The Last Voyage" who have branded it a "cinematic turkey"
are mislead, in my opinion. This film achieves a realism that is
superior to the many disaster genre films that followed it. But more
importantly, it is a visual record of one of the finest transatlantic
liners ever--the French Line's Isle de France. I don't know of any
motion picture that actually used a ship as a floating prop as
extensively as Stone's film. The Isle de France represented an
important departure in ship design. Earlier liners attempted to
disguise the fact that they were ocean-going vessels. The "Isle de
France" brought the new art deco and moderne styles to the high seas
and utilized some of the finest French designers to craft this ship of
state. When the later Normandie was lost, many of her furnishings were
transferred to the Isle including furnishings by the famous designer
Ruhlman. Here in this film are these exciting interiors for all to see
for the last time prior to sending the Isle to the ship breakers. The
film also heralds the very twilight of regularly scheduled
transatlantic and transpacific liner service as the jet began to
rapidly displace this very civilized way to travel.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2002093/comments</url><from>from Denver, Colorado</from><name> (tgodel@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

- 3/5 STARS -A family battles for survival as an explosion devastates their cruise
ship
and punctures its hull.  The father must race to free his wife as rising
waters threaten them all.The Last Voyage is fun to watch because it's so OLD.  This is the first
modern motion picture involving a sinking ship OTHER THAN the Titanic.
The
movie is squeaky-clean, and Robert Stack is as wooden as a two-by-four as
the desperate father.  There's not much dramatic tension created here,
but
that almost seems to be a function of the time period.This is the final voyage of the U. S. S. Claratin, and her primitive
construction becomes critical when a fire in the engine room melts the
fuel
flow valves in the fully open position.  Within minutes, the boiler
explodes
and creates a very visually satisfying hole blown through every deck of
the
ship.  Of course, this hole separates the family, and when the father
struggles to rescue his daughter by trying to cross this bottomless void,
we
know this movie is going to try hard.  And it does.The special effects are somewhat sparse but exceptionally well done for
the
period.  I was surprised by the level of expensive detail, such as water
pouring in through the dining room windows even though they're only
visible
for a few moments.  Dad's first challenge is to rescue his daughter from
her
perch alongside the path of the boiler.  Then he must find a way to free
his
wife, who lays pinned under several steel beams in her stateroom.  This
becomes his objective for the remainder of the movie.A friendly fireman (one who stokes the fires in the engine room) helps
Stack
get the equipment he will need to free his wife.  Meanwhile, the sailors
below decks attempt to reinforce the walls of the engine room to prevent
the
bulkhead from breaching.  It does, of course, and that's when everyone
really starts to run out of time.This movie is particularly memorable for its ending sequence, which shows
the survivors running down the length of the ship's upper deck, as water
splashes onto the floorboards from the sea.  This visual is striking, and
even a modern audience will wonder how the shot was done; was this a
giant
set or did the producers simply sink a ship and film its last few minutes
above water?Disaster enthusiasts should see The Last Voyage because it stands
uniquely
alone in the timeline of movie history.  It was the first modern movie
based
upon people being trapped in an enclosed construction (such as a boat or
a
building) that was NOT based on a historical event (such as the sinking
of
the Titanic).  More importantly, the plot of the movie was focused on
dealing with the disaster, rather than the disaster coming as a big
finish
to the main story line.  This is the formula that dozens of movies would
attempt to perfect for the remainder of the century and
beyond.Although it is rather bland, this film is crisp, efficient, and a key
turning point for the genre.  It represents Hollywood's first try at the
modern disaster movie:  it features a plot focused on multiple characters
escaping from a fictional situation, while fighting for survival amid
expensive special effects.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A good decade before the disaster films of the '70s we had this engrossing,
tightly knit disaster film about a luxury passenger liner's last voyage
after a fire and explosions make it sinkable.George Sanders is the Captain who doesn't want to alert the passengers and
thinks the fire can be contained before things get worse. Robert Stack is
traveling with his wife and daughter and having a wonderful time until they
learn the hard way that the ship is doomed. Most of the film has him trying
to find someone help him rescue his wife who becomes trapped beneath some
steel girders. Fortunately for him, Woody Strode agrees to help and most of
the suspense deals with their efforts to free her despite no help from the
Captain or his crew--until Edmond O'Brien joins forces with them to free
her.All of the details are realistic and certainly the actors had to undergo
some uncomfortable physical demands in going through their paces. Woody
Strode is impressive both physically and otherwise as the man who gives his
all to help Stack. He and Robert Stack give the strongest performances in
their physically demanding roles.George Sanders is rather bland as the stubborn Captain but since most of the
action concerns Stack and his efforts to free Malone, it doesn't matter too
much. Dorothy Malone is impressive as the woman who tells her husband and
daughter to save themselves before it's too late.A very engrossing thriller...but one that had me squirming uncomfortably
while watching situations that seemed painfully real. A forerunner of James
Cameron's TITANIC, it tells the tale in a swift one hour and thirty minutes
with some of the action filmed aboard the real Ile de France.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3747813/comments</url><from>from Northern California</from><name>tvsterling</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The other comments have restored my love for this film. Like another
reviewer I saw it as a kid &amp; never forgot. I saw a world, for the first
time, where things could go terribly wrong; Disney never showed me
stuff like that. And when things went wrong there were good men pulling
together to make it right again. One of them was a black man. A little
girl was scared but brave too. The mommy would do anything for her baby
&amp; husband to make it. Twenty odd years later I bought it &amp; took it to our little experimental
film group at the county schools. I wanted everybody to see the realism
of the approach &amp; the human values. I also wanted them to see what you
could accomplish if you took advantage of a unique setting or
situation. The Ile De France was on it's way to be scrapped &amp; this was
the basis for the film. Nobody would even watch &amp; that really bummed me
out. Then I lent it to my good friend Conrad. He was a retired merchant
marine officer (second). He said he laughed all the way thru because
many things were not exactly realistic. One thing, the stateroom was
down inside the ship not up in the superstructure where staterooms are
supposed to be; and stuff like that.Well you know they were WRONG. This is great film-making; a great story
well told. Gripping from start to finish. I believe it was titled '90
Minutes to Disaster' when I saw it. I was right. So what if every
little fact isn't exact. I will say that the narration is a bit
annoying, that is true. When a film is a memorable event in a kid's
life (more than one) it's a great film.I have just finished reading a book called 'Collision Course' by Alvin
Moscow about the Stockholm, Andrea Doria disaster in 1956. The script
seems to me to contain some interesting echoes from this tragedy; the
worst shipping disaster since the Titanic. Not coincidentally the Ile
De France was one of the rescue ships on the scene &amp; she was famous for
rendering aid in several other shipping disasters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
We have to say this was a real surprise when it was presented by TCM
the other night. Andrew Stone's "The Last Voyage" makes an impressive
film that got our attention from the start. Mr. Stone, working with his
own screen play, makes a great disaster film about a luxury ocean liner
that encounters problems in the middle of the Pacific.This film looks so real, it's hard to believe it's a filmed account of
a real disaster. The old Ile de France was used for the exterior shots
and sunk for realism sake. The story is compelling, as well as
terrifying. Imagine to find yourself in the middle of an ocean facing
death aboard luxurious surroundings!That is the fate the Hendersons encounter on their way to Japan. Cliff
and Laurie are happily married with a small daughter. Everything looks
good, but a funereal note is delivered to the captain in the middle of
a meal. "Fire in the engine room"! This is only be beginning of the
end. We realize this is going to be a horrible experience.The film feels real. When an explosion occurs, Cliff returns to his
cabin only to find Laurie trapped by some steel panels and he can't
move her. To make matters worse, he finds his young daughter in a panic
holding dearly to her life on a ledge of what used to be her room. The
rescue effort of the girl, in a terrifying scene, is one of the most
heart wrenching things in the movie. We watch, in horror, at the end,
as Laurie is kept alive from drowning, Excellent acting from all the principals. Robert Stack, Dorothy Malone,
George Sanders, Edmond O'Brien, Jack Krushen, Woody Strode and the rest
of the cast, makes this a film that delivers a lot of action and keeps
us glued to what's happening.A film to recommend those with a strong heart. A great achievement for
the director Andrew Stone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0208959/comments</url><from>from Abilene, TX</from><name>Florian Weiss</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Did you like 'The Poseidon Adventure' ??
If yes, you will love 'The Last Voyage'.
This is one of the most believable pictures I've ever
seen; and not without reason: did you know that most of
the sinking scenes were shot on the French Liner
'Ile de France' right before it was sold to Chinese wreckers
(by the way: that's the reason for all the Chinese Stewards in the
picture)?? They actually flooded parts of the engine room
for the shooting. And even the scene in the Dining room (at the end)was
real;
Wanna see how it REALLY is to see a ship sinking ?? Get
this
movie...
The only really disappointing scene is the actual sinking
of the 'Claridon'.
But it's worth it anyway...

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
If you watch THE LAST VOYAGE in 2005 you'll be mistaken in thinking
it's a disaster movie with very poor production values . Truth be told
the disaster movie genre as we know it started and ended sometime in
the 1970s and it's a genre unique to that era so I doubt if in 1960 the
producers were expecting it to stand in comparison to later films like
THE TOWERING INFERNO and EARTHQUAKE This is more of an action adventure melodrama and should be treated as
such so don't complain about this movie not having an all star cast or
the rather cheap production values like the very obvious revealing
mistake where the boiler explodes throwing some tailors dummies up into
the air . You shouldn't complain about that scene anyway since it's the
best bit of the movie and I always have a sadistic chuckle when I see
it . Despite being rather clichéd the basic plot of a man trying to
rescue his wife on a sinking ship is very compelling and I thoroughly
enjoyed this movie which is miles better than the one with a woman
called Rose saving a girlie man called Jack from a sinking ship
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The S. S. Claridon is scheduled for her five last voyages after
thirty-eight years of service. After an explosion in the boiler room,
Captain Robert Adams (George Sanders) is reluctant to evacuate the
steamship. While the crew fights to hold a bulkhead between the flooded
boiler room and the engine room and avoid the sinking of the vessel,
the passenger Cliff Henderson (Robert Stack) struggles against time
trying to save his beloved wife Laurie Henderson (Dorothy Malone), who
is trapped under a steel beam in her cabin, with the support of the
crewmember Hank Lawson (Woody Strode)."The Last Voyage" is a surprisingly good disaster movie, and certainly
one of the precursors of a popular genre in the 70's. The careful
production used the S.S. Ile de France, the major ocean liner built
after the end of World War I, which was considered the most beautifully
decorated ship built by the French Line. During World War II, this
vessel involved in extensive trooping, and finally she was sold to
Japanese scrappers. During the shootings, she was partially sunk. The
story is very tense, dramatic and real, with honorable characters, like
the black crewmember Hank Lawson or Cliff Henderson, but also people
under stress, like the Second Engineer Walsh played by Edmond O'Brien
and most of the officers and crew, or the captain concerned with the
future of his career. The story is narrated in off apparently by the
Third Officer Osborne, performed by George Furness. My vote is eight.Title (Brazil): "O Grande Naufrágio" ("The Great Shipwreck")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0786266/comments</url><from>from Solihull, England</from><name>vaughan.birbeck</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Legend has it that Andrew L Stone chartered the 1920's liner 'Ile de France'
from a Japanese wrecking crew and sank her as the cameras turned. The ship
was then raised and sent to the scrapyard.Exciting as this sounds it is not the truth. Stone did hire the ship for a
while and filmed scenes of panic and destruction (explosions, the funnel
collapsing). The ship was then *partly* sunk by flooding a couple of
compartments but that was all. When you consider the unpredictable behaviour
of a sinking ship, and the cost of raising it again, this is understandable.
This also explains the anti-climactic final shots mentioned by an earlier
reviewer.Some scenes were shot on the half-sunk liner, most notably a scene in the
dining saloon where seawater is pouring through the portholes. Robert Stack
injured himself trying to close one.If you examine the film carefully you will see that the long-shots of the
sinking are created by masking shots that *raise* the water-level, not by
sinking the ship. The final scenes of Robert Stack and company struggling
along flooding decks were filmed off Santa Monica. Again, study the scene
carefully and you will see the sets wobble as they're struck by waves.I'm sorry to ruin anyone's illusions. I feel 'The Last Voyage' is a great
job of film-making, totally gripping. Andrew Stone deserved an award for
daring to shoot even part of his film on a sinking ship. I think its
reputation can survive a little myth-breaking.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0786266/comments</url><from>from Solihull, England</from><name>vaughan.birbeck</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Legend has it that Andrew L Stone chartered the 1920's liner 'Ile de France'
from a Japanese wrecking crew and sank her as the cameras turned. The ship
was then raised and sent to the scrapyard.Exciting as this sounds it is not the truth. Stone did hire the ship for a
while and filmed scenes of panic and destruction (explosions, the funnel
collapsing). The ship was then *partly* sunk by flooding a couple of
compartments but that was all. When you consider the unpredictable behaviour
of a sinking ship, and the cost of raising it again, this is understandable.
This also explains the anti-climactic final shots mentioned by an earlier
reviewer.Some scenes were shot on the half-sunk liner, most notably a scene in the
dining saloon where seawater is pouring through the portholes. Robert Stack
injured himself trying to close one.If you examine the film carefully you will see that the long-shots of the
sinking are created by masking shots that *raise* the water-level, not by
sinking the ship. The final scenes of Robert Stack and company struggling
along flooding decks were filmed off Santa Monica. Again, study the scene
carefully and you will see the sets wobble as they're struck by waves.I'm sorry to ruin anyone's illusions. I feel 'The Last Voyage' is a great
job of film-making, totally gripping. Andrew Stone deserved an award for
daring to shoot even part of his film on a sinking ship. I think its
reputation can survive a little myth-breaking.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/shane-burridge/</url><url>/m/last_voyage/articles/770718/a_nifty_twist_on_a_familiar_theme/ /m/last_voyage/comments.php?reviewid=770718</url><name>Shane Burridge</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><comment>A nifty twist on a familiar theme</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/chuck-oleary/</url><url>/m/last_voyage/comments.php?reviewid=1444626</url><name>Chuck O'Leary</name><from>Fantastica Daily</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/last_voyage/comments.php?reviewid=1421373</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/80177/the_last_voyage.html /m/last_voyage/comments.php?reviewid=1480435</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9F01E1DF1E38E333A25753C2A9649C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/last_voyage/comments.php?reviewid=1388950</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>