<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Date Bait</original_title><imdb_rating>5.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>O'Dale Ireland</director><producer>Marathon Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A Troubled young man, Brad, returns home after six months rehab. On his first night he starts a fight in dance club with a man named Logan because he was dancing with Sue...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Gary Clarke</actor><actor>Marlo Ryan</actor><actor>Dick Gering</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1555452/comments</url><from>from Michigan</from><name>ethylester</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I disagree with the other comment on here. I really enjoyed this film.
There are hot car chase scenes, heroin junkies, cute guys (Logan!),
crazy gangster power struggles, dumb older brothers, cool music and the
greatest awkward wedding night scene I've ever seen in a movie. Perhaps
I'm easy to captivate, but I was into the movie the whole time, not
bored once! The acting and characters were interesting, too. I loved
Frida, who was always playing jokes on her lanky, tolerant boyfriend.
Danny Logan just keeps getting crapped on even though he seems to do
everything right, and you can't help but cheer him on the whole time.
The gangsters are laughably dumb and the heroin junkie Freddy is very
entertaining with his obsessive face-covering. I thought it was well
directed film and well thought out plot. If you think '50s teen movies
are lame, then don't watch this one because it's pretty classic in my
book.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur23534254/comments</url><from/><name>Serpico Jones</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I accidentally stumbled on this rarely seen movie and it was pleasant
surprise. Almost like finding a hidden gem. The story was rather silly
and naive but still interesting enough to engage you to screen. A girl
from wealthy family is in love to lower class boy and there are many
obstacles standing on their way. Girl's parents aren't much supportive
and then there is obsessive drug addict who is desperately in love of
the girl. And mix into a pair of brutal but funny gangsters and you get
quite intriguing little movie. Nice mixture of classical love story and
crime film.The acting wasn't cheesy. Another reason to be pleasantly surprised.
Specially I liked Richard Gering as drug addictive Brad. Don't wait
anything Oscar worthy though but I already know you won't.Date Bait is nice small JD film and I was personally more entertained
than watching Transformers. But it's just me. I am a sucker for old
movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Date Bait (1960) * (out of 4) Romeo and Juliet type story of a rich girl who falls for a poor kid.
Her father is against them dating as is her ex-boyfriend who just
happens to be crazy and has a gangster for an older brother. Bad
acting, bad direction and a bad script make for a pretty bad film that
feels five times longer than it actually is. The title song is a real
hoot however.High School Caesar (1960) * 1/2 (out of 4) A bully fixes a vote so that he can be elected Class President where he
then plans on stealing even more money from students. Here's another
drive-in era teen flick that tries to tell a message but even at just
over 60-minutes this thing drags along. No camp value whatsoever and
not bad enough to get any laughs. Just plain dull.High School Big Shot (1959) ** (out of 4) Drive-in era drama about a nerdy teen who gets his shot at the big time
when he hears about a million dollar drop off. If you're a fan of these
teenage "B" films of the 50s then this here is certainly one of the
better ones but we're certainly a long way off from Rebel Without a
Cause. The film runs out of steam around the fifty minute mark but the
bad acting leads to some nice laughs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
It's funny, but in a three film DVD involving juvenile delinquents, the
lowest rated on IMDb entertained me most ("High School Big Shot") and
this film, which was the highest rated, bored me the most! It seems
that some people really did like "Date Bait"--I just thought it had
tons of plot problems and spent too much time on two stories when it
probably would have been best to just stick with one plot...and do that
one better.The film begins with a psycho teenager getting out of months of drug
treatment. It seems, however, that his biggest problems aren't the
drugs but that he's a loony hot-head! Within minutes of arriving in the
hangout where the teens (most of which looked in their 20s) go to
dance, he pulls out a knife and tries to kill another guy--all because
this other guy 'stole his girl'---but the loony druggie never really
did go out with the girl more than a couple times. A bit later, the
loony druggie's brother arrives and convinces him to go home. BUT, this
is not the end of it...then the brother and one of his friends chase
the innocent guy who was almost stabbed--running him of the road and
beating him! Yet, despite a knife fight and near vehicular homicide, NO
ONE BOTHERS TO CALL THE POLICE!!!!! Up until near the end of the film,
you just assume this town doesn't have a police force!!! Now at this
point, the film appears to be an exposée on drug abuse or juvenile
delinquency or perhaps on a weird relationship between brothers.
However, oddly, much of the next 40 minutes or so consists of the
relationship between the girl and guy who was attacked at knife-point.
The idea of two frisky young lovers wanting to defy her parents and run
off to get married was rather interesting--even if her father in the
film was silly! The dad was rather irrational and his acting consisted
of irrational screaming 'for her own good'! His character really was
dopey.Late in the film, the loony druggie AND the two teens (who have since
secretly married) come together once again when loony-boy kidnaps the
young lady! Finally, after a knife fight and about a dozen assaults
through the course of the film someone thinks to get the police! And
it's a showdown in which you don't know who will and won't
survive...but by this point, who really cares?! Too disjoint, too cheap
and too unbelievable to be much good for anything but a few unintended
laughs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
It's funny, but in a three film DVD involving juvenile delinquents, the
lowest rated on IMDb entertained me most ("High School Big Shot") and
this film, which was the highest rated, bored me the most! It seems
that some people really did like "Date Bait"--I just thought it had
tons of plot problems and spent too much time on two stories when it
probably would have been best to just stick with one plot...and do that
one better.The film begins with a psycho teenager getting out of months of drug
treatment. It seems, however, that his biggest problems aren't the
drugs but that he's a loony hot-head! Within minutes of arriving in the
hangout where the teens (most of which looked in their 20s) go to
dance, he pulls out a knife and tries to kill another guy--all because
this other guy 'stole his girl'---but the loony druggie never really
did go out with the girl more than a couple times. A bit later, the
loony druggie's brother arrives and convinces him to go home. BUT, this
is not the end of it...then the brother and one of his friends chase
the innocent guy who was almost stabbed--running him of the road and
beating him! Yet, despite a knife fight and near vehicular homicide, NO
ONE BOTHERS TO CALL THE POLICE!!!!! Up until near the end of the film,
you just assume this town doesn't have a police force!!! Now at this
point, the film appears to be an exposée on drug abuse or juvenile
delinquency or perhaps on a weird relationship between brothers.
However, oddly, much of the next 40 minutes or so consists of the
relationship between the girl and guy who was attacked at knife-point.
The idea of two frisky young lovers wanting to defy her parents and run
off to get married was rather interesting--even if her father in the
film was silly! The dad was rather irrational and his acting consisted
of irrational screaming 'for her own good'! His character really was
dopey.Late in the film, the loony druggie AND the two teens (who have since
secretly married) come together once again when loony-boy kidnaps the
young lady! Finally, after a knife fight and about a dozen assaults
through the course of the film someone thinks to get the police! And
it's a showdown in which you don't know who will and won't
survive...but by this point, who really cares?! Too disjoint, too cheap
and too unbelievable to be much good for anything but a few unintended
laughs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>