<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>I Passed for White</original_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Fred M. Wilcox</director><producer>Fred M. Wilcox Enterprises Inc.</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A young girl meets and marries the man of her dreams--only she hasn't told him that she is half-black, and he and his rich family and friends are white.
</synopsis><actor>Sonya Wilde</actor><actor>James Franciscus</actor><actor>Patricia Michon</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1472650/comments</url><from>from Calif, USA</from><name>lolita (zerdio)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw this movie when it was released in 1960, I was 16 at the time. I'm
not
sure why I went to see it unless it was because I liked, actor, James
Franciscos, (sorry we lost him). I had a great friend that lived this very
story only her husband's family was not wealthy or socialites.  I didn't
understand all this racial crap at that age but as I grew to learn what
LIFE
is all about, I began to understand why people that are bi-racial make the
choice they do to live a life more "acceptible" by the social standards we
determine as such. This movie was very moving to me and although, at l6, I
had not fallen in love as yet, I could feel her fears and concern for
losing
someone she loved in the discovery of her "Dark" secret. I seem to recall
being disappointed by the ending when she returned to her mother or
grandmother. I believe that LOVE is a powerful entity and emotion and if
it
TRULY exists can overcome almost anything, including death. I would love
to
see this movie again and highly recommend it for anyone but especially for
anyone who is bi-racial enough to cross the color line and chooses to live
the life of the dominant race.  I refuse to believe doing so is a sell out
but a CHOICE that each person has the RIGHT to make...Who's life or
business
is it anyway? Perhaps those who persecute are jealous they can not elect
to
make the same choice. I believe the character left her husband without
every
revealing what she was (A mistake if it cost her happiness) rather than
risk
shame and rejection. It is a heart-warming and tear-jerker revelation of
reality. I enjoyed it immensely, even at a naive 16 and again, would
recommend it to anyone! Would love to have it or see it televised
again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This film stars Sonya Wilde as a biracial lady and James Franciscus
plays her boyfriend who has no idea she isn't 100% lily-white. At
first, Sonya doesn't want to pose as white--but she doesn't really fit
in with black folks as she appears white. After being refused jobs and
being mistreated as biracial, she meets Franciscus and lands a job--and
she's tired of not fitting in and just lets people think she's white.
After all, in America in 1960, you'd certainly be treated like a
second-class citizen if you weren't pure white--which is a stupid
shame.Once the pair marry, things are occasionally a little tough. After all,
she's told so many lies about her family and Franciscus and his parents
want to meet them. Her lies are a bit hard to swallow and it's not
surprising that his mother starts to worry. After all, when the pair
are going to LA on their honeymoon (where she told them her parents
were), she tells him they can't see her family....as they've just
hopped a boat for South America and don't plan on returning!! An
additional problem develops when she slowly starts to see that her
husband and his family are racists. Can this charade go on any
longer--especially when she becomes pregnant? This is generally a very
good and engaging film. Here and there are a few moments that seemed
like they could have been handled better, but for a relatively
low-budget film this can be forgiven. Well worth seeing and an
interesting curio. However, I must add that the ending sure felt a bit
anti-climactic.It's an interesting coincidence that this film (which had been on my
Netflix queue for some time) came when it did. Just a few days ago, I
finished the brilliant novel "Diary of an Ex-Colored Man"--which deals
with the same themes as well as discusses why a light-skinned person
would want to pose as white. It's a sad story--and a perfect compliment
to this film. I am quite surprised that the lovely Wilde didn't appear in any other
films--and only a few guest appearances on TV shows up until 1962. What
ever happened to her? I could find nothing on IMDb or when I did a
Google search. Odd...By the way, the DVD print is very, very scratched in places. This
doesn't seriously impede the film but it is surprising on a DVD. It
could really use some restoration work. However, there are no captions
and it would have been nice to have them.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9853463/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jjpulczinski-1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
What makes this movie special is that it is a true story written by
Mary Bradley about people known to her personally, Reba Lee and her
mother. The ending was what really happened in real life and the book
and movie were pretty much true to life, not "based on a true story"
like so many other movies that end up paying only lip service to the
true story. Reba Lee's mother was Mary Bradley's seamstress, so she got
the story first hand from the people it happened to. To me, that makes
the story even more meaningful than if the author had simply
interviewed someone she didn't know and told the story from her own
viewpoint. I saw the movie many, many years ago and I am not sure I
remember details exactly, but it seems to me that the movie was pretty
faithful to the book. If you can find either the book or the movie, it
is well worth your time to read or watch it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1088134/comments</url><from>from New York City</from><name>FORREST136 (ForrestandEthel@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

If "I Passed For White" was released today it would stur up quite a storm!
Imagine not knowing what race to identify yourself with? The character of
"ETHEL" gives a touching performance as a GAL that just does not know which
way to turn!  A B movie that few have seen this classic is alot of
fun!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2539535/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tz227</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie in the theater while I was in high school, I liked it.
It was about a beautiful woman, who was supposed to be a light-skinned
Negro. She never came across, to me anyway, as black. She met the
wealthy white man (Franciscus), they fell in love and were married. The
couple were very popular, in their circle of friends, and went out
often to night clubs. There was a band (black men) playing where they
went and the woman was very 'friendly' with one of the players. It was
her brother or other relative and she didn't want her husband to know
who he was. Later, she became pregnant and, just before delivery time,
her husband came to the hospital and heard her talking in her sleep,
saying, 'is it black?'. He assumes that she was having an affair with
the black man and wants a divorce. The baby was white, or light, just
like her. I was intrigued with the movie, but, can't remember the whole
plot or the ending.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2539535/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tz227</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie in the theater while I was in high school, I liked it.
It was about a beautiful woman, who was supposed to be a light-skinned
Negro. She never came across, to me anyway, as black. She met the
wealthy white man (Franciscus), they fell in love and were married. The
couple were very popular, in their circle of friends, and went out
often to night clubs. There was a band (black men) playing where they
went and the woman was very 'friendly' with one of the players. It was
her brother or other relative and she didn't want her husband to know
who he was. Later, she became pregnant and, just before delivery time,
her husband came to the hospital and heard her talking in her sleep,
saying, 'is it black?'. He assumes that she was having an affair with
the black man and wants a divorce. The baby was white, or light, just
like her. I was intrigued with the movie, but, can't remember the whole
plot or the ending.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2539535/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tz227</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>