<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>El cochecito</original_title><alt_title>La petite voiture</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Spain</country><director>Marco Ferreri</director><producer>Films 59</producer><producer>Portabella Film</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Seventy-something Don Anselmo, a retired minister, becomes obsessed with owning a motorized wheelchair and fakes infirmity to get it.
</synopsis><actor>José Isbert</actor><actor>Pedro Porcel</actor><actor>José Luis López Vázquez</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0457427/comments</url><from>from Madrid, Spain</from><name>Gagut (garcia_nacho@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Only the fusion of two genius -the director Marco Ferreri and the script
writer Rafael Azcona- could have created this magnificent movie. If we add
to this duet the acting of Pepe Isbert  (possibly one of the best Spanish
actors ever) the combination could not have been better. This is a dark
movie about characters usually scorned by the society. Characters normally
separated by the rest just because they are old or handicapped. All this
tension developed between this two poles of the society ends in a brutal
and
nonsense murder. This chapter of the movie was censored by the Franco´s
regime who could not bear such brutality. In any case the result is a dark
movie who lets us see how were the darker years of the Spanish recent
history.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0436275/comments</url><from>from New York, USA</from><name>exigente</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

If you like dark comedies, this is a fine film to watch. Some of the
nuances
may be lost to those that , have not experienced Spanish society/culture
first hand, specifically during the Franco regime. The element of
selfishness runs through very clearly - the young(er) treating the old as
necessary nuisances, the old trying to squeeze the last few drops from
life.
Funny but dark.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4800624/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>duke1029</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Despite a long and prolific career, Marco Ferreri is not as well known
outside his native Italy as contemporaries like Fellini and Antonioni.
His anarchic, iconoclastic vision of the world and bizarre, often
surreal humor may be the reason. Although on the surface this early
film initially seems grounded in the Neo-Realist tradition of DeSica's
"Umberto D," it carries a bittersweet subversive theme that would
become increasingly apparent in Ferreri's later work.Jose Isbert plays Don Anselmo Proharan, a retired government minister
who has ceded his home to son Carlos, an officious, condescending
solicitor, his bourgeoisie wife, and Yolanda, their homely daughter.
Carlos' law offices, which he shares with his daughter's ambitious
fiancé, are also located on the premises, so Don Anselmo is limited to
a single confining room. As he also has to share space with Yolanda,
the old man has no sense of peace and quiet or privacy. In addition,
Carlos has control of his father's pension, which he parsimoniously
doles out as a parent would a child, further restricting the old man's
freedom. Ferreri emphasizes this with very effective traveling shots
that follow the old man around the house's constrictive, almost
claustrophobic, corridors.Don Anselmo's only escape seems to be attending funerals, and when
friend and fellow widower Don Lucas asks him accompany him on a
cemetery visit, he readily agrees. The paralyzed Don Lucas has recently
gotten a motorized wheel chair, which soon becomes an object of
fascination to the elder Proharan. He soon is introduced to the subculture of the "cochecitos" as the
motorized wheelchairs are called. Their owners congregate outdoors in
open spaces and, despite their handicaps, have achieved a sense of
independence, camaraderie, and self-reliance that the septuagenarian
finds exhilarating and liberating. Among those that he meets are
Julita, a crippled sketch artist, her quadriplegic boyfriend, and
Alvarez, the philosophic guardian and caregiver to the mentally
retarded son of a Marchioness. However, in order to become part of this
new surrogate family, Don Anselmo needs his own "little coach."Like Toad in Kenneth Grahame's "The Wind in the Willows," Don Anselmo's
becomes obsessed with owning one and regaining his lost dignity.
Because his tight-fisted son dismisses his requests, the ambulatory old
man fraudulently orders a wheelchair from a medical supply house and
falsely claims orthopedic infirmity to a doctor. In desperation, he sells his late wife's jewelry, which Carlos and his
wife have already earmarked for their daughter, to buy his own
"cochecito." His outraged son humiliates him by reclaiming the gems and
demanding the return of chair. He berates his father and vows to
institutionalize him in an asylum, which delights Yolande, who is only
too eager to co-opt his room. His self-esteem shattered, a desperate
Don Anselmo poisons his family's food and, like an disaffected
teenager, runs away from home. The film ends ambiguously with many
issues left unresolved. Ferreri directed his early films in Spain, and Don Anselmo's repression
by his bourgeoisie family might be interpreted as a quietly subversive
allegorical criticism of Franco's fascist military dictatorship. It is
very revealing that in the opening scene Don Anselmo sees a surreal
line of men marching in a military fashion armed with mop handles and
wearing a toilet bowl on their heads. Conversely the last scene has the
old man being arrested by the iconically uniformed Guardia Civil. In any case, Ferreri left Spain for his native Italy after the release
of "El Cochecito" and soon received some international critical acclaim
for trenchantly scathing social satires like "The Ape Woman" and "The
Conjugal Bed." Ferreri would return to the theme of aging with dignity in "The House
of Smiles" nearly three decades later. Ferreri has been quoted as
saying that his job as director is to give the audience a "punch in the
stomach." "El Cochecito" is a punch, albeit a gentle one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3478561/comments</url><from>from Spain</from><name>Henry Fields (kikecam@teleline.es)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
All of the friends of Anselmo (Pepe Isbert, a genius) have their own
disabled-adapted little cars, they go anywhere they want: to the main
square, to the country... Anselmo's on his own, and he feels lonely. No
way! He decides he also wants one of those cars (doesn't matter if he's
not a disabled person) and he'll do ANYTHING to get one: to pretend
he's been left paralyzed, to steal... WHATEVER it takes. "El cochecito" is nothing but a classic of Spanish cinema (or of cinema
in general) and such a referent of European realism. It is a so funny
comedy written by Rafael Azcona (maybe the best Spanish scriptwriter
ever) and placed on the impoverished streets of Madrid (late 50's). You MUSTN'T miss this one (not if you love cinema).*My rate: 9/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4888011/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon, USA</from><name>Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"El cochecito" ("The Little Coach" in English) is the first Marco
Ferreri movie that I've ever seen. And it's certainly a good one.
Ferreri was Italian, but this black comedy is Spanish-made, focusing on
an elderly handicapped Madrilenian and his acquaintances. This is one
of the only looks that I've had directly into Franco-era Spain
(although little if anything focuses on Franco's rule). The protagonist
feels ostracized by society, but has some surprises in store for
everyone.So, I don't know if I would call this a great movie. I got the feeling
that the content, which did in fact have trouble with the censors, may
have influenced Pedro Almodovar. But that's just conjecture, so don't
quote me. Either way, a pretty good movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4888011/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon, USA</from><name>Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"El cochecito" ("The Little Coach" in English) is the first Marco
Ferreri movie that I've ever seen. And it's certainly a good one.
Ferreri was Italian, but this black comedy is Spanish-made, focusing on
an elderly handicapped Madrilenian and his acquaintances. This is one
of the only looks that I've had directly into Franco-era Spain
(although little if anything focuses on Franco's rule). The protagonist
feels ostracized by society, but has some surprises in store for
everyone.So, I don't know if I would call this a great movie. I got the feeling
that the content, which did in fact have trouble with the censors, may
have influenced Pedro Almodovar. But that's just conjecture, so don't
quote me. Either way, a pretty good movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4888011/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon, USA</from><name>Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>