<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Nihon no yoru to kiri</original_title><alt_title>Nuit et brouillard sur le Japon</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Nagisa Ôshima</director><producer>Shôchiku Eiga</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis/><actor>Miyuki Kuwano</actor><actor>Fumio Watanabe</actor><actor>Masahiko Tsugawa</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4044518/comments</url><from>from Kansas</from><name>Meganeguard</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Those who are familiar with the literature of Murakami Haruki are sure
to be familiar with the Zenkyoto, Joint Struggle Councils, student
movement that spread throughout Japanese universities during the 1960s
resulting in the temporary halt of classes at a number of schools,
including Waseda and Tokyo University. However, of course, the Zenkyoto
was not the first leftist student movement in Japan. Another and better
organized one was the Zengakuren which organized workers, students, and
left-leaning intellectuals against the Japanese State.It is during this time that Oshima Nagisa's film _Night and Fog in
Japan_ was filmed, 1960. Soon after the failed attempt to halt the
signing of the AMPO, Japan-United States Security Treaty, a young
protester named Reiko marries the older journalist Nozawa. However, all
is not revolution and roses because other members of the group have
beef not only with Nozawa, but with the group's leader Nakayama and his
wife Misako.What follows is a series of flashbacks showing the days in which Ozawa,
Nakayama, Misako, and several others were leftist students. Marxist
ideologies are thick, but in fighting and lust are thicker, and the
viewer witnesses several cases of personal disputes and the vacuous
preachings of Nakayama who while talking about the equality of man
seduces Misako away from Ozawa because of his wealth.This is an interesting movie, but it might be quite slow for some.
Mainly the film consists of arguments between the characters, but for
those interested in Japanese Leftist movements, this should prove quite
entertaining.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3231205/comments</url><from>from Tellus</from><name>Atavisten</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
A record of a time in the university-based 'Zengakuren'(?)(thanks
meganeguard)this.Economic and direct, this is almost two hours cut out of a student
Marxist movement and its feuds. The setting is a wedding between two
members which is happy and well until one comes from a demonstration
with low attendance, the protesters were outnumbered by police, and
fires out accusations against the bride and groom for falling out of
the movement in favour of family idyll. From then on the disputes hail
down in machine gun fashion ripping up 10 year old history which in
fact doesn't stop, but just gets faded down at the end of the movie!
Everyone is dead serious and strong-willed. We watch them with
distance, not sympathizing with any. The settings in which this event
takes place are as good as invisible. For great dramatic effect they
get toned down by turning off the light and spotlighting the central
characters (of which there are a few) instead. All is theater-style.
Making it a play instead would make little difference.Specialist tackle, as this is exclusively about this movement and its
key characters this is for those interested in leftist movements only!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This movie begins with a wedding. Nice, right? No, not really. The
guests all look kind of grim. Instead of lauding the bride and groom,
they are speaking of the demonstrations against the Japan Security
Treaty, a controversial act of its time. In the first scene the camera
moves a bit haphazardly, which I'm certain is on purpose. Little
lighting tricks like spotlights accentuate this tale of a group of
youngish (all younger than 35, I'd say) fighting for their rights. This
movie could have been a play, its staged that way. Whether you're
interested depends on your sense of history. I admit to having little
knowledge of the treaty, so this film makes the subject worth
exploring. This film got the director fired from his film studio, so
you know the film is gutsy. So, if you know about the treaty or want to
learn, this is a well made film. It is just not for everyone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This movie begins with a wedding. Nice, right? No, not really. The
guests all look kind of grim. Instead of lauding the bride and groom,
they are speaking of the demonstrations against the Japan Security
Treaty, a controversial act of its time. In the first scene the camera
moves a bit haphazardly, which I'm certain is on purpose. Little
lighting tricks like spotlights accentuate this tale of a group of
youngish (all younger than 35, I'd say) fighting for their rights. This
movie could have been a play, its staged that way. Whether you're
interested depends on your sense of history. I admit to having little
knowledge of the treaty, so this film makes the subject worth
exploring. This film got the director fired from his film studio, so
you know the film is gutsy. So, if you know about the treaty or want to
learn, this is a well made film. It is just not for everyone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>