<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Village of the Damned</original_title><alt_title>Le village des damnés</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Wolf Rilla</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer British Studios</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
In the English village of Midwich, the blond-haired, glowing-eyed children of uncertain paternity prove to have frightening powers.
</synopsis><actor>George Sanders</actor><actor>Barbara Shelley</actor><actor>Martin Stephens</actor><rt_rating>7.5/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>95</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2074560/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Gafke</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
On a perfectly normal, lovely afternoon in the English countryside, a
small town is suddenly taken over by an unseen presence. Everyone
within the town - man, woman and child - suddenly passes out cold for
no apparent reason whatsoever. Anyone who attempts to enter the town
from the outside is also stricken down, yet revive instantaneously when
removed from the danger zone. No one, not police or military, can pass
the invisible barrier, but within a few hours the strange presence is
gone. Everyone seems to be alright...until a few weeks later, when all
of the women in town who are of childbearing age discover themselves to
be pregnant. Nine months later, a dozen identical children are born to
these somewhat suspicious mothers, children with white- blond hair and
scary eyes that glow. The children are oddly emotionless and only
associate with each other, acting as a single entity. Worst of all,
they can make anyone do whatever they want them to do, which often has
fatal results. Can kindly schoolteacher (the wonderful George Sanders),
whose beloved wife has borne one of these creatures, help the alien
children embrace their human half? Or will he have to destroy them all?This is an absolute masterpiece of paranoia, sci-fi style. The acting
is superb, especially by the late and under-appreciated Mr. Sanders,
whose compassion and intellect sets the tone for this quiet and
somewhat sad little tale. The lovely Barbara Shelley as Sanders loving
wife is sweet and totally believable. Indeed, the townsfolk are all
very realistic and approachable, kind and simple folk who don't really
deserve the wrath of the spooky children who have invaded their small
town. Young Martin Stephens, who also turned in a creepy performance in
the ghostly masterpiece "The Innocents" is every bit as creepy here as
George and Barbara's "son." Filmed in moody black and white, this movie creeps along with all the
menacing stealth of a thick London pea souper. This is an intelligent
horror film which deserves better attention. It probably won't be
appreciated by people who consider expletives and explosions to be main
characters, but for people who prefer horror with brains (and not
brains ripped out of skulls) this is the film for them. Fans of George
Sanders shouldn't miss this; it's quite a switch from his usual smarmy
roles, and a nice switch at that.Highly recommended!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Village of the Damned is a strongly compelling Science-Fiction highlight and
easily of the eeriest movies I ever saw. Although it's a very modest and
simply made production, the scary-effect of this film is a lot more
effective than some of its big-budgeted colleagues. On a random day, the
entire English village of Midwich falls into a trance-like sleep. Completely
inexplicably, they awake again seemly normal but two months later it appears
that every fertile woman in town got pregnant on the day of the blackout.
The newborns show a strange resemblance in looks and – what is even more
bizarre – they're telekinetic! Due to their amazing intelligence and
emotionless behavior, they form a huge threat and freak out the entire
little town. `Village of the Damned' is loyally adapted from John Wyndham's
novel `The Midwich Cuckoos'. Throughout the whole film, you don't get much
explanation and, as a viewer, you're forced to guess at the mystery's
origin. Although highly unlikely, the events in Midwich really are alarming
and make you feel uncomfortable. This effect is reached through solid
tension and macabre atmosphere much more than through special effects. The
eerily lit eyes of the ‘children' are the only real effects but they cause a
lot more fear than gallons of blood ever could! Village of the Damned also
owes a lot of its power to a terrific casting job. Essentially to achieve
the obtained scary effect were the children. Well, they did a good job! The
offspring looks alienated almost naturally and their appearance literally
chills your blood. The concerned adult in Village of the Damned is
excellently played by George Sanders. Sanders was a terrific and shamefully
overlooked English class actor who committed suicide in the early 70's. He
has a got a few other delightful horror movies on his repertoire like
`Psychomania' and `Doomwatch' (both are some of his last films). Village of
the Damned is a highly recommended picture that'll certainly keep you close
to the screen till the end-credits role. Equally recommended is the
(unofficial) sequel called `Children of the Damned'. There's a bit more
background in that film, as well as some more explicit horror sequences. The
1995 remake by John Carpenter, however, is rather unexciting and one of the
most redundant films ever made. Stick to the original and be scared! 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1388629/comments</url><from>from West Virginia</from><name>Bucs1960</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This classic low budget, black and white film is right up there with
the best of the sci-fi/horror movies of the time. It appears that it
was shot on a very low budget ($300,000), thus no special effects
beyond the superimposed glowing eyes of the children and the burning
house at the end (not much of an effect). But it became a real
moneymaker and a cult developed around it. They went on to make a
sequel which doesn't live up to the original.The cast, though limited, is quite good. The ever sophisticated,
urbane, George Sanders as the scientist; Barbara Shelley from Hammer
films as his wife; and little Martin Stephens as David, putative
offspring of Shelley and Sanders. This kid is evil personified and does
a bang-up job for such a youngster.The story involves the village of Midwich and the birth of 12 children
fathered in a very strange way that is never totally explained, who are
intellectual giants with one purpose.....take over the world. Should
they be destroyed or studied?....that's the problem facing Sanders and
the government. Sanders comes to the inevitable conclusion and because
they can read his thoughts, he must think of a brick wall in order to
mask his intent. The ending, although not surprising is still
effective.This film is a keeper and is recommended to all those who like their
films straight to the point without all the special effects and
computer generated action. It's minimal with maximum punch.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0463200/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I originally saw this when I was in junior high on late night TV. Those
glowing eyes gave me nightmares for weeks! Seeing it now MANY years
later, it still scares me. It's very quiet but very spooky. No real
on-screen violence, no special effects (with the exception of the eyes)
and all talk but never dull. The film is intelligent, doesn't talk down
to the audience and handles the subject matter in a very realistic
manner. Most people in horror films act like idiots--not in this one!
Also some superb acting by George Sanders, Barbara Shelley (as his
wife) and those creepy little kids (especially Martin Stephens) helps a
lot. Proves a quiet little, goreless film can scare you silly. AT ALL
COSTS, AVOID THE 1995 REMAKE!!!!!!! Carpenter's a great director, but
you can't remake a great film. See this one!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I am giving this film a 10 based on the "bang for the buck" it
provides. Despite having a small budget, few special effects and an
unknown cast (aside from George Sanders), it is an engrossing and
terrifying sci-fi adventure.The movie begins with a VERY STRANGE occurrence--a small village just
STOPS. All people life within the village stops--machinery, animals and
people. And, when the military tries to enter the town, the soldiers
just STOP as well--falling into comas. Then, just as suddenly, everyone
awakens--none the worse for wear. Or so it would seem, for later, many
women in this small hamlet are found to be pregnant! Once these little
bundles of joy are born, the fun begins as these brilliant but
disturbingly freaky kids slowly scare the crap out of
everyone--especially as they walk, talk and look alike and speak as one
(sort of like an evil version of Huey, Dewey and Louie)! And, it turns
out, they are apparently unstoppable and up to some sort of evil
(though exactly what they intend is uncertain--but it MUST be bad
considering their evil proclivities)! NOTE: Do NOT see the supposed sequel, "Children of the Damned". It's
terrible. Instead of the kids harassing people (such as making them
crash their cars into walls or blow their heads off), the kids are
misunderstood and only want to live in peace!! What crap--I want murder
and global domination! Another NOTE: Do NOT see the recent remake of Village of the Damned. It
lacks the subtlety of the original and just does NOTHING to improve an
already great film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0562732/comments</url><from>from Luoyang, China</from><name>Michael DeZubiria (miked32@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Village of the Damned is a very well-made thriller that seems to have been
overlooked because of the sheer magnitude of its competition - Psycho. Both
of these films are testaments to the idea that low budgets are very capable
of producing great films. It is not the size of the budget that matters, it
is the skill of the filmmakers and the actors. Village of the Damned makes
use of a variety of very easily done but also very effective special
effects, such as the boundary across which all people and animals lose
consciousness, the creepy eyes on those kids, and their hypnotic powers.The discussion of the exact same phenomenon happening to a few remote towns
all over the world does a lot to show what these kids can do, and it
increases the dramatic tension of the film as a whole. Cheaply made, but
also very well made because a lot of thought was obviously put into it,
Village of the Damned is a timeless thriller, even in black and white. When
you watch a movie like this, if you are the kind of person who is so
superficial about your movies that you refuse to watch black and white
films, keep in mind that black and white photography REQUIRES good acting,
to put it in the immortal words of Orson Welles. You can't have black and
white photography and bad acting, the film would never work. Village of the
Damned takes black and white photography and fills it with excellent acting,
a fascinating story, and good direction that makes me wonder why this was
the only film that Wolf Rilla ever directed. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0679729/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>J. Spurlin</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The best way to watch this movie is ignorantly. Go to Netflix now, put
the movie at the top of your queue and watch it when it arrives. Read
about it later. If you enjoy sci-fi classics like "The Day the Earth
Stood Still" and "Them!"; if you love the Britishness of the Hammer
horror pictures; if you prefer a well-told story, rich suspense,
sympathetic characters and black-and-white photography to special
effects, color and gore, you will want to see this film right away.The movie begins in Midwich. We meet the scientist Gordon Zellaby
having a telephone conversation. Mid-sentence he passes out. At the
same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just
as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich
to sleep. When the army gets involved, we discover this force has
precise boundaries. One soldier, after being lassoed around the waist,
walks past the boundary, loses consciousness and immediately revives
when his fellows pull him out of the infected area. A few hours later,
this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery
remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. All Midwich women of
childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant.Watching this science-fiction movie paired with almost any modern one
demonstrates how storytelling has devolved as special effects have
advanced. It also demonstrates how one simple effect can be more
memorable than a thousand complex ones. I happened to see this just
before watching "The Forgotten" (2005), a stupid movie with expensive
effects; but not of those expensive effects is as potent as this
movie's signature device. When the blonde-haired Midwich children wreak
psychic havoc, the picture freezes and their eyes glow. That
inexpensive trick shot is worth the millions blown on "The Forgotten."Another nice effect: George Sanders. He plays the hero, Gordon Zellaby,
a scientist who becomes a dubious father to one of the Midwich freaks.
Sanders plays rogues in almost every other movie, but here he is
sweet-natured and convincingly so; he betrays not a shadow of his usual
cynicism. Were this his only surviving film, one would think he was
born to play kindly old men. The excellent cast has one other
outstanding performance by Martin Stephens, who plays Sanders's
cold-hearted "son." Would you be surprised to learn his voice was
dubbed by a female actress specializing in children? I was surprised to
learn it wasn't. That is the boy's own eerily precise diction.Special praise must also go to the director and photographer, Wolf
Rilla and Geoffrey Faithful, who give the movie the detached air of a
documentary. The script, credited to Stirling Silliphant, George
Barclay and Rilla, is an excellent adaptation of a fine book, "The
Midwich Cuckoos" by John Beynon Harris. Fans of this movie will want to
read it. The book has many enjoyable details that were necessarily and
wisely cut from the adaptation. To note one difference, the children in
the movie are psychically linked: what one knows they all know. But in
the book, the boys are psychically linked with the boys, the girls with
the girls; but there is little or no link between the two sexes. The
reasons for this are fascinating.I haven't seen the John Carpenter remake, and I don't want to. What
would the ideal remake of this film look like? It would look like the
original: black-and-white, set in the late fifties, cast with Brits and
scripted with the same restraint. Maybe modern resources could add a
piquant touch or two; it would be amusing to see all those sheep fall
asleep in the opening scene. Oh, and that awful model shot of the
school could be replaced. Otherwise, we have the film we want, so why
remake it?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1908551/comments</url><from>from Newfoundland, Canada</from><name>Space_Mafune</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

at least if you're a science fiction and horror fan. There's a great
build-up here and a very satisfying climax. This has a wonderful eerie
feel
reminiscent of the feeling one gets watching "the original Outer Limits".
The story feels a little bit more like "the Twilight Zone" however with
the
questions of morality, right and wrong it raises. This film might not
appeal
as widely to non-genre fans but it's classic great stuff for the fan. Best
scenes involve the eyes--it's a very effective nightmare when it's your
own
children who are the evil ones(or are they?).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A small countryside village in England experiences a time period of several
hours where all living things lie lifeless and helpless.  Anything living
that connects within this sphere of lifelessness gets the like treatment. 
Everyone soon awakens from whatever happened, and soon the women of
child-bearing years all get pregnant and are all due on the same day. 
Village of the Damned is one of those discerning, intelligent science
fiction films of yesteryear that tends to leave much to your imagination in
terms of gore and violence as well as make you think and ponder important
questions about the limits with which humanity should go to procure
knowledge.  The children are decidedly very creepy as their eyes glow when
they are angered.  Martin Stephens as George Sanders' boy is particularly
good as he looks and speaks with such class and distinction yet has the
conscience of a cold-blooded, calculated killer.  Sanders is also very good
in his role as a man torn between bridging the field of knowledge with the
unknown and protecting mankind from foreign/alien harm.  His wife, played
with credibility, is Hammer beauty Barbara Shelley.  A great British science
fiction film and certainly one of the more thought-provoking ones
around.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is a great Classic film mainly because of the great movie star
George Sanders(Gordon Zellaby),"Hangover Square",'45, who unfortunately
took his own life. In this film Sanders plays a professor and has the
great pleasure of raising a child with Barbara Shelley(Antnea Zellaby),
who turns out to become a child with glaring eyes and a very bad
temper! It seems the children in this film seem to grow at a very rapid
pace and have great hidden abilities to do just about everything they
want in controlling the minds of all ADULTS! In 1960, this was a great
Horror film and captivated the movie goers. This is truly a great
Classic Film to enjoy!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is a great Classic film mainly because of the great movie star
George Sanders(Gordon Zellaby),"Hangover Square",'45, who unfortunately
took his own life. In this film Sanders plays a professor and has the
great pleasure of raising a child with Barbara Shelley(Antnea Zellaby),
who turns out to become a child with glaring eyes and a very bad
temper! It seems the children in this film seem to grow at a very rapid
pace and have great hidden abilities to do just about everything they
want in controlling the minds of all ADULTS! In 1960, this was a great
Horror film and captivated the movie goers. This is truly a great
Classic Film to enjoy!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,895095-2,00.html /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1938049</url><from>TIME Magazine</from></reviewer><comment>Village is one of the neatest little horror pictures produced since Peter Lorre went straight.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/v/VillageDamned.html /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1887022</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Commie infiltrators? Bastard aliens? Advertisements for the pill?</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117796119.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1805643</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>This just tapers off from a taut beginning into soggy melodrama.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kim-newman/</url><url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/review.asp?DVDID=117187 /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1675109</url><name>Kim Newman</name><from>Empire Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>One of those little science fiction movies that, once seen (and it's a TV staple) is never forgotten.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=109901 /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1675108</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>The script and direction are rather creaky at times, but the children, whose eyes light up menacingly, are excellent.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/village-damned/review/122119 /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1675107</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Very frightening.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/8947_VILLAGE_OF_THE_DAMNED /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1675106</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>A strong and subtle horror film from England.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/62999/village_of_the_damned.html /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1475254</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>The atmosphere and pace are superbly handled, and the performances of the sinister, inhumanly intelligent 'children' never falter.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-oehley/</url><url>http://www.scifimoviepage.com/villageof.html /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1337192</url><name>James O'Ehley</name><from>Sci-Fi Movie Page</from></reviewer><comment>Plays on our dread of our children growing up to become Hitler Youth members with amazing superpowers . . .</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1330978</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Those eyes, those screams! Creepy classic.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/walter-chaw/</url><url>http://filmfreakcentral.net/dvdreviews/badvillagechildren.htm /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1317704</url><name>Walter Chaw</name><from>Film Freak Central</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>It's a humanist piece--no lightning bolt restores this society, just the cool light of right reason.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jon-niccum/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1303549</url><name>Jon Niccum</name><from>Lawrence Journal-World</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Creepy stuff</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=838428</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Mildly effective sci-fi thriller that suffers from being too restrained.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Village-of-the-Damned-(1960) /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=803714</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Wolf Rilla builds dread of these strange children through insinuation and mood, and the audience gets the real thing: fear</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/villageofthedamned.htm /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=803119</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>Village of the Damned remains an intelligent creepy tale that has not lost its luster over time.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/les-wright/</url><url>http://www.culturevulture.net/Movies/VillageoftheDamned.htm /m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=310117</url><name>Les Wright</name><from>culturevulture.net</from></reviewer><comment>Can still make contemporary audiences squirm in their seats.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1419750</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-r-leeper/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1338936</url><name>Mark R. Leeper</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=1190326</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1022823-village_of_the_damned/comments.php?reviewid=805255</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>