<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Too Soon to Love</original_title><imdb_rating>5.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Richard Rush</director><producer>Dynasty</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>Too young to marry...Too late to turn back...</synopsis><actor>Jennifer West</actor><actor>Richard Evans</actor><actor>Warren Parker</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Too Soon To Love (1960) ** (out of 4) Incredibly over-dramatic "message" film about a good girl (Jennifer
West) and a good boy (Richard Evans) who fall in love but make the
dramatic choice of having sex. Soon the girl ends up pregnant, which
makes her feel like a slut and it also puts a strain on the teenager's
relationship. This is in the same company as Reefer Madness as far as
being overbearing in trying to deliver a message but this film here
never quite hits the same level of camp. There are some over the top
moments, which make for a few laughs but for the most part this is
played straight forward and tries so very hard to be serious. The
biggest problem are the two leads who turn in horrible performances and
they bring more laughs when the film is going for seriousness. There's
one great sequence inside an abortion clinic, which was shot to look
like a horror film and actually manages to be just as creepy as the
majority of horror films out in this time period. Jack Nicholson has a
small role as a hot rod.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I saw that the other review compared this film to "Reefer Madness".
Well, although both of these films are exploitation fare, I just can't
see lumping them together. "Reefer" is a grade-z film--rotten and silly
from start to finish---and you just can't say that about "Too Soon To
Love". Yes, "Too Soon" is not a great film...but it isn't THAT bad.The film is about two high school students, Cathy and Jim. Like in most
exploitation films, instead of looking like teens, they are clearly
older--21 and 25 respectively. I don't know why they just didn't get a
couple real 17 year-olds to play these parts. The two fall in love and
get frisky--though the sex aspect of the film is just implied--after
all, it's 1960. Like many sex exploitation films, the girl ends up
pregnant (but without an STD--like she would in many of the more
salacious films of this ilk) and the pair don't know what to do next.
Exactly what they do next is pretty interesting--just tune in to see
more.The story is a tad overdone at points and some of the acting isn't
great, but overall the film is much better than I'd expected. The
acting of Richard Evans (Jim) is particularly good and the film does
hit on a few good issues--and only hits you over the head like a
meat-ax on occasion. While this film is easy to skip, it sure isn't one
the average person would love, but is more for fans of the genre.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I saw that the other review compared this film to "Reefer Madness".
Well, although both of these films are exploitation fare, I just can't
see lumping them together. "Reefer" is a grade-z film--rotten and silly
from start to finish---and you just can't say that about "Too Soon To
Love". Yes, "Too Soon" is not a great film...but it isn't THAT bad.The film is about two high school students, Cathy and Jim. Like in most
exploitation films, instead of looking like teens, they are clearly
older--21 and 25 respectively. I don't know why they just didn't get a
couple real 17 year-olds to play these parts. The two fall in love and
get frisky--though the sex aspect of the film is just implied--after
all, it's 1960. Like many sex exploitation films, the girl ends up
pregnant (but without an STD--like she would in many of the more
salacious films of this ilk) and the pair don't know what to do next.
Exactly what they do next is pretty interesting--just tune in to see
more.The story is a tad overdone at points and some of the acting isn't
great, but overall the film is much better than I'd expected. The
acting of Richard Evans (Jim) is particularly good and the film does
hit on a few good issues--and only hits you over the head like a
meat-ax on occasion. While this film is easy to skip, it sure isn't one
the average person would love, but is more for fans of the genre.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>