<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La regina delle Amazzoni</original_title><alt_title>La reine des Amazones</alt_title><imdb_rating>3.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Vittorio Sala</director><producer>Galatea Film</producer><producer>Glomer Film</producer><producer>Alta Vista</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
Two musclemen come up against a tribe of Amazon women.
</synopsis><actor>Rod Taylor</actor><actor>Ed Fury</actor><actor>Dorian Gray</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4807563/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>grghull</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The music score, which ranges from boogie-woogie to a sort of sleazy
Vegas romance music, cues you in right away that this is not a movie to
be taken seriously. Rod Taylor (as a sort of low-life grifter) and Ed
Fury (his muscle-man pal) find themselves prisoners of a tribe of man
hungry amazons. Gender bending comedy abounds (male prisoners who've
grown accustomed to their fate exchange recipes and complain about not
getting their laundry "sparkling", all with swishy mannerisms and camp
voices --- very un-PC and funny as hell) along with low-brow slapstick.
Viewers tuning in to a movie entitled COLOSSUS AND THE AMAZON QUEEN
expecting thoughtful, serious drama will of course be disappointed.
Those with more realistic expectations may find this a delight.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1919094/comments</url><from>from New York, USA</from><name>Steve Nyland (Squonkamatic)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This movie is cool! It's kind of dumb but it is really cool. Like,
there are these dudes, and they are like, Gladiators &amp; stuff?? And they
go on a boat somewhere, I don't know where, and it like, crashes &amp;
stuff. The guys all find themselves stranded on this island, you know,
and it's like BABE CITY!! There are only hot Italian B-actresses on the whole island, and they
all dress like the sluts in CALIGULA only nobody gets cut in half or
has Macolm McDowall put his ring where the sun don't shine on them. I
like all female society movies, especially when they are populated by
creamy, olive skinned, sharp nosed and firm bosomed Italian actresses
who's voices are dubbed into English. So I consider myself lucky: I
hope someday you get to find a movie that looks like it was pretty much
made with you in mind.So like, these Gladiator dudes are kind of funny. They have all these
heroic missions and are all like, former soldiers or something who
treat each other like they are closer than brothers. And they all dress
like Freddy Mercury from that Queen tour after NEWS OF THE WORLD, which
was such a cool album. But what I mean is that, like, they all run
around in tights and leather tunics, have big spears and big muscles
and always look sweaty or oiled, yet not one of them is gay. Not even
by a long shot. The movie is even kind of a silly comedy at times with
wacky noise effects and a talking parrot, but there isn't any of the
stuff that Oliver Stone found so necessary. And everywhere you look,
BABES!!And what babes they are. Jessica Simpson and Scarlett Johanssen and
Natalie Portman are like, twits from the underclass study hall compared
to the graceful, full figured 1960 era knockouts populating this very
sexist and male oriented entertainment. The women throw themselves at
these guys, sometimes quite literally, and since there are only about
eight of them and a whole island full of these women I would expect
that we'd see a working example of that male to female ratio thing that
Peter Sellers talked about in DR. STRANGELOVE about needing women with
exceedingly attractive characteristics, which sort of makes sense if
you hope to re-populate the world with the President and maybe the guys
who run Haliburton. Maybe this is where they got their inspiration for
Strangelove's speech. Because with an estimated female to male ratio of
about 35 to 1 -- and all of them hot -- these Gladiators had better not
be gay, or else there are going to be a lot of unhappy faces in the
morning.Look for this movie on a 50 Movie/12 DVD box set from Treeline Films
called SCI FI CLASSICS: It's a mucky fullframe English print that looks
like someone used it to hang their laundry on before the video transfer
was done, but it beats the hell out of anything that's been released
this year in the theaters so far, and there are what, 48 more to go??7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17450631/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>kurtwil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This whacky sword and sandal epic from Italy makes the rounds in
low-budget DVD collections (all from the same battered video dub of a
16mm print - Mill Creek's version has color correction). The plot's
been described elsewhere, but for this viewer the flick's over-the-top
acting and absurd music offered campish fun with a fast pace and some
clever if dated takeoffs. Rod Taylor detested this movie, but his
acting's fun, slap-stick-ish and done with style. Some plot elements
are bizarre (one character using a complex apparatus to light a fire by
activating it with a burning torch!!) but work if you remember film's
for comedy and don't go into deep analysis mode. Some outdoor shots and
dances in this film appear in other Italian Sword and Sandal movies (or
possibly it was the other way around). Those wanting politically
correct films should put this one back on the shelf and look elsewhere!
Otherwise, ignore the politically incorrectness and have fun!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2707735/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>classicsoncall</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
It would be hard to imagine this film as anything more than a parody of
the Hercules/gladiator genre, but it fails miserably even at that. I
can't believe that the film makers had anything remotely sensible in
mind when they patched this thing together, or if they even had an
overall working outline of what they were trying to do. The result is a
poorly executed picture that meanders between action and comedy, but
the outcome is simply embarrassing.At least if you have to watch this to complete the fifty movie DVD set
from Mill Creek/Tree Line Films, the lead characters are pleasing on
the eyes. Ed Fury is the main muscle man named Glauco, who has an eye
for Antiope, the would be queen who wants to replace La Regina (Gianna
Maria Canale). Glauco's sidekick Pirro (Rod Taylor) is busy chasing
down Melitta (Daniella Rocca), as the two women engage in a contest for
the 'sacred girdle'. A band of pirates and a wrestling bear also make
appearances for reasons that seem entirely irrelevant.The other point has to do with the musical score, it really had no
connection to the events happening on screen; most of the time it had a
'Gilligan's Island' feel to it. The thought just occurred to me that
watching the picture in reverse probably would make just as much sense
as watching it normally. However I use the term figuratively, there's
no way to watch this film normally.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7625363/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Son_Of_Hercules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Glaucus and Pirrus are two friends returning to Greece from the Trojan
War. Glaucus, played by Ed Fury, is the burly muscleman, a good natured
one-man army. Pirrus, played by Rod Taylor, is the smooth-talking
con-artist, more a lover than a fighter.The two friends are drugged by some shifty merchants and sold to the
Amazons as slaves. It doesn't take them long to ingratiate themselves
to the Amazons and eventually shake up the entire Amazonian nation.I have no idea how anyone could watch this movie and NOT understand
that it's a comedy. It's full of slapstick, puns, punch-lines, and
one-liners. There's a crazy Egyptian inventor who adds more comic
relief. The music is more often than not entirely unlike the standard
peplum sound track, with everything from ragtime to jazz to cha-cha. As
a matter of fact the ubiquitous harem girl dance is presented as a
combination sophisticated jazz performance and a take-off on a
Buzby-Berkley number. Since this takes place mostly in Amazonian
society the roles of men and women are reversed and you have the men
staying at home and raising the kids, cooking, doing laundry and
gossiping about each other. In its own way, believe it or not, it's
also, a sex comedy of sorts. (No really!)Eventually the men and women realize that they are better off living
together as equals, once they team up to fend off a pirate invasion and
Glaucus wrestles a bear.Anyone who has a genuine fondness for peplums would really enjoy this
movie. It doesn't take itself seriously at all. Instead it pokes a
little fun at the genre. It's just good natured, self-effacing fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
"Ed Fury stars as Glauco, the strongest man in Greece who finds himself
the unwilling member of an expedition across the seas. His pal Pirro
(Rod Taylor) accepts money from a band of pirates in return for
Glauco's undeniable muscle. When they land, they are drugged and
captured by a race of Amazons. Only Glauco escapes and falls in love
with the fair Antiope. After considerable action and intrigue, the
Amazons and Greeks learn to get along," according to the DVD sleeve's
synopsis.Re-titled "Colossus and the Amazon Queen" for English language
listeners, this "sword and sandal" epic benefits by not taking itself
too seriously. Bulging in all the right places, Mr. Fury is a blond
Adonis-like hero. While Fury strikes the correct light-hearted tone,
the more accomplished co-starring Mr. Taylor seems uncertain about the
sexual preference assigned his character. He acts gay, but goes for
breast-popping Daniela Rocca (as Melitta) over Fury, who digs
delectable Dorian Gray.***** La regina delle Amazzoni (9/8/60) Vittorio Sala ~ Ed Fury, Rod
Taylor, Daniela Rocca, Dorian Gray
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0358724/comments</url><from>from Metairie, La</from><name>Thomas Diemer (itd01@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I rate this movie as pretty good. The action part of the plot was not
bad for such fare - after all sword and sandal epics were not known for
top notch plots or dialog, but the attempt at humor were simply stupid.
It would have been a much better movie without them. The budget
obviously left no room for retakes; I noticed three goofs: A trumpeter
at the very beginning dropped his trumpet then picked it up; the queen
once had to lower her head to stifle a giggle and the high priestess
tripped over something.The attack of the horse mounted freed male slaves on the Amazon city
reminded me a lot of the Indian attacks on wagon trains in old
television and movie westerns I found the use of the beatnik style jazz sound track in this ancient
Greece set movie kind of interesting. So was the extended avant garde
dance sequence in the middle. Very "Bohemian". So bad it is good you
might say.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

This is horrible.I've seen pretty much every muscle man movie made in the 1950's and 1960's
and this is at the bottom of the list.First off the dubbing is terrible. The cliche of Japanese monster movies are
nothing compared to this. Secondly its suppose to be a comedy. It appears to have been written and
acted as one, unfortunately there is nothing funny about it. The problem is
that these films run so close to parody as is that its pointless to make fun
of them. The only one that ever worked was the original version of My Son
The Hero, which was a good movie even without the humor.Lastly the sets, costumes, ect are overly bad. Again these films run the
fine line between reality and parody. Its all of a style that took hold and
effectively killed off the genre about five years after this was produced
where spandex, beehive hairdos and Max Factor make-up made everything look
silly.The plot, concerning two muscle men and their encounters with the Amazons is
stupid and comes from the low sex comedies that rarely traveled outside of
Italy because they were more juvenile than funny.Its over acted and under done.One out of ten. Its just bad.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0863093/comments</url><from>from Seattle, WA</from><name>Steve O.</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Many of the Italian peplum (sword &amp; sandal) movies from the period
1959- 1965 are unintentionally funny, but this one is made as a spoof.
It's not great but it's different enough to make it pretty
entertaining.Unlike most pepla, this one focuses more on cheescake than beefcake.
Colossus, the Hercules character, is played by a slim Ed Fury who looks
like he hasn't been to the gym in a while. He's no more built than the
other men in the film, and his role is surprisingly small.Most of the story concerns his comrade, a wily mercenary played by a
very hammy Rod Taylor (the leading man of Hitchcock's THE BIRDS) who
enjoys being captured by a tribe of gorgeous Amazons.The Amazons turn their captives into male housewives, cooking, sewing,
and doing housework for the women. There is much role-reversal comedy
where the men act and speak like put-upon wives -- some of this is
actually funny. There are a number of bizarre touches like a talking
parrot, never explained, that sometimes comments on the action, and an
insane musical score made up of 1960s lounge-type jazz and hackneyed
"funny movie" music of the kind used in bad TV sitcoms during the
sixties.This movie has mercifully little of the elements that make so many
pepla boring: (a) endless battle scenes of soldiers, horses, and
plebeians rushing back and forth, where you don't know or care who's
fighting who, and (b) long dialog scenes about court intrigue that are
as convoluted as they are irrelevant.Peplum fans should definitely check this out for its peculiar
differences from the run-of-the-mill muscle man flicks. It should also
appeal to those who feel there's too much male flesh on display in most
pepla and not enough female. This movie is all about hot Amazon babes
in revealing outfits, led by their gorgeous, sultry queen (who
resembles a young Joan Collins). Absurd scenes like a girl fight
sequence are included just to up the cheesecake factor.Not great, but for the most part good fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2098959/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>papccs</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This is absolutely the worst movie ever made, and not just in this
genre. The actors look like props and act like robots. The dubbing is
laughable and makes the Japanese movie dubbing appear to be most
excellent.It is difficult to tell if this movie was intended as a comedy, or
supposed to be an adventure movie, since the whole thing is laughable
and it is hard to tell when the plot and acting is supposed to be
funny, since all of it is ludicrous. The acting is so atrocious, that
at times it becomes funny. This movie is/was most appropriate for fans
of Mystery 3000 Theater, in which Crowe, and his companions sat
watching as they ridiculed the film.This movie begs the question, 'Why was it made," and I can only surmise
the producer and director were on hallucinogenic drugs. Nothing in this
movie suggests that anyone had any idea why they made it. The whole
thing is either like a bad nightmare, or, an LSD trip gone bad. If you
like to sit and make fun of the movie with your friends, add your own
comments.If you can get over the fact that this movie actually had a screen
writer, a script, and nothing but idiots running around on the screen
without the slightest clue on why they are being filmed, forget the bad
colour, you may be able to stomach it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2098959/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>papccs</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This is absolutely the worst movie ever made, and not just in this
genre. The actors look like props and act like robots. The dubbing is
laughable and makes the Japanese movie dubbing appear to be most
excellent.It is difficult to tell if this movie was intended as a comedy, or
supposed to be an adventure movie, since the whole thing is laughable
and it is hard to tell when the plot and acting is supposed to be
funny, since all of it is ludicrous. The acting is so atrocious, that
at times it becomes funny. This movie is/was most appropriate for fans
of Mystery 3000 Theater, in which Crowe, and his companions sat
watching as they ridiculed the film.This movie begs the question, 'Why was it made," and I can only surmise
the producer and director were on hallucinogenic drugs. Nothing in this
movie suggests that anyone had any idea why they made it. The whole
thing is either like a bad nightmare, or, an LSD trip gone bad. If you
like to sit and make fun of the movie with your friends, add your own
comments.If you can get over the fact that this movie actually had a screen
writer, a script, and nothing but idiots running around on the screen
without the slightest clue on why they are being filmed, forget the bad
colour, you may be able to stomach it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-oehley/</url><url>http://www.movie-gurus.com/content/reviews/c/1518/index.html /m/colossus_and_the_amazon_queen/comments.php?reviewid=1350068</url><name>James O'Ehley</name><from>Movie Gurus</from></reviewer><comment>Should be a gay cult classic if it isn't one already . . . </comment></review></movie>