<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La rivolta degli schiavi</original_title><alt_title>Les révolte des esclaves</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Spain</country><country>Italy</country><country>West Germany</country><director>Nunzio Malasomma</director><producer>Ambrosiana Cinematografica</producer><producer>C.B. Films S.A.</producer><producer>Ultra Film</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>The revels... the ravages - the revolt of the ages!</synopsis><actor>Rhonda Fleming</actor><actor>Lang Jeffries</actor><actor>Darío Moreno</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0291062/comments</url><from>from Minneapolis</from><name>dinky-4</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Those Biblical "epics" of the 1950's and early 1960's usually fell into
two categories. There were the lavish, big-studio productions such as
"Quo Vadis" and "The Robe" and then there were the lesser,
sword-and-sandal productions exemplified by the "Hercules" movies."Revolt of the Slaves" is one of the few productions to fall in between
these two categories. It has the big-budget look of a Hollywood
spectacle -- sharp wide-screen photography, handsome sets and costumes,
etc. -- coupled with the kind of script and direction more closely
identified with those made-in-Italy mini-epics.Even the star of the show, Rhonda Fleming, is something of an
"in-betweener." She's not quite up in the Deborah Kerr or Jean Simmons
league but she's clearly a notch above, say, Sylva Koscina.
Unfortunately, she's about ten years too old to be playing this part,
especially since she's matched with an obviously-younger Lang Jeffries.
(Though about to be married in real life, there's not much on-screen
chemistry between these two.)As is often the case with these pious-Christians-vs-pagan-Romans
affairs, the plot works best when it's content to be an adventure or a
romance but turns stilted and even a bit cloying when the religious
angle is stressed.One item of note: the scene early in the movie when slave-boy Lang
Jeffries is whipped across his bare chest is unusually well-staged,
especially in terms of the physical relationship between the whipper,
the whippee, and the camera. Seeing this scene on TV without the
benefit of letter-boxing will not do it justice. (It ranks 2nd in the
book "Lash! The Hundred Great Scenes of Men Being Whipped in the
Movies.") Jeffries also feels the sting of a whip in "Alone Against
Rome" but this time on his bare back, thus making him one of the few
actors in screen history to be flogged on both sides of his torso.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1113565/comments</url><from>from Steubenville, Ohio</from><name>JLarson2006</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Revolt of the Slaves is loosely based on a famous novel called Fabiola
written by Cardinal Wiseman in the 1850s.  It strays drastically from the
original story, keeping some of the same characters (in particular the
martyrs Sebastian and Agnes), and some of the same scenes, but downplaying
martyrdom as a whole, and trying to make a movie that could be called
"Vibio
saves the Christians."  The "Vibio" character is not part of the Fabiola
story.  He is introduced as a slave who is also a Christian, but he isn't
about to be a martyr.  He rescues Christians a number of times throughout
the movie.  Action scenes are everywhere in this movie, and every one of
them is added--none are from the book.I loved the book Fabiola, and I found this to be a deconstruction of it,
not
only in story but in philosophy.  The screenwriters had some sympathy for
the Christians, and portrayed them somewhat positively, but wanted to make
them safe and happy in this world.  If you know anything about the
Diocletian persecution, Christians were anything but safe in those days.
Faith is present in some of the characters, and it comes in handy, but
physical combat seems to be the preferred mode of doing business.  This
movie had potential, but it was just Hercules vs. the pagan
Romans.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3747472/comments</url><from>from michigan</from><name>mhrabovsky1-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a typical "sword and sandal" so called "epic" of the early
1960s when these roman rebellion movies were being churned out by the
tons by Italian producers. Steve (Mr. Hercules himself) Reeves got this
sword and sandal stuff going with his movies "Hercules" and "Hercules
Unchained"....to great and smashing box office success. Italian
producers then on skimpy budgets hired cheap Italian actors and
actresses occasionally thrown in with an American star, such as in this
film with Rhonda Fleming to improve the box office. The movies were
always about a city of people oppressed by the ruling clan and usually
had a well muscled down actor to lead the people in a revolt. In this
film, Lang Jeffries lacks the physique of Steve Reeves or Mark Forrest,
but does an admirable job as the leader of a band of slaves....he leads
them on a rebellion to stop persecution by Roman rulers...along the way
a love/hate relationship develops between Fleming and Jeffries....and
yes they fall in love. Typical of the sword and sandal movies, evil
rulers, mean soldiers, whippings, and a slave revolt. If you like the
peplum you will like this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3747472/comments</url><from>from michigan</from><name>mhrabovsky1-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a typical "sword and sandal" so called "epic" of the early
1960s when these roman rebellion movies were being churned out by the
tons by Italian producers. Steve (Mr. Hercules himself) Reeves got this
sword and sandal stuff going with his movies "Hercules" and "Hercules
Unchained"....to great and smashing box office success. Italian
producers then on skimpy budgets hired cheap Italian actors and
actresses occasionally thrown in with an American star, such as in this
film with Rhonda Fleming to improve the box office. The movies were
always about a city of people oppressed by the ruling clan and usually
had a well muscled down actor to lead the people in a revolt. In this
film, Lang Jeffries lacks the physique of Steve Reeves or Mark Forrest,
but does an admirable job as the leader of a band of slaves....he leads
them on a rebellion to stop persecution by Roman rulers...along the way
a love/hate relationship develops between Fleming and Jeffries....and
yes they fall in love. Typical of the sword and sandal movies, evil
rulers, mean soldiers, whippings, and a slave revolt. If you like the
peplum you will like this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3747472/comments</url><from>from michigan</from><name>mhrabovsky1-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>