<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Crimen</original_title><alt_title>Chacun son alibi</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Mario Camerini</director><producer>Dino de Laurentiis Cinematografica</producer><producer>Orsay Films</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
Sei persone sono sullo stesso treno, in viaggio dall'Italia verso Montecarlo. Alcuni vorrebbero giocare (e vincere) al Casinò...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Alberto Sordi</actor><actor>Vittorio Gassman</actor><actor>Nino Manfredi</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15445210/comments</url><from/><name>Diogenes81</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Seven Italians - Remo (Vittorio Gassman) and Marina (Silvana Mangano),
Quirino (Nino Manfredi) and Giovanna (Franca Valeri), and Alberto
(Alberto Sordi) - are arrested in Montecarlo for the gruesome murder of
an old, rich woman. Quirino and Giovanna have been found near the crime
scene with the victim's dog; Marina and Remo have been arrested with
the corpse in their suitcase; Alberto had met them all in the previous
day and had a grudge against the victim. The Inspector (Bernard Blier)
investigates...The performance by the all-star cast make the movie so enjoyable. These
seven giants of Italian comedy play the wretched imbeciles who become
accidentally involved in the investigation, and yet, as they clumsily
try to lie out of fear of the police, see the incredible amount of
clues against them piling up. In particular, Sordi, Gassman and
Manfredi are brilliant. French character actor Blier (seen with Sordi
also in Riusciranno i nostri eroi) plays the inspector.Very enjoyable.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11983563/comments</url><from>from NYC suburbs</from><name>melvelvit-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Three Italian couples cross paths on a train to Monte Carlo and later
find themselves implicated in the murder of a rich old woman. Although
innocent, the more they lie and try to alibi -rather than simply tell
the truth- the more they incriminate themselves...This all-star Italian farce is really just a showcase for the comedic
talents of Alberto Sordi, Nino Manfredi, Vittorio Gassman, and Silvana
Mangano. Manfredi and his wife travel to Monte Carlo to return a lost
dog to its dowager owner and stumble upon her body; they flee but leave
their suitcase behind. Gassman and Mangano play beauticians hoping to
hit it big at roulette so they can open their own salon but lose their
stake and steal Manfredi's suitcase which now contains the old lady's
corpse. Alberto Sordi, a professional gambler who teams up with amateur
Gassman, is placed at the scene of the crime because his wife, Dorian
Gray, can't alibi him as she was entertaining another man at the time.
How these characters interact and implicate the more they try to
extricate themselves provides the film with a number of amusing
"Italians abroad" situations but not enough to sustain any real
momentum. Filmed in 1961 but not released in the U.S. until 1964,
CRIMEN was produced by Mangano's husband, Dino De Laurentiis, and tries
to invert the conventions of Agatha Christie whodunnits for laughs. Not
laugh-out-loud funny by any means but OK in an unexceptional way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11983563/comments</url><from>from NYC suburbs</from><name>melvelvit-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Three Italian couples cross paths on a train to Monte Carlo and later
find themselves implicated in the murder of a rich old woman. Although
innocent, the more they lie and try to alibi -rather than simply tell
the truth- the more they incriminate themselves...This all-star Italian farce is really just a showcase for the comedic
talents of Alberto Sordi, Nino Manfredi, Vittorio Gassman, and Silvana
Mangano. Manfredi and his wife travel to Monte Carlo to return a lost
dog to its dowager owner and stumble upon her body; they flee but leave
their suitcase behind. Gassman and Mangano play beauticians hoping to
hit it big at roulette so they can open their own salon but lose their
stake and steal Manfredi's suitcase which now contains the old lady's
corpse. Alberto Sordi, a professional gambler who teams up with amateur
Gassman, is placed at the scene of the crime because his wife, Dorian
Gray, can't alibi him as she was entertaining another man at the time.
How these characters interact and implicate the more they try to
extricate themselves provides the film with a number of amusing
"Italians abroad" situations but not enough to sustain any real
momentum. Filmed in 1961 but not released in the U.S. until 1964,
CRIMEN was produced by Mangano's husband, Dino De Laurentiis, and tries
to invert the conventions of Agatha Christie whodunnits for laughs. Not
laugh-out-loud funny by any means but OK in an unexceptional way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>