<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Gli amori di Ercole</original_title><alt_title>Les amours d'Hercule</alt_title><imdb_rating>2.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Carlo Ludovico Bragaglia</director><producer>Contact Organisation</producer><producer>Grandi Schermi Italiani</producer><producer>Paris Interproductions (PIP)</producer><genre>Fantasy</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
Hercules must save his true love from an evil queen.
</synopsis><actor>Jayne Mansfield</actor><actor>Mickey Hargitay</actor><actor>Massimo Serato</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2232026/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon</from><name>Greg Couture</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Years ago I managed to catch this one on a Saturday morning TV broadcast and
watched it through to the end, with an amused smile.  As other comments here
attest, it's definitely not one of the better sword-and-sandal epics and, if
you're a fan of that genre, you'd better appreciate what Jayne Mansfield has
to offer should you give it a look-see.  Like so many others in this canon,
it's one of the tombstones marking the declining careers of Hollywood
expatriates.A side note:  In the early 1960s Carol Burnett, in a one-woman engagement,
appeared at the Greek Theater (an outdoor ampitheater, northeast of downtown
Hollywood in Griffith Park, which each year had a summer season of big-name
acts, ballet companies, fully-mounted operas, etc.) and, as part of her
show, she did a very funny bit in which she imagined Jayne Mansfield
accepting her Academy Award as Best Actress in a Hercules extravaganza.  In
her acceptance speech Carol/Jayne recreated a scene and I can still remember
her screeching: "Hercules! Hercules! Put me DOWN!!"  Got a BIG laugh.  Carol
must have used this film as her inspiration, for in it there's a scene
toward the end where Mickey is rescuing Jayne from some peril or other and
he appears to be staggering under the totality of her considerable assets. 
Before they had left for Italy, Jayne and Mickey had frequently performed a
stunt, well-documented in filmed interviews, in which Mickey effortlessly
lifted Jayne overhead and paraded her around airplane-style.  His seeming
inability to recreate that feat in this movie is one of the film's comic
highpoints for this viewer.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9693729/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, California</from><name>sos12</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
HERCULES VS. THE HYDRA definitely ranks in the top 5 of the hundreds of
Hercules films made in Italy in the 1960's (the others being HERCULES
IN THE HAUNTED WORLD; the original Steve Reeves HERCULES; THE FURY OF
HERCULES; the delirious THE WITCH'S CURSE; and the equally gonzo
HERCULES PRISONER OF EVIL.) But back to HYDRA -- first, you've got
Jayne Mansfield and Mickey Hargitay, and the fact that they eventually
married, and that Mansfield died tragically, lends an undeniable
poignancy to this movie. There's no way around it, it's part of
Hollywood history, and it makes this a very melancholy portrait of two
people falling in love. Second, there's Hargitay -- and dammit, he's a
REALLY GOOD Hercules, possibly the best on a pure acting level (and
Hargitay wasn't really an actor, so that's saying something.) He's
dubbed (of course), but there's a real emotional yearning quality that
comes across here, and he puts his heart and soul into almost every
scene. Watch a bunch of the other Hercules actors and you'll see what I
mean. Best of all, the movie veers off into delirious Alexander Ptushko
territory about halfway through, when Herc encounters the three-headed
Hydra in the land of the Amazons. Anyone who loves Ray Harryhausen type
fantasy films will get a kick out of this one. The weird-ass forest of
human trees is especially good. Definitely a winner.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0909646/comments</url><from>from Hendersonville, TN</from><name>William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

SPOILER AHEAD:   There are two things which endear this movie to me: the
mythology aspect and Jayne Mansfield, one of Hollywood's lost goddesses. The
movie is really substandard and campy fare with limited effects, and Mickey
Hargitay does pull off a fair Hercules, but it is Jayne which makes this
movie bearable. She plays Hercules' true love Deianeira, who you should know
if you've seen the American 90s television series. When a female sorceress
trying to vamp Hargitay as Hercules, she ends up transforming herself into
Mansfield, and next you have Jayne's spectacular figure bound up in another
costume as if it is about to explode.Much of the story, however is just
filler until Hercules meets the Hydra, which is a major let down. The
creature is too fake and there's not much real action. The dubbed-in voices
are as obvious as the phony Hydra. I'd only really see this if you're a
Jayne fan like I am.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5721415/comments</url><from>from Hollywood, United States</from><name>tseybert</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I love Italian movies, and the sword-and-sandal epics constitute a very
special subset of this, the greatest of all national cinemas. There is
something hysterical or nonsensical going on every minute. Don't blink
your eyes, or you'll miss Jayne Mansfield with PURPLE HAIR. AT HER
Fiancée'S FUNERAL! Then there's the Hydra, with only three heads, that
can barely move, and Mickey Hargitay (as Hercules, natch) has to run
around like an idiot and pretend to be crushed under its foot. Then he
gets rescued by cave-dwelling, bird-headed Amazons who turn men into
trees ... for some reason. And if that doesn't do anything for you,
wait until you see Bigfoot! Jayne Mansfield has huge breasts, though.
And she's really pretty. So we forgive her. (Did anybody see "Primitive
Love"? Now that's a cult movie!) This movie cracks me up, even more
than "Hercules Against the Sons of the Sun." I have to give it a TEN!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0633432/comments</url><from/><name>Lars von Hegnet (von@apros.dk)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

The totally rare Danish videorelease of this "trashy" film is full screen
running 96.00 mins precisely. Italian tv channel RaiUno showed a
letterboxed
print(1: 1.70 cirka) the other day
running ½ a minnute shorter. The 2 versions features a whole bunch of
scenes
filmed from different/alternative angles and many are diff/alternative
takes. Quite "interesting" to compare actually...if you are into this sort
of movie-watching.
One scene found only in the Danish version shows Miss mansfield
(hidden behind some see-through cloth)covering her naked body with some
clothes. Extremely...uuhuuhhh...daring!!!!!
I give it 5 out of 10.....but "reflecting" on it afterwards is
worth a good laugh and....10 !!! Cheers sandal-genre comrades!!!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Perfectly awful peplum/Hercules-movie: you know you're in trouble when
leading lady Jayne Mansfield's prominent bust (forever on the verge of
bursting through her togas) commands greater attention than the plot,
the action or the special effects!; of course, the fact that the
muscular hero is played by her real-life husband – Mickey Hargitay –
adds to the fun quotient (of the unintentional kind, that is)…for
rarely has there ever been an actor so clueless as to how approach this
mythical part! Usually seen as a blonde, Mansfield here dons a black and a red wig:
she appears as a couple of sovereigns – the heroine and an Amazonian
(though the latter is technically played by another actress who takes
up Mansfield's appearance via a magic potion in order to ensnare
Hargitay). Of mild interest is the fact that the latter has a penchant
of disposing of her lovers by having them turned into living trees – as
if one needed further proof of how wooden this thing could be, the plot
here takes it to a literal level! The chief villainous role in this one
is entrusted to Massimo Serato, often a reliable presence in this type
of flick, but in this case sporting long curly hair – which only serves
to enhance the film's overriding camp factor. Also in the cast, as one
of Serato's advisors, is Giulio Donnini from the obscure peplum FRINE,
CORTIGIANA D'ORIENTE (1953) – which I watched as part of last month's
"Epic Movie Challenge" (in time for the Easter period); incidentally, I
had intended to rent the 5-Disc/7-Film set among which this was
included back then but it wasn't available.By the way, THE LOVES OF HERCULES was also known as HERCULES VS. THE
HYDRA: this monster, which appears fairly on in the game, is one of the
worst of its kind ever constructed – what's the point of having a
three-headed menace if lopping one of them off kills it instantly!
Indeed, the mechanical creation is so bulky that it can barely move and
so obviously fake that one is liable to burst out laughing at the mere
sight of it, as I did, thus effectively destroying the illusion of the
entire scene! Another hilarious obstacle the hero has to overcome
during the course of the film is a meek-looking cow absurdly sprayed
black by the penny-pinching film-makers in a lousy attempt to pass it
off for a menacing bull!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1197445/comments</url><from>from Columbia County, NY</from><name>Flixer1957 (flixer1957@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

**Possible Spoilers Ahead**Former Mr. Universe Mickey Hargitay takes his turn as the top-grossing
strong-man of the early 1960s.  At the beginning of the film he goes
gallivanting off and leaves his wife unprotected.  Smart move, Herc.
She's
murdered and our muscle-bound, muscle-headed hero is out for revenge.  The
hydra of some titles turns out to be a giant, triple-headed dragon that
guards the gate to the underworld.  It has all the mobility of a washing
machine and just sits there nodding its heads and looking stupid as
Hercules
runs up and kills it.  The loves of another title are Queen Deinera
(brunette Jayne Mansfield) and evil amazon queen Hippolyta (red-haired
Jayne
Mansfield).  Hippolyta has the nasty habit of turning her lovers into
talking trees when she's tired of them.  The actors playing the tree-men,
ironically, give the least wooden performances in the picture.  Mansfield,
a
blonde in most pictures, manages to be equally dopey as a brunette and a
redhead.  However, on this production, there was plenty of dopiness to go
around.  Hubby Hargitay hardly comes across as a rocket scientist.  The
director, writers and whoever did the deplorable dubbing weren't too swift
either.  When this lulu aired on AMC in 1999 they followed it with 1960s
Hercules cartoons, clips from drive-in intermissions and home-movie
footage
of Mansfield trying to touch her toes while wearing high heels.  I don't
know which was funniest.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0377491/comments</url><from>from Glasglow, Scotland</from><name>Tails-3</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>

The sound is terrible! Not until Dr. Zhivago did I ever hear such a
hellishly awful soundtrack! Anyway, Jayne Mansfield plays a back-to-back
role as a queen of Greece (in a red wig) and an evil Amazon queen (in a
black wig.) Mickey Hargitay plays the burly demigod Hercules, who must save
the good Jayne from the evil Jayne. Meanwhile, the villagers act like
babbling simps. Overall I didn't care for it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0377491/comments</url><from>from Glasglow, Scotland</from><name>Tails-3</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>

The sound is terrible! Not until Dr. Zhivago did I ever hear such a
hellishly awful soundtrack! Anyway, Jayne Mansfield plays a back-to-back
role as a queen of Greece (in a red wig) and an evil Amazon queen (in a
black wig.) Mickey Hargitay plays the burly demigod Hercules, who must save
the good Jayne from the evil Jayne. Meanwhile, the villagers act like
babbling simps. Overall I didn't care for it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0377491/comments</url><from>from Glasglow, Scotland</from><name>Tails-3</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/loves_of_hercules/comments.php?reviewid=1426549</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>