<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Pote tin Kyriaki</original_title><alt_title>Jamais le dimanche</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Greece</country><country>USA</country><director>Jules Dassin</director><producer>Lopert Pictures Corporation</producer><producer>Melinafilm</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
An American scholar in Greece sets about improving a prostitute he's infatuated with.
</synopsis><actor>Melina Mercouri</actor><actor>Jules Dassin</actor><actor>Giorgos Foundas</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4340008/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Holdjerhorses</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
No one else in the history of cinema became a star in America playing a
sexpot at the age of 40. Melina Mercouri did. "Never on Sunday" is why.Aided immeasurably by Manos Hadjidakis' unforgettable score (you're
probably already humming the theme) and Jules Dassin's story,
Mercouri's incredible presence stole the show -- and hearts worldwide.Dassin is perfect in what would be the "nebbish" role, were he Jewish.
The Greeks have, perhaps, 27 words for "nebbish" as they do for "love."
Dassin brilliantly inhabits one of them.Rarely has the energy and life force of a particular time and place
been so economically and delightfully captured on film.There's a reason "Never on Sunday" is a legend and part of every
serious film lover's collection. Once you've seen it, you'll know.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0068788/comments</url><from/><name>Boyo-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Melina Mercouri takes an often-played role - the 'Whore with a Heart of Gold
who Loves Life Despite It All' - and makes it her career-defining movie
role, and she is the entire reason to watch the movie.  Fiercely
independent, sexually progressive, not spending her life trying to find the
perfect man and gorgeous, she's a force of life.  Jules Dassin has directed a great movie but he should have hired an actor to
play Homer, and not played it himself.  He almost ruins all the charm the
movie has going for it with his ineffective acting, bad line readings and
stupid motivations.  A better actor might have found a way around the rough
spots but Dassin magnifies them. Mercouri probably should have won Best Actress that year, but who can beat a
Liz Taylor death scare?  Plus Simeone Signoret had won Best Actress the year
before, and Sophia Loren would win the following year..you don't want to
upset icons like Louella Parsons, Frank Sinatra and John Wayne by giving ALL
the Oscars to foreigners, do you??  Maybe the fact that she does not die at
the end was too much..we all know the odds of longevity for a hooker in a
Hollywood movie.  Taylor met that criteria, as if she needed to help her own
odds after almost dying of pneumonia. Worth watching for sure.  8/10. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11627100/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>smits59</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Never on Sunday is a beautiful, down to earth, romantic comedy. It's a
feel-good movie without the Hollywood over-sweetness. A well to do
American is educated by a Greek courtesan who is not so sophisticated
but full of life. And life proves to be more important then money or
sophistication. And there even is a happy ending even though is one
with a tear, if you a a sucker for such things. The music is prefect.
The title-song is just great. The scenery makes you want to got to
Greece for your next holiday. In an nutshell; this is one Greek
Delight. Watch it on a cold Sunday and you'll get all warm inside.
Watch it on a hot summers-night and you'll believe your in Greece
already.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7703840/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>reebee11</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
One of my all-time favorite movies! Coming from the 50's generation, I
remember seeing this movie when I was a teenager and being absolutely
fascinated by the Greek setting, music and dancing. I believe that this
movie contributed to my interest in foreign movies to this day. The
song "Never on Sunday" was very popular on the radio in the 60's. If
you don't remember it now, you probably will, once you hear it. The story line in this movie is clever and charming. The variety of
characters pull you right into the story. It's dramatic, funny and at
the same time, romantic. Tame by today's standards, this movie must
have been considered very risqué for its time, but it remains
entertaining to this day.....timeless!!! A must-see for old movie
buffs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1098460/comments</url><from>from Virginia, USA</from><name>Galina</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Melina Mercouri, "The Last Greek Goddess", stars in the comedy "Never
on Sunday"(1960) directed/written by Jules Dassin. She plays Illia, the
most sensuous and radiant "lady of the night" in the seaport Pyres
where every man adores her and she is the one who chooses her partners.
Mercouri was 40 years old when she played Illia but she did not hide a
single day of her age and she was gorgeous, full of the inner fire and
absolutely irresistible. When the new Pygmalion, the intellectual
American named Homer (of course) sails into the town and meets Illia,
he decides that his search for meaning of life would end in Pyres if he
would reform Illia and make her change her way of life. With all his
intellect and education he couldn't understand a very simple truth
about Illia - only true love might change her. Homer played by
director/writer Jules Dassin is the weakest part of this mostly
charming comedy. I agree with one of the IMDb commenters who said that
"Jules Dassin has directed a great movie but he should have hired an
actor to play Homer, and not played it himself... A better actor might
have found a way around the rough spots but Dassin magnifies them." I
guess that in real life Dassin was much more charming that in the film
because he and Mercouri were married in 1966 and stayed married until
her death in 1994.7.5/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8286515/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mannida</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I first experienced "Never on Sunday" shortly after I had visited
Greece while in the US Navy. I loved the movie because of the
atmosphere which it caught so well. Ilia was like so many of the Greek
women and a wonderful character. The sensitive and skillful direction
of Jules Dassin ranks as one of the best efforts I can remember in a
film because of the humor and pathos he managed to combine and capture
as well as the great love of life of the Greek people. The wonderful
characterization makes the film a joy to watch. I have seen it
countless times and each time it has been a delightful experience. The
wonderful title song is quintessentially Greek that is a tune that I
still adore and go back to, often humming for days. The plot is simple,
direct and charming. The love of life that Melina Mercouri demonstrates
in her performance is one to envied, admired and emulated. She was a
truly gifted actress and Greek treasure. This is a must see film for
anyone who loves life and all it can hold.David Manning
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2084838/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>warmlands</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I believe so many of the reviewers have lost the true fun of the film.
Of course the character that Jules Dasson is a chowderhead without much
in the way of character. He seems to see himself as a great reformer.
When I first saw the film in 1950, I thought he was terrible, but
seeing the film again I realize that the character must be this way to
show the difference between him, and the people of Greece.The fat whores in the very tight dresses were just wonderful. There
chubby legs walking in time with the music to visit Mr. No Face was so
very funny.In heavens sake, don't take it so seriously; sit back relax and enjoy
the wonders of Greece and this includes Illa and her friends.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1522352/comments</url><from>from Washington, D.C.</from><name> (normangelman@verizon.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I haven't seen "Never on Sunday" in ages but I remember it as a really
wonderful comedy. This was the very first time I saw Melina Mercuri --
and it's she and the Greek musical sound track that made it so
pleasurable. The story doesn't matter really: It's enough to know that
Mercuri plays a prostitute with a gift for joy and denial of harsh
realities. If I remember correctly, she has a way of rewriting Greek
tragedies in her head so that, at the end, "everyone goes to the
seashore." I imagine that the film isn't as vivid as it was in its day
because while the scenery was beautiful the photography was not
special. You might not like Jules Dassin as Mercuri's foil -- he acted
in as well as wrote and directed the film -- but see it for Mercuri.
She played roles of greater significance in films that were perhaps
more artful. But she is luminous and funny and sweet and gorgeous in
this picture.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2138545/comments</url><from/><name>middleburg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

From the second the film begins to the moment it ends, Jule's Dassin's
bouyant 
movie brims with life, love, laughter, great music, great food, wonderfulcharacters and a delightful modern fable.    It is a party that one never
wants to 
see end.  In these precarious times it is great to search out a film like
this which 
is life-affirming, beautiful and profound.  Melina Mercouri's Ilia is one of
the great 
screen creations of all time--and every man will fall in love with her when
they 
watch this film.   Her expressions, her vocal range, her combination of
earthy 
sexiness and maternal wisdom---make her an indelible and beloved characterfor all the ages.  And that laugh!  You want to watch the movie again and
again--
just to hear her laugh.  Give yourselves a treat--and watch one of the most
truly 
delightful movies ever made.  You will take this film to your heart  and it
will 
make you smile and laugh long after you've seen it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0033913/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (sylviastel@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
It is easy to see why I am fascinated with Greece. It is not because of
it's role in this film. Melina Mercouri plays a self-made woman of the
world's oldest profession in one of the world's greatest civilizations.
She is beautiful, intelligent, and independent from men. In fact, she
entices men to her rather than play subservient and inferior. Melina
Mercouri was perhaps Greek's best known actress. While American born
and bred, Jules Dassin's character, Homer, tries to capture his
vacation in Greece. He tries to change her like Professor Higgins in
Pygmalion and My Fair Lady. He cannot change what is special and unique
about her. Ilia is a force to be reckon with and returns to her glory
as the best person around, herself. She is a strong woman who makes no
excuses for her lifestyle. The men adore and worship her like a Greek
Goddess. Perhaps, that's what she is--a Greek Goddess! It makes you
want to go to Greece ever more. It is no wonder that in real life,
Jules Dassin and Melina Mercouri fell in love.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0033913/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (sylviastel@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
It is easy to see why I am fascinated with Greece. It is not because of
it's role in this film. Melina Mercouri plays a self-made woman of the
world's oldest profession in one of the world's greatest civilizations.
She is beautiful, intelligent, and independent from men. In fact, she
entices men to her rather than play subservient and inferior. Melina
Mercouri was perhaps Greek's best known actress. While American born
and bred, Jules Dassin's character, Homer, tries to capture his
vacation in Greece. He tries to change her like Professor Higgins in
Pygmalion and My Fair Lady. He cannot change what is special and unique
about her. Ilia is a force to be reckon with and returns to her glory
as the best person around, herself. She is a strong woman who makes no
excuses for her lifestyle. The men adore and worship her like a Greek
Goddess. Perhaps, that's what she is--a Greek Goddess! It makes you
want to go to Greece ever more. It is no wonder that in real life,
Jules Dassin and Melina Mercouri fell in love.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0033913/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (sylviastel@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/never-on-sunday-4/ /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1960087</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>This culture collision comedy is full of cliches, but as the Greek prostitute with a heart of gold, Melina Mercouri gives an infectiously joyous Oscar-nominated performance.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/neveronsunday.htm /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1603871</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>Mercouri's energetic performance took it to greater heights than it deserved.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/moira-sullivan/</url><url>http://www.shoestring.org/mmi_revs/neveronsunday-ms-110674683.html /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1202244</url><name>Moira Sullivan</name><from>Movie Magazine International</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>While the film serves to exploit the myth of the happy prostitute, it reveals the charm and powerful simplicity of the Greece people.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/walter-chaw/</url><url>http://filmfreakcentral.net/dvdreviews/neveronsundaymanfromelysianfields.htm /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1192709</url><name>Walter Chaw</name><from>Film Freak Central</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Her earthiness is grounding, the only element keeping the world from spinning off its axis; beware the man, and woe to mankind, for formulating her to a wall.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-kaplan/</url><url>/m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1712646</url><name>David Kaplan</name><from>Kaplan vs. Kaplan</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1407670</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1361920</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>/m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1322889</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>F5 (Wichita, KS)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794101.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1807581</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/63239/never_on_sunday.html /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1474091</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=106430 /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1146534</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9803EEDB1E31EF3ABC4152DFB667838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=1140981</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.bostonphoenix.com/boston/movies/trailers/documents/01846967.htm /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=297290</url><from>Boston Phoenix</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chireader.com/MovieCaps/N/NE/10327_NEVER_ON_SUNDAY_POTE_TIN_KYRIAKI.html /m/1014832-never_on_sunday/comments.php?reviewid=13392</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>