<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Girl in Lovers Lane</original_title><imdb_rating>2.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Charles R. Rondeau</director><producer>Robert Roark Productions</producer><producer>Brigadier Pictures</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Two drifters contend with love and murder in a small town.
</synopsis><actor>Brett Halsey</actor><actor>Joyce Meadows</actor><actor>Lowell Brown</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0853972/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>sbm82</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Here is a movie that was so pedestrian for 90% of it that it had no right
to
become so challenging and frustrating at the end.  Did the director decide
to become auteur suddenly, 80% through the making of this movie?
Yeesh.
SPOILER ALERT
Thing start out typically enough for 50's youth-gone-wild; there are
drifters, good girls, bad girls, gangs, the kindly old diner manager, and
the town creep.  Things follow the expected path until about 15 minutes
before the end, when the only likable character is killed off and the
anti-hero is blamed (this would not be so unexpected if this were the main
plot of the movie... but all this stuff starts happening and unravelling
during the final reel!  Major curve ball).  Then things get weird; the
kindly old codger forms a mob and beats the hero to a bloody pulp.  The
mere
presence of the hero's friend somehow drags a confession out of the real
killer - the leering, creepy town nut (which in any real universe, he'd
have
been the prime suspect to begin with, even if the anti-hero was found with
her body).We're left with a somewhat feeble "happy" ending, which is about as out of
character with the rest of the movie as the events of the 10 minutes
preceding it.Even more odd is this film's insistence on playing homosexual innuendo to
the hilt, but constantly presenting the two male leads as straight.  Maybe
this was on purpose - perhaps Bix's resistance to settling down with the
girl was more because of his sexuality (which in the 50s would have to be
kept quite repressed, and thus not discussed or even admitted by him) than
his need to be a "drifter".  If the director's intent was to spin this as a
sexual yarn - that the drifter drifts because he feels he's an outcast
sexually; that his paternal regard towards Danny is not, in fact, paternal
but spousal; that his inability to remain with Carrie is rooted in a sexual
revulsion that even he does not quite understand - it could have been made
more clear.  Instead, we get this very bizarre alchemy of homoeroticism and
behavior that is completely heterosexual.These young men sleep next to each other even when they can get some room
to
spread out.  When Danny is propositioned (and once even in bed with a
woman), Bix flips out and takes him away.  Danny pays Bix's way (sure,
there
is another explanation for it, but it still strikes a chord every time you
see Danny buy Bix's lunch).  They end up living together at the end.  Not
since Hitchcock's "Rope" has homosexuality been so blatant but
denied.MST3K did the right thing by taking this one on.  Aside from Jack Elam,
there is little to commend the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0861465/comments</url><from>from Queens, NY</from><name>InzyWimzy</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

This one is one of those classic B movie following the exploits of 2 hobos. 
It's done really cheesily and Big Stupid running off one-liners like a
cardboard cassanova.  But Jack Elam steals every scene he's in as the
creepazoid Jesse (now Jerome!).  My favorite scene is the lynch mob and the
dad's voice going up 10 octaves ("You loved her?").  Danny, Big Stupid's
protege, is surprisingly stupider, but not as loathsome as our lead star. 
There's also a quaint scene of a guy pimping at the diner.  Joyce Meadows is
the sweet, naive nice gal and probably the least annoying.  And those yellow
ruffles (RAWR!).  Oh, and booze is evil according to Mr.
Stupid.This movie's a hoot.  Watch the MST cover of this and Crow's terrific  Elam
homage!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
****SPOILERS**** Late 1950's youth movie about two young drifters Bix &amp;
Danny, Brett Halsey &amp; Lowell Brown, drifting in on a fright train into
the peaceful little town of Sherman. A town where the police chief says
that nothing bad ever happened there in 20 years. It didn't take long for something bad to happen in peaceful Sherman
where on just the first night there the two outsiders are attacked by a
gang of local thugs because one of them had a $50.00 bill that he
changed at the towns pool hall to play a game. $50.00 seems to be a
very small price to corrupt the local boys from their 20 years of
peaceful endeavors. The people of Sherman weren't that bright either by beating to a pulp
,and almost lynching, Bix for raping and murdering his girlfriend
Carrie, Joyce Meadows, after her body was found in the woods. The
locals didn't have enough sense to know that Carries killer may well
have been the local town weirdo Jesse ,Jack Elam, who was alway after
Carrie. Jesse even tried to rape her the day before but was stopped by
none other then Bix himself who belted Jesse and left him in dreamland. Bix was saved from being lynched by the mob led by Carrie's emotionally
upset father Cal,Emile Meyer, by his friend Danny who came to his
rescue, just when he was about to leave town, by telling them that it
may very well have been Jesse who killed Carrie. Jesse who just
happened to be at the scene to watch the lynching then broke down and
confessed to the crime and was taken away into custody by the police.
The cops were released from the towns jail in which they were locked up
in when the townspeople stormed the police station to get and then try
to lynch Bix. The townspeople, including Carrioe's dad Cal, were more
kinder to Carrie's actual killer then Carrie's boyfriend by not trying
to apprehend or kill him like that tried to kill Bix who they should
have known was innocent. It was also interesting to see that Danny who was in town for just a
few days could put two and two together and come to the conclusion that
it was Jesse who killed Carrie when the local townspeople, who lived in
the town all their lives, who knew about Jesse's dangerous obsession
for Carrie didn't have the brains to figure that out by themselves?
Danny who ran away from home when his parents divorced gets the good
news at the end of the movie, I guess that his parents are back
together, and happily invites his friend Bix to come home and live with
him and his parent which Bix readily agrees to do, just what was meant
by that? Isn't two grown up young men living together a bit odd
especially in movies made back then in the 1950's? The movie "The Girl
in Lover's Lane" seems to have more under the covers then over them,
when it comes to Bix &amp; Danny, and may have been made for other reasons
other than what those watching it back then really thought.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0568902/comments</url><from/><name>dhmac2001</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

A young man, named Danny, has run away from home and meets a drifter, named
Bix, who agrees to tag along with Danny and watch out for him... and his
money.  They end up in a small town where they meet Carrie - a shy, naive
girl working in her father's diner.  Bix starts seeing Carrie but he plans
on leaving soon (because he's a drifter, see?  He's no good! Understand?).
Meanwhile, the town creep, Jesse (played by a perfectly casted Jack Elam),
keeps showing up at the diner and bothering Carrie.  Danny keeps
inadvertently picking up whores left and right (because he's loaded with
money – he has almost a hundred dollars!) whom Bix has to constantly chase
away (there are a lot of ambiguously gay overtones between Danny and Bix in
this flick).  Eventually, Bix and Danny decide to leave town but trouble is
a-brewing, due to Jesse the creep.My review of the movie itself: a terrible, dated "Troubled Youth" flick
from
the '50s.My review of the MST3K version of the movie:  I've got to say that this is
one of the best episodes of MST3K ever.  The riffing is dead-on, all the
time.  Except for the somewhat downbeat ending, this movie is easy material
for Joel and the Bots, especially Danny's constant screw-ups that Bix has
to
rescue him from.  The host segments are pretty good too, especially the
segment with the `Train Song.'  Hopefully, Rhino releases this episode to
home video one day.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I have noticed that a lot of films that have been featured on "Mystery
Science Theater" have received a tons of low ratings on IMDb. However,
a few of the films featured on the films weren't that bad and it's not
fair to rate a film that's been given the "MST" treatment--with the
hosts making funny comments during the film. Now I am NOT saying that
"The Girl in Lover's Lane" is a great film, but it's not nearly bad
enough to merit its current IMDb score of 2.1.The film begins with Bix and Danny meeting. Bix is a veteran drifter
and Danny a younger guy who seems to have no particular reason to be
wandering about the country. Once they blow into a small town, Bix
needs to rescue Danny again and again because Danny is quite naive--a
nice way of saying he has the intellect of a tomato.Along the way, something happens to the self-assured Bix--he finds a
nice young lady and finds the lure of staying put pulling at him. And,
in an odd subplot, Jack Elam plays a super-creepy sicko who wanders the
town scaring the crap out of everyone--yet oddly, the police don't seem
to take much notice nor does anyone on their own do anything about him.
Ultimately, however, when Elam puts the moves on a girl who Bix is
falling for, things come to a full boil.Overall, while not at all a great film, there were many interesting
plot elements in this film--enough to merit a score higher than 2.1.
The biggest negatives are a simplistic conclusion to the mystery that
occurs near the end as well as the total stupidity of Danny one time
too often. Considering the minuscule budget, however, it's a watchable
little film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
The Girl in Lovers Lane is one strange little low-budget film. On its
surface, the movie tells the story of a tough drifter named Bix (Brett
Halsey) who spends his time looking out for a young kid named Danny
(Lowell Brown) and the girl, Carrie (Joyce Meadows), that Bix meets who
would like to look out for him. Nothing overly interesting happens (Bix
goes out with Carrie, Bix gets Danny out of trouble, Carrie's father
drinks a lot, etc.) until about 10 minutes to go in the movie when
Carrie is murdered. Her father blames Bix, pulls him out of a jail
cell, and just about beats him to death. Now their roles are reversed
and Danny has to save Bix.Until I read the reviews on IMDb, I thought that maybe it was just me
reading more into Bix and Danny's relationship than was really there,
but I see now that I'm not alone. It was quite obvious to me early on
that Bix and Danny had more of a relationship than you usually see in a
movie from 1959. The homosexual nature of their relationship, while
never openly expressed, is still quite obvious. Their living and
sleeping arrangements, Bix's reaction to finding Danny in bed with a
prostitute, Bix's inability to commit to Carrie, and that phone call at
the end when Danny tells his parents he's "brining home a friend are a
few examples of moments that lead to the inevitable conclusion that
there's more to their relationship than initially meets the eye. I'm
sure they exist, but I can't think of any movies I've seen from the 50s
that scream homosexual quite as loudly as this one.As for the movie, I don't know any other way to put this – it's boring.
As I wrote earlier, nothing much at all happens for 90% of the run
time. The characters are dull and the actors aren't good enough to give
The Girl in Lovers Lane much of a spark. The lone exception is Jack
Elam. His crazy Jesse is the one character interesting enough to be
worth watching. Elam had creepy down pat! But I guess the biggest
problem I had with the movie was with character motivation and logic.
Carrie is killed and Bix is immediately blamed? What about crazy Jesse
who has been stalking Carrie for probably her whole life? Anyone think
to ask Jesse where he was that night? Her father has seen him bother
Carrie at the diner, yet he never considers that the leering Jesse
might have something to do with his daughter's death? Not a lot of
logic there. And what about Jesse's confession? Danny grabs Jesse by
the lapel and this is all it takes to force a confession out of Jesse?
Real tough guy, huh? Why would he confess so easily? And after he
confesses, no one thinks to grab him? It's awfully nice of Jesse just
to stay put and not run off. In any other reality, he would have never
spilled his guts and would have run like a rabbit if he had been
fingered for the murder. The fact that The Girl in Lovers Lane asks me
to accept these ridiculous actions on the part of the characters is
something I'm not willing to do. Overall, I'm giving The Girl in Lovers
Lane a 4/10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0530536/comments</url><from>from Amsterdam, Netherlands</from><name>Rod Evan</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Queer cinema took off in the 1990's but this weird little gem from 1959
was an early example.SPOILERS AHEADBack then if you were a writer with a good gay plot there was no way
you could get it produced unless you coded it. William Inge, &amp;
Tennessee were past masters at applying the code. But 'The Girl in
Lovers Lane is another matter. Nothing makes sens in this film anymore,
and that makes it very intriguing to watch.The film is about two guys, but it's the 'girl' that gets into the
title and onto the poster.At the beginning of the film one guy picks the other up for no reason,
when he could have just stolen his wallet. They shack up. They undress
(at times for no reason). They try to outdo each other at getting
girlfriends. One pushes his girlfriends away whenever they gets 'too
friendly' and 'rescues' his friend whenever he's about to get lucky
with some of the town's colourful dames.The women in the film are fantastically bad girls, celebrated in a
delirious brothel scene, except for one nice girl. And guess what? It's
the nice girl that gets bumped off in the end, leaving the way clear
for our two (male) lovebirds in denial to face a happy future of
domestic bliss together.Watch this film (with or without MST3K) and enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2354065/comments</url><from>from New Jersey</from><name>BillDP</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a film I would have thought I would be seeing as part of one of
those Something Weird Video double feature disc's. Pretty much your
typical
1950's "troubled youth" films. Though this one is a bit talky and light on
the action, I did enjoy it somewhat. I guess I have a soft spot in my
heart
for these kinds of films. Basically you have this young guy who leaves
home
in order to come to terms with the fact that his parents have decided to
get
a divorce. He meets Bix, a road weary and very experienced drifter. They
end
up in a small town and stay longer then they expected which leads to
romance, complications, confrontation, rape and murder. Brett Halsey stars
as Bix and gets fine support from Joyce Meadows and a perfectly cast Jack
Elam as the town letch. All in all, it's no great shakes but it is
entertaining enough.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2707735/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>classicsoncall</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
There was a time when Jack Elam was actually a pretty good looking
young actor, but by the time his late Fifties TV Western days rolled
around he had that weird eye sinister look going and it's on display
here in all it's glory. Man, what a creepy looking guy! And speaking of
Westerns, this might be the only time outside of one where there's a
lynch mob going after a suspected murderer. Considering it was set in
modern times, I had some trouble reconciling that scene with my own
recollection of 1960 and growing up in a small town. I guess it could
have happened somewhere, but I don't recall ever hearing of one.Anyway, this story is about as off the beaten path as you'll find
considering the understated yet overt subtext between the principals -
Britt Halsey as Bix Dugan and Lowell Brown as Danny Winslow. Other
reviewers have elaborated on the subject convincingly enough so I won't
have to go into detail with my own review. I will say though, it did
give me the creeps the very first time Danny put his hand on Bix's
shoulder way back on the freight train ride. The other thing that kept
me off balance was Bix's unusual resemblance to Michael Landon which I
just couldn't get out of my mind while watching.With all that, I'm not sure why this one was called "The Girl in Lovers
Lane". Maybe it was for the benefit of the unidentified couple out
parking near the lake when they heard Carrie scream. Now there was a
real hero, the guy who went to investigate. And Bix never even saw him.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1111192/comments</url><from>from Alabama</from><name>Aaron1375</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
This film is about the fun of being a drifter, while not really
drifting all that much. The film has a young man, named Danny riding
the rails. Well actually he is about to get mugged at the beginning of
the film and so starts his amazing adventure as he soon meets up with a
guy named Bix. Bix seems to be an all right fellow as he could have
taken the young man's wallet and cash, but instead teaches a valuable
lesson. The young Danny begs Bix to tag along with him to show him the
ways of the drifter and they soon embark on a wonderful adventure
drifting. Actually, they arrive at this one town and kind of stay there
the rest of the film. It is a small town too, but even though it is a
small town there is a nice brothel and a local pool hall where if you
have money you are going to get taken down. Seriously, life was rather
difficult back then, granted there are muggings and such now too, but
you can usually walk around with money and not get an automatic
mugging. Well the reason they stay in this town for the entire movie is
that there is a cute gal working at the café and she likes Bix. Which
surprised me, I thought the main character of the flick was going to be
young Danny, but he turns out to be more of a side note to the movie.
He is important, but really as just a kind of plot device to show what
a swell guy Bix can be as Bix not only gets him out of trouble time and
again he also tells Danny of the hard life he led. The movie is
blessedly short, and not all that bad compared to other movies I have
seen on Mystery Science Theater 3000. The end is sort of a surprise,
but not so much because of what happened to the female love interest
for Bix. Saw that coming, just not how it ended with Bix and Danny. The
film though is rather unremarkable in plot, perhaps a couple of more
towns visited would have helped the film out. As it stands, this film
just feels like looking at to average drifters going about their daily
lives. And since when is a drifter coming into town a super prospect at
being a boyfriend? That town must have been very limited in selection
to be sure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1111192/comments</url><from>from Alabama</from><name>Aaron1375</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
This film is about the fun of being a drifter, while not really
drifting all that much. The film has a young man, named Danny riding
the rails. Well actually he is about to get mugged at the beginning of
the film and so starts his amazing adventure as he soon meets up with a
guy named Bix. Bix seems to be an all right fellow as he could have
taken the young man's wallet and cash, but instead teaches a valuable
lesson. The young Danny begs Bix to tag along with him to show him the
ways of the drifter and they soon embark on a wonderful adventure
drifting. Actually, they arrive at this one town and kind of stay there
the rest of the film. It is a small town too, but even though it is a
small town there is a nice brothel and a local pool hall where if you
have money you are going to get taken down. Seriously, life was rather
difficult back then, granted there are muggings and such now too, but
you can usually walk around with money and not get an automatic
mugging. Well the reason they stay in this town for the entire movie is
that there is a cute gal working at the café and she likes Bix. Which
surprised me, I thought the main character of the flick was going to be
young Danny, but he turns out to be more of a side note to the movie.
He is important, but really as just a kind of plot device to show what
a swell guy Bix can be as Bix not only gets him out of trouble time and
again he also tells Danny of the hard life he led. The movie is
blessedly short, and not all that bad compared to other movies I have
seen on Mystery Science Theater 3000. The end is sort of a surprise,
but not so much because of what happened to the female love interest
for Bix. Saw that coming, just not how it ended with Bix and Danny. The
film though is rather unremarkable in plot, perhaps a couple of more
towns visited would have helped the film out. As it stands, this film
just feels like looking at to average drifters going about their daily
lives. And since when is a drifter coming into town a super prospect at
being a boyfriend? That town must have been very limited in selection
to be sure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1111192/comments</url><from>from Alabama</from><name>Aaron1375</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>