<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sons and Lovers</original_title><alt_title>Amants et fils</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Jack Cardiff</director><producer>Twentieth Century-Fox Productions</producer><producer>Company of Artists, The</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>You'll never forget the young lovers in sons &amp; lovers</synopsis><actor>Trevor Howard</actor><actor>Dean Stockwell</actor><actor>Wendy Hiller</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8554038/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>wlawson60</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Jack Cardiff, the director of "Sons and Lovers" was one of the greatest
cinematographers ever. Just think of "Black Narcissus" but as a
director he lacked that extra something, call it egomania, single
mindedness or whatever you want. "Sons and Lovers" is beautifully
crafted but it doesn't have a real center and by that I mean, no real
point of view, no personality. What a feast however. Trevor Howard got
an Oscar nomination for his role here and he is truly wonderful. The
marvelous Wendy Hiller manages to give a soul to the monstrous mother
and make her sympathetic without betraying the misogynistic nature of
DH Lawrence's vision. But the film belongs to Dean Stockwell. His truth
and his beauty is what I took away with me and stayed with me, always.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1464358/comments</url><from>from NY, NY</from><name>David (Handlinghandel)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Freddie Francis's cinematography is in some ways the star. It is not
showy or intrusive. It's totally organic to the unfolding of the plot.
Yet it is exquisite -- both with landscapes and with actors. This is
especially true with Trevor Howard, very powerful as a boozy miner.The other star is that great actress Wendy Hiller. Her role is far from
entirely sympathetic. She suffocates her favorite son, well played by
Dean Stockwell. She is demanding in a quiet way and selfish in a manner
passing itself off as martyrdom. But what a gorgeous performance! Mary
Ure was a fine actress. Somehow, though, the character she plays
doesn't entirely work in my view. It seems more from kitchen-sink
realism, like the Shelagh Delaney plays that were filmed around this
time. (And where have they gone? Why don't we ever see "A Taste of
Honey" or "The Leather Boys" anymore?) Heather Sears is good but I have
to admit, to my embarrassment, I found it hard to shake her excellent
performance in the tile role of "The Story of Esther Costello" from my
mind. Her being a bright young woman taken with Stockwell, therefore,
startled me throughout. That is my own failing and surely not hers.This is a superb movie. All of it is good. But for me, the scenes
involving Hiller are the most compelling. Howard, too, is superb. And
Stockwell as Paul. The family story is heart-wrenching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This exquisite adaptation of D.H. Lawrence's novel is famed
cinematographer Jack Cardiff's most accomplished film as a director; in
fact, he was nominated and indeed won several major Best Direction
awards (including the Golden Globe). Sadly, none of his other
directorial efforts were anywhere near as rewarding although I'd still
like to watch at least 2 of them - the epic THE LONG SHIPS (1963) and
the horror film THE MUTATIONS (1974; a SE DVD of which has been
released under the title THE FREAKMAKER).Amazingly, this was a Hollywood production (made by 20th Century Fox)
and, as such, leading man Dean Stockwell (who was probably never
better) was imposed on Cardiff by producer Jerry Wald - though he seems
to have been pleased with his performance. The acting of the
Oscar-nominated Trevor Howard (as Stockwell's boorish and drunkard
coal-miner father) and Mary Ure (as the married but separated young
suffragette with whom Stockwell has an affair), as well as Wendy Hiller
(as his strong but possessive mother), is irreproachable. The
supporting cast includes Ernest Thesiger (in one of his last films) and
Donald Pleasence, with both unfortunately having limited screen-time.Freddie Francis' luminous black-and-white cinematography earned the
film its only Oscar; interestingly, Francis also followed in Cardiff's
footsteps and became a film director himself (with similarly erratic
results, ironically enough). Mario Nascimbene's lovely music score and
the film's vivid recreation of an era (in authentic locations, no less)
add immeasurably to its lasting impression.The coal-mine setting recalls earlier films like Carol Reed's THE STARS
LOOK DOWN (1939) and John Ford's HOW GREEN WAS MY VALLEY (1941), with
which it can be favorably compared. Still, for all its quaint
Englishness and the inherent sentimentality of its narrative, the film
is a remarkably adult and frank depiction of sexual and artistic
awakening vis-à-vis repressed Edwardian society and, together with Ken
Russell's equally celebrated adaptation of WOMEN IN LOVE (1969),
remains undoubtedly the finest screen rendition of D. H. Lawrence's
work.It's a shame, therefore, that this is as yet unavailable on R1 DVD but
the R2 edition I own is a more than adequate substitute, with a very
nice-looking print of the main feature, surprisingly strong audio and,
apart from the basic supplements of the original theatrical trailer and
a stills gallery, features a wonderful interview with Cardiff about the
making of SONS AND LOVERS (interspersed with relevant clips from the
film itself) which clocks in at around half-an-hour.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0137908/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>didi-5</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is perhaps Jack Cardiff's best known film as a director, and it is
certainly not a letdown. 'Sons and Lovers' was DH Lawrence's most
autobiographical novel, and here, although some aspects have been shorn
down or removed, the substance of that novel comes through.In the main roles we have US actor Dean Stockwell as Paul Morel, the
son who is suffocated by his overbearing mother, and derided by his
miner father. His parents are played by Wendy Hiller and Trevor Howard,
and they are brilliant in difficult roles. Stockwell, less so, although
he certainly looks the part.The women in Paul's life are played by Heather Sears - another annoying
part as Miriam which reminds me of her 'Room at the Top' performance a
few years earlier - and Mary Ure, who is a little bland but watchable
as Clara. Somehow Ure never really found her niche on the screen.The film looks sumptuous and the black and white photography is exactly
right. There are moving scenes and moments of comedy, plus a wicked
cameo appearance by Ernest Thiesinger as an art collector.This film is much less known than more showy Lawrence adaptations such
as 'Women in Love', but it is excellent, well-paced, and is far from a
disappointment.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1166402/comments</url><from/><name>filmkr (filmkr@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

How can there be so little attention and knowledge about this
film?
Nominated for SEVEN academy awards including Best Picture!I have always felt that CinemaScope was made for B&amp;W films.  Scope films
look really good B&amp;W.  And to my mind the best B&amp;W photographed movie of
All
Time is SONS &amp; LOVERS.
This was a prestige picture for distributor 20th Century-Fox, as
indicated
by the rare lack of drum roll over the Fox Logo - instead the beginning of
the outstanding music score is heard.
In the Chicagoland area in 1960 and again at a theatre in Okland, CA in
1976
I had the pleasure to view the film with Mag Stereo Sound. I also saw a new
print in NYC sometime in the early 80's.
So why has Fox let this picture set in obscurity? My only knowlege of any
TV exposure was on American Movie Classics Channel (scanned only) about ten
years ago.
This one NEEDS to be on DVD!!!!!!!!One last comment. if you've ever read the book, you will really
appreciate
the great job that was done in "adapting" the novel.  The screenplay, which
is SO well done, is I'd say a good 80% original material.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0484304/comments</url><from>from Stroudsburg, PA</from><name>fordraff (fordraff@ptd.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The limitations of space for comments make it impossible to detail this
film's many virtues.  The film is so good that I couldn't begin to do
justice to its merits with my words.  Don't miss the opportunity to see
this
film.There is an excellent script by Gavin Lambert aided by T.E.B. Clarke,
which
does a fine job of putting into 103 minutes a long, complex novel.  Each
scene in this film has a purpose to reveal character and make thematic
points.  There are no wasted scenes or aimless dialogue, yet the dialogue
and action all seem natural.  The characters are real and immediately
involved me.There is a complexity to the characters.  Paul's mother wants the best for
him, yet at the same time she wants him for herself.  Paul both wants to
be
free of his mother and is inextricably bound to her, so much that he
refuses
an all-paid education at a London art school to stay home with her, saying
he doesn't want to see her alone with her abusive husband.Gertrude and Walter Morel's marriage is a complex one that befuddles Paul
as
he tries to understand the complex connection between the sensitive mother
and the outwardly angry, rough father, who is, underneath, a very
sensitive
man, too.  Walter fully understands the close relationship between his
wife
and Paul and knows he's locked out of that.  He's both jealous of and
angry
at their closeness.Many excellent scenes here could stand alone.  One such is the scene
leading
up to Paul and Clara having sex for the first time.  There is good use of
close-ups here in which Clara and Paul must convey much with their
eyes.A certain restraint to the performances here give the characters an
intensity they might not have were their performances more flamboyant, if
they'd been given "big" scenes to play with shouting, tears, and so
on.The cast in this film is perfect.  I don't know of another film about
which
I could make that statement.  I don't see a single poor performance.  I
can't imagine any other actors doing these roles.  Each one fully inhabits
the character that he/she is playing.  It was a pleasure to see Heather
Sears and Mary Ure again; both died far too young.  And Dean Stockwell is
at
his youthful, handsome best.  Wendy Hiller and Trevor Howard are both
excellent.  The excellence extends to the supporting players.The film is beautifully photographed in black and white.  I'm sure this
derives partly from director Jack Cardiff's background as a photographer,
though Freddie Francis was the cinematographer here and won an Oscar for
his
work.  Gavin Lambert and cast members Hiller and Howard didn't think much
of
Cardiff as director, whom 20th Century Fox forced upon producer Jerry
Wald.
Hiller and Howard both said they directed themselves throughout the
film.The film was made in Cinemascope and should be seen in that form, for it
doesn't scan well.  (Another IMDb commentator has written well about this;
see his comments.)  Cardiff made good use of close-ups, but every part of
this film is excellently framed, the positions of the characters in the
frame, their relation to various items in the landscape.  And the
landscape
adds a lot to the mood of the film.The film has an excellent score (It should be seen in a theatre with a
fine
sound system), but it is not overscored, and the theme song doesn't become
intrusive.  This theme never became a hit like the theme from "A Summer
Place" did, though the theme did turn up on a number of instrumental
albums
back in the 60s.  People often didn't know from what film it
came.I'm glad to know this film and appreciate its virtues.The film will probably send viewers to the novel, where they can find
complete details about the Morel family yet also realize how well the film
conveys the novel.A PBS version of this novel, starring Eileen Atkins as Gertrude Morel, Tom
Bell as Walter Morel, and Karl Johnson as Paul, was shown in 1981.  It has
never been shown subsequently on PBS or elsewhere to my knowledge nor was
it
ever issued on video.  Was it that bad?    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0406448/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rossco-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I probably saw this film when I was in college and it made a big
impression.It then seemed to vanish, at least for me, until, amazingly, the
American Cinematheque in Los Angeles screened it on a Monday night some
months ago. I was extremely impressed with it again, especially the BxW
CinemaScope cinematography (and I agree, wide-screen is the way to see
this rare film, if indeed you ever can).So many thanks to the Cinematheque for this unusual revival.RE the musical score (by Italian composer, Mario Nascimbene): actually
the theme was so melodic Percy Faith recorded it as a follow-up to his
hit single of Max Steiner's SUMMER PLACE theme, (complete with similar
1950s piano triplets in the accompaniment!) In spite of the nod to '50s
pop the SONS AND LOVERS theme was not a hit, but it remains one of the
more lyrical (and obscure) movie themes from this period.Remember when movies actually had original musical themes????Ultimately I feel SONS AND LOVERS ranks with Russell's WOMEN IN LOVE in
the admittedly small canon of excellent cinematic Lawrence adaptations.It's also one of the adult Dean Stockwell's best roles, a long, long
day's journey away from the almost too adorable, curly headed moppet in
ANCHORS AWEIGH.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0406448/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rossco-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I probably saw this film when I was in college and it made a big
impression.It then seemed to vanish, at least for me, until, amazingly, the
American Cinematheque in Los Angeles screened it on a Monday night some
months ago. I was extremely impressed with it again, especially the BxW
CinemaScope cinematography (and I agree, wide-screen is the way to see
this rare film, if indeed you ever can).So many thanks to the Cinematheque for this unusual revival.RE the musical score (by Italian composer, Mario Nascimbene): actually
the theme was so melodic Percy Faith recorded it as a follow-up to his
hit single of Max Steiner's SUMMER PLACE theme, (complete with similar
1950s piano triplets in the accompaniment!) In spite of the nod to '50s
pop the SONS AND LOVERS theme was not a hit, but it remains one of the
more lyrical (and obscure) movie themes from this period.Remember when movies actually had original musical themes????Ultimately I feel SONS AND LOVERS ranks with Russell's WOMEN IN LOVE in
the admittedly small canon of excellent cinematic Lawrence adaptations.It's also one of the adult Dean Stockwell's best roles, a long, long
day's journey away from the almost too adorable, curly headed moppet in
ANCHORS AWEIGH.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0406448/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rossco-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/sons-and-lovers-1960-9/ /m/sons-and-lovers1960/comments.php?reviewid=1965288</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Jack Clayton's adaptation of D.H. Lawrence's autobiographical novel is intelligent, exquisitely shot, and well acted, if also too restrained.</comment></review></movie>