<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>North to Alaska</original_title><alt_title>Le grand Sam</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Henry Hathaway</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
Sam and George strike gold in Alaska. George sends Sam to Seattle to bring George's fiancé back to Alaska...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>John Wayne</actor><actor>Stewart Granger</actor><actor>Ernie Kovacs</actor><rt_rating>4.7/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>33</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Stewart Granger in his memoirs said he was very glad to receive the
role of George Pratt when he did and was always grateful to John Wayne
who got him cast in the part. He had just left MGM and offers were not
piling up. Granger's career was in a transitional stage and he would
soon take off for Europe and all kinds of spaghetti westerns. Right at
that point he needed a paycheck.Granger and Fabian play the brothers Pratt, George and Billy and John
Wayne is their partner Sam McCord in a gold claim that's just hit it
big. He's got to buy mining equipment in Seattle and Pratt's fiancé
Jennie is there too. Wayne's to bring back both the equipment and
Jennie.But Jennie has off and got herself married. So Wayne in a moment of
alcoholic brilliance spots another girl with a French accent in a
pleasure palace called the Birdcage and decided to take her back to
Alaska for Granger. She's played by Capucine. But things don't quite
work out.Of course there's another kind of claim jumping going on led by no-good
cynical gambler Ernie Kovacs. All kinds of problems for the
McCord-Pratt partnership. If you like your comedy broad and unsophisticated North to Alaska is
your kind of film. The Duke has some of his funniest screen moments in
this film. There's a whole routine with Granger and Capucine trying to
make Wayne jealous and with Fabian serving as a straight man to Wayne,
it's a pretty funny bit of business. Wayne's facial expressions are
alone worth seeing the movie.John Wayne was always shrewd in marketing his films and he sought to
woo a younger audience by having current teenage idols in his films
around that time. He had Ricky Nelson in Rio Bravo and Frankie Avalon
in The Alamo and now Fabian in North to Alaska.I saw an interview with Fabian some years ago where he said Wayne was a
formidable presence on the set of his film. He was great when you got
to know him and he accepted you. But you did things his way or it was
the highway, no questions asked.Fabian has some moments too as a 17 year old whose hormones get going
at the sight of Capucine. He sings a song in the film, If You Only
Knew. But the real song hit is the title tune sung by Johnny Horton
over the title. It was a big hit for Horton in his short and tragic
career. Frankie Laine also sold a few platters with this song.If your taste is sophisticated drawing room comedy, this ain't your
film. But fans of the eternal Duke will love it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1760547/comments</url><from/><name>eaglejet98</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a great movie.  Funny and entertaining.Each of the characters could fill up a movie by themselves. Ernie Kovaks
steals the show as the ultimate cheat and chiseler. John Wayne knows he is
doing a parody of himself, plays it to the hilt and pulls it off
brilliantly. Capucine is a classy lady. Even though she works in a
bordello,
you somehow know she's a nice girl. Even Clancy the shaggy dog has a great
role. Johnny Horton's title hit, North to Alaska, is his best song ever.
Classic cowboy movie fight scenes at the beginning and end.A total hoot.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1733466/comments</url><from>from Connecticut, USA</from><name>Capucine</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie is too funny! And too heartwarming! I can watch this movie over
and over and still laugh! And it is not slapstick! Just good ole wholesome
American comedy! My favorite! Three men, (well, two men and a teen) and a
French woman! What a combo!!
John Wayne is his usual macho self. That is always fun to watch. And
Stewart
Granger is soooo good here! I have seen him in many things, but I think he
out-did himself here! He's too funny! And poor Fabian. He breaks my heart
with his love-sick adoration of Michelle! If you haven't seen this, you
must
rent it. You will be glad you did. And you WILL end up watching it again.
It's that type of movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0867063/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>FilmFlaneur</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Hathaway's genial directing style, with its frequently rich mise-en-scene,
seemed to suit Wayne's later career, and some of the films which resulted
remain firm favourites today. Before the overrated True Grit (1969) and the
underrated Sons of Katie Elder (1965) came this typically rumbustious piece.
Wayne's first real foray into self-mocking comedy, North to Alaska is not as
broad humoured as McLagen's McLintock! (1963) but still suffers from a
degree of sexism which some modern viewers may find annoying, others just
ironic. It is redeemed by being a very good natured film with a strong set
of performances by the central cast, as well as some handsome production
values.It's interesting that the film opens as the all-important ‘strike', at least
in a conventional sense, has already happened. Despite the future
depredations of Frankie Canon (a well-cast Ernie Kovacs), Sam (Wayne) and
George (Granger) will continue to enjoy their new-found wealth. Sam in
particular seems to be perpetually well heeled, with a thick wad of the
folding stuff always to hand. These two prospectors are now concerned with a
second, more pressing ‘mother lode' - this time of the heart. The film is
less about rich seams of ore than the veins of romance, with Sam, George and
Billy (Fabian) each doing their own emotional ‘prospecting'.  When Sam heads
South to recover George's fiance, it turns out that he is being just as
adventurous as leading a packHathaway was brought into the project after Richard Fleischer's departure,
and the finished result shows an interesting balance between the veteran's
predictably sure touch as well as the improvisational nature of some of the
filming. Wayne apparently thought of the film as being little more than a
contractual affair, and the great success of the finished product was
presumably a surprise. While some modern viewers may balk at the comedic
sound effects added during the two big fight scenes, more reminiscent of Tom
and Jerry than a Western, arguably Wayne's great ‘jealousy scene' is one of
the greatest sustained moments of comedy in the actor's career. It seems
likely that Hathaway recognised this during filming, as he dwells upon this
enjoyable moment (George pretending to make out with Angel in the Honeymoon
Hut while Sam fumes across the water) as long as possible, giving the scene
amplification and timing which would have been impossible to write into a
script.Being respectively indifferent, enthusiastic, and besotted, in their own
ways Sam, George and Billy each represent varying attitudes to women and
romance. It's their continuing education in such matters that's at the heart
of the film, and provides the principal interest. Far more so than the
claim-jumping plot which, while it provides some dramatic excitement and
degree of suspense, is actually of little consequence. (It provides an
useful parallel, though, when George assumes that Sam has usurped his
‘claim' on his newly arrived fiance's affections.). Sam's change of heart is
fittingly the most momentous -  moving from the cynical "(The) wonderful
thing about Alaska is that matrimony hasn't hit up here yet." to the
grudging public announcement "I love you!" to Angel, and the wedding bells
that surely follow. Billy's romantic naivite also undergoes a transformation
of sorts, as he experiences his first strong crush then gentle, inevitable
rejection. By the end he has to reconcile the ‘loss' of Angel with Sam's
obvious happiness. George's radical transformation of outlook (despite his
slightly underwritten role), in which he journeys from starry-eyed fiance,
via outraged suitor to gleeful romantic conspirator, while demanded by the
story, is far fetched in dramatic terms. Would a man really be that fickle,
and then that forgiving, in such a short length of time?. One wishes that
the script had allowed us to see more of his earlier anguish, perhaps while
Sam was absent fetching his longed-for fiance home.North to Alaska is divided into two halves, covering respectively Sam's
sojurn down south, then his return to Nome, Angel in tow. The broad comedy
of romantic embarrassment so characteristic of the film is contained in the
second half. That this is the most enjoyable part is no coincidence. Removed
from his eager beaver partner, and with an absence of any cutting-back to
Alaska during these scenes, while Wayne and Cappucine work well as an acting
couple, their characters Sam and Angel need more context than they get to be
effective dramatically. Angel's initial rejection at the social by the lake,
then her response, does suggest the self possession of her character, which
acquires a calm strength of its own. Its an explicit dignity, rarely
accorded the Western whore, (a memorable example, albeit posthumous, exists
in Ford's The Sun Shines Bright (1953)),  although there are bad girls
enough in the genre who try to make good. As the love-puppyish Billy supporting the Duke, Fabian instantly recalls
Ricky Nelson in Rio Bravo (1959) as ‘Colorado'. An obvious sop to the
emerging younger audience, such a character can sit uneasily with the elder
statesmen in a genre where a man's world, for the time being anyway, was
that of mature men. Recognising this in Rio Bravo, Chance (Wayne) goes out
of his way to praise and assimilate the youth into his world. A year on, as
North to Alaska proceeds, Billy is less assured as a character, thus easily
dismissed by an overriding Wayne/Sam. The youngster is clearly out of his
depth in the love-making contest - just as (one is tempted to add) Fabian
the actor is sandwiched unsatisfactorily on screen, between a larger than
life Wayne and the experienced Stewart Granger. Extracting what pathos there
is from his one note character, especially in the long cabin dining scene
with Angel, he manages a final, if understated reconciliation with the idea
that Sam is the victor in love.Its apt that Hathaway's ‘Alaska' was actually much closer to Hollywood
(being filmed at Point Mugu, California). Ultimately it is a warm-hearted,
forgiving film which just happens to be set in a cold place. Perhaps the
humanity of a rare Western with few or no deaths on screen is what sustains
its popularity. Or it could be because a genial Wayne was allowed to relax
into a role so successfully. Either way, it is still revived frequently on
TV and has just received a DVD release.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1019294/comments</url><from>from Ottawa, Ontario, Canada</from><name> (bsmith5552@rogers.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"North To Alaska" is a rollicking action filled comedy western from
Director Henry Hathaway and a departure by star John Wayne from his
usual westerns.Sam McCord (Wayne), George Pratt (Stewart Granger) and Billy Pratt
(Fabian) are partners in a rich Alaskan gold mine in 1900. They have
just struck it rich and go to the local saloon to celebrate. There, a
raucous saloon brawl breaks out, played more for its comedy aspects
than for real. Now that he has struck it rich, George can finally send
for his long suffering fiancé Jenny who lives in Seattle. Before he
leaves he meets scheming gambler Frankie Cannon (Ernie Kovacs) with
whom he will tangle at a later date.Since Sam has to go to Seattle to buy new mining machinery anyway,
George charges him with the task of fetching Jenny back to him. In
Seattle, Sam finds that Jenny has, much to her regret, since married.
Sam goes to a local brothel called "The Hen House" where he happens to
meet Angel (Capucine) who is French like Jenny. Sam decides to
substitute Angel for Jenny and asks her to accompany him to Alaska.
Angel as luck would have it, falls in love with Sam.Before leaving for Alaska, Sam goes to a logger's picnic at the request
of his old friends Lars and Lena Nordqvist (Karl Swenson and Kathleen
Freeman). There he protects Angel's honor to the point that she
believes he is taking her back to Alaska as his girl.Back in Alaska, Sam brings her to his camp to find that George is away
fighting claim jumpers at another camp. Sam leaves Angel in the "care"
of George's young brother Billy who tries to woo her for himself with
comedic results.When George and Sam return, George is presented with Angel as a
replacement for his beloved Jenny. Reluctant at first, he becomes
attracted to her until he realizes that she is in love with Sam. The
two then plot to make Sam jealous and well you know.Meanwhile Cannon has cross-filed on Sam and George's claim under the
name of town drunk Boggs (Mickey Shaughnessy), and then the fun begins.Director Hathaway keeps the story moving and entertaining. Wayne proves
to be quite adept at light comedy in his role. Fabian surprises as the
horny kid brother in perhaps the best role of his movie career.
Granger, long an action star in his own right, is equal to the task as
George. Ernie Kovacs who was an innovative TV comedian at this time, is
wasted as the the slimy chief villain. He hardly has a chance to
display his comedic talents. Capucine is lovely and captivating as
Angel. Her scenes with Fabian are hilarious.There is plenty of action from the opening saloon brawl to the logger's
picnic to the fight with the claim jumpers to the final street fight.
And who can ever forget the great Johnny Horton's singing of the title
song over the opening credits.One of Wayne's most entertaining pictures.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

John Wayne plays Sam McCord, who teams up with George Pratt, played by
Stewart Granger, striking it rich with a gold mine around the turn of the
century in Alaska. Fabian plays George's younger brother, Billy. George
sends Sam back to Seattle to bring back his bride to be; instead, Sam brings
back a chorus girl played by Capucine.Henry Hathaway directs this fist swinging comedy. Of course, Mr. Wayne is in
charge of the fist fights and Fabian is the butt of and source of most of
the comedy. Comic Ernie Kovacs plays a snide claim jumper.  Fast paced
frolic of a picture. An enjoyable lighter side of 'Duke'
Wayne.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8975912/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>martinbijkerk</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
North to Alaska is one of the most northerly western to be brought out,
playing mostly in Nome. The movie is complete fiction, but the location
and how it looked there during the gold rush are surprisingly correct.
After Klondyke, Nome had a kind of second rush, but since most people
searched for gold in/near the rivers - like Sam (Wayne) and his
companions did - the real rush came to Nome after a local was chased
away from his claim and as he started to wash at the beach(!) he found
a real bonanza! Nome had no haven, which is shown in the movie: ships
(mostly arriving from Seattle) had to anchor before the coast and
freight and passengers had to be brought aland by smaller vessels. Also
characters like Frankie are realistic, for crooks where indeed not
hesitating to kill people or steal claims (as I mentioned above). How
it looks in Nome is also realistic: however most of the year frozen, in
the short period the ice melts, the streets were one ditch of thighhigh
mud; Frankie is made aware of that fact very firsthand.Humanity note: After Sam brought a girl from Seattle to Nome, which was
an silly alcohol decision, he regrets it and leaves her in town so she
could take the next boat back. Also in this movie there are people
offering apologies, even Sam himself; try to find regret and apologies
in other westerns!Music: The title song by Johnnie Horton is a real C&amp;W hit.Totally: The movie is very entertaining, funny, human and realistic in
historical context. A good film for the whole family!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2232026/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon</from><name>Greg Couture</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A recent issue of Vanity Fair magazine contained a lengthy article (riddled
with some annoying errors, by the way) about the exploits of legendary
Hollywood agent (and producer, on occasion), Charles K. Feldman.  For John
Wayne he at one time obtained a three-picture deal at 20th-Century Fox that
included this one, as well as "The Comancheros" and "The Barbarian and the
Geisha."  This comedy, set in Gold Rush Alaska, is the best of that trio,
thanks to Henry Hathaway's hand at the helm, and some extremely astute
casting.  Stewart Granger, presumably a free agent after fulfilling his MGM
contract, is credible as Wayne's partner; Ernie Kovacs, in one of his few
film roles, before his untimely death, makes a thoroughly convincing cad;
and Fabian, shoehorned in to lure the teenage females, is refreshingly funny
in probably his best film performance.  Capucine, one of Feldman's
conquests, according to that same Vanity Fair article, was given the role of
Michelle/'Angel' and she gave a preview of her ability to play a glamour
role with an emphasis on comedy that came to full flower in 1964's "The Pink
Panther," in which she skillfully matched pratfalls with Peter Sellers in
his first incarnation as the immortal Inspector Clouseau.With the great Kathleen Freeman, the always funny Mickey Shaugnessy, and
Karl Swenson rounding out a cast giving full play to the script's comic
aspects; Leon Shamroy lensing the proceedings with his usual
professionalism; and Lionel Newman contributing an apposite score; this one,
with a title song that managed a place on the Hit Parade back then, is lots
of not-too-taxing fun.  It's soon to be available on 
DVD, I notice, so its CinemaScope ratio will no doubt be restored, the only
way to revisit a film made when widescreens were really wide.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1733466/comments</url><from>from Connecticut, USA</from><name>Capucine</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie is too funny! And too heartwarming! I can watch this movie over
and over and still laugh! And it is not slapstick! Just good ole wholesome
American comedy! My favorite! Three men, (well, two men and a teen) and a
French woman! What a combo!!
John Wayne is his usual macho self. That is always fun to watch. And
Stewart
Granger is soooo good here! I have seen him in many things, but I think he
out-did himself here! He's too funny! And poor Fabian. He breaks my heart
with his love-sick adoration of Michelle! If you haven't seen this, you
must
rent it. You will be glad you did. And you WILL end up watching it again.
It's that type of movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The idea for this movie was born in the mind of a writer with the
improbable name of Kafka. Wait. What was that slight thud? Oh, only
Franz rolling over a bit. But it was directed by Henry Hathaway, known
as "a man's director" for his impatience, vulgarity, and fondness for
drink.It's not badly done either, for what it intends to be. Wayne and
Stewart Granger are partners in a successful gold mine near Nome,
Alaska. Wayne takes a ship to Seattle, partly to pick up Granger's
French girl friend and bring her back with him. Alas, the feckless
Jennie has married a bald butler in Granger's absence, not knowing he
has struck it rich. Wayne's original mission having failed, he meets
the stunning Capucine and decides to bring her back as a substitute for
Granger's lost love, Lenore. Wayne shows more than his usual insight
into the nature of femininity."Women -- peculiar," he mutters at one point. And then, "A Frenchie
broke George's heart, a Frenchie can FIX it." Capucine misunderstands,
thinks that Wayne himself is interested in her, and therein lie the
grounds for later contretemps that are finally solved to everyone's
satisfaction.The movie was clearly influenced by the success of Wayne's previous
Western, "Rio Bravo." "Rio Bravo" had one dud in the casting of the
principles but it was overcome by craftsmanlike direction and a solid
script. The problem is that Hathaway is no Howard Hawks and the script
itself is deliberately loony, so the dud stands out."Rio Bravo" had Ricky Nelson, a reigning heart throb of the late 1950s.
"North to Alaska" has Fabian, captured here in the final seconds of his
fifteen minutes. Everyone has been told to overact. You can see it in
Wayne's shouting and Granger's wild un-English gesticulations. But you
can't tell it with Fabian because acting and overacting are the same to
him. He drools with lust. His face turns into that of a chubby,
pop-eyed gargoyle. And when he croons a tender love song to Capucine,
well -- you know how YOU sound when you sing? Not at your best, but at
your most mediocre? Well, that's better than Fabian.There are too many fist fights to count. They take place among dozens
of rolling beer barrels spouting shifting cones of foam, among vast
seas of mud, among drenching waterfalls from demolished sluices. When a
bar tender is punched in the face, his hat pops up a foot in the air
and settles quickly back on his head. When Ernie Kovacs punches Wayne,
Wayne's toupee flies off and no one bothers to correct the error. At
times it all feels too forced, leaving the viewer feeling like a
Strasbourg goose.Yet, it's kind of fun too. Everyone seems to be on vacation. Nothing is
held back. And if you're in the right mood, you'll get a kick out of
it. Capucine is exquisite and a fine actress. Wayne gets to climb a
tall tree, and when punched in the nose he gets to look cross-eyed
before falling flat on his back. Nobody gets killed. It's a movie in
which a Donneybrook can flatten a saloon but from which all blood is
banished.Of course, if you're NOT in the right mood, you may feel like the only
sober guest at the party.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The idea for this movie was born in the mind of a writer with the
improbable name of Kafka. Wait. What was that slight thud? Oh, only
Franz rolling over a bit. But it was directed by Henry Hathaway, known
as "a man's director" for his impatience, vulgarity, and fondness for
drink.It's not badly done either, for what it intends to be. Wayne and
Stewart Granger are partners in a successful gold mine near Nome,
Alaska. Wayne takes a ship to Seattle, partly to pick up Granger's
French girl friend and bring her back with him. Alas, the feckless
Jennie has married a bald butler in Granger's absence, not knowing he
has struck it rich. Wayne's original mission having failed, he meets
the stunning Capucine and decides to bring her back as a substitute for
Granger's lost love, Lenore. Wayne shows more than his usual insight
into the nature of femininity."Women -- peculiar," he mutters at one point. And then, "A Frenchie
broke George's heart, a Frenchie can FIX it." Capucine misunderstands,
thinks that Wayne himself is interested in her, and therein lie the
grounds for later contretemps that are finally solved to everyone's
satisfaction.The movie was clearly influenced by the success of Wayne's previous
Western, "Rio Bravo." "Rio Bravo" had one dud in the casting of the
principles but it was overcome by craftsmanlike direction and a solid
script. The problem is that Hathaway is no Howard Hawks and the script
itself is deliberately loony, so the dud stands out."Rio Bravo" had Ricky Nelson, a reigning heart throb of the late 1950s.
"North to Alaska" has Fabian, captured here in the final seconds of his
fifteen minutes. Everyone has been told to overact. You can see it in
Wayne's shouting and Granger's wild un-English gesticulations. But you
can't tell it with Fabian because acting and overacting are the same to
him. He drools with lust. His face turns into that of a chubby,
pop-eyed gargoyle. And when he croons a tender love song to Capucine,
well -- you know how YOU sound when you sing? Not at your best, but at
your most mediocre? Well, that's better than Fabian.There are too many fist fights to count. They take place among dozens
of rolling beer barrels spouting shifting cones of foam, among vast
seas of mud, among drenching waterfalls from demolished sluices. When a
bar tender is punched in the face, his hat pops up a foot in the air
and settles quickly back on his head. When Ernie Kovacs punches Wayne,
Wayne's toupee flies off and no one bothers to correct the error. At
times it all feels too forced, leaving the viewer feeling like a
Strasbourg goose.Yet, it's kind of fun too. Everyone seems to be on vacation. Nothing is
held back. And if you're in the right mood, you'll get a kick out of
it. Capucine is exquisite and a fine actress. Wayne gets to climb a
tall tree, and when punched in the nose he gets to look cross-eyed
before falling flat on his back. Nobody gets killed. It's a movie in
which a Donneybrook can flatten a saloon but from which all blood is
banished.Of course, if you're NOT in the right mood, you may feel like the only
sober guest at the party.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bob-bloom/</url><url>/m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1678377</url><name>Bob Bloom</name><from>Journal and Courier (Lafayette, IN)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>An OK John Wayne up north comedy western. Not one of his better efforts, but it has its moments.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/north-to-alaska-1960-big-hit-6/ /m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1607199</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>One of John Wayne's most popular Western-adventures, North to Alaska reveals his light comedy skills, and benefits from Shamroy's on-location shoot, hathaway's smooth helming, and great cast, headed by Cappucine, Ernie Kovacs, Stewart Granger, and Fabian</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/northtoalaska.htm /m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1414526</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Never amounts to even a speck of gold.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/widgett-walls/</url><url>/m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1277990</url><name>Widgett Walls</name><from>Needcoffee.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Harmless watchable cheesefest.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/chuck-oleary/</url><url>/m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1621158</url><name>Chuck O'Leary</name><from>FulvueDrive-in.com</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1350886</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117793587.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1808467</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/63531/north_to_alaska.html /m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1475062</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C01E5DB1030EF3ABC4952DFB767838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1394966</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=106569 /m/north_to_alaska/comments.php?reviewid=1148870</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>