<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>All the Fine Young Cannibals</original_title><alt_title>Les jeunes loups</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Michael Anderson</director><producer>Avon Productions (II)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Music</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
The minister of the town has died and his son Chad has no tears for him. Sarah, who now calls herself Salome...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Robert Wagner</actor><actor>Natalie Wood</actor><actor>Susan Kohner</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2715610/comments</url><from>from Culver City, CA</from><name>OrdinaryfoolisNJ</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
What I love about this film, is the fact that it includes a respectful
and loving relationship between a black woman and a white man during
the apartheid era of racism here in the United States (before the
"Freedom Rides," which occurred not long after).I admire Robert Wagner and Natalie Wood (especially), as rising young
stars in Hollywood, for taking the chance to be in this type of picture
at that time in history.When Susan Kohner's character calls Pearl Bailey a "nigger," Robert
Wagner whacks her one but good! And then he educates Miss spoiled brat
and much misinformed Kohner, that Pearl is more decent than any of the
white people in this movie! And more deserving of love and respect.And folks, was he right. Bailey's character and performance are the
most worthwhile in the film.Yes, the basic story between Natalie Wood (poor country girl looking to
move up in the world by passing Wagner's baby off as rich boy
Hamilton's), Robert Wagner (poor confused misunderstood boy with talent
for "race" music, but seemingly not much ambition to do anything with
it), George Hamilton and Susan Kohner (spoiled RICH siblings taken in
by Wood and Wagner -- but both hopelessly in love with the two)is
schlock.But the story between Wagner and Pearl Bailey (suicidal famous singer
mourning the loss of her lover, who becomes charmed with Wagner and
does her best to help him before she purposely succumbs to alcoholism)
saves the day.Also, Natalie Wood is simply outrageously gorgeous in this picture. And
Robert Wagner and Hamilton are pretty easy on the yes as well. So, when
the story gets to be too much, just enjoy the view! I wish that Wood and Wagner had more screen time together in this film
(and that they ended up together), but that's because I love RJ and Nat
together as a couple under any circumstances (and believe me one has to
love them unconditionally -- as their story lines and acting and
accents don't feature either near the top of their talents).Still, a brave story to undertake. Its bad/good and very interesting. I
recommend it for having the guts to be ahead of its time.Nancy J Ordinaryfool
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5246346/comments</url><from>from Nijmegen, Netherlands</from><name> (h.calis@chello.nl)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I happened to see this film years ago in a sleepless night, zapping
through some of the less commercial public canals we still had at the
time in Europe. It really opened my soul because of the music included.
I will not comment on the quality of the script or the acting of the
young couple Natalie Wood and Robert Wagner; others can do better than
I. But I like the slow pace, the melodramatic story, the dialogue lines
that stay in your head, and - above all - I was thrilled by the singing
and acting of Pearl Bailey as Ruby Jones. If ever you have to explain
the feelings that gave rise to the blues, ahead of the ubiquitous
slavery hardships and working in the cotton fields, then this movie is
a 'must-see'. When Chad is in the lowest of spirits and ends up in a
morning-after hang-out, he runs into this Ruby Jones, an alcoholic, but
warm-hearted black singer. And she treats him with a song,
unaccompanied, raw voice, that expresses his feelings so well, and
gives him the idea he is not the only unhappy, lost man on this globe.
I don't know if Mrs Bailey sung the track herself or was dubbed, but
she succeeds in getting the blues feeling across as I've never heard
thereafter. Same when later on in the movie she sings to Chad, playing
the trumpet: "What am I heading for? Blues is knocking at my door".
Alas! this song is spoiled by a dubbed in band and even background
vocals if I remember well - anyhow, it takes away from the simplicity
of just a singer and a "horn player" (as she puts it throughout the
picture). The sad story of the twists and impossibilities of human
relationships is to me more real-life than most of the soapy Hollywood
plots that come to us by shiploads these days. Endearing, that's
probably the word that says it all.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0650226/comments</url><from>from Universal City, TX</from><name> (michael.e.barrett@worldnet.att.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A very interesting soaper, certainly much better than the Maltin review
gives it credit for. The sharp dialogue is probably its best feature; the
characters say things very bluntly and pseudo-honestly, like people
struggling to be clever when they know, as members of a "postmodern"
generation, that it's all been said before and they are doomed to
re-enact
old cliches themselves. They understand their own ailments and
continually
refer to how spoiled, afraid and enervated they are. Plot is in territory
similar to "Splendor in the Grass" (love is a sickness you grow out of
and
can eventually re-create where you have settled) but it's real subject is
how restless, discontented people spread their unhappiness around, and
how
this is symptomatic of these modern times. Despite Wagner playing trumpet
(he does not make any attempt to sound like Chet Baker, although he IS
pretty) and Pearl imitating Billie Holiday (down to a performance of "God
Bless the Child") with some unfortunate prescience before Holiday's
death,
this is not really a music film. It's like a delayed "beat" movie that
should have been made in the 50s. (Hollywood is always some years
behind.)
40 years later, we needn't worry whether it seems out of date; time has
been
kind to this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2721657/comments</url><from>from brooklyn NY</from><name>sol1218</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
**SPOILERS** With no money and no future to look forward to a young
couple from the dirt-poor Texas town of Pine Alley Chad Bixby &amp; Sarah
"Salome" Davis, Robert Wagner &amp; Natalie Wood, went out in the world to
find a better life for themselves. With his abusive father, the town's
minister, passing away Chad felt that he can now do what he wanted to
do for so long pay his horn and marry Salome. Things got a bit strained
when Salome turned out to be pregnant with Chad being the father of her
unborn child. Salome running away from home runs into Yale Ivy Leaguer Tony McDowell,
George Hamilton,on a train going north. Tony on summer vacation had met
Salome earlier back in Deep Elem, the black part of the town of Pine
Valley, under not the best of circumstances.Not having any money and with Tony having a slight acquaintance with
Salome he pays her way to ride with him to New Haven Connecticut.
During that long ride up north they fall in love with each other.
Salome and Tony getting married and settling down soon have a new
member of the McDowell family a son Peter, what Tony doesn't know is
that Peter is not really his son but Chad's. Chad meanwhile back in the sticks strikes up a friendship with the
burnt out former jazz great Ruby Jones, Pearl Bailey, who since her
husband left her for a younger women, as well as took all her money,is
slowly drinking herself to death. It's Chad concern and compassion for
her that gave Ruby a new lease on life as well as it gave Chad the
opportunity to show his talents as a jazz musician. In no time at all
Chad made it big in the Big Apple's,New York city, nightclub scene. Salome now happily married and with a young child gets the news from
her sister-in-law Catherine, Susan Kohner, about Clad's success in the
music world. Salome talks Tony into going to New York in order to see
his act which in the end opens up the old wounds, that both Salome &amp;
Chad had from their failed and sorrowful relationship back in Texas. Big budget soap opera that has both Chad and Salome trying to get even
and hurt each other, over what happened between them back in Texas. In
the end only hurting those who were nothing more then innocent
bystanders as well as the only one's that really and truly loved and
cared for them. Chad marries Catherine just to get back at Salome for leaving him.
Cathy is driven to where she almost ends up killing herself by Chad's,
being so obsessed to hurt Salome, total disregard for her and the love
that she genuinely had for him. Salome is also guilt-ridden over the
fact that her and Tony's son Peter isn't really Tony's and feels that
if he ever found out the truth it would end up killing him. Clad is
also hit with the double tragedy of Ruby dying from the effects of
alcoholism and it's her sudden, but not unexpected death, that finally
brings him back to earth in not just realizing what he did to Salome
but what he did to his wife Cathy as well. When Tony is finally told by
Salome the truth about their son Peter it hits him so hard that for a
moment you would have thought that he would walk right in the middle of
the highway in front of a speeding 18 wheeler and end it all. The movie "All the Fine Young Cannibals" does in fact have a happy
ending that in it's own way counterbalances all the depressing aspects
that are in the film up until then. Not as bad as you would think it
would be from all the bad reviews that it got "All the Fine Young
Cannibals" may be a bit too depressing to take at first but the cast
does it's best to keep it both interesting and poignant. The ending,
though a bit too artificial, didn't hurt the storyline that much in
it's attempt to right all the wrongs that were in it at the conclusion
of the movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3975509/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>Roseofsharon969 (Roseofsharon979@live.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I remember seeing (and taping) this movie off of Superchannel one
night. It was part of a "Natalie Wood Double Feature", and it was
followed by "Love With The Proper Stranger", and, being a die-hard fan
of her, I wasn't about to pass this one up.This film seems, initially, as a soapy, over-the-top, melodramatic
feature like many movies of the time. However, if you can overlook the
flaws, you will find it very interesting and rewarding. The original
attraction of this movie was, for me, the early on-screen teaming of
real-life couple Natalie Wood and Robert Wagner. Wood was apparently
worried as to whether Wagner could handle a dramatic role, and in
retrospect she was justified in that concern. Wagner is more of a
personality than an actor, and his performance as the sullen musician
comes across as stiff. And Wood's southern accent can be distracting at
times - her pronunciation of her lover's name, "Chaad" can get a bit
grating! That aside, the most interesting aspects of the story happen
later, after Sarah/Salome becomes pregnant by Chad, leaves her
overbearing, zealous-nut father and her stifling, confining home life
and meets up with Tony McDowall.Her vulnerability and his love for her helped sustain my interest, as
did the character of Catherine, Tony's spoiled, bored and man-hungry
sister. Pearl Bailey also scores points for her portrayal of the
down-on-her-luck, boozing blues singer Ruby Jones. In fact, Wagner's
Chad has the best relationship and chemistry with her. When Chad
reappears in Salome's life, of course that adds to the tension within
the plot. After a while, though, I couldn't understand how Salome could
still tolerate him (especially when he marries Catherine out of spite),
and I don't get why Tony didn't suspect that the baby was not his (ever
think of doing the math, Tone?) The character of Tony, for me, is one
of the most sympathetic. His love and concern for Salome, his devotion
to Catherine and to little Peter, makes him much more emotionally
reachable.(Why didn't Salome realize that she loved him earlier?). Chad
only speaks of Peter as if the boy is his property, and doesn't seem to
care about his welfare, only revenge on Salome. Granted, she should
have told him that she married someone else and that she was passing
off the child as her husband's. You can almost feel Salome's longing
for Chad, but I don't know how she could pine for him with Tony lying
right next to her! When it comes right down to it, I couldn't tear
myself away, even now, a few years later after I first saw it, it has
some sentimental value. I was already a fan of Natalie, but I barely
knew George Hamilton existed before - although was interested after! -
and I developed a great respect not only for Wood but also Susan
Kohner, who deserved a longer career. Fun little bit of trivia : Did
you know that Susan and George had made a film together before this and
that at one point, they were engaged? The music makes the moody,
longing tone of the film - in fact, it's one of the highlights. And if
you enjoyed it, see the 1959 version of "Imitation Of Life" starring
Lana Turner, Sandra Dee, John Gavin and Susan Kohner. I recommend "All
The Fine Young Cannibals" to adventurous viewers who are willing to
take the risk. See if you can tear your eyes away!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0064529/comments</url><from>from Málaga, Málaga, Spain</from><name>Miguel Angel Diaz Gonzalez (dalton22@terra.es)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

If you're looking for happy moments, then this isn't
your film. The problems grow and grow and you never
see a solution for them. Under my point of view, it's not
a
bad film, but the story hasn't got a message and it's
so sad that the only way
to enjoy the film is by appreciating the acting,
the directing, etc...My rating is 7 out of 10

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0169112/comments</url><from>from North Carolina</from><name>Ripshin</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The opening twenty, or so, minutes of this film are ludicrous, and I
had to force myself to stay away from the delete button on my DVR.
Pretty couple Wagner &amp; Wood unconvincingly play two white-trash Texas
teenagers, utilizing some of the worst faux Texas/Southern accents to
ever grace (or in this case, disgrace) the screen. Granted, once the
film has Pearl Bailey to work with, there are some nice moments, but
they are few and far between.Hamilton has little to do, and Susan Kohner plays spoiled rich girl
Catherine so broadly, you expect the character to grow horns and carry
around a pitchfork.Sets and costumes are the usual MGM glam.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Anderson's movie is derivative.It looks like lite Douglas Sirk: the
spoiled kid sister (played by Susan Kohner who worked with Sirk) is not
unlike Marylee (Dorothy Malone) in "Written on the wind" ;besides
,Ruby's funeral will fatally make you think of that of Annie in
"Imitation of life" ,a black choir singing "Free at last" replacing
Mahalia Jackson.The screenwriters also borrow from Kazan's "splendor in
the grass" as far as the two leads' fate is concerned.And the baby
trick was used a hundred times or more in the thirties and forties
melodramas (notably Bette Davis' "the big lie" and "the old maid"
;Olivia De Havilland' s "to each his own").Having said this,one must credit Natalie Wood for making the best of
the stereotyped part of a go-getter;Robert Wagner's moody looks work
wonders too when he plays the trumpet and in the scene when he backs
Pearl Bailey's impressive vocals.This is the kind of movie they don't do anymore;this is the kind of
story which could go on and on and on and on;in a word,it's the perfect
soap opera ,and it still exists today in the form of the TV series.Like this?try these.......Peyton Place Mark Robson 1957Imitation of life Douglas Sirk 1959
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10797344/comments</url><from>from Belgium</from><name>winstonfg</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Better still, buy the soundtrack on CD. Dated, pretentious angst-ridden
nonsense that is saved only partially by the fine music; and certainly
not by an over-the-top Natalie Wood and Robert Wagner. I usually like
Wood (not quite so sold on Wagner), but here she seems shrill and the
whole film looks and feels awfully dated. I'd rate it just ahead of the
truly criminal Subterraneans of the same year (with another of my usual
favourites, Leslie Caron). That also had a great soundtrack, including
the great Gerry Mulligan, but in it's case it wasn't enough to induce
me to watch it all the way through.This one I did, but I'm not sure it was worth the bother.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12830849/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tejanaZ</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
They don't make films like this anymore but they made a lot of them
then. This is one of the better ones ... a perfect 2 hour indulgence on
a rainy afternoon.I've seen this film many times in the course of my life but I just
realized it's a modern reworking of Emily Brontes' "Wuthering Heights".
It wasn't until tonight that I realized the similarity. I think that's
because it works with the added elements that distinguish it.It's full tilt melodrama of the Harlequin novel variety but its a good
one ... emotional, overwrought and overacted in Technicolor. Pearl
Bailey steals the show from all the beautiful people at the center of
this soap opera. I just wish she sang more ...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12830849/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tejanaZ</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
They don't make films like this anymore but they made a lot of them
then. This is one of the better ones ... a perfect 2 hour indulgence on
a rainy afternoon.I've seen this film many times in the course of my life but I just
realized it's a modern reworking of Emily Brontes' "Wuthering Heights".
It wasn't until tonight that I realized the similarity. I think that's
because it works with the added elements that distinguish it.It's full tilt melodrama of the Harlequin novel variety but its a good
one ... emotional, overwrought and overacted in Technicolor. Pearl
Bailey steals the show from all the beautiful people at the center of
this soap opera. I just wish she sang more ...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>