<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Oscar Wilde</original_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Gregory Ratoff</director><producer>Vantage Films</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis/><actor>Robert Morley</actor><actor>Phyllis Calvert</actor><actor>Ralph Richardson</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0150928/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>David Matthews (dmatthews03@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Whatever money was spent on this movie certainly didn't go on the sets, the
furniture looks as though it was assembled by a local handyman and the trial
scenes, which make up the largest part of the film, seem to be taking place
in a converted church hall or  school gymnasium with hastily constructed
props. However this happens to be a very good film indeed, the superb acting
carries the film and makes it far better than the more lavish Peter Finch
version which was released about the same time.I've always thought of Robert Morley as just a comic character playing
himself but here he really becomes Oscar Wilde. You can imagine Wilde
talking and behaving as he does in this movie . The verbal exchanges between
Morley as Wilde and Ralph Richardson as the prosecutor are magnificent.
Wilde enjoying the limelight, plays to the gallery and  wins every one of
the exchanges until he gets too confident, makes one fatal error and then
the prosecutor starts to chip away at his defense.The minor characters are uniformly well acted with Phyllis Calvert as
Wilde's wife, Dennis Price as his loyal friend and Edward Chapman as the
boorish Marquis of Queensbury . John Neville is probably a little too old to
play Sir Alfred Douglas but  his skilful acting  makes it work . The final
scenes between Wilde and his family are very touching.Well worth seeing.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Oscar Wilde reputation is set for all time. He was a brilliant, witty
writer of graceful style. He was also a bi-sexual, whose affair with
Lord Alfred Douglas led to a tragic final fall when exposed in court.
What most people forget is that the trial where he was exposed was a
libel suit against Lord Alfred's brutal and mad father the Marquess of
Queensbury (the one who gave us the rules for boxing). Queensbury hated
his sons and their mother, and his antics helped lead to the suicide of
one of the sons (the private secretary of Prime Minister, Lord
Roseberry). Queensbury disliked Wilde for his influence over Lord
Alfred and his unspeakable homosexual affair with his son. He sent him
a note on a card, "To Oscar Wilde, disguised as a "somdomite"." The
Marquess presumed that by misspelling sodomite he was protecting
himself but smearing Wilde. Wilde had an opportunity then to ignore the
slur and go abroad for awhile (which most men in his position would
have done). He decided to sue - goaded into it by Lord Alfred (who saw
this as a safe opportunity to hit at his father). Never has such a
critically important legal decision been made on such a stupid basis. The barrister for Queensbury was Edward Carson, one of England's
greatest lawyers. He is the model for the barrister played by Robert
Donat in "The Winslow Boy" (based on Carson's defense of young
Archer-Shee in the 1911 legal action). Carson was a master of
cross-examination, and he had plenty of information that Queensbury
(and Wilde's many enemies) had gathered about his sexual activities.
But Wilde was able to fend off the attack for hours, until he reached a
series of questions about a telegraph boy who was available for sex for
hire. Carson had been unable to make a dent into Wilde's hide so far,
and then out of sheer desperation asked, "Did you kiss him?" Wilde was
amazed - the question did throw him. "Did I kiss him?", he repeated.
"Yes", answered Carson with a lack of real interest. Wilde had been
trumping Carson with one-liners that left the court in stitches.
Instead of saying, "Of course not!" or "How dare you!", which would
have helped, Wilde quipped the sentence in the summary line above. And
Carson saw the light at the end of the tunnel. Wilde never recovered
after that.The jury was able to absolve Queensbury of libel (after all, it was
shown that Wilde was homosexual). The authorities now held back for
nearly twelve hours from going after Wilde. They simply hoped he would
flee to the continent. Instead, Wilde decided to stay and fight. It is
the second trial that really demolished him. He was now on trial of
committing sodomy, and the evidence was too overwhelming. Found guilty,
he was sentenced to three years in prison. He left prison and lived in
France until he died in Paris, a broken, impoverished wreck, in 1900.If you are a homosexual, Wilde is one of the great martyr's to the
cause. If you love good writing his end is a dismal tragedy. All the
films of his life retell it's denouement. It never gets any better in
the retelling - there is no repaired last act. Even (historically) a
"reformed", right-wing supporting Lord Alfred rejected the image of his
"Bosie" period in later years - claiming he never was a homosexual. One
ends just pitying Wilde, unless one is just a reactionary type or a
mindless idiot like Queensbury.Robert Morley never gave a better dramatic performance on film (as
opposed to his comic performances) than in this film. Witness his
moment on the witness stand, when he realizes the result of his
blunder. The cast of John Neville, Ralph Richardson, Edward Chapman,
and Dennis Price do equally well in this tale of talent that was shot
down so stupidly. I certainly recommend watching it...and then reading
"Dorian Gray", "The Importance of Being Earnest", "Salome", "The Ballad
of the Reading Gaol", to get a glimmer of the talent that was smashed
beyond repair.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0389263/comments</url><from>from Pa.</from><name>peacham</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Unlike the stiff and flashy Peter Finch film released a year later,this film
is a gem. Robert Morely more than captures the wit,pain and humanity of
Oscar Wilde. The film is very daring for its time,not only by presenting
Wilde's trials for Gross Indecency on film,but for its loving and
sympathetic portrayal of the man.John Neville is also wonderful as Bosie Douglass,Wilde's lover,and Sir Ralph
Richardson as Edward Carson illuminates the trial scenes. The interrogation
of Morley by Richardson,and Morley's witty comebacks are not only tyhe
highlight of the film,but possibly could be one of filmdom's greatest trial
scenes. Where the Finch film glossed over the surface of the events,this film takes
you into the real people involved,Phyliss Calvert as Wilde's Wife,Constance
and Dennis Price as his friend Robbie Ross are also wonderful in their role.
Its a shame this film is not yet available on video for all to
cherish.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Without a doubt, this is the film to see if you are deeply interested
in this unconventional and fabulous writer that was Oscar Wilde. Two
other films about him were shot: "the Trials of Oscar Wilde" and Brian
Gilbert's work in 1997 but they aren't found wanting to Gregory
Ratoff's version.Of course, it's indisputable that Ratoff's film was made with
restricted means as the cheap scenery testify. It sometimes gives way
to drawbacks like in the very last sequence which shows Wilde after his
lost trial sitting at the terrace of a Parisian café and next to him,
one can hear a musician playing the accordion. A perfect cliché about
France. But it's minor quibble and anyway, given the means Ratoff had
at his disposal, was there another way to show the audience that Wilde
was in Paris under the pseudonym of Sébastien Melmott? Anyway, one can
eminently forget the scenery and admire how Ratoff conceived his film.
First, he eschewed many traps of the biopic film including the
following one: to relate all Wilde's life from his childhood. He chose
to steer his film on the period of his life which began with the
relationship Wilde developed with his young protégé Lord Alfred
Douglas. In a nutshell, this scandalous love (for the time) was the
beginning of the end for the witty writer who fell foul of the chic,
posh Victorian society. As everyone knows, homosexuality was banned in
this very conservative, ossified society and it could only end up as a
trial for Wilde. A trial he could only lose but during which he showed
a stalwart courage thanks to his own witty answers. This trial is the
pinnacle of the film and Ratoff succeeds in incorporating elements of
Wilde's anterior life like the introduction at the outset of his
wondrous novel "the Picture of Dorian Gray" (1889). And one can only
admire his style to film the evolution of this trial and the verbal
exchanges between Wilde and sir Edward Carson. At first, Wilde seems
sure of himself and his cues make the audience laugh but bit by bit
confidence leaves him as he is dwarfed by dogged Carson's ruthless
questions. In the long run, Ratoff weaves a stifling atmosphere and
it's impossible not to feel it.All you have to do is to sit and admire the quality of the dialogs and
also of the actors. Robert Morley confers to his main character the wit
and wisdom which made Wilde famous. And Ralph Richardson equally
delivers a prime performance. But John Neville seems too old for the
role Lord Alfred Douglas. In the most recent version, Jude Law was a
better choice thanks to his relatively young age.Of course, this film will never supersede a good book about one of the
most crucial writers who existed on this planet but Ratoff's work makes
him justice.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0450172/comments</url><from>from Mountain View, Ca</from><name>Frank Dudley Berry, Jr. (fdber@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The other comment describes Sir Edward Carson as the prosecutor of
Oscar Wilde. That's incorrect.What happened was that, in a fit of madness, Oscar Wilde sued the
Marquis of Queensbury (the father of his lover, Sir Alfred Douglas and
the author of the rules of modern boxing) for slander, based on an
accusation by Queensbury that Wilde was a 'somdomite' (sic). All of
Wilde's friends tried to talk him out of it - Victorian England worked
on a 'don't ask, don't tell' basis, and Wilde was quite safe had he
done nothing. But his success as a playwright emboldened him, and he
filed suit.Carson was retained by the Marquis to defend him. The famous
cross-examination occurred during the trial of Wilde's slander
complaint. He was destroyed on cross examination, in such a way that
the nature of his lifestyle became too public to be ignored. Carson,
after he had won the slander case, actually tried to dissuade the Crown
from prosecuting, but to no avail. A criminal prosecution did follow,
in which Carson was not involved, ending in Wilde's conviction, and a 2
year prison sentence that effectively ended his career and life.Carson, an Irish Protestant, earned my own condemnation for his role in
opposing Irish independence. But in the Wilde case, he was responding
for the defense, and he took active steps thereafter to prevent a
prosecution. Wilde was the principal cause of his own legal
destruction.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0509769/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I am a fan of both Oscar and Robert but am very disappointed in Morley's
portrayal of Wilde. Physically, he is both too old, too short, too plain
and
too fat to capture the magnificent physical presence of Oscar.  I had
trouble also with the script which practically obliterates Oscar's
homosexuality. John Neville is too old and stilted to give us the beauty
and
appeal of Bosie. Oscar's well known sardonic wit is also missed in this
interpretation.  I much preferred Stephen Fry's later performance.  When I
think of Oscar, I think of glamour, vanity, beauty, genius, all of which
is
missing in this 1959 attempt.  5 out of 10 for Phyllis Calvert and Ralph
Richardson. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Across the decades, cinematic directors have sought to discover the
essence of the noted 18th century humorous, poet and playwright Oscar
Wilde. Some films shower him with so many accolades, they drown his
image in wine and sexual innuendos. Other movies hardly delve into the
magical but certainly secret complexity of the talented English writer,
using his notorious trial, tribulations and eventual imprisonment as
Gris, reducing him to a mere scandalous shell of his life. Perhaps,
there are many film versions of Mr. Wilde, but only one stands out
which personifies the ideal man. I believe this offering, "Oscar
Wilde," (1960) portrayed by enormously talented Robert Morley as the
playwright, is the best. True Mr. Morley is such a versatile actor in
other films, some would suggest his comic side, or his stuffy, droll
demeanor, detract from this impressive writer. I disagree. Despite his
inner personal conflicts, Morley exemplifies the quick wit, delightful
charm and social elegance befitting the true character of the 18th
century cosmopolitan gentleman. Moreley more than adequately depicts
the larger than life of Oscar Wilde. Ralph Richardson, plays, Sir
Edward Carson the prosecuting attorney who's sole ambition was to
destroy the popular writer and his libertine attitudes. Although
seeking to protect the upper-class from scandal, his attack was nothing
short of evisceral. As one newspaper noted at the trial, the prosecutor
was seen to be as objective as a circling shark. All in all, this film
is an excellent attempt at epitomizing the historical icon, and is
accepted as the very best to-date. ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Across the decades, cinematic directors have sought to discover the
essence of the noted 18th century humorous, poet and playwright Oscar
Wilde. Some films shower him with so many accolades, they drown his
image in wine and sexual innuendos. Other movies hardly delve into the
magical but certainly secret complexity of the talented English writer,
using his notorious trial, tribulations and eventual imprisonment as
Gris, reducing him to a mere scandalous shell of his life. Perhaps,
there are many film versions of Mr. Wilde, but only one stands out
which personifies the ideal man. I believe this offering, "Oscar
Wilde," (1960) portrayed by enormously talented Robert Morley as the
playwright, is the best. True Mr. Morley is such a versatile actor in
other films, some would suggest his comic side, or his stuffy, droll
demeanor, detract from this impressive writer. I disagree. Despite his
inner personal conflicts, Morley exemplifies the quick wit, delightful
charm and social elegance befitting the true character of the 18th
century cosmopolitan gentleman. Moreley more than adequately depicts
the larger than life of Oscar Wilde. Ralph Richardson, plays, Sir
Edward Carson the prosecuting attorney who's sole ambition was to
destroy the popular writer and his libertine attitudes. Although
seeking to protect the upper-class from scandal, his attack was nothing
short of evisceral. As one newspaper noted at the trial, the prosecutor
was seen to be as objective as a circling shark. All in all, this film
is an excellent attempt at epitomizing the historical icon, and is
accepted as the very best to-date. ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>