<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Song Without End</original_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Charles Vidor</director><producer>William Goetz Productions</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Music</genre><synopsis>His Scandalous Affairs Shocked the World!</synopsis><actor>Dirk Bogarde</actor><actor>Capucine</actor><actor>Geneviève Page</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Ferencz Liszt was by most accounts a kind and pious man who shared his
talents and privileges of his fame with his fans, students and fellow
artists like Berlioz and Wagner. This film does him an injustice by
portraying him as a prima donna and Lothario. Nevertheless, the
producers must be commended for making it. It aroused my interest in
classical music when I saw it at the age of 10.I thrilled to the bombast and impossible fingerwork of Hungarian
Rhapsody No. 2. But the final piece Liszt (portrayed by Bogarde) played
as he retreated to the monastery haunted me throughout my teenage
years. Liebestraume No. 3 ("Dreams of Love") can either be a soothing
balm or a cutting knife for the lovesick. Bogarde, who obviously knew his onions about piano playing displayed
the exact fingerwork on the proper fields of the keyboard and his body
English was totally convincing. Well after all, he was not only an
actor but a true artist - an accomplished writer and a painter. Capuccine, touted as one of the most beautiful women at the time,
portrayed the Princess of Witgenstein. But my heart fell for the jilted
wife, the Belgian countess portrayed by Genevieve Page whom I found
more,"simpatica."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Franz Liszt back in the day was maybe the first popular musical icon.
Since we have no phonograph records of what he sounded like on the
piano we only have his music to judge him by today. Good thing he wrote
a lot of it.A Liszt concert back then if played for a mass audience was something
like the reception that Elvis and The Beatles got back in their day. It
aroused the jealousy of a lot of Liszt's contemporaries, but they
respected his talent.Dirk Bogarde is a capable and charismatic Liszt who had a weakness for
married women. He ran off with one and had a couple of kids by her and
then seduces a royal countess. The two women in question are played by
Genevieve Page and Capucine. Dirk and Cappy have a whole lot of hurdles to overcome before they can
be happy, put there by the Romanov family and the Catholic Church, but
it does sort of work itself out in the end.My favorite performance in the film is that of Martita Hunt who plays a
dowager German princess who offers Liszt employment when he needs it. The film only covers a small portion of Franz Liszt's life, still it's
a worthwhile biographical study.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5032489/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Kar595</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Song Without End is indeed a film that does not display the characters
in a believable situation. However, the music score is among the
greatest in motion pictures.I will always remember that performance of ' Les Prelues'as being the
most powerful that I have ever heard even from the best symphony
orchestras.The performances of the late Jorge Bolet are
magnificent.Especially during the clever arrangement of the
Concerto/Hungarian Fantasia. It is clear that Dirk Bogarde is not
playing the piano,yet one cannot help but take pleasure in the
greatness of the music whomever is playing.The producer of the film also takes great pains in letting the audience
know that Franz Liszt often performed the music of other composers like
Wagner and Berlioz.He also was a great fan of Chopin. This is addressed
in the film with care and intelligence.I remember this film as a child and can still remember the great
music.Thank God! for the score from Song Without End.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"Song Without End" has a low score here on IMDb. I'm not sure why. It
is superior, in my opinion, in every way to "A Song to Remember" which
is a nearly totally fictionalized story of Chopin. "Song without End"
has the basic facts right, not to mention 40 absolutely gorgeous
musical interludes. Jorge Bolet, who plays all of the piano pieces,
captures the technical pyrotechnics, the richness of tone, and the
passion for which Liszt was known as a performer.The film only covers part of Liszt's life and concentrates (naturally)
on the turmoil in his love affairs, which leads to his attempt to marry
the already married Princess Carolyne Wittgenstein; he left his married
girlfriend, Countess Marie D'Agoult, the mother of his children for
her. (One of his daughters, Cosima, married Richard Wagner, who
features in this film.) I disagree with a previous comment complaining
about the way Liszt is portrayed. While it's not emphasized, it is
obvious that he was a man of great charity, donating many of his fees
to various organizations, and playing many benefit concerts. Later on,
he concentrated on composing, at which he was very successful. As a
performer, Liszt was a bona fide rock star in his day, complete with
hysterical fans. He was most certainly attractive to women and
religiously conflicted.Dirk Bogarde does a sensational job as Liszt. This and "The Angel Wore
Red" were his only Hollywood films. Even if they had been successful,
it's doubtful Bogarde would have stayed in the states, as he probably
wouldn't have been cast in the kinds of films he wanted to make and/or
the kinds of parts he wanted to play. He makes a very romantic, intense
Liszt, and his fingerings are nothing short of amazing. Capucine is
good, if a little wooden, as Carolyne. The supporting cast is very
good.The production and costumes are opulent, but they are dwarfed by the
music. Definitely some of the most brilliantly performed classical
music in film.Highly recommended for classical music lovers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2542703/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edwagreen</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Opulent film is terrific with Dirk Bogarde playing Franz Liszt in a
totally memorable performance. Capucine, as the Princess Carolyne, and
Genevieve Page, as the abandoned mistress, were truly terrific here as
well as a fine supporting performance by Martita Hunt, as the Czar's
sympathetic sister. Hunt literally made a career of playing strong,
erudite women.The set decorations here are phenomenal, they're on par with the great
1944 film "Wilson."The music is magnificent although we could have done without knowing
about the friendship between Liszt and the anti-Semite Richard Wagner.
Another flaw is the miscasting of Lou Jacobi as Bogarde's manager.
Jacobi sounded like he came out of the Catskills. This film for Jacobi
came after his super performance, the year before, in the beloved "The
Diary of Anne Frank." (Happy Birthday Lou as you turn 95 on Dec. 28th.)The first part of the film deals with Liszt's career. His playing in
concerts in various European countries was remarkable. The second part
deals with his ill-fated love with the Countess Cathryne of
Lichtenstein.While we see that Liszt entered the priesthood when his proposed
marriage to Cathryne was rejected, we really can't tell if Cathryne
became a nun. I imagine no since she was still technically married in
the eyes of the church. Nonetheless, we have a powerful, beautifully
acted film. Too bad that Totentanz, a Liszt masterpiece, was not played
here. I had to know that piece of grand music in a required music
course at college. Like the movie, Totentanz was a masterful piece.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie for one reason--it starred Dirk Bogarde. He was a
wonderful actor and I'd watch him in anything--even a bio-pic! My
dislike of most bio-pics is important to note, as unlike the other
reviewers, I really didn't adore Franz Liszt and the idea of a film
about him. That's because in my opinion (and I am sure many will
disagree), most biographical movies are either short on entertainment
value (they can be sluggish) or they avoid this by playing fast and
loose with the facts. Frankly, I don't like either extreme. But when it
comes to Liszt, I have no idea if this film is accurate--he is someone
about whom I know very little (other than the fact that Bogarde looked
nothing like him and the film makers did little to correct this). But I
do know that the film is lethargic...very, very lethargic. So, despite
his affairs and illegitimate children, the film managed to make all
this very, very dull--and that is a crime. How can a film that often
focuses on the composer's scandalous relationships be so turgid?!
Perhaps because all too often nothing happens in the film--just lots
and lots and lots of scenes with Bogarde playing either the piano or
the organ. And, as many of the songs were not Liszt's compositions, I
just felt a bit bored. So, aside from nice music (though a bit too much
of it) and nice costumes, I found the whole thing pretty stale. If you
are a musician and/or adore Liszt, perhaps you'll have a very different
opinion--I just know that Dirk Bogarde made other films with a lot more
energy and entertainment value.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1349838/comments</url><from>from Lincolnshire, England.</from><name>JBall75487</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

In a confused welter of artistic licence, this is the classical music
biopic
which makes 'Song to Remember'look like a masterpiece. Bogarde succeeds in
diminishing the reputation of the musical colossus who spanned European
music for most of the 19th Century. The absurdities of the plot, the
sequoia-like quality of the acting and the prevalence of historical,musical
and linguistic anachronisms combine to elevate this offering to the status
of an A1 turkey.How a pianist of the stature of Bolet came to be mixed up
in
this fiasco can only be guessed at. The characterisation of Liszt fails to
convey even a minute impression of his magnetic personality and the
overwhelming effect that he had on not only his audiences, but also his
pianistic rivals.Clara Schumann herself said that 'we toil over that which
Liszt reads at sight!'
Whilst the emphasis seems to focus on his romantic prowess,rather than his
status as the greatest pianist of the century or,arguably, of all time, one
feels,nevertheless, that this was an opportunity lost.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1349838/comments</url><from>from Lincolnshire, England.</from><name>JBall75487</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

In a confused welter of artistic licence, this is the classical music
biopic
which makes 'Song to Remember'look like a masterpiece. Bogarde succeeds in
diminishing the reputation of the musical colossus who spanned European
music for most of the 19th Century. The absurdities of the plot, the
sequoia-like quality of the acting and the prevalence of historical,musical
and linguistic anachronisms combine to elevate this offering to the status
of an A1 turkey.How a pianist of the stature of Bolet came to be mixed up
in
this fiasco can only be guessed at. The characterisation of Liszt fails to
convey even a minute impression of his magnetic personality and the
overwhelming effect that he had on not only his audiences, but also his
pianistic rivals.Clara Schumann herself said that 'we toil over that which
Liszt reads at sight!'
Whilst the emphasis seems to focus on his romantic prowess,rather than his
status as the greatest pianist of the century or,arguably, of all time, one
feels,nevertheless, that this was an opportunity lost.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1349838/comments</url><from>from Lincolnshire, England.</from><name>JBall75487</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/song_without_end/comments.php?reviewid=1717093</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>The great music is THE thing in this musical biography.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/song_without_end/comments.php?reviewid=1419205</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/75007/song_without_end.html /m/song_without_end/comments.php?reviewid=1481797</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9B03E6D6163CEF3ABC4A52DFBE66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/song_without_end/comments.php?reviewid=1389738</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=108531 /m/song_without_end/comments.php?reviewid=1147107</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/11315_SONG_WITHOUT_END.html /m/song_without_end/comments.php?reviewid=26348</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>