<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Grass Is Greener</original_title><alt_title>Ailleurs l'herbe est plus verte</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Stanley Donen</director><producer>Grandon Productions Ltd.</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Victor and Hillary are down on their luck to the point that they allow tourists to take guided tours of their castle...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Cary Grant</actor><actor>Deborah Kerr</actor><actor>Robert Mitchum</actor><rt_rating>6.6/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0307374/comments</url><from/><name>Robert D. Ruplenas</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This delightful film's script is a descendant of the sort of archly witty
portrayals of British upper-class life that came from the pens of Somerset
Maugham and Noel Coward (one of whose songs serves as musical lead-in, and
at least one of whose tunes ["Mad About the Boy" - listen for it] serves as
background music to comment on the action). The atmosphere of this sort of
comedy may be a bit foreign to American tastes (the whole topic of
infidelity is discussed in such a civilized and gentlemanly fashion among
the parties- Stiff Upper Lip and all that -  where Americans would be
screaming at each other and going for weaponry) but as a devotee of British
drama I enjoyed the movie hugely. It's a stellar cast - everyone shines,
right down to Moray Watson in the small but delicious part of the befuddled
butler Sellers. Jean Simmons is especially enjoyable in her out-of-character
portrayal as the  outspokenly vampish Hattie. Despite opinions below to the
contrary, the incomparable Cary Grant fills the part of this
down-at-the-heels English Lord like old brandy fills a crystal decanter. The
sumptuous setting of the baronial manor and the high production values make
the film beautiful to look at, to boot. (The fact that the unfortunate Lord
is forced to open his manor to paying visitors to support his lifestyle is
based on the historical truth of the confiscatory tax policies imposed on
the British hereditary gentry by post-WWII Labor governments; everyone is
entitled to their own opinions on these policies, but be assured the film
makes no political comment). It does stretch the imagination a tad that Victor could treat the whole
issue of his wife's infidelity - going on right in front of his nose - in
such a dispassionate manner, but that is a characteristic of this genre.
Further, Grant manages to convince us that, beneath his outer
imperturability, his wife's disloyalty has pained him deeply and he could
not stand to lose her. This is a not-well-known film whose appeal might be a bit specialized, but I
think it's a minor gem. And I could not omit mentioning the charming opening
credits with their bevy of delightfully cavorting babies.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3028519/comments</url><from>from san francisco, ca.</from><name>gilgeoIII</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Although I'm a film buff, I was unaware of the existence this
delightful,sophisticated comedy until I saw it recently on TV in Buenos
Aires, of all places. Grant, Kerr and Simmons are splendid, as usual,
and Mitchum is, well, Mitchum and that's good enough for me. The plot
offers the conceit of Mitchum taking Kerr away from Grant, her fusty
husband, because Mitch is hot and Grant's not, a rather daring concept
for 1960. Grant, of course, has a trick or two up his sleeve and alls
well that ends well. The witty dialogue and snappy direction (Stanley
Donen) puts to shame the witless, charmless crap churned out by
Hollywood hacks for the past 25

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239428/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name>harry-76</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Drawing room comedies seem to be a thing of the past.  Their demise was
apparently one reason Cary Grant decided to thin down his late career: his
kind of parts just weren't being written anymore. By the time this film version of a stage hit came out in 1960, the genre had
just about run its course. How fortunate to have four full-fledged stars take on the leading roles. 
What is Robert Mitchum doing in an English castle, interacting with "upper
class royalty"?  For one thing, he plays a Texas millionaire--an impressive entree most
places.  Then, the rest of the cast are all transported Brits, so long
established in America as to be de facto Americans. They can still deliver
their clipped English lines, thought, with great flair.("So, now you're a millionare, and I'm growing mushrooms . . . oh well,
that's the way the world wags.")Deborah Kerr is bright and vulnerable, Jean Simmons, pert and sophisticated,
Robert Mitchum, cool and crafty, and Cary Grant urbane and witty.   It's fun
to see this quartet trading double entendres and quaint quips. Stanley Donnen does his best with a stagy script, relying on his experienced
cast to carry off the humor and action. It succeeds nicely, and its
downright fun to follow their stylish jousts.Tea, brandy, or champagne? 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is a film that does try to be good - and it is actually amusing at
points. The central story about the aristocrats finding interest in an
American millionaire (Mitchum) and an old flame of Grant's (Simmons)
had potential. But the problem was that the screenplay is too talky and
too cerebral, but not (paradoxically) as complete as it should be.There are pages and pages of the dialog which are (frankly) long
winded. Cary Grant is not amusing when explaining his behavior to
people, even Deborah Kerr. Whatever emotional chemistry worked for them
so wonderfully in AN AFFAIR TO REMEMBER is cut down considerably here.The additions of Robert Mitchum and Jean Simmons does not really help.
Mitchum's growing interest in Kerr, and her growing response to his
seeing her in London is okay, but Simmons' relationship regarding Grant
is not developed. We know they had an affair before he married her
friend Kerr, and she has remained a friend of both, and she is funny
regarding her open interest in sex, but why Grant's rejection of her is
never really gone into. Also, at the tale end, there is the suggestion
that Simmons and Mitchum might find each other a worthy lover. But
nothing in the film really builds up to that final look between them!
There are good moments - Grant and Mitchum going fishing, and muttering
under their breaths about each other, and the business about the fur
coat gift that Mitchum buys Kerr, and she tries to hide (and Simmons
ends up wearing as her own). But the good moments are fragments. The
duel scene towards the end is analyzed to death. It says a lot that the
use of Noel Coward's song THE STATELY HOMES OF ENGLAND on the
soundtrack at the start and end of the film is one of the highlights.
One wishes Coward wrote the screenplay here - it might have been
brighter or more consistent.Because the cast really tries I have given it a "7", but it is not as
good a film as it should have been.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0857426/comments</url><from/><name>fletch5</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Enjoyable cast and often deliciously witty dialogue succeed enlivening
this
otherwise rather static comedy. It can't shake off its staginess, which
results in occasional moments of slight weariness, but for the most part,
"The Grass Is Greener" is classy and quite entertaining. There are some
splendid scenes between the four leading actors that make you smile.
Really
big laughs aren't guaranteed, but the film leaves an overall good
feeling.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7757426/comments</url><from>from Pittsburgh</from><name>dishington</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This delightful morsel is even more impressive given the bare
post-Eisenhower era of its release. While we tend to view 1960 as the
beginning of the JFK cultural renaissance, in fact the decade dawned
with Ike in the White House and Nixon on the horizon. Extramarital
hijinks, dealt with adult sophistication, tolerance and forgiveness are
rare enough, but the Bible-thumpers must have bust a gut on this one. I
disagree with those who chastise the title, I think it's perfect. That
such a topic is explored without losing the light comedic magic of
Grant, the earnest angst of Kerr, the irreverent sexuality of Simmons
and the brooding strength of Mitchum is testament to the ability of
Stanley Donen to guide without herding. It all fits, wonderfully, in a
movie that glows brighter with the passage of time, and the tsunami of
trash that was to follow.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0172017/comments</url><from>from Israel</from><name>Jonathan Doron (yonatandoron@walla.co.il)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Fine, funny and recommended. It has its weak points, the storyline is the
least important with these fine actors and brilliant direction. Cary Grant
and Jean Simmons' first scene together is absolutely wonderful. Deborah
Kerr
is also good; Robert Mitchum, maybe intentionally, is a bit of an odd
player
here. Familiar to the Grant-Ingrid Bergman split-screen telephone scene in
Donen's Indiscreet, there's an adorable scene with all four leading actors
here. Very very nice.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Lord Cary Grant and Lady Deborah Kerr as nobility have fallen on hard
times and now they show their fabulous estate off to the tourists for
pin money. One of those tourists is American millionaire Robert Mitchum
who thinks the best sight he's seen is Kerr. He sweeps her off her feet
and her marriage is put in danger.Cary's not going to take this lying down and Mitchum is invited to the
estate for the weekend. Along for the ride is Jean Simmons, a friend of
Grant's and Kerr who wouldn't mind getting Cary on the rebound. It's
quite a weekend.Cary Grant and I assume Deborah Kerr's parts according the recent
biography of Robert Mitchum were originally intended for Rex Harrison
and Kay Kendall. When Kendall died, Harrison dropped out. Cary Grant's
part probably would have been better in Harrison's hands. But you can't
say that Grant didn't learn a lesson. He was widely quoted as saying
after he turned down My Fair Lady that he wouldn't even by a ticket to
see the film of Harrison didn't play Henry Higgins.Simmons does come off the best in this comedy of manners. She's full of
wisecracks and is no hypocrite about her life.You know when you think about it the same premise was used for Sleuth
with much more serious overtones. It's sometimes a small margin between
comedy and drama.Not the best work that any of this talented quartet has done.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0171504/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>Rene' Smeraglia</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The cast is obviously the star of this film, with headliners Grant, Kerr,
Mitchum and Simmons each doing a fabulous job in a movie that depends very
heavily on intelligent, witty dialogue strewn with double-entendres. The
subject is adultery, and whether one (Grant) should make a public fuss when
his wife (Kerr) is being swept off her feet by a rich American (Mitchum).
Mix in a beautiful, if somewhat dotty, friend (Simmons) who makes sly
observances throughout. Although set in England of the late 50s, the film
doesn't show much countryside and occasionally feels a bit claustrophobic
as
the action takes place on a very few sets.  The film feels like it has
stage
origins, and it plays much like Neil Simon's better film adaptations (e.g.
California Suite, Barefoot in the Park).  If you are a fan of any of these
stars, this movie will entertain you.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0536292/comments</url><from>from Heart of England</from><name>Jacquline</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

There is a glittering cast (Cary Grant, Deborah Kerr, Robert Mitchum and
Jean Simmons), a witty script  and  beautiful  scenes of the English
countryside in superb colour. So why is this film so flat? Whether it is a
movie, a play or a novel one has to believe in the characters.
Unfortunately Cary Grant is not believable as an English lord.   Deborah
Kerr is not believable as an unfaithful wife. Robert Mitchum is believable
as an American tourist but , seemed uncomfortable in the role. When he
walked into the private apartments of Lord and Lady  Ryall in their Stately
home he looked as if he should have been walking into a Chicago speakeasy.
Only Jean Simmons seemed to fit her part.   It was a funny script which was
wasted.   Still, anything with Cary Grant in it is worth watching.  See
what
you think.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0536292/comments</url><from>from Heart of England</from><name>Jacquline</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

There is a glittering cast (Cary Grant, Deborah Kerr, Robert Mitchum and
Jean Simmons), a witty script  and  beautiful  scenes of the English
countryside in superb colour. So why is this film so flat? Whether it is a
movie, a play or a novel one has to believe in the characters.
Unfortunately Cary Grant is not believable as an English lord.   Deborah
Kerr is not believable as an unfaithful wife. Robert Mitchum is believable
as an American tourist but , seemed uncomfortable in the role. When he
walked into the private apartments of Lord and Lady  Ryall in their Stately
home he looked as if he should have been walking into a Chicago speakeasy.
Only Jean Simmons seemed to fit her part.   It was a funny script which was
wasted.   Still, anything with Cary Grant in it is worth watching.  See
what
you think.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0536292/comments</url><from>from Heart of England</from><name>Jacquline</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1802390</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Fun Cary Grant, Deborah Kerr comedy romp with Stanley Donen touch.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lori-hoffman/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1616196</url><name>Lori Hoffman</name><from>Atlantic City Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Robert Mitchum will surprise you</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=759699</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Airless, but well acted comedy</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1610576</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1403506</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rebecca-murray/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1258845</url><name>Rebecca Murray</name><from>About.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=794057</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/70489/the_grass_is_greener.html /m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1517900</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eugene-archer/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=950CE6DD1531EF3ABC4C51DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1390497</url><name>Eugene Archer</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=103941 /m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=1149265</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/don-druker/</url><url>http://onfilm.chireader.com/MovieCaps/G/GR/04208_GRASS_IS_GREENER.html /m/grass_is_greener/comments.php?reviewid=8487</url><name>Don Druker</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>