<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Bombai Ka Babu</original_title><imdb_rating>7.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>Raj Khosla</director><producer>Naya Films</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Family</genre><genre>Musical</genre><synopsis>
Babu and Malik are two inseparable friends who live in a small town in India. One day they decide to play a prank and steal something...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Dev Anand</actor><actor>Suchitra Sen</actor><actor>Jeevan</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4315095/comments</url><from>from Losa Angelosa</from><name>MubukuGrappa</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Yeah, this dirty linen of Rajinder Singh Bedi belongs to someone named
William Sydney Porter, also known as O'Henry, a not extremely unknown
literary figure, and the original story is entitled "A Double-dyed
Deceiver". Interestinly, there was also a movie made,with the same
title,way back in 1920.Bombai Ka Babu was a complete copy of this O'Henry short story, until
Bedi brought in the angle of supposedly brother-sister love (something
perhaps unthinkable in India even by today's norms), and thus made this
movie very bold and quite interesting/impressive. This movie was my
all-time favorite Hindi movie until I read the O'Henry story. But then,
the most sincere tribute inferiority pays to genius is by copying their
work.I was really impressed by Bedi's book "Ek Chadar Maili Si" and it's
difficult for me to attribute the adjective of "inferiority" to him.
But as far as I remember now (maybe I'm wrong!), this movie does not
acknowledge the source, and thus Bedi, as the author, should be
accountable for this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22493182/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Nagesh Kumar C S</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is by far one of the most sensible and sensitive films Dev Anand
has acted in..Director Raj Khosla weaves a fine blend of Music, romance and intrigue
in to a classic human emotions story that makes a lasting appeal to our
sensibilities..It is known to be a story inspired by O Henry's short,
but not acknowledged as such, but has an added romantic angle between a
long-lost brother ( Impostor in this case)_ and sister in their youth
falling for each other much against the norms of family and societal
ethics. A bold attempt certainly in the 60s India although the story
does not go fully on that route!A criminal on the run ( Dev Anand) finds a fine refuge to hide as well
make hay at the behest of a village crook with an eye on the family
cash-box..But a transformation of the heart and falling in love with the daughter
of the house(A memorable performance by the mercurial Suchitra sen) was
not in his original scheme of things, so the destiny decides to teach
him that there are finer values in life like sacrifice, duty etc which
are far more precious and lofty than making a quick buck as a criminal.Excellent music, atmosphere, and a classic befitting climax makes this
film a must see for discerning movie goers who like old classics.
Easily an 8/10 rating...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0204122/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Suresh C. Verma</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Apart from the good direction of Raj Khosla, and good performances by the
lead players, Dev Anand and Suchitra Sen, the music by S. D. Burman was the
highlight of the movie. Three songs particularly stand out. "Chal ri sajni,
ab kya soche", by Mukesh, "Saathi na koi manzil, diya hai na koi mehfil" by
Mohd. Rafi and "Deewana mastana hua Dil" by Mohd. Rafi and Asha
Bhosle. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0204122/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Suresh C. Verma</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Apart from the good direction of Raj Khosla, and good performances by the
lead players, Dev Anand and Suchitra Sen, the music by S. D. Burman was the
highlight of the movie. Three songs particularly stand out. "Chal ri sajni,
ab kya soche", by Mukesh, "Saathi na koi manzil, diya hai na koi mehfil" by
Mohd. Rafi and "Deewana mastana hua Dil" by Mohd. Rafi and Asha
Bhosle. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0204122/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Suresh C. Verma</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>