<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>A Terrible Beauty</original_title><alt_title>Les combattants de la nuit</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><country>USA</country><director>Tay Garnett</director><producer>D.R.M. Productions</producer><producer>Raymond Stross Productions</producer><genre>War</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Action</genre><synopsis>
In 1941, the IRA plans a campaign to coincide with the planned German invasion of England. Dermott O'Neil (Robert Mitchum) finds it easy to get into the IRA, but can he get out?
</synopsis><actor>Robert Mitchum</actor><actor>Richard Harris</actor><actor>Anne Heywood</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The IRA in Northern Ireland during the last world war was in a strange
boat.Since, as is said in the Near East, "the enemy of my enemy is my
friend," there was naturally a certain positive attitude towards Nazi
Germany. (You can find this social dynamic explicated by Fritz Heider,
the German psychologist, if you like.) Well, the Nazis are mentioned
here, and there is a broadcast by Lord Haw Haw, but other than that
this is a story of the IRA against the British establishment in
Northern Ireland. What a tangled web they wove. And what a cast to be caught up in it.
Robert Mitchum sounds passably Irish, and looks it too. His hair is
long and curly and it gives him a poetic look. (How many times did he
play an Irishman? I'm beginning to lose count.) Anne Heywood looks just
fine but occasionally sounds as if she's reading from cue cards. The
rest of the cast give first-rate performances: Richard Harris, Dan
O'Herlihy, and Cyril Cusack especially. O'Herlihy is, I think, an
underrated actor. Here he does his "Odd Man Out" number, only he's a
good deal more ambitious here than there. He had considerable range:
distant and deceitful in "Home Before Dark," compassionate and
humanistic in "Fail-Safe." Likewise Cyril Cusack, who has a pretty
interesting last name. It's a common enough name in Ireland, but it was
English before that, and before that it was brought from France by the
Normans, to whom it was a location name (one who lived in Cotius's
place). It's also a Ukranian name meaning "cossack." Cyril Cusack is an
exceptional performer. He was one of many excellent things about, "The
Day of the Jackal," in which he gave his finest performance, brief
though it was. Alas -- fascinating political situation, wonderful cast -- great
potential wasted on a narrative that should have been polished. It
isn't that they don't have the ethnographic details right, because they
do. Mitchum is the "O'Neill boy," although he's 35. He'll remain a
"boy" until he's married, an event which takes place late it life in
traditional Irish villages. (That's their form of birth control.) The
Irish also practiced primogeniture, meaning that the oldest son gets
the farm, skimpy as it is in this case, so poor Mitchum will have to
get out on his own. And the script captures some of the ways the Irish
tend to play with words. When Mitchum informs on the IRA inside the
police station, the Sargent tells him that his friends are waiting
outside to kill him, and Mitchum replies, "I think I'll go home by the
back way, pendin' the coolin' of their ardor." (There's a hilarious
scene in "Angela's Ashes" in which a teacher pities a young boy because
"you're so poor you haven't a shoe to your foot.") But, the narrative is not taut. The characters and their motives are
not clearly drawn, except in the way that cartoons are drawn. Not
because of a deliberate attempt at ambiguity but through carelessness.
Mitchum is entirely too casual when he joins the IRA, as if accepting a
drink from a friend at the bar. And he informs on them with equal
aplomb. O'Herlihy's character is one-dimensional, a glory-hungry IRA
commandant who is also the jealous, rejected lover of Mitchum's girl.
If the script is weak, so is Tay Garnett's direction. Toward the end,
O'Herlihy mistakenly shoots a young boy. No one bothered to include a
shot of the boy falling from his bicycle.Then O'Herlihy turns and runs away into the rain, and we never find out
what happens afterward, leaving not just a loose thread hanging but a
veritable hawser. Next, we get a quick change of scene to Mitchum and
his girl sailing away on a ferry into the sunset. Ho hum. What a waste.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"The Night Fighters" was shown recently in a cable channel. When we
came to IMDb to comment on it, we just couldn't find it. Doing a little
research, we came to realize it is listed under "A Terrible Beauty", a
deceiving title for a movie that has nothing to do with beauty.
Considering it had been directed by the great Tay Garnett, and with a
cast that included Robert Mitchum, Richard Harris, Ann Heywood, Cyril
Cusak, and Dan O'Herlihy, among others, the early promise seemed to
evaporate as we watched it.It is not a horrible movie by any means. The story about the
organization of an IRA faction in Northern Ireland is at the center of
the story. Evidently the adaptation of the novel in which this book is
based by R. Wright Campbell doesn't make much sense. To make matters
worse, the ending leaves the viewer even more confused. It appears the
screen play must have had many changes and the finished version doesn't
shed new light on the subject matter.The best thing in the film are Robert Mitchum and Richard Harris who
seemed to have been having a great time with one another as it is
evident in the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1162550/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>movieman_kev</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Robert Mitchum is an irish-man who joins the IRA during the WW2 era. They
plan to fight the British while they're occupied with the Germans. Could
have been a much better movie if the people didn't act so one-
dimensional.
I almost yawned a few times.Where I saw it: Showtime Extreme (ironic, i know)My grade: C-
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1162550/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>movieman_kev</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Robert Mitchum is an irish-man who joins the IRA during the WW2 era. They
plan to fight the British while they're occupied with the Germans. Could
have been a much better movie if the people didn't act so one-
dimensional.
I almost yawned a few times.Where I saw it: Showtime Extreme (ironic, i know)My grade: C-
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1162550/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>movieman_kev</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>