<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Il bell'Antonio</original_title><alt_title>Le bel Antonio</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Mauro Bolognini</director><producer>Arco Film</producer><producer>Cino del Duca</producer><producer>Societé Cinématographique Lyre</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Women love handsome Antonio because they think of him as the perfect lover. But he has problems to fullfill this ideal and Barbara only notices his failures when they are married...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Marcello Mastroianni</actor><actor>Claudia Cardinale</actor><actor>Pierre Brasseur</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4344252/comments</url><from>from Rome, Italy</from><name>Asa_Nisi_Masa2</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
You realise that millennia of civilisation have been quite useless if
the functioning of a whole community ultimately depends on whether a
man can have an erection or not! The subject of Mauro Bolognini's movie
Il Bell'Antonio – male impotence – would be audacious in 2006, let
alone in 1960. Yet here, it's treated with unflinching honesty, one
that surprised me for 1960. No euphemisms, no sensationalism, no
malicious elbow-nudging, nor sentimental melodrama, but a
heart-on-the-sleeve openness which also allows its long-suffering hero
to maintain his dignity through a fierce portrait of a ruthlessly
paternalistic society. This is all done without the aid of a single
sex-scene, which IMO would have been redundant.The movie shows us upper-class Sicily in the late 1950s (though
actually, it's based upon a novel set in the 1930s – Fascist-era
Italy). This is a society in which appearing is the essence of being
and the accepted norm are arranged marriages between the children of
the richest families, celebrated by the entire town in the same way as
Prince Charles and Diana Spencer's was back in the early 80s. As is the
case with the best classic Italian movies, Il Bell'Antonio couples
bitterness/fierce social satire with comedy/humour seamlessly. Superb
leads in the form of the timeless Marcello Mastroianni and the divine
Claudia Cardinale, impeccably playing an unpleasant character for once,
give the movie extra depth, beauty and soulfulness. Claudia is Barbara
Puglisi, the "golden girl" that Antonio is expected to marry, the
daughter of one of the richest families on the island and a virginal
social-climber of the most conventional, blinkered, obtusely stubborn
kind. The even greater tragedy is that despite their marriage having
been arranged by their families, Antonio really falls for her very
badly.Marcello Mastroianni, who neither as an actor nor as a man remotely
deserved to be considered the typical "Latin lover" type that Hollywood
producers wished to market him as, plays the titular lead, the
"beautiful" Antonio Magnano. On the verge of 30, in his prime as far as
looks, health and opportunities are concerned, Antonio has just
returned to his native Sicilian city of Catania after having lived in
Rome for three years. We very quickly gather that Antonio is from an
upper class Sicilian family, is the apple of his father and mother's
eye, and something of a superstar in the whole of Catania, where his
family is well-known and respected. He is adored by women, who believe
him to be an irresistible seducer, a Casanova with hundreds of notches
on his bed-post. He is also courted by important men, all dying to act
as his patrons in some prestigious profession or the other. Women's
heads make 90-degree turns when he walks into a room, and older ladies
gasp in wonder at his handsomeness from their balconies when he walks
past them, fantasising that he may become their son-in-law. Antonio's
father is played by Pierre Brasseur, who receives much praise in
reviews of the movie. In my opinion, he is actually the least credibly
cast actor in this movie, losing out to Rina Morelli who plays his
wife, Antonio's mother (she really comes into her own in a memorable
"showdown" scene between herself and Claudia Cardinale in a church, and
in the second half of the movie generally). On the other hand, so many
of Brasseur's expressions and mannerism betray a blatant Frenchness,
rather than a credible Italianness, or even better, a Sicilianness.Mr Magnano Senior swells with pride at the very thought of his son's
alleged sexual prowess and reputation. He pretty much bases much of the
reasons for boosting his family's public image precisely on Antonio
being able to continue the virile oeuvre started by himself, in his
youthful days, all over Sicily! With such a premise, you just know that
the movie's dramatic climax is going to be the ruinous fall from glory
experienced by the poor Antonio, who seemingly carries the weight of
the whole of Sicily's expectations on his all too human shoulders right
from the start! It's as if this poor man were expected to lift the
whole island up with his erection. You don't expect the extent of the
tyranny of such a patriarchal society on its male children. The story
of the dishonoured girl cast out of her society certainly finds a male
equivalent in Il Bell'Antonio.Also worthy of note is the Cuban actor Tomas Milian playing Edoardo,
Antonio's cousin, the only sane, rational and detached voice among a
chorus of shrill scandal-mongers. It's thanks to this character that we
get to hear Antonio finally speak at the end of the movie, telling us
his first-hand experience as an impotent Sicilian man catastrophically
fallen from glory. I do wonder if before or since this movie, such an
honest and charitable, as well as credible psychological study of male
sexual problems has ever been filmed - perhaps in part only in Sex,
Lies and Videotape. The conclusion of Antonio's story exemplifies the
bitterest and most satirical form of so-called "happy ending" – if the
movie weren't already so good overall, the ending would be worth the
watch alone! For any fan of classic Italian cinema, this will be a rare
treat indeed. If you love Mastroianni, you simply cannot afford to miss
this. And for any fan of cinema generally… ditto.The literary source the movie is based upon, the Sicilian writer
Vitaliano Brancati's novel of the same title, furthermore lends itself
perfectly to this dual mood of fierce social satire and classic Italian
comedy. Few men of letters have pinpointed the true natural of
latter-day Southern Italian machismo as well as Brancati. Cliché-free,
with such an eye for the absurd, the comical, the down-right
frightening and angering, I highly recommend not only Il Bell'Antonio,
but also all of Vitaliano's major novels: it wasn't just Giuseppe
Tomasi di Lampedusa and his novel The Leopard who evocatively captured
a long-gone Sicily in the written form.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0496887/comments</url><from>from Auckland, New Zealand</from><name>Eric Sayettat (sayettat@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Humour, good acting (Pierre Brasseur and Marcello are excellent)and a not
so
innocent theme.Antonio is a victim of traditional Sicilian society where the church is
ubiquitous and categorizes women in either sluts or Saints. Platonic love
is
reserved for the Saints, sex is for the rest. Sex and love are so far apart
that Antonio can not reconcile them, it will ruin his life.Mauro Bolognini has made a great deal of good movies, this one is not its
most famous but it deserves more attention. The taste and accent of
Southern
Italy 40 years ago is in every scene.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0496887/comments</url><from>from Auckland, New Zealand</from><name>Eric Sayettat (sayettat@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Humour, good acting (Pierre Brasseur and Marcello are excellent)and a not
so
innocent theme.Antonio is a victim of traditional Sicilian society where the church is
ubiquitous and categorizes women in either sluts or Saints. Platonic love
is
reserved for the Saints, sex is for the rest. Sex and love are so far apart
that Antonio can not reconcile them, it will ruin his life.Mauro Bolognini has made a great deal of good movies, this one is not its
most famous but it deserves more attention. The taste and accent of
Southern
Italy 40 years ago is in every scene.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0496887/comments</url><from>from Auckland, New Zealand</from><name>Eric Sayettat (sayettat@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>