<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Story of Ruth</original_title><alt_title>L'histoire de Ruth</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Henry Koster</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Inspired by the scriptural tale. Moabitess priestess Ruth is drawn both to a Judean man and to his talk of a forgiving God. After tragedy strikes, she begins a new life in Bethlehem.
</synopsis><actor>Stuart Whitman</actor><actor>Tom Tryon</actor><actor>Peggy Wood</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3874788/comments</url><from>from Israel</from><name>rosalavra1 (rosalavra1@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

At the age of 14, I idly turned on the TV in the afternoon and saw this
movie just beginning. I felt drawn to see it as I was brought up on
Bible stories and knew the story of Ruth pretty well. I was intrigued
to see how it would be dramatised.I was fascinated at the movie's expansion of the Book of Ruth's simple
account of Ruth's Moabite beginnings, the evil of this pagan
civilization which sacrificed its own children to Moloch. This part of
the movie is in fact well authenticated by other parts of Scripture.I was impressed by the beauty of the actress playing Ruth, and by her
portrayal of the beauty of Ruth's character. I was immediately aware that some license was taken with the beginnings
of the relationship between Ruth and Boaz. In the Biblical version he
was certainly never hostile to her! However as the love story
progressed it had exactly the character of the loving kindness of the
kinsman redeemer exemplified in the Biblical Boaz.So much did this quality of deep love based on respect and loving
kindness which cares for and wants to look after the beloved impress me
that it actually became a standard against all future love stories,
both fictional and real, were to be measured by me. For quite a number
of years it was almost an unconscious influence, but in my mid 20's
when I started seriously considering marriage,it surfaced and became a
requirement for me in the man I would marry, and in the love we would
have for each other. Somehow this love of Ruth and Boaz seemed much
more REAL than almost all the romances I would see in movies or read
about.In fact the whole story of Ruth became a pattern for my life, after I
returned to faith and sought a life in which God would be my Guide.So much so that I now live in Israel, not far from where Ruth came to
live with Naomi . I did find my "Boaz", who had been in some ways so
clearly exemplified for me in "The Story of Ruth". I still vividly remember the movie and am grateful that , even though
it took some small "liberties" with the Biblical story, it was true to
the spirit of the Book of Ruth!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This 20th Century Fox Biblical epic deals with the beautiful Ruth (
Elana Eden ), she is a Moabit priestess under orders of hight religious
hierarchy ( Viveca Lindfors ) , as their cruel religion makes
sacrifices children to the God Moloch in a pagan civilization . Later
on , Ruth is enamored by a young Jewish ( Tom Tryon ) and decides to
renounce his former gods . After that, arriving to Israel along with
her mother-in-law( Peggy Wood ), where she discovers true faith and
works as ear-woman. Although she is excluded by the Jewish community,
however she gets various suitors as Boaz ( Stuart Whitman ) and Tob (
Jeff Morrow ).This Biblical retelling film results to be an enjoyable story with
romance , drama, a love story and fascinating scenarios . It's a known
epic story of Ruth whose descendant will be King David . Elana Eden as
Ruth is marvelous, however she barely acted after this realization ,
the veteran Peggy Wood is magnificent and Stuart Whitman as the tough
Boaz makes an agreeable interpretation . Colorful and spectacular
cinematography in CinemaScope by Arthur Arling as is reflected on the
sensational outdoors . The luxurious costumes by the usual designer
Nino Novarese . Sensible and evocative musical score by the classic
Franz Waxman . The film is well directed with big budget by Henry
Koster . The picture will appeal to religious genre fans and Biblical
history buffs . Rating : Good and nice , it's worthwhile seeing. I
would recommend to see it wholeheartedly.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0186847/comments</url><from>from North Woodmere, NY</from><name>cinemel</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

"The Story of Ruth" was a modest production of a biblical story in the
days
when most tales from the Bible were large scale epics. The screenplay does
expand the early portion of Ruth's story. Ruth (lovely Elana Eden) is a
priestess in the temple of the religious idol worshipped in her native
country of Moab. She meets the Hebrew Mahlon (Tom Tryon) whose invisible
diety she cannot understand. Mahlon marries Ruth as he dies and she
follows
her mother-in-law, Naomi (Peggy Wood), back to her native land of Judah.
Here the relationship between Ruth and Naomi is beautifully developed as
the
two women try to eke out a meager existence. All the while they have to
deal
with the strict rules of the Hebrews and particularly the council of
elders
who find out about Ruth's former belief in the pagan religion. It is
Ruth's
new faith in the one G-d of Naomi which finally brings her love and hope
for
a future in her adopted homeland. Stuart Whitman portrays her new romantic
interest, Boaz. Jeff Morrow (Tob) is his rival for Ruth's hand and adds a
welcome bit of humor to the proceedings. Viveca Lindfors portrays the High
Priestess back in Moab in her inimitable style. The second half of the
films
adheres fairly close to the biblical text, and its pastoral scenes and
quiet
drama contrast to the more action oriented first half. However, director
Henry Koster has kept his story moving along aided by a fine musical score
by Franz Waxman. The story transcends some wooden acting and occasionally
static dramatic scenes. The viewer will be swept along by the unusual tale
of women triumphing over adversity in a male-dominated
society.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1136492/comments</url><from>from STOKE-ON-TRENT, ENGLAND.</from><name>DAVID RAYNER (HONEYWALL1)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I first saw this movie in October, 1960, when I was thirteen and a half.
Like many others of my generation, I had purchased the wonderfully made
Dell
Movie Classic comic book adaptation of the film, with its impressive color
photo cover...obviously designed as pre-release publicity to make you want
to go to see the film when it arrived in town. I was very impressed with
the
film and it became one of my all time favorite movies. I watched the great
Biblical love story come alive and unfold itself across the CinemaScope
screen and I found certain parts of it very moving...especially the death
of
Mahlon (Tom Tryon) in that cave. As Ruth, twenty years old Elana Eden is
superb. As she realises that Mahlon has just died in front of her, she
falls
to her knees, buries her face in her hands and sobs bitterly (very much in
the mold of Jennifer Jones in that final scene of LOVE IS A
MANY-SPLENDORED
THING) and I found the scene so moving that, as Elana Eden sobbed, so I
began to sob, also. It was so well done, I became totally involved in it
for
two hours and twelve minutes of screen time. Because this is one of the
quieter Bible stories, and contains no chariot races or battle scenes, it
has been somewhat overlooked by most of today's movie historians and has
only been shown on UK television once...in December, 1972, when it was
already twelve years old...and not shown since. So, a couple of
generations
have come into the world since its original release who have never had the
opportunity to see it. But it's certainly worth seeing and I give it ten
out
of ten. Thankfully, it's available on video in the USA and I was able to
send to amazon.com for a copy last year. As to what became of Elana Eden,
I'd like very much to know. According to the British November, 1960,
edition
of Photoplay, she signed a long term contract with 20th Century-Fox in
1960,
presumably on the strength of her superb debut performance in this movie.
Yet, as far as I know, she never acted again. Does anyone out there know
why
and whatever became of her? She was so very, very beautiful. I fell in
love
with her from the first time I saw her on the cover of that Movie Classic
comic. A wonderful movie with an unmistakable air of sincerity about the
whole production, THE STORY OF RUTH is something quite removed from most
of
Fox's output of the period.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Anyone expecting an elephantine spectacle with a cast of thousands for
this Old Testament story will be sadly disappointed. The Story of Ruth
simply does not lend itself to that kind of treatment. In fact for the
screen quite a bit of liberties were taken with the story in terms of
adding plot that the Old Testament Book of Ruth simply doesn't have.Ruth is an unusual character in the Bible. First she's a female
protagonist, one of a select few there. Secondly her story gets its own
book in the Old Testament, a short item of only four chapters. Lastly
she's the first non-Hebrew protagonist in the Bible since Abraham sired
the Hebrew people.It's a simple story in the Old Testament. Ruth is one of two Moabite
women who marry the sons of Elimelech and Naomi. When Elimelech and
sons Mahlon and Chillion die, leaving Naomi a widow with two widowed
daughters-in-law, Naomi decides to return to Israel. One
daughter-in-law, Orpah, bids her goodbye. Daughter-in-law Ruth however
says she will not desert her. She's going to give up the life and
culture of Moab and her people will be Naomi's people in the most
famous line from the Book of Ruth.That's all there is to explain Ruth the Moabite coming to live in
Israel with her mother-in-law. Director Henry Koster directed a film
with a whole involved plot which goes into Ruth being a Moabite
priestess and the reason for the death of all the men in that family.
It's a nice story, but not the Old Testament.The second half of the film involves Ruth and Naomi and a blood
relative's named Boaz and Boaz's courtship of Ruth. Boaz has a rival in
another relative who is closer to Naomi who's name isn't mentioned, but
the film names as Tob. We get a few more details from the Bible for the
screenwriters to work with in this part.Henry Koster directed many a film with a religious theme and had
success with The Robe and A Man Called Peter among others. This film is
not as good as the other two, but still is both reverent and
entertaining.The cast performs well. Israeli actress Elana Eden is in the title role
and like her fellow Israeli thespian Haya Harrareet from Ben-Hur saw
her career dissipate in the Sixties. The two men in her life are Tom
Tryon as Mahlon and Stuart Whitman as Boaz. Broadway veteran Peggy Wood
is Naomi and the best in the film is Jeff Morrow as the overbearing and
drunken Tob who with a little bit of trickery Eden gets to renounce his
claim on her. It was the law back in the day.The real story of Ruth is in that title phrase. Before there was a New
Testament and a group of men were told to spread the faith, this story
shows that God is taking converts. His wisdom and mercy are not the
exclusive property of one race, but are universal. And in fact the
children of Boaz and Ruth start the royal line of Israel beginning with
their great grandson David.But it all begins with how Boaz and Ruth get together.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467011/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Frances</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I would stay up late watching this when it aired on television back in
the late 60's early 70's. And of course the "Book of Ruth" has always
been one of my favorite books of the Bible. This is truly a great love
story. And in my eyes, there could never be another 'Ruth' other then
Elana Eden. She is the most beautiful woman I have ever seen on the big
or small screen, hands down. When I read the Biblical account of Ruth,
she is the one that I picture in my head as Ruth.Granted, the movie doesn't follow the Bible word for word, but that's
Hollywood for you. But it does follow the general story pretty close.
For those of you who enjoy a great love story, (and I grew up reading
Harlequin romances) this is one to add to your collection. And now it
is finally available on DVD! My VHS copy is pretty well worn out by
now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2029693/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, California</from><name>Dejael</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

(*May contain spoilers*)
This fine 20th Century Fox production directed by Henry Koster (The ROBE,
1953) is a timeless classic of hope, faith and inspiration based on the
book
of Ruth in the Bible.
The characters are well defined, the cast is superb, and the writing of
the
script is both literate and meaningful, handling this subject with a deft
sensitivity.
Add to that the elaborate production values of the Fox studio, color, and
wide-screen CinemaScope, an uplifting, rousing music score, and you have a
well-mounted film of style and substance.
Pretty young Elana Eden shines in her only starring role as Ruth, the
Moabite girl who loves a Jew named Mahlon (handsome, stalwart Tom Tryon),
marrying him moments before his untimely death, and befriends his elder
kinswoman Naomi (Peggy Wood in a finely crafted performance) who embraces
her as Ruth becomes part of the family.
Now Ruth must choose between the beguiling but mischievous Tobit (Jeff
Morrow sparkles in a fine character role), or handsome young stud Boaz
(burly Stuart Whitman in an outstanding part) as they both vie for her
affections.
The film's story is a true celebration of life overcoming the adversities
of
death and sorrow, and faith overcoming the difficulties of calamities and
complications due to ethnic barriers (the Jews were not normally allowed
to
associate with the Moabites). It also illustrates the conflicts caused by
pagan idolatry.
The marriage of Ruth to Boaz is a triumph of faith and love, for through
this union would come the lineage of King David of Israel, and ultimately,
the Messiah, Jesus of Nazareth, a thousand years later.
Highly recommended Biblical classic is literate and faithful to the
original
story in the Bible.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0020866/comments</url><from>from Minnesota</from><name>Gunn</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I have always liked biblical epics and thought that I'd seen them all,
but while watching a feature on them I saw listed "The Story of Ruth."
I knew nothing of this story of the Old Testament, so I purchased the
DVD. The film, made in 1960, shortly after the release of "Ben Hur" was
not an epic in the sense of 'a cast of thousands' with big name stars,
but rather a simply told story, both moving and charmingly portrayed by
a cast who excelled in their respective roles and brilliantly directed
by Henry Coaster, with a literate script by Norman Corwin. Stuart
Whitman was never better than in his role as Boaz and newcomer Elana
Eden was stunningly beautiful and very impressive as Ruth. In fact, it
surprises me that her career waned after "Story of Ruth." The always
great Peggy Wood was Oscar worthy as Naomi and the rest of the players
were also well cast. Franz Waxman's score was moving and added a
reverence to the entire film. It seemed pretty accurate for the most
part. I wondered if there was any truth to the fact that Ruth was sold
to the Moabites by her father, as my sources (Biblical dictionaries)
are pretty concise. To summarize, I must say that I really enjoyed this
film!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
After having missed out on it several times on Italian TV, I've managed
to catch up with this - as it turned out - underrated Biblical epic via
Fox's pleasing DVD edition. It's a typically lavish production with a
nice Franz Waxman score and a decent cast: unknown Elana Eden makes for
a convincing heroine; Tom Tryon is the leading man during the first
half (until he is killed off), with Stuart Whitman taking over in the
second part of the narrative; Peggy Wood is a dignified Noemi; and Jeff
Morrow delivers an amusing performance as a perennially drunk Jewish
merchant and Eden's suitor.Not knowing much about the Biblical story, the lengthy expository
events - akin to the similarly irrelevant ones (of the young Moses in
Egypt) depicted in THE TEN COMMANDMENTS (1956) - were a welcome
addition; as a matter of fact, Viveca Lindfors - a strong presence
during these early stages - disappears altogether once the scene shifts
to Judea! Typical of most epics of the time, the film feels overlong
and could do with some trimming - especially in its more reverent
second half - but it's one I wouldn't mind owning on DVD, especially if
Fox would consider releasing a collection of their Biblical epics
(comprising as well David AND BATSHEBA [1951], THE ROBE [1953],
DEMETRIUS AND THE GLADIATORS [1954] and THE BIBLE...IN THE BEGINNING
[1966]).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I remember seeing this on its first run and its color was marvelous.
The human sacrifice scene to the god Moloch was chilling.Of particular interest is the dialogue between Mahlon (Tom Tryon) and
Ruth (Elana Eden) about religion. Mahlon, the Hebrew, tries to explain
to Ruth, a pagan virgin votary, how his people could worship an
invisible God. This deep theological discussion came about because Ruth
asked the question. Mahlon gave a wonderful illustrative example.He said: "Imagine that you are soldier in the battlefield and you wish
to pray to save your army and for victory. How would you do that?"Ruth answered that she would think of the image of her god and pray. Mahlon then explained that in that case, the god she would be praying
to would be invisible.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I remember seeing this on its first run and its color was marvelous.
The human sacrifice scene to the god Moloch was chilling.Of particular interest is the dialogue between Mahlon (Tom Tryon) and
Ruth (Elana Eden) about religion. Mahlon, the Hebrew, tries to explain
to Ruth, a pagan virgin votary, how his people could worship an
invisible God. This deep theological discussion came about because Ruth
asked the question. Mahlon gave a wonderful illustrative example.He said: "Imagine that you are soldier in the battlefield and you wish
to pray to save your army and for victory. How would you do that?"Ruth answered that she would think of the image of her god and pray. Mahlon then explained that in that case, the god she would be praying
to would be invisible.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117795233.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/story_of_ruth/comments.php?reviewid=1806806</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9B06EFDF143FE333A2575BC1A9609C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/story_of_ruth/comments.php?reviewid=1389910</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>