<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>À bout de souffle</original_title><imdb_rating>7.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><director>Jean-Luc Godard</director><producer>Les Productions Georges de Beauregard</producer><producer>Société Nouvelle de Cinématographie (SNC)</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
A young car thief kills a policeman and tries to persuade a girl to hide in Italy with him.
</synopsis><actor>Jean-Paul Belmondo</actor><actor>Jean Seberg</actor><actor>Henri-Jacques Huet</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4403800/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, Ohio</from><name>izmatt  (izmatt18@cinci.rr.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I don't blame those who state that they do not "understand" the
superlatives surrounding Jean-Luc Godard's 1960 masterpiece,
Breathless. It's primarily because to appreciate Breathless, one has to
view the movie from a historical context, which also requires studying
of not only the French New Wave, but film theories as a whole, and the
lives of those apart of the New Wave. Breathless accomplished many
things unprecedented prior (many completely unprecedented, but some
things are not-so-much).Roger Ebert put it best when he said that just as film fanatics may now
stand outside a movie theatre waiting for the next Quentin Tarantino
movie to be released, film enthusiasts were doing so for Godard in the
1960s. He was a revolutionary, which is why MovieMaker magazine called
him the 4th most influential director of ALL-TIME (only behind Welles,
Griffith, and Hitchcock)! What did Godard do different? Breathless is
all style, simple as that. The story line is interesting, yes, but is
Godard's aesthetics, production modes, subject matters, and
storytelling methods that are key. First of all, the whole movie was
shot on a hand-held camera, just like most all New Wave pictures. It
was, however, only shot by two people (Godard and his cinematographer,
Rouald) on a budget that did not top $50,000, a mere fraction of what
most pictures cost at the time (another facet of the New Wave). It was
shot completely on location in Paris, and utilized new film-making
techniques that would be used by film-making students for decades to
come (such as putting the camera in a mail cart on the Champs Elysees
and following Belmondo and Seberg). Note Godard's use of American
cinema influence, and how the montage art of the 1950s impacted this
aesthetic.(A brief New Wave lesson: Most New Wave directors were displeased with
the "tradition of quality," or the older generation directors who, as
Truffaut put it, made the "twelve or so" pictures per year that
represented France at Venice and Cannes. Most of these pictures classic
or modern literary adaptations, completely stagnant in artistic quality
with rehashed subject matters based on historical periods. New Wave
directors supported NEW tales of modern Parisian life, primarily, and
were sick of the themes found in the tradition of quality films.) The
storytelling methods in Breathless are perhaps the most fascinating
part of the film. The jump cuts may seem lame, but one must again view
them from a historical context: it had never been done before. This is
exactly why Breathless is important -- practically every technique was
revolutionary. They are so submerged into film-making practices now
that Breathless seems typical. Yet at the time, it was, as I said
prior, unprecedented.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1100924/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Mark Taylor (mark_kevintaylor@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This is the one that started it all kids, the daddy of post-modern
cinema. MTV jump cuts, fractured soundtrack and images aplenty Self reflexive to the point that it not only acknowledges its own
existence, it revels in it.All style and no substance is considered a bad thing today, unless its
Tarantino. Well, if it wasn't for Godard, chances are there would be no
QT.All the characters and images, and dialogue and sets are constructed
from all aspects of life - Michel is a Bogart collage. Patricia apes
everything she sees, from her Interviewee's facial gestures to Michel's
own.Don't let all this technical mumbo fool you, I did my thesis on Godard
and would happily bore the ass off you with a lecture in great detail
about this film, but the fact is, it's a stormer.Grips you by the throat and shakes the hell out of you, and it doesn't
let go until the final breath.Fantastically, artistically magnificent. If Godard wanted to make his
debut picture to show how well he understood American ideals and the
history of cinema, he couldn't have made a better picture.Top stuff French guy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1405008/comments</url><from>from Dublin, Ireland</from><name>NykDex</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This Movie, a triumph of the French Nouvelle Vague, marks a turning point,
not only for the Director, Jean-Luc Godard, but for anyone who sees it.
The
plot, though intriguing, is secondary to the incredible presentation. Use
of
hand-held cameras and jump-cuts (where the director cuts from one angle to
a
shot of the same angle two seconds later, a stylistic effect that can show
freneticism or boredom) were revolutionary at the time, yet can still
surprise and delight today.Jean Seaberg is excellent, with the nicest accent you'll ever hear, as are
the supporting cast, all rounded stereotypes. But the leading man
outshines
all the others. A virtuoso display from Jean-Paul Belmondo as Michel
Poiccard makes the viewer swoon and scorn in equal measures. He doesn't
make
it easy for us to empathize with him, yet we still do, and in doing, we
feel
we have earned something.Revolutionary. Brilliant. Oh so pretty.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1477295/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Richard Anderson</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Jean-Luc Godard's, A Bout de Souffle is possibly the brightest star to
shine
from the French New Wave. The 'Nouvelle Vague' came about from a group of
like minded film critics writing for the Cahiers du Cinema.With his knowledge of classic film narrative and style Godard went out to
create his own film in homage to, and also complete contradiction to,
classic Hollywood film.The plot reads almost like a crime thriller typical of the 1930-40's. A
criminal on the run from the police; the distraction of a beautiful woman;
the escape and eventually someones death. But it is in Godard's approach
to
film style and use of new technologies that the typical crime thriller was
turned on its head.In a break from classic Hollywood narrative the film opens with little
equilibrium. Our protagonist's motives are unclear as he tears off to
Paris
leaving a woman and a dead cop in his trail. This in turn makes the ending
somewhat open ended. With no sense of equilibrium to start with how can
there be closure on what has happened throughout the film.Another twist on the classic storytelling in film is the progression of
plot. It is naturally assumed in classic Hollywood film, that everything
the
spectator sees they see for a reason. With Michel's constantly pointless
phone calls to retrieve owed money the plot is not pushed along at all.
The
inclusion of a 25 minute digression from the plot stands to emphasise the
spectators reliance on narrative structure in the watching of films.
Although watching the film closely is, as always, important in following
the
story A Bout de Souffle requires that little bit extra to define where the
plot is being progressed and where Michel or Patricia are just flattering
their egos or each other.All in all I personally think that A Bout de Souffle brought about a sense
of realism not seen in Hollywood cinema before 1959 and even now. The fact
that life isn't full of clues that will help us progress in say our
relationships or escape from authority, but is infact full of digression;
self exploration; and the confusions of love, ego and
aspirations.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7338453/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jdoan-4</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
So says the novelist in response to Patricia's question, "What do you
hope to attain out of life?" That response is the philosophy of the
film and of every character in the film. All want to be in control of
their destiny. All want to be something that they are not. None are
able to do any of these things. They are all contradictions. How can
you die as an immortal? How can Patricia be free and independent is so
many other things determine what she can do? How can this film
transcend the screen while existing on the screen? This is an amazing
film to watch. Goddard fills every scene with ingenuity and energy. He
puts his actors in a beautiful environment and lets them do their
thing. And they do it extremely well. The actors are beautiful. Not
just cosmetically, but spiritually and psychologically. I am not sure
that I liked either of the two main characters. I am sure I could not
keep my eyes off them. I could not take my eyes off the screen.
Techniques that novices today use for no substantial purpose are
utilized by Goddard to amazing effect. The greatest filmmakers are the
great editors. Goddard makes the editing a character itself. It is the
nervous narrator hurrying the film along. It breathlessly awaits the
next scene, and leads us to do the same. I like the way Goddard spends
prodigious time simply watching his characters. The conversation scene
at the center of the film is amazingly long and drawn out, yet I did
not find it boring. I found it fascinating. People are fascinating.
Everyone is trying to be something. It takes tremendous talent to
indulge in the minutiae of existence. A great film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1098460/comments</url><from>from Virginia, USA</from><name>Galina</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I finally did it. I finished watching À bout de souffle. I kept putting it
off because I usually have problem when everybody tells me that such and
such film is the epitome of its era or it breaks all the rules, starts the
revolution, and reinvents the cinema. That's why, probably, I cannot like
Citizen Kane - try to watch the arguably best film ever made - you will be
under a lot of pressure. Well, À bout de souffle does not put you under the pressure, it takes you
for a ride, and you follow for 90 minutes its incredibly young characters,
common crook (Jean-Paul Belmondo) and his American free-spirited girlfriend
(Jean Seberg) on their journey on the streets of 1960-th Paris along with
Raoul Coutard's legendary camera. I am not going to tell here how great the
camera work was, how fantastic the music score and the views of Paris were -
the fans of the film know that already. They also know about the beginning
of French New Wave, and how it influenced the future cinema. I just want to
say that the movie was made over forty years ago - the smoking was cool back
then, and Belmondo made smoking look very sexy. Belmondo fascinates me in
this film. I've seen him in a lot of later movies - he's always been good (I
recommend Le Magnifique, 1973 and Le Professionnel,1981 ) - but in À bout de
souffle he is not just good - he is embodiment of cool, his face changes its
expression every moment, you can not take your eyes off him. Is it me or he
does remind the very young Mick Jagger - not commonly handsome but
irresistible and sexy? He and young (she was 21 at the time) Jean Seaborg
made one of the best screen couples ever. 
My favorite scenes: Michel drives the stolen car in the beginning of the film, and he starts to
talk to us, the audience. The day is nice, the sun is shining, and the life
is beautiful... Michel and Patricia drive in the convertible. The wind plays with her short
hair. We only see the back of her head and her neck. Michel tells her that
he loves the girl with a beautiful neck, wrists, knees, but she is a
chicken... Patricia comes to the hotel to find Michel in her bed. They start talking
about nothing and about very serious things. They smoke, she tries to find a
good place for her new poster, and he wants to sleep with her. In the end of
the scene, his face, he looks at her - there is love in that look...There is more - I am sure everyone who saw it has his/her favorite scenes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8258961/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>marissas75</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Together with François Truffaut's "The 400 Blows" (one of my
favorites), Jean-Luc Godard's "Breathless" is considered the defining,
instigating film of the French New Wave. It's more ironic and detached,
less emotionally accessible than "The 400 Blows," and its technical
innovations like jump cuts are perhaps even more surprising. For these
reasons, I found "Breathless" easier to admire than to love—though by
the end I grew to enjoy its too-cool- for-(film)-school tone.Ironically, the pace of this movie isn't "breathless" at all. It begins
abruptly and takes a while to get going: Michel (Jean-Paul Belmondo), a
character we barely know, drives a stolen car around, talks at the
camera, and shoots a police officer who has tried to pull him over.
Then he goes to Paris and tries to borrow money from some friends,
while the police-shooting plot goes undeveloped. I only became fully
engaged with the introduction of Patricia (Jean Seberg), a young
American who sells newspapers on the Champs-Elysees. The relationship
between Michel and Patricia is the heart of the film, especially a
25-minute-long scene in Patricia's apartment where the characters
smoke, flirt, and laze around in bed, though nothing really happens.
That's where I really started to admire "Breathless," because I was so
captivated by a scene that, on paper, doesn't sound all that
captivating.Eventually the police catch onto Michel and launch a manhunt, but this
doesn't really ratchet up the suspense. Instead, Michel is (or at
least, Michel acts) aimless and nonchalant about the whole thing—this
is not a typical "man on the run" movie. The cool jazz score adds to
the hip, laid-back tone.Since I didn't care for the movie too much until the scenes between
Michel and Patricia, I believe a lot of the credit for the film's
success has to go to the charismatic performances of Belmondo and
Seberg. Belmondo, with a perpetual cigarette dangling from the corner
of his mouth, is the archetypal cocky criminal who models himself after
Humphrey Bogart (there's a great scene where he sees some Bogart photos
and gets a vulnerable look in his eyes, as though saying "I'll never be
as cool as this"). Seberg plays Patricia as a confused girl who is
delighted by the attention she gets as an American in France.It's easy to see why "Breathless" was so influential—the jump cuts, the
ragged style perfectly match this story about amoral, aimless youth.
Definitely a movie that expanded the range of stories the cinema can
tell, and perhaps a major precursor to youth-oriented '60s culture.
Nearly fifty years later, it still seems "hip," and still challenges
our expectations of how movies should behave.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2772404/comments</url><from>from Olympia, Washington</from><name>nutsy</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is the one that started it all. With the story of a man on the run
calling himself Laszlo Kovacs (a cinematographer of the time), Jean-Luc
Godard arrived in the movies (well, on the production end, at least). This
also more than his typical film essay. The story by Francois Truffaut makes
for a terrific Godard script (the Truffaut stamp makes it comparable to
SHOOT THE PIANO PLAYER). Jean-Paul Belmondo does well in the Kovacs role,
humanizing our bad-guy hero right up to the slam-bang finish. Jean Seberg is
his conflicted lover who must... well, just watch. A landmark of the French
New Wave, which is one of the most important movements in cinema. Vastly
superior to the 1983 BREATHLESS with Richard Geer and Fassinder's homage THE
AMERICAN SOLDIER. This is guaranteed to be like few movies you've seen
before (unless, of course, you're a fan of the New Wave). BREATHLESS is also
very memorable for its music and unusual photography. Shows how European
film brought out the importance of character in film and raised it to new
heights (whereas in American film, a close-up is the closest you'll get to
character development). This is a must for any film student and for anyone
who just loves movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3417327/comments</url><from/><name>TheHeartAsksPleasureFirst</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"À Bout de Soufflé" aka "Breathless", was the first full-length film
directed by the controversial Jean-Luc Godard, and the first film of
his long career that I've had the chance to see so far. "Breathless" is
the landmark film of the Nouvelle Vague (New Wave), when young
filmmakers such as François Truffaut thrilled the audiences and shocked
the Establishment.Although some people may not be as impressed with "Breathless"
structure as they were in 1960, it remains a terrific, breathtaking
film experience and has aged wonderfully. Such masterpieces live up to
the hype and time, even though they're not as technically impressive as
they were 40 years ago, and they're still powerful thanks to what great
films consist of: passion. As another user rightfully stated, we have
to look at "Breathless" from a historical point: it's different from
any other previous film. Godard was truly a visionary and an incredibly
talented, passionate "auteur"."Breathless" plot is rather simple: Michel Poiccard/Laszlo Kovacs
(Jean-Paul Belmondo), our anti-hero, is a young criminal on the run
from the police, after stealing a car and killing a cop. He has an
affair with a beautiful young American, Patricia (Jean Seberg), an
aspiring journalist who sells the New York Herald Tribune in the middle
of the Champs Élysées (her first scene here was paid a tribute by Eva
Green in Bertolucci's "The Dreamers"), and is also expecting Michel's
baby. Patricia helps Michel to dodge the police, while they steal cars
together in order to raise money for a trip to Rome. But when you want
to "vivre dangereusement jusqu'au bout" - or, live dangerously till the
end, things may end up not so well.When you see Belmondo touching his lips, trying to imitate Humphrey
Bogart's trade mark, Seberg walking on the Élysées as lovely as a girl
can be, the unforgettable final moments...you don't worry about
theories on why this is a classic. "À Bout de Soufflé" is Cinema.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1479127/comments</url><from>from Dundee, Scotland</from><name>Chris@hame.org.uk</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This is the film that started it all, and ended my insomnia! What a
boring, dull film. talk about Nouvelle vague, it was VAGUE alright. no
distinguishable storyline what so ever.'Plot': It's that age old story of boy kills cop, boy meets girl, girl
and boy lie in bed doing and saying ab-so-lute-ly nothing important or
interesting at all, girl tells boy shes pregnant just to see boys
reaction but isn't actually, girl grasses boy up to cops because
she"doesn't know if she loves him", boy refuses to run because he is
'tired' and apparently 'stupid', boy gets shot in butt and dies,
girl..not bothered.Ye, ye i know. It revolutionized the film industry (apparently). I was
told in film studies, i wrote an essay on it. But it reminds me of the
St Louis Rams between 2002-2005. Lots of flashy new ideas but very
little substance. The use of natural lighting seems like a good idea
but in practice just looks pathetically amateur.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1479127/comments</url><from>from Dundee, Scotland</from><name>Chris@hame.org.uk</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This is the film that started it all, and ended my insomnia! What a
boring, dull film. talk about Nouvelle vague, it was VAGUE alright. no
distinguishable storyline what so ever.'Plot': It's that age old story of boy kills cop, boy meets girl, girl
and boy lie in bed doing and saying ab-so-lute-ly nothing important or
interesting at all, girl tells boy shes pregnant just to see boys
reaction but isn't actually, girl grasses boy up to cops because
she"doesn't know if she loves him", boy refuses to run because he is
'tired' and apparently 'stupid', boy gets shot in butt and dies,
girl..not bothered.Ye, ye i know. It revolutionized the film industry (apparently). I was
told in film studies, i wrote an essay on it. But it reminds me of the
St Louis Rams between 2002-2005. Lots of flashy new ideas but very
little substance. The use of natural lighting seems like a good idea
but in practice just looks pathetically amateur.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>