<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Studs Lonigan</original_title><imdb_rating>5.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Irving Lerner</director><producer>Longridge Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A young man tries to escape the South Side of 1920s Chicago.
</synopsis><actor>Christopher Knight</actor><actor>Frank Gorshin</actor><actor>Venetia Stevenson</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0570008/comments</url><from>from New England</from><name>Son of Cathode</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Arty and overwrought and dynamic, using every cliche in the book yet rising
above them, this flick literally jumps off the screen to attack you, and
must have alienated the pants off its original audience. It's just too much
for the era, a type of unique vision that wouldn't arise again for another
five years or so, with films like A THOUSAND CLOWNS and LORD LOVE A DUCK.
The utterly bombastic score by Jerry Goldsmith helps. Also, "Studs"
portrays
1920s teens in a completely modern way, as if they were just your average
1950s Beatniks, a strange but very winning idea. Title youth Christopher
Knight was promoted as being the new James Dean, but reminds me more of a
contemplative Montgomery Clift character. Frank Gorshin and Jack Nicholson
are both good as angry, aimless bums. The film is powerful, strong and
highly episodic, probably due to trying to cram in as much as possible from
the source novels. There is rape and tragedy, violence and family
dysfunction, heavy stuff told in a very angst-ridden way. And it all ends
with a big life-changing question mark that's like falling off a cliff.
You'll either hate this flick, or sit back, take a deep breath and go
"Wow!"

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0102677/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>John Seal</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Uneasily straddling the ways of the old Hollywood and the coming openness of
the late 60s and 1970s, Studs Lonigan is neither fish nor fowl and is simply
hard to watch. The main attraction for contemporary audiences is the cast,
but the most interesting aspect of the film is Haskell Wexler's
cinematography. At times overly busy--his use of noirish angles gets
annoying at times, and isn't aided by poor editing by Verna Fields--Wexler
nonetheless leaves a great impression and hints at the great work to come in
films like Bound For Glory. When he gets it right, the photography is simply
stunning, channeling elements of the French New Wave and the
outside-the-studio naturalism that was soon to be the norm. Unfortunately
these moments only comprise about ten minutes of total screen time, the rest
of the film consisting of a hackneyed tale of youth in revolt during the
Roaring Twenties. Even Jack Nicholson and Frank Gorshin can't do much to
render Philip Yordan'
s screenplay particularly appetising. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2158049/comments</url><from>from Long Island, NY</from><name>curtaincall9000</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

adopted from the novel, this movie is one of the best movies EVER!
christopher knight plays the misguided teen through a tough life in
chicago.
i saw this movie to see frank gorshin in his early career and i've never
regretted it! the story really makes you think and if you're looking for
good actors this is the movie to see! the cast was really in tune with
their
characters which made the movie really real. a superb film with an
excellent
cast and a great story! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1174539/comments</url><from>from www.moviemoviesite.com</from><name>JoeytheBrit</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I remember reading James T. Farrell's labyrinthine account of youthful
futility in the late 70s or early 80s when the trilogy was published as
one house brick-sized tome as a tie-in to the TV mini-series starring
Harry Hamlin. Funnily enough, ITV suffered a month-long strike by its
workers that began during an ad break in the middle of the programme's
first episode and I never did get to see the full mini-series – all I
can remember about it now is Studs (Harry Hamlin) describing a baby as
being 'perfectly bald.' Anyway, I wasn't expecting great things from this low-budget 60s
version but it's plain to see that a lot of thought and effort has gone
into condensing Farrell's books into a 95-minute film. While that
doesn't necessarily make this a great film (or anything near) it does
give it an edge over much of the similar, higher budget fare coming out
of Hollywood at the time, and can almost be described as being ahead of
its time in the stark manner in which it portrays the wasted,
near-dissolute life of a 20s Chicago youth desperate – but incapable of
– improving his lot.Newcomer Christopher Knight plays the title character. Given the fact
that much of the time he has to provide facial expressions and
reactions to the internal dialogue we hear as a voice-over, he does
pretty well for a debutant in a role that would have stretched more
experienced actors. Apart from a small role in a Sandra Dee comedy,
Knight seems to have disappeared from the screen entirely, which is
surprising given his ability and looks. He's supported here by Jack
Nicholson and Frank Gorshin, two performers who went on to better
things, but is in no way overshadowed by them. In fact Nicholson is
pretty bland here, although he admittedly has little to work with.Of course, many of the incidents from the book are missing entirely
and, in trying to fit in as much source material as he can, Philip
Yordan has created a somewhat episodic saga. Sometimes a throwaway line
reveals that a couple of years has passed since the previous dramatic
episode and, instead of conveying a sense of the boring routine of the
character's lives it simply leaves the viewer wondering what has
happened to them in between. Everybody's life, no matter how routine
and dreary it may be, changes to some degree.What does come through, though, is Lonigan's sense of frustrated
ambition, of life controlling him instead of the other way around. In
the book, Lonigan dies, his health and spirit broken by the dissolute
lifestyle he finally embraced as a result of the frustration of his
ambitions, but here, although the film is open-ended (and quite bravely
so for the time) there is some kind of hope, or at least the indication
that his and Kathleen's story isn't over yet.If you're familiar with Farrell's books ignore the relatively low
rating on this site and give the film a chance. Even though it might
not succeed in its aims it is always interesting to watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2620874/comments</url><from>from South Carolina</from><name>sgfarrell_9</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I read the Studs Lonigan trilogy in the early Seventies and I was blown
away by how James T. Farrell accurately described my own Irish-Catholic
working-class background. I also saw the made-for-TV movie that was
based on the novels when it came out in 1979. I didn't see the 1960
film until the late Eighties, and I had mixed feelings about it. I was
surprised at how it had the feel of movies like REBEL WITHOUT A CAUSE
and the THE WILD ONE. I thought Christopher Knight was fine, if rather
tormented as Studs, and Nicholson and Gorshin were fine as Weary Reilly
and Kenny Kilarney. However, I wasn't wild about the happy ending of
the movie. Studs Lonigan was suppose to die after living a pointless
life. I also felt neither of the movie versions were able to
effectively focus on the Dead End Kids or West Side Story aspect of
Studs' south side of Chicago.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9575272/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>GaryVidmar</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Christopher Knight got fifteen minutes of fame portraying the title
character in this Irish-based, coming-of-age melodrama. It's
expectantly episodic, and overplayed by all. The unnerving urge to rise
from lower to middle-class by our puzzled pilgrim is rightly
discomforting, and the cryptic finale seems to suggest it is the
inevitable punishment of all dumb, working-class studs to listen to
their priests and find a wife, have a family, and pursue monotonous,
middle-class monogamy. The only thing of interest in the film are the
fates of Stud's pool-hall cronies (one of which is an engaging Jack
Nicholson). A ludicrous product of its time, albeit with a stirring,
early music score by Jerry Goldsmith.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9575272/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>GaryVidmar</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Christopher Knight got fifteen minutes of fame portraying the title
character in this Irish-based, coming-of-age melodrama. It's
expectantly episodic, and overplayed by all. The unnerving urge to rise
from lower to middle-class by our puzzled pilgrim is rightly
discomforting, and the cryptic finale seems to suggest it is the
inevitable punishment of all dumb, working-class studs to listen to
their priests and find a wife, have a family, and pursue monotonous,
middle-class monogamy. The only thing of interest in the film are the
fates of Stud's pool-hall cronies (one of which is an engaging Jack
Nicholson). A ludicrous product of its time, albeit with a stirring,
early music score by Jerry Goldsmith.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117795290.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/studs_lonigan/comments.php?reviewid=1804938</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9901E3DF1531EF3ABC4D52DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/studs_lonigan/comments.php?reviewid=1390435</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pat-graham/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/11672_STUDS_LONIGAN.html /m/studs_lonigan/comments.php?reviewid=1236878</url><name>Pat Graham</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>