<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Schachnovelle</original_title><alt_title>Le joueur d'échecs</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>West Germany</country><director>Gerd Oswald</director><producer>Roxy Film</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In 1938 Austria shortly after the Nazi occupation, a prominent Viennese intellectual, Werner von Basil...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Curd Jürgens</actor><actor>Claire Bloom</actor><actor>Hansjörg Felmy</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487926/comments</url><from>from Vienna</from><name>bettyblue_77</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This movie is based on the novel by Stefan Zweig and takes place during
the
second world war in Austria. A rather wealthy, good situated citizen of
Vienna gets in conflict with the Nazis (- he organizes the rescue if
important art -) and gets imprisoned. As he is a very intellectual and
intelligent man he is "tortured" by the lack of books, music, words or
other
"food for brain". Nearly becoming insane, he is able to steel one book.
First he is very disappointed because there are no words in it: it is a
book
full of check-games. But this book saves his life...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0141039/comments</url><from/><name>rb202</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is a wonderful film, even better and darker than Stefan Zweig's short
story upon which it is based.It moves along at a leisurely pace by contemporary standards, which makes
it
all the better by providing a good sense of context for recently
Nazi-occupied Austria.  It Imparts an atmosphere of anxious apprehension
and
quiet desperation as poor Curd Jurgens struggles to hold onto his sanity
while in solitary confinement, deprived of all stimuli.Recommended for film buffs and chess players alike.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur18848434/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>trailinghome</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I'll never forget this movie. Full of intrigue and suspense.The main reviewer has a typo, he managed to steal a book on World
Championship Chess Games with just the notations, (The Moves)regarding
the games. As he was locked up, a prisoner, that was the only mental
stimulation he had.Possible spoilers: He was so excited, after stealing the book from a
Nazi Officers coat pocket, but he was devastated when he opened the
book in his cell, he had thought it was a novel, instead it was on
chess, a game he didn't really enjoy. However he became the equivalent
of a Grand Master of the game after studying all the games in the book,
in secret, hiding it from his captors. I'm not saying anymore except
that this movie had me on the edge of my seat the whole time!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This movie is the first (and the last?) adaptation of Stefan Zweig's
short story "Die schachnovelle". I read it and I studied it for my
exams when I was in high school. But above all, I loved it so I was
quite impatient to discover this movie. I watched it and I must say
that I was disappointed. Not only is the short story a toned down and
softened adaptation of Zweig's masterpiece but it's also a betrayal.
For example, when Mr B... is prisoner of the Gestapo, he's succeeding
in finding a book that deals with chess. In the movie, the Gestapo's
leader's taking it from him and not on the short story. Moreover, Mr
B... is appearing at the beginning of the movie whereas in the book,
he's entering the plot in the middle. I also noticed that the subjects
broached in the short story like Mr B...'s madness against chess or
Nazis' goal to dehumanize their prisoners were more sketched out than
showed and analyzed. On another hand, unlike Zweig, Gert Oswald doesn't
succeed in recreating a choking and unhealthy atmosphere in the part
where Mr B... is prisoner of the Nazis. Nevertheless, I thought that
the actor who played Czentovic's role was quite convincing thanks to
his physical appearance (Zweig is writing about his head "a farmer's
fat head") and he's recreating perfectly his feelings: he's conceited,
unpleasant even ridiculous and he's despising his adversaries during
the chess game. But this positive side isn't sufficient enough to save
the movie and I hope that there'll be another (better) adaptation of
the short story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This movie is the first (and the last?) adaptation of Stefan Zweig's
short story "Die schachnovelle". I read it and I studied it for my
exams when I was in high school. But above all, I loved it so I was
quite impatient to discover this movie. I watched it and I must say
that I was disappointed. Not only is the short story a toned down and
softened adaptation of Zweig's masterpiece but it's also a betrayal.
For example, when Mr B... is prisoner of the Gestapo, he's succeeding
in finding a book that deals with chess. In the movie, the Gestapo's
leader's taking it from him and not on the short story. Moreover, Mr
B... is appearing at the beginning of the movie whereas in the book,
he's entering the plot in the middle. I also noticed that the subjects
broached in the short story like Mr B...'s madness against chess or
Nazis' goal to dehumanize their prisoners were more sketched out than
showed and analyzed. On another hand, unlike Zweig, Gert Oswald doesn't
succeed in recreating a choking and unhealthy atmosphere in the part
where Mr B... is prisoner of the Nazis. Nevertheless, I thought that
the actor who played Czentovic's role was quite convincing thanks to
his physical appearance (Zweig is writing about his head "a farmer's
fat head") and he's recreating perfectly his feelings: he's conceited,
unpleasant even ridiculous and he's despising his adversaries during
the chess game. But this positive side isn't sufficient enough to save
the movie and I hope that there'll be another (better) adaptation of
the short story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/brainwashed.htm /m/brainwashed/comments.php?reviewid=1125840</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>...just passable entertainment...</comment></review></movie>