<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>5 Branded Women</original_title><alt_title>Cinq femmes marquées</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>USA</country><director>Martin Ritt</director><producer>Dino de Laurentiis Cinematografica</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
Yugoslav partisans grimly crop the hair of a village quintet of women believed to have consorted with the occupational Nazis...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Van Heflin</actor><actor>Silvana Mangano</actor><actor>Jeanne Moreau</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0030805/comments</url><from>from Philly</from><name>N.L.</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

From the same director who brought us "Norma Rae" this classic World War II
"resistance band fights guerilla warfare against Nazis in the snowywoods"
has an interesting twist: they're all women and decked out in leather bomber
jackets, crew cuts and machine guns.Jeanne Moreau, Barbara Bel Geddes, Silvana Mangano, and Vera Miles - all
shaved, humiliated, and thrown out of their peasant villages for sleeping
with the enemy - now have taken arms against that enemy, but the "real"
resistance doesn't want them. So these women must fight the men who are
against them AND the men who are supposedly on their side, as well as each
other.Melodrama, to be sure, but different enough and with a fascinating sub-text,
that it has become a "guilty" pleasure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1705055/comments</url><from>from Commerce, TX</from><name>larrymp</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I have not seen this movie in many years. But I remember it being very
interesting. I always love Barbara Bel Geddes. She is one of the most
overlooked actresses of our time. When I saw those women walking down the
street with their heads shaved, it was a shock for a little boy. I was
about
10 when I saw this movie, but it left an impression on
me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1113856/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>pljewkes</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Director Martin Ritt had reportedly disowned this sleeper. If true,
that's perplexing because it's a well-made, exceptionally acted
anti-war film. In WWII Yugoslavia, five women are accused by partisans
of consorting with the enemy (in this case, callous Nazi stud Steve
Forrest). Run out of town, the women trek through the countryside
having one brutal encounter after another. Soon, they show their
collective courage and rejoin their compadres. Silvana Mangano, Vera
Miles, Jeanne Moreau, Barbara Bel Geddes and Carla Gravina are the
women and while they're all fine, Mangano is the standout as the
de-facto leader. Moreau is the lovelorn shop girl and Bel Geddes is a
bitter widow. Miles finds herself in the most ironic spot...never
having been with Forrest in the first place. Gravina, the youngest, is
pregnant. Van Heflin is the lead partisan, first hell-bent on punishing
the women, then, possibly, falling in love with the strong-willed
Mangano. Richard Basehart is a captured German soldier and Harry
Guardino is one of Heflin's hot headed cohorts. Ritt's direction is
fine and the script is really unflinching. There are no happy endings.
The cinematography is by the great Giuseppe Rotunno, who shot
Visconti's ROCCO &amp; HIS BROTHERS the same year.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

Just short of two hours is lengthy for 1960. This melodrama is set in Middle
Europe during WW2 and does have its moments. Five young women are scorned
and humiliated for consorting with Nazis. Now with shaved heads, they band
together to prove their patriotism and set out to fight the Germans. The
resistance fighters don't want their help; so they seem to be fighting both
forces...plus themselves. Strange casting is very obvious; and this moody
movie may be hard for some to get into. War buffs will watch. I watched
because of the enticing Vera Miles. Beside Miss Miles the very diverse cast
includes: Barbara Bel Geddes, Silvana Mangano, Van Heflin, Richard Basehart,
Jeanne Moreau and Steve Forrest. War causes people to do regrettable
things.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2438478/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>MONA0825</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This relatively unknown gathers a very impressive cast of both European
and American actors and actresses. Silvia Mangano gives a fine
performance as the leader of the titled women. These women are casted
away from a little town in Yugoslavia 1943 because they have slept with
a Nazi Sargent (except innocent Vera Miles who didn't go beyond kissing
but anyway is accused as the others), not before they are humiliated by
their own people by cropping their hair.The girls bound together and they wander around the country until they
resolve to join the partisans despite their initial resilience. The
women will form relationships with the partisans and a captured German
Captain (R. Basehart).But it's wartime and this is no Hollywood movie: there are no happy
endings or black and white feelings or situations. The movie is gritty
and somehow cruel. The movie has its flaws, the pacing could be better
and some characters feel underdeveloped, but all things considered,
this is a very good movie. It's not released on DVD, but you can find
it over the Internet. It's well worth the search.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0859027/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>Venus-25</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film on television when I was about 11 or 12 and it made a
deep impression on me. While I had little understanding of war and
certainly no personal experience of it, it pointed out the danger of
isolation in the midst of endless violence and the horror of rejection
for what would in peacetime have been regarded as a youthful
transgression.The casting of Vera Miles and Barbara Bel Geddes among the European
actresses was a clear ploy to make this film resonate with American
audiences whom during this period were more accustomed to light,
frivolous films. Films of a more serious and thoughtful nature were
mostly coming from Europe. At the dawn of the 60s this was a shocking
exploitation film, preying on women's feelings of vanity, Americans'
collective puritanism about sex, and our waning jingoism. It would be
interesting to see how audiences would react to it now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0859027/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>Venus-25</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film on television when I was about 11 or 12 and it made a
deep impression on me. While I had little understanding of war and
certainly no personal experience of it, it pointed out the danger of
isolation in the midst of endless violence and the horror of rejection
for what would in peacetime have been regarded as a youthful
transgression.The casting of Vera Miles and Barbara Bel Geddes among the European
actresses was a clear ploy to make this film resonate with American
audiences whom during this period were more accustomed to light,
frivolous films. Films of a more serious and thoughtful nature were
mostly coming from Europe. At the dawn of the 60s this was a shocking
exploitation film, preying on women's feelings of vanity, Americans'
collective puritanism about sex, and our waning jingoism. It would be
interesting to see how audiences would react to it now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0859027/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>Venus-25</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>