<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Taiyô no hakaba</original_title><alt_title>L'enterrement du soleil</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Nagisa Ôshima</director><producer>Shôchiku Eiga</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In Osaka's slum, youth without futures engage in pilfering, assault and robbery, prostitution, and the buying and selling of identity cards and of blood...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Masahiko Tsugawa</actor><actor>Kayoko Honoo</actor><actor>Isao Sasaki</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0797486/comments</url><from/><name>byron early</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie manages to undo every romantic notion of poverty and life in
the
slums anyone might have. The characters here are not noble, or unfortunate
and they are not victims. They are simply all cruel animals clawing on
each
other to get to the top of the jar.
Every character's face is continually covered with sweat and if they are
not afflicted with some deformity you can usually see the bones under
their
meager flesh. There is little distinction of charcters in the film. It is
like an entymologists film of an ant-colony.
Oshima's best film in my opinion, it doesn't suffer from the misogyny of
"Cruel Story of Youth." or the try hard porno universe of "In the Realm of
the Senses". These things are combined with a brutal realism that makes
this film the most surreal and shocking, but without trying to
be.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2028697/comments</url><from/><name>nicholhawking</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Some spoilers follow:
I haven't actually watched any other Oshima movies, although I certainly
intend to after seeing this. The plot can be hard to follow at times, as
the
characters are almost all selfish, greedy, and naive. Even Takeshi, the
innocent pseudo hero can't save himself from the self-centered, violent
lifestyle he is surrounded by. As downright despicable as nearly all of
the
characters are, one has to admire Hanako's ability to survive, and also be
the cleanest person in the movie. How she keeps that dress so clean is
beyond me, but perhaps it is a metaphor for her unique ability to see a
way
past the slum. Even the doctor that Shin corrupts shows the gradual decay
all the slummers have in common. As they lose hope, and fail to see the
light at the end of the tunnel, their clothes are stained, darkened,
ripped,
and worn.
As a commentary on depravity, this movie is excellent, as an examination
of
deceit and betrayal, a classic. The film's title, Grave of the Sun, can be
construed as an allusion to the fall of the Japanese empire, and indeed
the
characters who believe they can rebuild the empire by exploiting the
Japanese, and selling their identities to foreigners indeed suffer the
most.
(But even so, just about everyone in this movie suffers pretty
badly.)
Note that it takes place in the slums of Osaka, where they speak a
colorful,
unique Japanese dialect. One girl in my Japanese Film class said 'they
might
as well be speaking Chinese.' Not quite, but it would be hard to follow
without subtitles.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14855747/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>Sergiu Bursuc</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Haunting, melodic, melancholic, poetic... many more praising adjectives
suit this movie. It marks the birth of Japanese modern cinema. Oshima
brilliantly continues the masters Mizoguchi and Ozu, while at the same
time marking a big turn in style and themes.The movie is modern in both: style and themes. I dare saying that this
style marked many great contemporary directors (as different as
Tarantino, Jia Zhang-KE or Michael Mann). It has, for instance, a
questioning and a renewal of the dramatic content that a scene can
exhibit. Another novelty in Oshima's style is the manner in which he
treats social themes: a mixture of documentary-style and fiction-style,
greatly developed later by Jia Zhang Ke, and having an affiliation with
the French nouvelle vague (the time overlap is no coincidence).As for the themes: even if Mizoguchi was already interested in social
problems and their reflection upon the individual, he was never so
pessimistic as Oshima. Watch the movie and you'll see what I mean. But,
in spite of a much more cruel view upon society, Oshima has the same
deep message as Mizoguchi: the beauty. You can see it in every scene.
Look carefully: there is much light in this dark movie!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This sometimes brutal look at post war Osaka seems like a companion
piece to Oshima's "Naked Youth". Seemingly aimless young people engage
in criminal gang behavior, generally causing mayhem. You have to
immediate give credit to Oshima for being unflinching in this story.
This is not a story where you'll even like any character, least of all
Hanoko, who has pretty but also pretty dead black eyes. In her eyes you
see the futile existence in living there and leading the lifestyle they
lead. The film's title appears to be a political one, as if Japan will
be no more. The film's message is now dated, but its an effective film
nonetheless. Oshima didn't compromise in his work, sometimes for better
or for worse, but he is unique. If you're looking for redemption, its
not really here. watch it for its portrait of gang life in a Japan
rarely shown at any time to the general public. Its violent but worth
your time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This sometimes brutal look at post war Osaka seems like a companion
piece to Oshima's "Naked Youth". Seemingly aimless young people engage
in criminal gang behavior, generally causing mayhem. You have to
immediate give credit to Oshima for being unflinching in this story.
This is not a story where you'll even like any character, least of all
Hanoko, who has pretty but also pretty dead black eyes. In her eyes you
see the futile existence in living there and leading the lifestyle they
lead. The film's title appears to be a political one, as if Japan will
be no more. The film's message is now dated, but its an effective film
nonetheless. Oshima didn't compromise in his work, sometimes for better
or for worse, but he is unique. If you're looking for redemption, its
not really here. watch it for its portrait of gang life in a Japan
rarely shown at any time to the general public. Its violent but worth
your time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/s/SunsBurial.html /m/suns_burial/comments.php?reviewid=1878319</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>The sun is the crimson one in the imperial flag, given a scalding funeral in Nagisa Oshima's implacable view of postwar scavenging</comment></review></movie>