<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Strangers When We Meet</original_title><alt_title>Liaisons secrètes</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Richard Quine</director><producer>Bryna Productions</producer><producer>Richard Quine Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Architect Larry Coe has a wife and family, but becomes embroiled in an affair with beautiful Maggie Gault...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Kirk Douglas</actor><actor>Kim Novak</actor><actor>Ernie Kovacs</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1367429/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, CA</from><name>bjorkfan</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I've seen much commentary depicting this film as little more than a soap.
If
the themes of marital infidelity and dissatisfaction are soap-operish, then
I guess it is.That said,  I want to add that the subject matter is handled quite
delicately and skillfully by all involved.  Kirk Douglas is good as the
architect who finds himself attracted to his new neighbor.  He delivers the
dialogue quite well, not falling into the easy trap of overacting.  The
only
dissatisfaction may come with the Ernie Kovacs subplot, but that is so
minor, it barely registers.  More lasting are the scenes between Douglas
and
Kim Novak. One scene in particular, when they find themselves together at
the beach discussing his wife, is particularly poignant.The film belongs to Kim Novak, however, as the housewife who has the affair
with Douglas.  She is heart-breakingly good in this movie.  Joshua Logan,
director of "Picnic", once said that Novak wore her beauty like a 'crown of
thorns' and that quality is on full display in SWWM.  A natural desire for
love and affection come through wonderfully, and her subtle style of acting
is pitch perfect. Her best moment comes when she is talking to her
husband -
in effect trying to seduce him.  The moment could come off hokey or
overdone, but Novak doesn't miss a beat.  She is neither crass nor coy.
The
desire is honest and heartfelt, and one senses real pain at her
rejection.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3266840/comments</url><from>from Mankato, Minnesota</from><name>markspangler1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I was totally shocked when I saw this film as a kid, home sick from
school. Here was one of my movie heroes, Kirk Douglas and the lovely
Kim Novak at her sexiest, and they were NOT doing good things in their
neighborhood. Ahhhhhhhhh... so THIS is what was happening while I was
at school.This "adult" themed soaper showed that Hollywood was beginning to
change its tune when it came to dealing with issues like infidelity.
Douglas plays a successful architect who starts an affair with Novak
because he's, well, bored. Douglas' macho performance is tempered a bit
and we really feel that he is in love with Novak. This isn't a tawdry
affair, we're supposed to believe, because Douglas' performance is so
strong. It isn't until late in the film do we realize that these types
of affairs are incredibly damaging to all involved and that there are
no heroes here.For establishing a subtle ground-breaking subject matter, for a strong
Douglas performance, for the neat cars and a really cool barbecue on
the patio (hello 60s... you can just see the neighborhood gang out
there, firing up the steaks, sipping on gin and tonics and watching a
space shot on one of those metal portable TVs) and most of all for the
gorgeous Kim Novak, this soaper has a little more depth than you'd
expect.Watch it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0888661/comments</url><from>from Munich, Germany</from><name>medmai</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I was rather surprised when I saw this love story. I found it very moving,
serene and very inspired in all aspects. The perfect balance between main
plot (the relationship of Douglas and Novak) and substories (writer,
Douglas' wife, neighbours) is amazing. The culmination of the film is the
final scene in the recently finished house that architect Douglas has
designed. A very big bravo for Novak and Douglas performances, two (still)
living legends. If there were only films like this in the cinemas
now...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5906757/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>cotaboy1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I echo the sentiment of the other reviewer. This is so much more than a
soap opera...I caught this movie on the late show about 20 years ago and if recall
correctly, was going through the end of a relationship at the time. The
movie struck a chord, though frankly I'm not sure why I received it's
message so deeply. This is my favorite Kirk Douglas movie by far. Kirk
is not known for subtlety but he's great here.I typically judge movies by their ring of truth, and this one has it in
spades.A must see...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1129446/comments</url><from/><name>bethster2000</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Kim Novak and Kirk Douglas positively steam up the screen in this
well-done
film depicting a torrid suburban affair in Eisenhower's sexually
repressed
America.  It is a great story and is singlehandedly responsible for my
being
a huge Kim Novak fan.  Not only was (is) she undeniably beautiful, she is
a
remarkable actress.  Look for Walter Matthau in a villainous turn, and
the
great Ernie Kovacs in one of his final performances.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0601627/comments</url><from/><name>bdplaid</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

If viewed from the morality of the period, this is actually quite a good
movie. It attempted to tell a story about and comment on American family
life, particularly on repressed desires and wedded relationships in the
suburbs just before the "swinging 60's" exploded.  Hearing Walter Matthau
sum up his marital role as merely being considered "furniture in his own
home" speaks volumes about what this film is about. Kim Novak is the sexy
wife and mother to one family. Living down the manicured street is Kirk
Douglas, the virile husband and dad in another - both living their lives
against the backdrop of 1950's-60's morality. You do the
math...Is it worthy of awards?  No.  Is the conflict entertaining? You bet!
Definitely worth a look to those who like films from this era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1132004/comments</url><from>from Allentown, PA</from><name>Noir-It-All</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The film was noteworthy because it showed how Maggie (Kim Novak) was
ripe for infidelity: her spouse was cold to her and her mother knew it.
It was interesting how her mother said "told you so", having warned her
not to marry her conventionally-handsome husband. Maggie's mother
caught on to the chemistry between her daughter and her passionate
neighbor at once, because it was what she wanted for Maggie all along.
Kim's longing for love was also revealed by her confession about a
dalliance with an outspoken truck driver. Wouldn't you know the driver
catches the twosome dining at an out-of-the-way restaurant, hurling
insults at her for dropping him. Kim Novak took the cold facade/hot
interior combination so beloved by Alfred Hitchcock to another level.
It is significant that that the story took place at the end of the
conservative Fifties, just in time for the turbulent Sixties.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4781191/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vizfam</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie when it first came out in 1960. I loved it then, and I
still find it appealing 4 decades later. I was a teenager in the 50's
and Kim Novak was the epitome of beauty and sexuality for that era, and
she is at her peak in this role. There is so much to say about this
movie; Kirt Douglas strong masculine performance, with Novak
complimenting him with her subdued, almost melancholy performance. The
storyline is simple, Kirt and Kim are both married, but not to each
other. Kim is love starved, her husband he a cold individual, who is
more interest in open the mail, than opening her blouse, he spurns her
attempts at romance at every turn. I can't imagine that happening with
a woman like her. I don't know if the director was aware of it at the
time, but her husband today would be view as a repressed homosexual,but
in the 50's any hint of that was taboo. Kirt has a nice enough wife and
2 children and seems to be somewhat content, but apparently under the
surface smothers a restlessness, that I don't think he was even aware
of existed. When he sees Kim at a school bus stop where they both drop
off their child, he is smitten. He pursues her, she resists in the
beginning, but when her husband continues to ignore her, she gives in.
The results are a passionate affair resulting in 2 destroyed marriages
and the separation from each other. There are a few subplots that keep
the story moving but it is Kim and Kirt who set the screen on fire
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218325/comments</url><from>from Muros, Galicia-Spain</from><name>Ranse</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

What I liked in this movie was the way the screenplay, as well as the
director, gets close to what happens in real life. I mean, the doubts that
assault many people when they think they have already got what society makes
us consider as the right stuff: a job, a wife, sons. People in this
situation one day realize that their life is empty in many senses, and they
search for understanding in someone else outside their home inner circle.
Only one thing annoyed me: the ending leaves the character played by Douglas
in a very comfortable situation, considering he's the real motor of all the
thing; besides, Maggie's (Kim Novak) husband (John Bryant) disappears from
action in a very important, in my opinion, moment.
Leaving apart these last things I consider as faults, the whole movie
deserves to be watched; I think it's profitable and can make all of us take
a minute or two for a meditation.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2646705/comments</url><from>from roanoke, va</from><name>eaglesfan152000 (eaglesfan152000@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This might contain possible spoilers. First off, this is Kirk Douglas
in one of his usual roles ( he was once quoted as saying "I've made a
career of playing s.o.b's). Kim Novak is quite nice as the wife who
doesn't get the total affections of her husband and falls into a
relationship with a married man (Douglas). I saw this film on AMC and
if you can record it please do, because this film is currently
unavailable. It is one of the best films that depicted suburban 1960's
Los Angelas. Walter Matthau's performance was probably the best in this
film. The scene where he encounters Douglas on the patio at the party
and informs him of his knowledge of the affair is really good. Then at
the end when he confronts Douglas's wife (Barbara Rush) is disturbing.
Matthau was alway's a great actor. The music is pretty good, Ernie
Kovaks does a good job also. This is pretty much a chick flick but
worth it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2646705/comments</url><from>from roanoke, va</from><name>eaglesfan152000 (eaglesfan152000@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This might contain possible spoilers. First off, this is Kirk Douglas
in one of his usual roles ( he was once quoted as saying "I've made a
career of playing s.o.b's). Kim Novak is quite nice as the wife who
doesn't get the total affections of her husband and falls into a
relationship with a married man (Douglas). I saw this film on AMC and
if you can record it please do, because this film is currently
unavailable. It is one of the best films that depicted suburban 1960's
Los Angelas. Walter Matthau's performance was probably the best in this
film. The scene where he encounters Douglas on the patio at the party
and informs him of his knowledge of the affair is really good. Then at
the end when he confronts Douglas's wife (Barbara Rush) is disturbing.
Matthau was alway's a great actor. The music is pretty good, Ernie
Kovaks does a good job also. This is pretty much a chick flick but
worth it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-nusair/</url><url>http://www.reelfilm.com/sonyclss.htm#strangers /m/strangers_when_we_meet/comments.php?reviewid=1364306</url><name>David Nusair</name><from>Reel Film Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
2/4
					</rating><comment>The bloated running time is exacerbated by a focus on pointless subplots...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lori-hoffman/</url><url>/m/strangers_when_we_meet/comments.php?reviewid=1532176</url><name>Lori Hoffman</name><from>Atlantic City Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/strangers_when_we_meet/comments.php?reviewid=1403725</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-szymanski/</url><url>/m/strangers_when_we_meet/comments.php?reviewid=1397122</url><name>Michael Szymanski</name><from>International Press Academy</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117795258.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/strangers_when_we_meet/comments.php?reviewid=1804539</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/75465/strangers_when_we_meet.html /m/strangers_when_we_meet/comments.php?reviewid=1515303</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>