<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Pure Hell of St. Trinian's</original_title><imdb_rating>6.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Frank Launder</director><producer>British Lion Film Corporation</producer><producer>Hallmark Productions</producer><producer>Tudor Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
The hellions of St. Trinians are recruited to a sheik's harem. Little does he know what he's letting himself in for.
</synopsis><actor>Cecil Parker</actor><actor>George Cole</actor><actor>Joyce Grenfell</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2823605/comments</url><from>from Hampshire, England</from><name>The_Secretive_Bus</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
There's just something utterly magical about the first three St.
Trinian's films. Almost every character in them is played by an actor
recognisable from over fifty other British films of the time, and they
frequently have the best cast lists of comic talent ever seen in a
British comedy. Quite often a film with a cast this distinguished can
turn out to be a grave disappointment (such a fate befell efforts like
"The Magnificent Seven Deadly Sins", in which most of the effort on the
part of the film-makers seemed to have been in actually recruiting the
actors, rather than giving them anything worthwhile to perform).
However, "Pure Hell", like "Belles" and "Blue Murder" before it, has a
script and a story good enough to support the weight of these amassed
comedy greats, most of whom you'll probably never have heard of.
They're usually actors who appeared in loads of films of the period,
and you'd never have thought of making a film at the time without them,
but who never became stars in their own right - chaps like Raymond
Huntley and Nicholas Phipps (most memorable in "Doctor in Love" as the
frankly spiffing Dr. Cardew). Those actors who, if you're a vintage
comedy connoisseur like me, you'll see and then go "Ahhh, yes!"As well as an admirable leading performance from Cecil Parker (taking
over from Terry-Thomas in the last film as the guesting star), we have
marvellous return appearances from the likes of Joyce Grenfell as
Sergeant Ruby Gates, Lloyd Lamble as the superintendent who got engaged
to her 16 years ago and still hasn't tied the knot (they almost achieve
it, twice, in this film), Eric Barker as the civil servant
Culpepper-Brown, Michael Ripper as the philosophical lift attendant,
and, of course, George Cole as the best spiv in the business, Flash
Harry. Quite why I think he's so class I don't know - I mean, he quite
obviously *is* top notch, but I can't put my finger on why. He's
just... hurrah! It's Flash! With his cockney lingo and jaunty theme
music (yes, it's here again, punctuating most of his scenes and it
never gets tiresome)!We also have the likes of Thorley Walters (hurrah!), Dennis Price
(double hurrah!) and John le Mesurier (HURRAH!) as various members of
the civil service, and Raymond Huntley, Cyril Chamberlain, Nicholas
Phipps and Sid James making random appearances (actually, the double
act of Eric Barker and Thorley Walters is one of the continued
highlights of this film), and even some scenes with perhaps the best
comedy actress there ever was, Irene Handl (probably best known for
having played Peter Sellers wife in "I'm All Right Jack). Irene always
seems to play these "posh commoner" roles, with wonderful lines like
"So what bit of culture are you going to have a bash at then?",
effortlessly stealing most of the laughs in whatever scene she appears
in.That's another reason to love the film - genuine wit. Whilst a lot of
comedies of the period tended to rely on farce and gurning and people
falling over, such scenes are kept to a minimum here (and, furthermore,
even when they do happen they're actually amusing), with witty lines
and comments being brought to the fore instead. There's far too many to
choose from, but my favourite probably has to be in a scene where Cecil
Parker, George Cole and Joyce Grenfell are stuck in a boat in the
middle of the ocean, sipping tea like the stiff-upper-lipped British
citizens that they are. "Stranded in the middle of the ocean," Parker
laments mournfully, "With only enough food and water to last us for...
six months; two sugars please." Lines like this are delivered in a dry
throwaway manner and just tickled me all the way through.The plot in this is far more complicated than those of the other films
in the series, with most of the action being focused on the civil
servants and adult characters, as opposed to the schoolgirls
themselves. But the rambling story, which at one point seems to have
ten plot lines running and intertwining at once, takes on a wonderfully
surreal quality which further adds to the majesty of it all. In one
scene, Parker, Cole, Grenfell, Barker and Walters are stuck out in a
desert market place sipping tea at a cafe, and Phipps and Chamberlain,
British soldiers in disguise, sit down at the table next to them.
Chamberlain leans back to Walters to try and give his identity.CHAMBERLAIN: "Psst. I'm a-"WALTERS: "No, sorry, I don't want any postcards thank you."...PHIPPS: "Well, what did he say?"CHAMBERLAIN: "He said he didn't want any post cards."PHIPPS: "Oh... You haven't got any have you?"Oh, and as for the schoolgirls, though they don't appear that often
(and when they do it's usually the fourth formers, played by child
actors), there are a few "sixth formers" dotted about - the glamorous
twenty-something year old actresses dressed in uniforms and the
shortest skirts you're ever likely to see. The initial courtroom scene
contains a slow pan up the most gorgeous of the lot, with her... legs,
and everything, and my word, by jove, indeed. Ha ha.It's a quaint British comedy and I'm feeling a trifle warm just
thinking about. I should have taken the tablets.The film does at times seem to be running out of steam, but there's
usually another random plot twist to pull it back into shape. Though I
probably still prefer "Blue Murder" for the sheer Terry-Thomas factor,
"Pure Hell" is only slightly less marvellous, and stands up as a true
comedy classic in its own right. Especially for dull 50s/60s comedy
fans like me.9/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0978359/comments</url><from>from Stockton, England</from><name>david-697</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

The Pure Hell Of St Trinian's, the third movie in the series, never
approaches the comic heights of the first two.  Part of this is down to
the
absence of Alistair Sim, but also it is due to a script that switches the
emphasis largely away from the school and places it more on the men from
the
Ministry Of Education.  For long stretches you can hardly spot a
schoolgirl,
while the movie lacks a strong comic climax.You can also see a lack of inspiration at work here, as the
Grenfell-Parker
`romance' is more or less a replay of (the better handled) relationship
with
Terry-Thomas in the previous movie, while the whole 'desert island'
business
seems designed to fill up the movie's running-time.If it's not as fun as `Belles' or `Blue Murder', `Pure Hell' does have its
good points.  Cecil Parker's down-at-heel headmaster is a major asset to
the
movie, while it's nice to see the likes of Sid James, Denis Price and Liz
Frazer make an appearance.The comic high-points come early in the movie, with Raymond Huntley
stealing
the movie as a Judge distracted by the charms of a leggy Sixth-Former,
while
later the 'striptease' Hamlet provides the film's most memorable moment.
Irene Handle is also on top form as a more than slightly batty
teacher.It's not the best of the series by a long way, but forty or so years on it
is still worth watching.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2237221/comments</url><from>from New Zealand</from><name>peter-w</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I just watched this on TV, and it was great to see so many well known
actors looking young ! This film is very interesting as a part of our
British cultural heritage, and a window on a time when Pythonesque
humour was developing.The idea of a British schoolgirl being a stripper in a club called
"Mohammed's" in "Arabia" may seem awfully non-PC today, but the other
characters are also caricatures of British types. I particularly enjoyed the British Officer in the "Bath" unit and his
preoccupation with Scotch. But as another reviewer has said, George
Cole is outstanding.Great fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0361603/comments</url><from>from Bath, UK</from><name>C M Lloyd</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

There is something beautifully reassuring and warm about this film. The
story is almost incidental to the characters. It is packed with superb
performances and is a feast of character actors. The comedy is often
subtle,
but beautifully presented. It ranges from slapstick to the pure surrealism.
The bizarre military bath unit stationed in the desert, the ballet-dancing
civil servants, the desert island cookery - all superb. The civil servant
chap handing over his wallet had me in stitches too. Its innocence is
wonderful, although if you look a little closer the darker side is visible,
along with lots of little touches that give the whole thing surprising
depth.  It isn't going to suit everybody. I don't expect too many Americans
or teenagers to get the point. It is however a superb piece of work.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0918514/comments</url><from>from Bristol, England</from><name> (walmington@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is the final of the three original St. Trinian's films. Alastair Sim
doesn't appear in this one, which leaves quite a space but is filled well
by
new characters and extensions of existing ones. The plot is a lot
different
from the 2 before, in that it's more surreal. In the other 2, the fact
that
Flash Harry, a police woman and a professor would become stranded on a
desert island wouldn't have happened. Neither would the storming of an
Arab
sheiks palace.
The charceters of Sergeant Ruby Gates (Joyce Grenfell) and Flash Harry
(George Cole) are explored much more, with us learning things like Harry's
middle name and where Ruby's mother lives. Fantastic performances form the
whole cast but I think Cole and Grenfell steal the show. Comedy at its
best.
Watch out for the scene in the strippers club. Watch Harry's face.
Probably
the best comedy without words ever.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When the school is burnt to the ground, all the girls find themselves in the
dock.  However the judge decides mercy and takes up the offer of one
Professor Canford to open a new school with a backer and try to change the
girls.  The backer, Alphonse O'Reilly, takes the whole school on a trip to
Europe, but Flash Harry finds that the ship is actually on it's way to
Africa, where Alphonse plans to sell the older girls into
harems!This entry in the series starts really well.  Not only does it have what I
consider to be a great line (`there's always trouble when there's arson
around') but the courtroom stuff is very funny.  The rest of the film from
there starts to tail off, the continuation of the film sees the old
characters come back in (mostly) are this is good.  However once the action
moves to Africa etc it all becomes a little silly but doesn't manage to be
fun for it.The action gets more frantic and less amusing as it goes along and, by the
end of the whole thing, I'd pretty much lost interest in it.  The cast are
reasonably good.  The girls are in two camps – the young thugs and the sexy
`girls' (albeit it they are happily in their 20's).  The support cast
includes good performances from George Cole (complete with cheeky chappy
music in case you didn't get it).  Parker and Grenfell are OK but their
stuff on the island doesn't really wash.  Barker and Walters are fine, as is
a cameo from Le Mesurier, but Sid James is pretty wasted.Overall this is worth seeing if you like the series (although it fades
throughout the 90 minutes), but there are better films in the series if
you're just coming in now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This film begins with the school burning down and there is a trial for
arson against the girls (all of them!). They are found guilty but set
free by the judge. The girls are taken on a ship, supposedly going to
the Greek Isles. The ever lovelorn Sargeant Gates (the wonderful Joyce
Grenfell) goes to meet up with them to see whats going on. She ends up
on a desert island with Flash Harry (George Cole) and another man who
has designs on her. Will they save the girls? Do they need saving? This
film is not as good as the other two, since it deemphasizes the girls.
Its a lot more of an adult film, they are much more prominent. Its not
bad, just not quite as good. As for whether Sargeant Gates gets
married..see the film. Its fine, just not essential unless you want to
watch the series (all 4 films are available in a box set but
unfortunately with no extras). So, check it out if you want to.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0235204/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>NJMoon</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Third time the charm? Well, not really. This installment in the
original and classic St. Trinian's films doesn't actually take place at
St. Trinian's at all! The school is a pile of embers at the top of the
first reel! Gone, too, is Alistair Sim (everyone's favorite Scrooge) in
the drag double role as headmistress and her brother. The up side is
this allows more shenanigans from the likes of Joyce Grenfell (a
personal favorite) and the supporting cast. But with school girls of
St. Trins only set decoration, it's just not the same. There's a remake
of the original that's also spawned two sequels (Rupert Everett subs
for Sim) but these are inferior goods - stick to the glorious black and
white originals!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12022508/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>icaredor</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Third, and third best, film in the St. Trinian's series. The decline in
quality is gentle and, although it looks a bit tired, this one still
offers a lot of entertainment largely due to some wonderful comedic
performances.The movie begins with the Fourth Form (Junior) girls burning down St.
Trinian's and the entire school finding itself on trial for arson. The
joy of the Barchester police and at Ministry of Education turns to
gloom when Professor Canford (Cecil Parker) offers to provide a new
school and promises to reform the girls. Canford turns out to be the
dupe in a plot to abduct the Sixth Form (Senior) girls and marry them
off to the sons of an Arab sheik. Off to Arabia in pursuit go the
League of Incompetents: Flash Harry, Sergeant Ruby Gates, Professor
Canford; bureaucrats from the Ministry of Education; and a Bath Unit
(of highly trained ablutionists, no less) of the British Army. Luckily
for all of them, the Fourth Form girls are on the trail too.This film has two major shortcomings. The girls are sadly misused.
There are none of the distinct girl characters that helped drive the
plot along in Belles. Here, the girls are simply a horde of hair and
hockey sticks. Consequently, the story rests on the adult characters
with mixed results. Flash Harry gets entirely too much screen time and
becomes irritating, and the romancing of Ruby Gates gets rehashed from
Blue Murder. On the other hand, the alcoholic ablutionists are amusing
and the Ministry bureaucrats are splendid. Indeed, Thorley Walters
gives the standout performance as Butters the education official driven
to neurosis by years of dealing with St. T's. When he suddenly breaks
into a pastoral dance it is as hilarious as it is unexpected, as
incongruous as it is apt.The second shortcoming is that the film builds to a big, slapstick
finale and then inexplicably skips out on it. When the hairy hockey
horde comes careening across the desert in the requisitioned military
vehicles – complete with band playing the St. Trinian's fight song –
one expects, nay, one feels entitled, to see them rampage through the
sheik's palace, returning much of it to deserty dust and banishing the
sheik and his sons to maunder the merciless dunes. Sadly, no. The first
vehicle crashes through the palace gate and we fade to the epilogue
left only to imagine the mayhem that may have ensued. Sigh! Despite its
faults, Pure Hell contains plenty of good stuff and remains a must see
for St. T fans. The acting is wonderful with major talent in roles both
major (e.g., Joyce Grenfell and Cecil Parker) and minor (e.g., Dennis
Price and John Le Mesurier). And needless to say (but I will, anyway),
it far outshines Train Robbery and the egregious Wild Cats.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I can't claim to be an expert on THE ST TRINIAN series . I have some
vague notion that it's about some hellcat girl pupils which in today's
political climate would probably never been considered as a film seriesStrangely enough the film starts with a liberal agenda after the pupils
have burnt down their school and are shown compassion , but at this
point the film deviates from what you'd expect . The title is THE PURE
HELL OF ST TRINIANS right ? so why does the film then revolve around
Flash Harry and a couple of other characters being stuck on a desert
island with the naughty schoolgirls absent for most of the narrative .
It's also difficult to work out what the plot is since the movie feels
rather episodic . It is interesting to see foreign office types going
to a city called Bahgdad with some of the comedy coming out of this
situation but this makes the film feel even more dated than it already
is No doubt made for a British commercial market THE PURE HELL OF ST
TRINIAN is something of a reminder of more innocent times but that's
probably its only reason to watch as entertainment in 2005 . Compare
this with the CARRY ON films of the early 1960s and see what series has
aged better
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I can't claim to be an expert on THE ST TRINIAN series . I have some
vague notion that it's about some hellcat girl pupils which in today's
political climate would probably never been considered as a film seriesStrangely enough the film starts with a liberal agenda after the pupils
have burnt down their school and are shown compassion , but at this
point the film deviates from what you'd expect . The title is THE PURE
HELL OF ST TRINIANS right ? so why does the film then revolve around
Flash Harry and a couple of other characters being stuck on a desert
island with the naughty schoolgirls absent for most of the narrative .
It's also difficult to work out what the plot is since the movie feels
rather episodic . It is interesting to see foreign office types going
to a city called Bahgdad with some of the comedy coming out of this
situation but this makes the film feel even more dated than it already
is No doubt made for a British commercial market THE PURE HELL OF ST
TRINIAN is something of a reminder of more innocent times but that's
probably its only reason to watch as entertainment in 2005 . Compare
this with the CARRY ON films of the early 1960s and see what series has
aged better
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>