<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Toby Tyler, or Ten Weeks with a Circus</original_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Charles Barton</director><producer>Walt Disney Productions</producer><genre>Family</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Taken in by distant members of his family after being orphaned, Corcoran runs away to join the circus.
</synopsis><actor>Kevin Corcoran</actor><actor>Henry Calvin</actor><actor>Gene Sheldon</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169216/comments</url><from>from Southern California</from><name>acbottomley</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

My 7 year old grandson was held spellbound by Toby Tyler.  I'd love to buy
him his own copy, but it's not available.  I'd be thrilled to see Disney
release a lot of their archival films. How about a DVD starring Jiminy
Cricket?  I can still hear Jiminy singing "I'm No Fool".  "Seabiscuit" is
riding a wave of current popularity, but I still remember Nautilus,
Disney's
"The Horse With the Flying Tail".  A recent commercial on T.V. features
rabbits multiplying out of control, but way back when there was a Disney
short cartoon about multiplying guinea pigs.  It would be great if future
generations of children could savor and enjoy these little cinematic
gems.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0358997/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Geff</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
You can't find this one to buy anywhere. I finally found it at
Moviehunter.com. It was a thrill to see the most important film of an
eleven-year-old's life. I saw this film when I was eleven and never
forgot it. I sat in the movie theater all day and saw it three
consecutive times. You could do that back then. I would have seen it a
fourth time, but I had to go home for dinner. This is a sweet, warm,
loving, exciting adventure film about a boy joining the circus and
making new friends, including a mischievous chimp and a dishonest boss.
It's the old Disney style all the way. It's great for kids, and there's
nothing negative to say about it. Too bad Disney doesn't realize it and
re-release it and make it available on DVD and VHS. Barbara Beaird is a
blonde 12-year-old in this film, and she was the first puppy-love of my
young life. I always wonder what ever happened to her. Kevin "Moochie"
Corcoran steals the show, or maybe I should say the chimp does.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1416076/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Sparrow_in_flight</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

But not quite as much as some make out...the circus characters in the book
were not that grotesque, not was Toby in an orphan's home, constantly being
punished for dishonesty. And, he did become a star, in a sense, on
horseback. However, he was a glutonous boy who runs away to the circus, for
no reason other than his own selfish ones. He does have a hard life. And his
riding on the horses lasts for only about a day, but for that day, he and
the girl who rode with them were required to do encores of their
performances,Anyways....the story is cute. Yes, Mr. stubbs lives in the movie, but that
is typical Disney giving a happy ending, and is to be expected. Watch it for
fun, not because you want to compare it to the book. Personally, I like
both.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5031210/comments</url><from>from Costa Mesa, CA</from><name>eebarnett</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Michael Eisner seemed to market every Disney film on video then he
re-leased them again on DVD. This is one of the films that I love but
it just hasn't been released.Hey, Robert Iger, this movie is special to LOTS of people. Please
release it to the new generation of children who have never seen "Toby
Tyler."I saw this movie first in Lake Tahoe, CA, while on vacation with my
parents. I am 49 now and I would still watch it many times--if I could
only find it.Classic Disney--family oriented, familiar cast from other Disney films,
great storyline. If it ever comes out on DVD, I will run to buy it as soon as I know
about it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0478958/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Sean Richard McCarthy (srmccarthy@charter.net)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I love Kevin Corcoran's acting in the first place, but this is most
likely my favorite movie with him STARING!  What sets this one above the
rest is it does NOT rely on a sound-track to keep the interest of the
viewers.
Toby is an orphaned boy being raised by his aunt and uncle. His uncle
tells him he is a burden, so Toby joins the circus.
What makes this movie most entertaining is Toby's horse training!  As I
said, this movie does not rely on a sound-track to keep the interest of
the
viewers, but in fact it is this very aspect that makes it a charm!  As
Toby
is trained to ride a horse, you see him fail, fail, learn, learn some
more,
then eventually succeed!  All the time, the only thing you hear is the
trot
of the horse!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12938935/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>kidboots</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I loved "Toby Tyler"!!! I can remember it being my brother's birthday
treat movie and mine was "Pollyanna". My memories of seeing "Toby
Tyler" at the local cinema are vivid. We drove across Taren Point
Bridge to the Oakley Picture Theatre on a sunny Saturday afternoon.
Having a Golden Book and also a Whitman comic helped keep Toby Tyler in
my mind . Also when it was shown on Disneyland but I had not heard of
it for about 40 years. Then a cable station we had called the Disney
Channel showed it and I was able to view it. The bright vivid colours
of those Disney films bought memories flooding back.Kevin Cochran came from a family of actors - his sister Donna had had
minor success in films and Noreen was in the TV series "Bachelor
Father" with John Forsythe. May be that explains why such an irritating
child actor could be such a success.When the circus comes to town Toby Tyler (Kevin Cochran) has stars in
his eyes. He runs away to join the circus after his Uncle tells him he
is "no kin to us - nothing but a millstone 'round our necks". He is
taken on by Harry Tupper, who runs the refreshment stand, and gives
Toby the princely sum of 50 cents a week. Harry Tupper has the
reputation of treating his helpers mean so Ben, the strong man, keeps a
look out for him. Toby meets a clown with a family of dogs and a lovely
bareback rider, Jeanette and her uppity partner Ajax.Mr. Stubbs, the chimp, raids Toby's refreshment box and gets sick.
Against orders Ben lets Mr. Stubbs ride atop the wagon when the parade
goes into town. When there is an accident Ben is sacked and Toby
rescues Mr. Stubbs - he is in the sheriff's office shooting up the
town. After disarming him Toby is given full responsibility for the
chimp.When Ajax is showing off (riding without his safety harness) he falls
off and Toby, who has bragged that he has ridden horses on the farm is
ordered to take his place. After some funny rehearsal scenes he goes on
at the next town and is a big hit. He also finds out that Mr. Tupper
has been hiding letters that his Aunt Emma has written. His uncle is
sick and the farm is too much for them - they want him back. Toby runs away from the circus and Mr. Stubbs follows him. When Toby
thinks a passing hunter (James Drury) has killed Mr. Stubbs he is taken
back to the circus where he is reunited with a much nicer Uncle Daniel
and also his Aunt Emma.It was a very entertaining film and in those times there were no
forgettable songs to slow down the action.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This Disney production was released at about the same time as
"Pollyanna".Both heroes have problems with their families: Pollyanna is
taken in by her auntie Polly Harrington a good but proud woman who
thinks that money can buy everything;Toby has to escape from the farm
where he lives with his uncle and his aunt -who are far from being as
rich as Polly but who are finally good people-.The subtitles reads "ten
weeks with a circus" and that's exactly what it is.Toby takes refuge in a circus where he will meet people from a world he
does not know:he becomes good friend with Mr Tibbs ,the chimp and falls
in love with the beautiful rider;but his job is to sell peanuts,and
Monsieur Ajax,Mademoiselle Jeannette's partner ,always laughs at
him.Toby's dream is to become part of the show but he stands no chance
till....A nice memory from your childhood from long ago.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
James Otis Kaler's book becomes too-glossy Walt Disney saga of a
spotless, overly-polite orphan boy from a rural town who runs away from
his uncle's farm and attaches himself to a traveling circus. He makes
himself useful as a concessions salesman before joining the
horse-riders in the center ring, garnering friends for the first time
(some of whom only see dollar signs in the lad's untapped potential).
Disney skimps a bit on the big top fun while loading up the plot with
various characters, including a hateful uncle who manages a complete
change of heart by the finale (what is the message of this movie...that
success is the best revenge, particularly if you're an orphan?). We do
get clowns and a parade, plus a chimp who reacts to everything like a
human would; however, the central figure is played by the leaden Kevin
Corcoran, a Disney favorite, who can barely read a line. The youngster
has a consistent look of bewilderment on his face and is generally
unable to carry the more dramatic scenes proposed by the tale (if you
do watch, see if you can count how many times Corcoran stumbles over
the name "Mr. Tupper"). There's a regrettable moment wherein the
audience is made to think an animal is killed by a hunter's rifle,
while the subplot about Toby Tyler's financial worth is never quite
resolved. A few scenes of color and merriment, but the elements of the
story (basic as they are) are bungled. *1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19532258/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>johnstonjames</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
come on everybody! is everyone blind or something? KEVIN CORCORAN DOES
HIS OWN STUNT WORK HERE. so do the other two children. i have read many
reviews like Leonard Maltin's and even looked at the wikipedia for this
film and nobody points this obvious fact out. i mean what a thing to
leave out. if you don't at least mention this you are not giving Kevin
Corcoran the true credit he deserves for his outstanding performance.
if one more person writes a review of this film without mentioning this
i'm gonna scream "foul"! you might really like the film but if you
don't mention this you are being too forgetful, unobservant, and
unfair.hopefully one day this minor children's classic will get the good
treatment it so richly earns and deserves. it is definitely one of
Disney's very best from the studio's golden age. it is very solid film
making and even though there might be better films, few films have
achieved this kind of neat and tidy perfection. every little element
works beautifully.not to mention the film is very cute with an abundance of simple heart.
i was surprised to find out the book was so unpleasant. i read 'Toby
Tyler' when i was about nine yrs old but i don't seem to remember
anything about the book. i certainly didn't remember it was that dark.
but i'll take that reviewers word for it. the books themselves are
usually darker and grittier than their Disney film adaptations which
tend to be more wholesome. i always remembered the film better because
i saw the film a few times first. i remember loving the film but not
having much of an opinion about the book. probably because i was afraid
of it or something.besides an amazing performance by the film's lead, Kevin Corcoran, the
film also highlights the wonderful Henry Calvin and Gene Sheldon, two
of my favorite Disney performers. they were both cute and funny when
teamed up as Laurel and Hardy look alikes for 'Babes in Toyland', but
their performances here resonate more warmth and realistic human
appeal. especially Calvin, who i think should have been nominated for
this. but Disney films were not taken seriously in the "actor"
categories back then. Kevin Corcoran should have at least been given a
special "outstanding juvenile performance" award.it's also fun to see veteran Disney Composer/conductor Oliver Wallace
in a cameo role as the circus band leader.love the heck out of this film. i first liked it because of the cute
monkey 'Mr. Stubbs', but now i appreciate so much more about it's
timeless appeal and cheery message. this is one of those Disney "feel
good" movies that always reminds me why i am such a "Disney groupie,
fanatic".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2904081/comments</url><from>from Kentucky</from><name>aimless-46</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Toby Tyler" (1960) is one of my earliest movie memories. In
combination with the film Whitman Publishing released a book of the
screenplay, which differed considerably from the source novel, managing
to lighten up the story.Most boys (at least in my class) were at first reluctant to see the
film because it's star, Kevin "Moochie" Corcoran, had pretty much
ruined the "Spin and Marty" serial when he was added to the cast after
the first season. We also had suffered through his "too cute" acting in
"Old Yeller". Rare is the child actor who was more irritating to his
contemporaries. But "Moochie" was just a hammy kid who did what the
director wanted; and fortunately the director of "Toby Tyler" dialed
down the standard "Moochie" cuteness for his first staring role. The film was the perfect escape for boys. Running away with the circus
was almost as good as getting to spend the whole summer riding horses
on the Triple "R" Ranch. Plus Toby's protector was Ben Cotter, our old
friend Sgt. Garcia from "Zorro". Mr. Stubbs the chimp is given the "too
cute" supporting role that "Moochie" normally played, which was most
likely an attempt to expand the target audience to include pre-teen
girls. It worked as the film entertained the entire family. The story involves Toby's efforts to move from peanut vendor to circus
performer. He eventually replaces a snotty boy in a bareback riding
act. His partner is Mademoiselle Jeanette (Barbara Beaird), my first
crush and most likely the reason that I remember the film so fondly. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2904081/comments</url><from>from Kentucky</from><name>aimless-46</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Toby Tyler" (1960) is one of my earliest movie memories. In
combination with the film Whitman Publishing released a book of the
screenplay, which differed considerably from the source novel, managing
to lighten up the story.Most boys (at least in my class) were at first reluctant to see the
film because it's star, Kevin "Moochie" Corcoran, had pretty much
ruined the "Spin and Marty" serial when he was added to the cast after
the first season. We also had suffered through his "too cute" acting in
"Old Yeller". Rare is the child actor who was more irritating to his
contemporaries. But "Moochie" was just a hammy kid who did what the
director wanted; and fortunately the director of "Toby Tyler" dialed
down the standard "Moochie" cuteness for his first staring role. The film was the perfect escape for boys. Running away with the circus
was almost as good as getting to spend the whole summer riding horses
on the Triple "R" Ranch. Plus Toby's protector was Ben Cotter, our old
friend Sgt. Garcia from "Zorro". Mr. Stubbs the chimp is given the "too
cute" supporting role that "Moochie" normally played, which was most
likely an attempt to expand the target audience to include pre-teen
girls. It worked as the film entertained the entire family. The story involves Toby's efforts to move from peanut vendor to circus
performer. He eventually replaces a snotty boy in a bareback riding
act. His partner is Mademoiselle Jeanette (Barbara Beaird), my first
crush and most likely the reason that I remember the film so fondly. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2904081/comments</url><from>from Kentucky</from><name>aimless-46</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>