<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Who Was That Lady?</original_title><alt_title>Qui était donc cette dame?</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>George Sidney</director><producer>Ansark-Sidney</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
In order to get back into the good graces with his wife with whom he has had a misunderstanding, a young chemistry professor concocts a wild story that he is an undercover FBI agent...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Tony Curtis</actor><actor>Dean Martin</actor><actor>Janet Leigh</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
"Who Was That Lady?" has no deep theme underlying the comedy, but
neither do many of the best comedies. This one begins as it ends, with
laughter. It's not belly laughs all the way through, but even the
laughless parts consist of plot mechanisms that are per se at least
amusing and serve as set-ups for later guffaws. There are moments when
you'll feel as if you're about to split with laughter.A summary is in order, although it will sound silly. An assistant
professor of chemistry at Columbia (Curtis, who lives with his wife,
Janet Leigh) in a pad no assistant professor would allow himself to
dream of, is caught being kissed by one of his students. Leigh enters
his office at the wrong moment, turns on her heel and walks out to go
home and begin packing. (All we see of this opening scene are the legs
of the three participants.)A desperate Curtis calls his old pal Martin, a writer of TV mysteries,
to help him figure out a way to keep his wife. Over drinks of lab
alcohol Martin comes up with something like, "I've got it. You know why
you were kissing that girl? Because you're a secret agent in the F.B.I.
and she's a Russian spy." Curtis believes this is the dumbest story
he's ever heard. But Martin pulls down the shades and locks the doors
and tells him that he, Martin, is himself an F.B.I. agent, having been
trained at Quantico while Curtis thought he was on duty in the Army.
Martin even pulls off his sock and shows him four dots tattooed on his
heel, the sure sign of a secret agent. "J. Edgar Hoover has five."
Curtis is convinced. And Martin begins tattooing his heel with a pen
and an electric fan. Queried by a still puzzled Curtis, Martin tells
him, "Me? In the F.B.I.? I couldn't even get to be an eagle scout, you
jackass." As far as the dots go, Martin doesn't know about Hoover but
everybody in his fraternity at Cornell has them. I'm going to avoid
going into this because it would spoil things. Suffice it to say that
in order to convince Leigh that Curtis really is an F.B.I. agent,
Martin goes to his prop department at CBS and has a fake F.B.I. ID card
printed and requisitions a pistol. The F.B.I. gets wind of the fake
card. So does the C.I.A. So do the Russians. In the end, a drugged
Curtis and Martin wake up in the basement of the Empire State Building,
believing they've been kidnapped and are aboard a Russian submarine. I
swear I'm not making this up. They decide to sacrifice their lives and
sink the submarine, which they attempt to do by hugging each other,
then turning every valve and faucet in sight, pulling levers, releasing
cascades of water, until they short out the electrical circuit of the
Empire State Building.I'm going to leave it there, I think. It hasn't appeared much on TV
lately, and that's the only reason I can think of why there aren't any
previous comments on this hilarious comedy. Really, folks, it doesn't
deserve to pass unseen. Everyone in it is at his/her comedic best. Even
James Whitmore manages to evoke a sympathetic smile or two. And Barbara
Nichols in a small but important role has never been funnier. In a
Chinese nightclub, Martin and Curtis promise her a job on TV, a
proposition which they argue should be discussed over the course of a
weekend at the shore. Nichols excuses herself and phones her agent:
"They're talking' about a job," she tells him, "but now they're
throwin' in Atlantic City." She and Joi Lansing are the prey in this
scene. "Get a load of the way these gals are assembled," Martin mutters
to Curtis. And adds: "They sing and dance -- like rabbits."It's not sophisticated but when you come right down to it comedy
doesn't really need elegance to be funny. Was Feydeau sophisticated?
Was Aristophanes? Was Daffy Duck?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When Janet Leigh interrupts assistant chemistry professor husband Tony
Curtis at work she finds him in the arms of a female student ,and promptly
sets about leaving him and petitioning for divorce .He turns in desperation
to his friend -a TV scriptwriter played by Dean Martin.Together they concoct
a story that he is an FBI agent whose romantic activity was all in the line
of duty .Somewhat implausibly she believes the far fetched tale and the
marriage is once again set fair.Or it would be but for unexpected
complications--the real FBI are not amused by the deception;Martin siezes
upon the deception as a cover for his serial womanising and some foreign
spies believe Curtis and Martin may have secrets they can use.It builds to a
frantic climax deep in the bowels of the Empire State Building,
The movie has pace and this is what sustains interest for the script is
pretty feeble -thin to the point of anorexia.The movie zips along briskly
enough to paper over the cracks in the script and while rarely laugh out
loud this is a genial and engaging comedy very much of its period in its
attitudes to women who are here confined to domesticity and looking
good.Strong performances all round with James Whitmore especially good as an
ulcer ridden FBI man and John mcIntyre as his superior.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I'd always wanted to check out this well-regarded if rarely-seen comedy
– for the record, some years back I missed out on its sole Italian TV
screening (that I know of). For Tony Curtis, it meant something of a
follow-up to the classic SOME LIKE IT HOT (1959) – where he's forced,
with his co-star (in this case, Dean Martin), to pass himself off as
something he isn't (an F.B.I. agent), leading to misunderstanding,
various complications and imminent danger.Similarly, a female is involved in the shenanigans (Curtis' on and
off-screen wife Janet Leigh) though, here, the whole ruse starts off
because of her: Chemistry Professor Curtis' fling with a female student
is discovered by his jealous wife, so he turns for help to his best pal
– TV writer Martin – who procures him with papers (and a gun) denoting
his Bureau affiliations; Leigh is finally convinced of this and, soon
after, is contacted by a real F.B.I. operative (James Whitmore) who
uses her to keep track of just what Curtis and Martin are up to! One of the highlights of the film is the extended yet splendid incident
in a restaurant: Leigh accepts Curtis' excuse to go on the town with
Martin, believing it to be another federal job – but, in her
over-eagerness to help, effectively blows his cover…which then lands
the F.B.I. itself in hot water! The biggest trouble, however, is that
enemy agents take the two men to be the real deal and kidnap them (and
Leigh) in order to extract vital information they believe Curtis is in
possession of! The aftermath of this sequence is again hilarious as,
dazed by the drug he's been given, Curtis thinks they've been taken to
a Russian sub and persuades Martin to flood it…but it transpires that
they're in the basement of the Empire State Building! The script (adapted by Norman Krasna – who also produced – from his own
play) balances witty dialogue with inspired zany situations, which are
then delightfully put across by an excellent cast. Both male stars, in
fact, were already adept at this type of thing (crooner Martin also
sings the title tune), but Leigh surprisingly proves a fine comedienne
in her own right: it's a pity that her marriage to Curtis was crumbling
by this time which is doubly ironic given the film's plot, but they
were professional enough not to let the real cracks show in their
performances.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A trio of major stars, close to their peak of fame at the time, help to
enliven this overdrawn farce based on a moderately successful Broadway
play. Curtis is a university scientist who is canoodling with a female
student when his wife Leigh walks in and catches him. In no time flat,
she is packing for Reno to get a divorce and orders him out of the
house by 7:00pm. Curtis's pal Martin, a writer for CBS television,
helps to concoct a scheme designed to fool Leigh into calling off the
split. He aids Curtis in convincing Leigh that they are FBI agents and
that the girl being smooched was just a small part of a much bigger
plan. After some deliberation, Leigh falls for the story, but thanks to
a loose end from the props department at CBS, the real FBI gets
involved and things become more and more convoluted and complicated
from there. Curtis is appropriately manic and desperate as he tries to
inject a sense of imperativeness to the silly and unrealistic plot.
Playing a cheating husband couldn't have been too great a stretch for
him as he admitted to fooling around on Leigh many times during their
real life marriage and, in fact, would leave her for a younger girl
only two years after this. Martin appears to be investing his role with
a little more conviction than he would later in his Matt Helm series
and tries to add texture to his performance (or is he just trying to
steal focus?) by fiddling often with props. He's mostly second fiddle
to Curtis, but does get to toss out a few zesty lines now and then.
Leigh (saddled with an unflatteringly tousled hairdo) overacts with
abandon in order to keep up with the guys' zaniness. She cuts a nice
figure in her black cocktail dress, but has a pretty dense role to
play. Fortunately for her, "Psycho" would come out the same year as
this and immortalize her forever in a more flattering way. Some strong
supporting players, notably Whitmore as a beleaguered FBI agent and
Nichols and Lansing as a couple of bottle-blonde pickups, give their
all in an effort to liven up the film. Whitmore very wisely underplays
his role in contrast to the more broadly acted ones. Unfortunately, the
play was dated before too long after its run and the film is badly
dated now. The stage origins show through frequently despite attempts
to move the action around. Curtis's apartment is interestingly laid
out, though very artificial in nature. This was made at a time when the
big trend was to involve the Russians (see also Leigh's version of
"Bye, Bye Birdie") or to throw in a big, sloppy spectacle such as a pie
fight or an overflowing washing machine. Here, the Russians make their
obligatory appearance and the unlikely flooding of a New York City
landmark accents the climax. It wouldn't be so bad if the script didn't
take so long to set things up and dwell on so many unnecessary details
along the way, but it would hardly matter because the whole enterprise
is both inane and distasteful in any case. There's an odd layer of
(unintentional?) homoeroticism dispersed throughout as well, with
Curtis and Martin contorting their way through the machinations of the
plot and Curtis nearly kissing a male Soviet agent. What it's got are
three charismatic stars trying their best and some clean black and
white photography, but what it's lacking is a compelling premise that
is carried out proficiently.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3887838/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jla16</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
"Who was That Lady" is an amazingly creative comedy.Tony Curtis is a
loving husband with a beautiful but very jealous wife.His best friend
Dean Martin is hysterical! These two men plot to relieve Tony's wife
Janet Leigh of her jealous suspicions with the most outrageous
fabrications ever invented. I don't want to give away all the fun, but
you have to see the number of schemes Dean Martin comes up with and she
continually is more proud of her husband, an innocent professor,who was
seen by his wife being kissed by a female as she leaves class.Janet
Leigh wants to know who was that lady kissing you and why,she then
decides to just leave him.So he goes to his womanizing buddy for
advise. He's desperate therefore takes some crazy idea and tells her
he's doing work undercover for the govt..Some real spy's over hear and
trouble ensues.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6814110/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>hondo551</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I was always a Dino fan, still am all these years later, and this film
makes me wish he and Tony Curtis had made a couple more of these in the
60s. Conventional wisdom says the real talent in Martin and Lewis was
Jerry, and the real talent in Some Like It Hot is Jack Lemmon and not
Tony Curtis, but when these two straight men, or at least straighter
men, get together, this story gets as wacky as any Hope and Crosby,
Martin and Lewis, or Abbott and Costello vehicle. Both guys can be as
charming as always and as goofy and funny as their other partners, with
Dino running away with a little more of the comedy than Tony. This one
is strictly a guy flick, a boy's club guilty pleasure about two friends
conspiring to repair a marriage with a made up story of FBI agents and
Russian spies and beautiful women, and just has to be funny, especially
when the real FBI, James Whitmore and John McIntire, and the real KGB,
Simon Oakland and Larry Storch, get wind of it and turn up. Throw in
the ever lovely Janet Leigh as Tony's wife, and the pre-silicone/saline
implant miracles of Barbara Nichols and Joi Lansing as two blond bimbos
Dino wants help schmoozing, and this becomes every post-pubescent boys
dream come true comedy of the 60s. It looks like so much fun that you
have to believe these people weren't even working when they made it.
And just when you think they can't go any farther or get more
ridiculous, they set off to "sink" the Empire State Building. These
guys could have gotten Kong down without a shot! Without apologies to
anyone, I just loved this one!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I remember seeing this film around the time it first came out and
looking at it again today, I had forgotten how wildly funny it was. In
fact listening to my record collection, the thing I had remembered most
about Who Was That Lady? was the very good title song that Dean Martin
sung and had a record of which sold a few platters back in the day.But the film itself is a hilarious Cold War spy farce. It's based on a
Norman Krasna play that ran for 208 performances on Broadway in 1958
with the slightly elongated title of Who Was That Lady I Saw You With.
On Broadway the roles played by Tony Curtis, Janet Leigh, and Dean
Martin were done by Peter Lind Hayes, Mary Healy, and Ray Walston.It all begins when chemistry professor at Columbia University Tony
Curtis is caught by wife Janet Leigh in fast embrace with a foreign
exchange student. She's back to their apartment and packing her bags
for Reno. Curtis who really loves his wife is in a terrible state, what
to do?Depending on how you look at it, long time pal Dean Martin is eager to
help. He's a television writer for CBS and he's good with figuring out
plot explanations. Mainly because Curtis is convinced Leigh just won't
believe that the foreign exchange student was kissing him in gratitude. So what do these two knuckleheads conceive? That Curtis was kissing the
girl in the line of duty because he's an undercover agent for the FBI.
In fact they get an FBI card printed up and a gun from the prop
department at CBS. And to further 'aid' the story, Martin gets Curtis
to get four dots tattooed on his heel as he did back in his fraternity
days. Isn't that what all FBI agents have.But when Leigh buys the story all too well and the printer goes to the
real FBI when the card doesn't show up on the CBS program as Martin
said it would, the fun really starts. Even a pair of chuckleheaded
Russian agents played by Simon Oakland and Larry Storch actually
believe Curtis is an FBI man working on a super secret project at
Columbia.The biggest change from stage to screen had to be Dean Martin for Ray
Walston. Certainly Dean is far more believable as the wolfish
television writer, but there are some outrageous comedy bits that
Martin has that I could definitely see Ray Walston doing on stage.This was the last screen pairing of Tony Curtis and Janet Leigh, within
three years a Hollywood storybook marriage would be at an end. Janet
has her innings in this film also especially in the restaurant tailing
her husband and Martin who has set him up on a double date with the
Coogle Sisters, a pair of foreign agents from Brooklyn. All I can say
there is that there is no doubt that these two had to contain four
weapons of mass destruction in the persons of Joi Lansing and Barbara
Nichols.A lot of the problem is caused by FBI agent James Whitmore who after
interviewing Leigh first, realized what was going on, but decided to
hold off until he could get Curtis alone. Whitmore plays the part as a
good foil for Leigh's ingenuousness. Of course Whitmore has to answer
to his field office boss John McIntire who in turn has to answer to you
know who in Washington.It all ends quite uproariously in the basement of the Empire State
Building when Curtis and Martin think they're on a submarine and
proceed to try and 'sink' it. Got to be seen to be believed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3619805/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn, NY</from><name>STEVEN DANKO (chesslover55@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This film has to be one of the very best romantic comedies ever made.
It works well on so many levels and leaves the viewer with a good
feeling at the end. I remember seeing it numerous times when it was
released in the year 1960. This is a real feel-good movie, made in a
more innocent time before the antiwar protests and campus revolts which
characterized the latter years of that decade. This movie stays with
you long after you see it. It was just released on DVD, 47 years after
it came out. I have always had fond and wonderful memories of this
film. Watching it tonight just before sitting down to write this review
was like seeing an old friend whom you haven't seen for decades. All
those warm feelings and fond remembrances just came flooding right back
and it's like you're 10 years old again. The storyline is simple and
straightforward. TONY CURTIS plays David Wilson, an assistant professor
of chemistry at Columbia University. His wife Ann(JANET LEIGH) decides
to surprise him by dropping in unexpectedly and catches him in a
liplock with a female co-ed who initiated it. She runs out, jumps in a
cab and angrily announces that she's divorcing him and he'll be out of
their apartment that evening. Panic-stricken, David calls his old
friend Mike Haney(DEAN MARTIN), a mystery writer for the CBS television
network. David pleads with him to come up with a good excuse that he
could use with Ann to explain away what happened. Over tall drinks of
90-proof chemistry lab hootch, Mike comes up with an explanation- and
it's a doozy. He tells David that he was kissing her in the performance
of his duty- as an undercover agent for the FBI! David thinks that Mike
is nuts and tells him that Ann would never buy such a ridiculous tale.
But Mike convinces him that it would work and takes him to the prop
department at CBS where he orders up an authentic looking FBI
identification card and a police revolver that ostensibly will be used
on his show. They confront Ann at the apartment that evening and go
through a whole routine to convince her that her hubby is a G-man.
Skeptical at first, she winds up buying it after seeing the card and
the gun. A comedy of errors ensues when the FBI gets involved after the
props are not used on the show and when DEAN MARTIN decides to
capitalize on the situation by suckering David into going on a
double-date with two platinum blonde bombshells played by BARBARA
NICHOLS and JOI LANSING, all in the line of duty, of course. David and
Ann wind up on the six o'clock news when Ann goes to the Chinese
restaurant with a real FBI Agent(JAMES WHITMORE) to give David "his"
gun which he forgot to take with him. Misinterpreting what she
overhears in the powder room, Ann thinks the two blondes plan on
killing her husband and Mike! She attempts to stop them at gunpoint and
in the ensuing struggle for the revolver, the gun goes off and Agent
Powell takes a bullet in the arm. David is rendered unconscious by a
flowerpot falling off a window ledge that lands on his head. A mobile
television news crew arrives and Ann, cradling her unconscious husband
in her arms, tells the reporter that he works for the FBI and the two
blondes are enemy agents! The next day the newspapers have blaring
headlines about FBI undercover agents capturing Soviet spies in Times
Square! The plot thickens when government wiretaps reveal that actual
Russian agents want to get their hands on David because he knows the
names of fellow scientists at Columbia University who are conducting
research on germ warfare and radioactivity. Posing as FBI Agents, the
Russians(LARRY STORCH and SIMON OAKLAND) sucker David, Ann and Mike to
the Empire State Building for a photo shoot by the Bureau's Public
Relations Division. The FBI sets up a stakeout but the Russians succeed
in isolating the trio in an elevator and administering sodium pentothal
to make David talk while using chloroform on Ann. This is one of the
funniest sequences in the film. David doesn't reveal anything and
STORCH tells him if he doesn't cooperate, they'll take his wife and put
her on a submarine and he'll never see her again! When the Russians
realize that the pentothal is starting to wear off and the FBI is hot
on their heels, they abandon the three in the building's basement. When
his wife regains consciousness, David, still coming off the pentothal,
tells her he's going to jail for 180 years because it's against the law
to have a fake FBI card. Then he asks her if she'll wait for him! When
she asks him about the two platinum blondes, he tells her "They sing
and dance- like rabbits." Angered, she runs out of the basement. Mike
had been knocked out and when he and David "wake up", David, seeing
turn valves, levers and utility pipes, thinks they're on board a
Russian submarine! They decide to sink it by opening all the valves and
pulling all the levers. As the basement floods with water, it shorts
out the building's electrical system, causing the even-numbered floors
to boil over and the odd-numbered floors to freeze! The film ends on a
happy note as firemen break in to halt the flooding, the Russian spies
are captured, and Ann, now knowing the whole truth of what happened,
tells her husband, "Come on home, my darling." The last scene is a shot
of Manhattan taken from Queens, showing a mushroom cloud of steam
rising from the top of the Empire State Building! This is one of my
all-time favorites and I give it a 10 out of 10. Don't miss this one.
It's an absolute gem!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4067661/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>DKOSTY</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
While Tony Curtis &amp; Janet Leigh are considered the stars of this film,
Dean Martin is practically a co-star in this Curtis movie doing a lot
of the heavy lifting like Jack Lemmon often does in Curtis movies. The
film starts with Curtis wife (Leigh) catching him (a college professor)
kissing a college coed. From here, comes Dean Martin playing a TV
script writer, trying to write Curtis back into his marriage to Leigh
before she fly to Reno for a quickie divorce.The cover story is that Curtis is an FBI agent kissing the young girl
on assignment. Then it gets complicated when James Whitmore (a real FBI
agent) becomes interested in what Curtis &amp; Martin are pulling over.
This is screwball comedy done by the writer of Alfred Hitcock's only
real screwball comedy (Mr &amp; Mrs. Smith).What is most interesting is that the premise of the film hasn't
changed. Today, if you catch your mate kissing (or doing) somebody
else, you need an explanation or else you dump them. Usually the
dumping is still the first instinct. In the case of this film, Leigh
catching Curtis might have predicted the near future as 2 years later,
they would divorce.There are at least 2 Martin songs &amp; a special cameo by Jack Benny in
this one. An interesting effort though the FBI line does wear a little
thin about halfway through. Still, it is a nice diversion &amp; the
director has previous experience in this type of movie, so the pace &amp;
everything feel right here.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5268621/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>schuelke-1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The movie defines the word "farce."Tony Curtis and Dean Martin are good performers, but the characters
they play are pathetic. The FBI "thing" gets tiresome. Janet Leigh
looks great, as usual. There are few really funny lines throughout the
movie, but the viewer can easily get distracted during "dead zones" of
absurd planning and plotting.The highlight of this movie occurs when the Coogle sisters (Barbara
Nichols and Joi Lansing) enter the restaurant. The movie is worth
watching if only for this one memorable and provocative scene.I have rated this movie a 6, but I almost gave it a 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5268621/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>schuelke-1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The movie defines the word "farce."Tony Curtis and Dean Martin are good performers, but the characters
they play are pathetic. The FBI "thing" gets tiresome. Janet Leigh
looks great, as usual. There are few really funny lines throughout the
movie, but the viewer can easily get distracted during "dead zones" of
absurd planning and plotting.The highlight of this movie occurs when the Coogle sisters (Barbara
Nichols and Joi Lansing) enter the restaurant. The movie is worth
watching if only for this one memorable and provocative scene.I have rated this movie a 6, but I almost gave it a 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5268621/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>schuelke-1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/whowasthatlady.htm /m/who-was-that-lady/comments.php?reviewid=1934543</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>It stretches more comedy than one could expect from such thin material, and passes as a so-so comedy vehicle for the appealing stars.</comment></review></movie>