<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Savage Eye</original_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Ben Maddow</director><producer>City Film Corporation</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
This drama takes the form of a story told using documentary material as an intrinsic part of the narrative...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Barbara Baxley</actor><actor>Gary Merrill</actor><actor>Herschel Bernardi</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0404139/comments</url><from>from Herndon, VA</from><name>taro-4</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Anyone who thinks of the 1950s as a plastic people sort of
place
must see this marvelous film. Cast as a documentary about a woman the
first
year after her divorce, it is really a travelogue through the underside
the
1950s, the part the Beaver Cleavers didn't want to see. In a deeper sense,
it touched on the universal sorrows of a person cast loose from her
contact
with people (something I understand well as I go through my own divorce).
It
shows graphically that there is nothing sadder than a human being cast out
of her or his group. So it's a tale specific to the late 1950s, but
simultaneously universal in its assessment of the human
condition.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0846728/comments</url><from>from Houston, TX</from><name>rollo_tomaso (rollo_tomaso@excite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

One of cinematographer Haskell Wexler's earliest efforts that unabashedly
reflects the influence of Edward Hopper and depressing street scenes.
Barbara Baxley's heartfelt "everywoman" performance is nothing short of
amazing.  The supporting cast, led by Herschel Bernardi, is also
magnificent.  THe funny thing about this chronolgue of American
hopelessness
is that it is much better known in the European Art House circuit than
here
among the US indy crowd.
It definitely should get more exposure; I give it 10 out of
10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0055812/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, California</from><name>Joel Rane</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

That sounds like a heady comment, "best film about LA street life ever
made," but I stick by it.  Encapsulated in the rather thin plot, about a
divorcee wandering the city, this is really a documentary on Los Angeles
in
1959, and an amazing one at that.  No one who lives here should feel they
really know what it was like until they see this film, which includes
footage of a New Year's celebration, the roller derby, a wrestling match,
a
strip club, and yes, the Second Street Tunnel again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur18385528/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>progenitor-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I would either give this movie 1 or 10. It's stunning relevance to
modern day life goes far beyond that of the divorcée. This contains
amazing truths about humanity - too long denied by our face-value
culture. It's relevance can be denied simply because of the issues it
confronts - life, superficiality, death and everything in between. It's
moments of striking ambiance are empty and fulfilling at the same time.
Don't get me wrong - I hate this movie - but only because it explains a
deeper truth that might be better off hidden if anything else. The
absence of futility abounds in this epic, and I suggest you judge for
yourself and make your remarks known.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0438548/comments</url><from>from Sheffield, England</from><name>Dave Godin (Dave G)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

An amazing roller-coaster ride through the full range of human emotions,
THE
SAVAGE EYE is just as remarkable today as when it was first made, and the
title is so apt and pertinent. Didactic and profound, it comes across
almost
as a warning or an alert to human society showing us the high price paid
by
our psyches for the "joys" of civilisation. The things we really need we
ignore and despise, and instead pursue an empty materialism that leaves
our
"souls" impoverished and starved; not because we choose to do so, but
because we mindlessly drift along with whatever the dominant ideology of
the
day tells us we should want. Brilliantly assembled and conceived, it is
one
of those films that once seen will linger deep in your subconscious
forever.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0852197/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>wilbrifar</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This film features wonderful documentary footage of Los Angeles circa
1959, and is a valuable artifact for that reason alone. Unfortunately,
the woeful attempt to form the footage into a narrative featuring
actress Barbara Baxley as a lonely woman wandering the city and sharing
insufferably pretentious voice-over with Gary Merrill (pompously billed
as "The Poet") make the film a chore to endure.I enjoy seeing this kind of footage, showing me how a city I love
looked in another age, but the grandstanding voice-over is a deal
breaker. Except for the disturbing faith-healer sequence, which is the
only portion of the film to use sync sound, this is a movie best
enjoyed with the volume turned down and some good music playing, maybe
a little jazz from the era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0852197/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>wilbrifar</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This film features wonderful documentary footage of Los Angeles circa
1959, and is a valuable artifact for that reason alone. Unfortunately,
the woeful attempt to form the footage into a narrative featuring
actress Barbara Baxley as a lonely woman wandering the city and sharing
insufferably pretentious voice-over with Gary Merrill (pompously billed
as "The Poet") make the film a chore to endure.I enjoy seeing this kind of footage, showing me how a city I love
looked in another age, but the grandstanding voice-over is a deal
breaker. Except for the disturbing faith-healer sequence, which is the
only portion of the film to use sync sound, this is a movie best
enjoyed with the volume turned down and some good music playing, maybe
a little jazz from the era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0852197/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>wilbrifar</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kelly-vance/</url><url>http://www.eastbayexpress.com/eastbay/angel-dust/Content?oid=1074301 /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1883117</url><name>Kelly Vance</name><from>East Bay Express</from></reviewer><comment>A sorrowful and beautiful film, the kind you never see from mainstream Tinseltown studios, then or now.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dan-lybarger/</url><url>http://efilmcritic.com/review.php?movie=19993&amp;reviewer=382 /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1855989</url><name>Dan Lybarger</name><from>eFilmCritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Kent Mackenzie's 1961 movie 'The Exiles' was so revolutionary that even now it seems gutsy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/exiles.htm /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1846176</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>It's an essential film that hardly anyone saw upon its release in 1961.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nora-lee-mandel/</url><url>http://www.film-forward.com/theexiles.html /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1785028</url><name>Nora Lee Mandel</name><from>Film-Forward.com</from></reviewer><rating>
9/10
					</rating><comment>For its beautiful black-and-white aesthetics, docudrama realism, and, sadly, still fresh portrait of off-reservation Native Americans, an excellent rediscovery</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/shawn-levy/</url><url>http://blog.oregonlive.com/madaboutmovies/2008/12/movie_review_low_on_the_hill_i.html /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1784924</url><name>Shawn Levy</name><from>Oregonian</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>The amateur actors, many of whom in reality met sad ends on those same streets, are utterly convincing. You have the sense again and again that you've unearthed a time capsule -- a sensation that cinema alone of all the arts can impart.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-phillips-11845/</url><url>http://www.chicagotribune.com/entertainment/movies/chi-exiles-review-1121nov21,0,2546996.story /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1781900</url><name>Michael Phillips</name><from>Chicago Tribune</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>The Exiles ... presents one boozy night in the lives of Homer, Cliff, Tommy and Yvonne, from a convertible joy ride through the Third Street Tunnel, to an early-morning powwow.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/andy-klein/</url><url>/m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1780099</url><name>Andy Klein</name><from>Los Angeles CityBeat</from></reviewer><comment>Mackenzie imposes no obvious attitude or mediating outsider's perspective on the material; he just presents it to us, a snapshot of an otherwise unknown culture, with details specific to its time and place.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/wesley-morris/</url><url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=12586 /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1767703</url><name>Wesley Morris</name><from>Boston Globe</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>Kent Mackenzie's magnificent, long-undistributed, unclassifiable first feature, The Exiles, stands as a rare consideration of the inner and outer lives of American Indians in a big American city.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-villarreal/</url><url>http://www.aznightbuzz.com/stories/262356.php /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1762750</url><name>Phil Villarreal</name><from>Arizona Daily Star</from></reviewer><rating>
2/4
					</rating><comment>Just because a movie was lost and found doesn't mean it's worth your $8.75.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lisa-kennedy/</url><url>http://www.denverpost.com/movies/ci_10671350 /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1762102</url><name>Lisa Kennedy</name><from>Denver Post</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>Rife with astonishing black-and-white images of an unknown L.A. and clashing sounds of bars, cinemas and poker games, The Exiles is one of those movies that functions as both artifact and fresh discovery.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/27123_EXILES /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1762101</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>Its moving portraiture is refreshingly free of cliches and moralizing platitudes, and the high-contrast black-and-white photography and dense, highly creative sound track are equally impressive.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeff-vice/</url><url>http://www.deseretnews.com/article/700004983/The-Exiles.html /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1757093</url><name>Jeff Vice</name><from>Deseret News, Salt Lake City</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>The Exiles is a vivid portrait of Native American culture. Even more astonishing is the fact the movie is more than 40 years old.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kenneth-turan/</url><url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-exiles15-2008aug15,0,5170494.story /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1751065</url><name>Kenneth Turan</name><from>Los Angeles Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>A cinéma vérité look at the rootless Native American community that once upon a time lived in Bunker Hill and hung out in downtown bars such as Club Ritz, this Kent Mackenzie film is a brooding picture of a darkly beautiful, long-gone Los Angeles.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/2008/exiles.shtml /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1745336</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>The movie has an undeniable emotional punch and its historical place in cinema is undisputable (there's still nothing else quite like it).</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/roger-ebert/</url><url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20080717/REVIEWS/900668598 /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1744067</url><name>Roger Ebert</name><from>Chicago Sun-Times</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>It is like cracking open a time capsule.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/owen-gleiberman/</url><url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20213124,00.html /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1742772</url><name>Owen Gleiberman</name><from>Entertainment Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>A ghostly and startling tale of Native Americans in Los Angeles -- a fusion of documentary and fiction -- in the late '50s. Never previously released, it's a revelation.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kam-williams/</url><url>http://www.eurweb.com/story/eur45209.cfm /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1742742</url><name>Kam Williams</name><from>EURWeb</from></reviewer><rating>
1/4
					</rating><comment>Best if approached as a nostalgic curiosity shot a half century ago rather than as a conventional flick offering a satisfying cinematic experience.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/chris-barsanti/</url><url>http://www.filmjournal.com/filmjournal/reviews/article_display.jsp?vnu_content_id=1003826773 /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1741940</url><name>Chris Barsanti</name><from>Film Journal International</from></reviewer><comment>...one of the great under-seen cinema gems of the 1960s.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-edelstein/</url><url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/48514/ /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1741176</url><name>David Edelstein</name><from>New York Magazine</from></reviewer><comment>You can only brood on the near half-century since The Exiles was shot -- and be grateful that someone went to that place and captured it all.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>http://filmcritic1963.typepad.com/capsules/2008/07/the-exiles.html /m/10010099-exiles/comments.php?reviewid=1740965</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>Director Brent MacKenzie's black-and-white documentary/narrative genre blender about urbanized Native Americans in 1961 Los Angeles is a cold glass of cinematic water drawn from the same well as Joseph Strick's "The Savage Eye" (1960).</comment></review></movie>