<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Teseo contro il minotauro</original_title><alt_title>Thésée et le minotaure</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Silvio Amadio</director><producer>Gino Mordini</producer><producer>Giorgio Agliani Cinematografica</producer><producer>Illiria Film</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
In ancient Crete, a monster called the Minotaur (half bull, half man) can only be satisfied by virgin sacrifices...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Bob Mathias</actor><actor>Rosanna Schiaffino</actor><actor>Alberto Lupo</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
King of Crete named Minos(Carlo Tamberlani) has two daughters, one good
name Ariadna and one evil named Fedra(Rosanna Schiaffino in double
role). Fedra orders Sciron(Alberto Lupo) to kill Ariadna, but the
murder fails thanks Teseo, prince of Athens, and Demetrio(Rick
Battaglia). Freda rules over Crete and supported by Scirion wage war
Athens. Athenians are defeated and obligated tribute of fourteen maids
for feed minotaur, a horrible monster , part human and part bull.
Meanwhile Teseo taking on Freda and Sciron , when Ariadna into cave of
monster using the famous thread.This Sword and Sandals movie packs adventures, fights, mythology,
impressive battles, spectacular scenarios and is quite amusing. The
film confronts Greek culture as pacific, civilized,luxurious and Crete
or Minoic culture as cruel, brutal and worshipping Gods with human
sacrifices. However, from discovery Crete by archaeologist Evans is
considered Crete a very developed civilization, above average the
countries of that time. In fact, the palace of Knosos in Crete
-partially reflected on the movie- was the greatest and luxurious at
the time. Furthermore, the picture mingles wrongly the Crete setting
from 1600 B.C. with Greeks dressed like V century. The film is starred
by Bob Mathias, an US athlete, twice world champion decathlon and
justifying his fans, he plays a scenes about his abilities, along with
another starring, Rick Battaglia. The pic contains evocative
cinematography by Giordani and atmospheric musical score by Carlo
Rustichelli accompanying the usual dancing choreography. The motion
picture is well directed by Silvio Amadio who directed a Peplum set in
Babylone titled ¨Seven thunderbolts¨. Rating: Acceptable and passable.
The film will like to muscle-men sub-genre buffs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0291062/comments</url><from>from Minneapolis</from><name>dinky-4</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

The legend of Theseus finding his way through the Cretan maze in order to
battle the Minotaur and rescue Ariadne is one of the great tales in Greek
mythology. Alas, this version takes the tale and dilutes it into the
standard "sword and sandal" plot. You know how it goes. The
coldly-beautiful
but evil queen lusts after the handsome, muscular hero. He already has a
girlfriend and is a foe of tyranny and so spurns the queen. She's
outraged,
has the girlfriend imprisoned, and subjects the hero to a torturous trial.
He triumphs, frees the girlfriend, and overthrows the tyrant. Grateful
citizens cheer the happy couple. The End.Steve Reeves might have been able to lift this mixture to a higher level
but
in his place we have ex-Olympics champion, Bob Mathias. Mathias is an
affable sort and he's given an opportunity to show off his athletic
prowess
by engaging in a display of javelin throwing, pole vaulting, and discus
throwing. He also looks pretty good with his shirt off, though not quite
as
good as you'd hope and he seems a bit self-conscious about baring his
chest.
On a more troubling note, however, his personality is bland, his acting
ability no more than passable, and he lacks the swaggering sexuality
needed
to give his character that necessary edge.Rosanna Schiaffino gets to play the evil queen as well as her virtuous
twin
sister. She's good at being bad but bad at being good. As for the
Minotaur,
traditionally represented with the head of a bull, it's poorly depicted
here
as a stunt-man dressed in sort of a King Kong suit, and the climatic
battle
between Theseus and the Minotaur doesn't deliver the expected thrills.
Also,
little is made of the strand of yarn which leads Theseus out of the maze,
and the Minoan culture is only vaguely hinted at in the sets and costumes.And once again, the movie bungles the torture scene. Theseus winds up in
the
queen's torture chamber, chained to a wall, but he's modestly allowed to
keep on the top of his tunic! So when the torturer approaches with the
red-hot iron, he must reach out and make a discreet rip in the hero's
shirt
in order to expose a bit of bare flesh next to the hero's left nipple.
Hey,
this is a "sword and sandal" movie featuring a muscular actor as its star.
Why not rip that shirt all the way off and put the hero's sweaty torso on
proper display?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Fanciful rendition of one of the most famous Greek myths.To write that
the movie takes liberties with the tale is to state the obvious:first
of all,Phaedra and Ariadne are twin sisters both played by Italian
beauty(and an usual sword and sandal heroine of the era)Rosanna
Schiaffino : the former is the villain ,a wicked princess ,whereas the
latter is an innocent clueless good girl .Theseus is still the king of
Athenes ' son but his father won't throw himself into the sea which
bears his name (Aegean sea);and if my memory serves me well,he marries
Phaedra after abandoning her sister on an island.People who are eagerly waiting for the Minotaur will be disappointed
for the monster looks like King Kong and would not scare a four -year-
old .They did include Ariadne's thread and she is devoted enough to go
and meet him in the labyrinth.Closer to Robert Siomak's "Cobra woman" than to Greek tales.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16680000/comments</url><from>from United</from><name>bens_dream</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This opera was played on 7 June 2008, it is bad. I watched it with my
family and we laughed at it, calling it "compulsive viewing", due to it
being laughably bad... Do not watch this, I will never get that hour of
my life back. Every "song" sounds the same, and when the writers cannot
find anything that works, they chuck in a bit of Greek. If you like
"opera", do not watch this. If you don't like "opera", don't watch
this. Only watch this if you want something to laugh at. Terrible. The
orchestra managed to chuck in every note that exists, and then some.
Get a book, like Macbeth, and just sing the words to it in an
"operatic" style, and you will get what The Minotaur sounds like. Don't
let anyone convince you that it is too sophisticated for you to
understand. IT IS STUCK UP TOSH!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16680000/comments</url><from>from United</from><name>bens_dream</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This opera was played on 7 June 2008, it is bad. I watched it with my
family and we laughed at it, calling it "compulsive viewing", due to it
being laughably bad... Do not watch this, I will never get that hour of
my life back. Every "song" sounds the same, and when the writers cannot
find anything that works, they chuck in a bit of Greek. If you like
"opera", do not watch this. If you don't like "opera", don't watch
this. Only watch this if you want something to laugh at. Terrible. The
orchestra managed to chuck in every note that exists, and then some.
Get a book, like Macbeth, and just sing the words to it in an
"operatic" style, and you will get what The Minotaur sounds like. Don't
let anyone convince you that it is too sophisticated for you to
understand. IT IS STUCK UP TOSH!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16680000/comments</url><from>from United</from><name>bens_dream</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>