<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Midnight Lace</original_title><alt_title>Piège à minuit</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>David Miller</director><producer>Arwin Productions</producer><producer>Universal International Pictures (UI)</producer><genre>Thriller</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><synopsis>
In London, a newly-wed American woman's sanity comes into question, when she claims to be the victim of a stalker.
</synopsis><actor>Doris Day</actor><actor>Rex Harrison</actor><actor>John Gavin</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1388629/comments</url><from>from West Virginia</from><name>Bucs1960</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

If that telephone voice doesn't give you the creeps, you are one tough
cookie! Don't be fooled because this film stars Doris Day, noted for her
frothy, professional virgin roles in movies with Rock Hudson, et al.  This
is another Ms. Day, although the movie showcases her in some great clothes. 
Driven to the brink of insanity by anonymous threatening phone calls which
nobody believes, she plays it to the hilt.  The elevator scene is especially
gripping.  John Gavin is totally miscast and is bland, as usual.  The rest
of the cast is top drawer....Rex Harrison, suave and sophisticated....Myrna
Loy, as the worldly aunt, is wonderful.....and the greatest of English
support players, John Williams, repeating his inspector role from Dial M for
Murder.  In a small part is Anthony Dawson, the perfect villain,also from
Dial M for Murder. Herbert Marshall and Richard Ney are good in small roles.
This looks and feels like a Hitchcock picture.  You may guess the ending but
it is worth the watch to see Doris Day give her all.  Besides, everybody
likes a good thriller and this fits the bill! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0463200/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
American Kit Preston (Doris Day) lives in London with husband Anthony
(Rex Harrison). She starts being stalked and getting phone calls by a
man saying he's going to kill her. But nobody else is around when he
calls. Is he real or is she going crazy? A VERY loose remake of "Gaslight". The film is far-fetched (especially
at the end) and full of obvious red herrings. Also there were one or
two plot threads never adequately explained at the end. Still, this was
entertaining. It's very glossy with breath-taking sets and 17 costume
changes (!!!) by Day--but this IS a Ross Hunter movie (he did
"Imitation of Life" which had the same kind of treatment). So, even
when the movie slows down there's always something to look at.There's mostly solid acting by the entire cast. Harrison was just so-so
as the husband but everybody else was fine. John Gavin pops up a few
times just being incredibly handsome but actually isn't that bad. Myrna
Loy steals the show as Aunt Bea in every scene she's in--and check out
the incredibly ugly yellow hat with green sash she wears at one point!
Best of all is Day. You might think she would be terrible in a straight
dramatic role but she's actually quite good. Her terror at what's
happening is totally believable and there's an incredible scene where
she has a complete nervous breakdown. She hated making this film
because it emotionally wore her down--she vowed never again to do a
thriller. That's too bad--she was so good here.So it's not believable but is still worth watching. Recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17114164/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>claudiaeilcinema</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I've loved Doris Day in her most famous comedy roles, I loved her
"Calamity Jane" and always though she gave real depth to her American
wife and mother in "The Man Who Knew Too Much" But Doris in "Midnight
Lace" is something else. The suspension of disbelief that the film
expects from its audience is totally achievable because of her. She
goes through it for real and manages to involve us and to actually care
for this rich American lady. Her anguish rings true and that's all we
need to get involved. There is not a single moment within the
preposterous plot in which we catch her acting, that in itself lifts
this yarn to unexpected levels. Terrific fun. Rex Harrison plays
Professor Higgin's brother with the same kind of aplomb. Myrna Loy is a
hoot. John Gavin , beautifully wooden as usual, Roddy McDowell is a
creepy delight and Hermione Baddely creates something with her seconds
on the screen. Thank you Doris for a surprising thrilling fun ride.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2030420/comments</url><from/><name>perfectbond</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

As macabre as it sounds, I really enjoyed seeing Doris Day (The Man Who Knew
Too Much) get terrorized. She was so convincing in this role especially when
she provided a tour de force in acting during that scene where she finally
breaks down. I can't believe other commentators were not as moved by this as
I was. Rex Harrison (The Ghost and Mrs. Muir, Cleopatra, My Fair Lady) is
also very good in this role though I don't think he is challenged very much
here. John Williams is once again the diligent inspector as he was in the
two Alfred Hitchcock hits Dial M For Murder and To Catch a Thief, both of
which coincidentally starred Grace Kelly. The great Roddy McDowell (Planet
of the Apes) is here just as a red herring but he is welcome nonetheless.
All in all a good thriller, 8/10.   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0516422/comments</url><from>from Santa Maria, CA</from><name> (willrams@earthlink.net)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I haven't seen this since 1960 and it was on AMC TV today.  I still think
it
is one of the most exciting and well written mysteries ever.  A
who-dunnit
mystery with husband and wife, Doris Day and Rex Harrison, with other
great
stars John Gavin, Myrna Loy, Roddy McDowell, and Herbert Marshall.  Doris
puts her heart and soul into this, and she is good at weeping!  We don't
know who is driving her mad until near the end.  Should we tell who done
it?
See it and I believe you'll like it!  I don't know if Doris was
nominated
for this.  Does anyone know?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13850684/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>suemartin23264</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I caught this on Channel Five last week, and I expected another
plodding Doris Day film. However, I was pleasantly surprised! This
little gem isn't actually that bad. I give you that Doris Day does
overplay her role horrendously in some parts, and that you can guess
the twist ending when you're only half - way through, but all in all,
this quite a good movie thriller! It's about a woman who starts getting mysterious death threats from
some unknown person, and as the film goes on, we see her mental health
deteriorate into the twist in the climax.The scariest scene is in the London fog in the very first scene, and
the rest of it builds up suspense. A little over acted, and perfectly
see - through, but a good thriller all the same! Rent it for a night
in! I recommend it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0653582/comments</url><from>from Hilleroed, Denmark</from><name>Bent Christensen (bchil103@worldonline.dk)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I started seeing this movie without great expectations but I must admit
that
it was a very positive surprise. David Miller has made a movie which in my
opinion is to be compared with the best Hitchcock ever made. An excellent
cast: John Gavin and Myrna Loy give good performances and Rex Harrison
is -
as always - Rex Harrison.But it's Doris Days film. She was perfect in "The Man Who Knew Too Much"
but
here she's better. An outstanding performance. No other actress can look
so
terror-stricken, without overacting.
The sequence where she is stuck in an elevator, gives a good impression of
what she can.If you haven't seen this movie - rush to see it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1206191/comments</url><from>from Bristol, England.</from><name>MIKE WILSON (MIKE.WILSON6@BTINTERNET.COM)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

After watching most of her other films, with Rock Hudson, andJames Garner, this is a major departure for Doris Day. MidnightLace, requires an actress of considerable ability, but Day provesup the task. Her performance is one of the best  that I have everyseen. She plays the wealthy wife of Rex Harrison, who is havingfinancial problems, running the family firm. After receiving severalphone calls, threatening her life, she has problems proving to thepolice, and Harrison, that the calls really took place.Other threads of the story,including Roddy McDowall as thepenniless son of Day's maid, Herbert Marshall as a gambler withmoney troubles, and John Gavin,as the builder, with flashbacksfrom the war, there is no lack of possible suspects,who may bethreatening Day.
This film has the same look and feel as ‘Dial M for Murder' so that is as good a recommendation as anybody could want.  8 out of
10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
SPOILERS. There's nothing spectacularly original about this glossy Hitchcockian
thriller but it's likable in its own commercial way. The theme is
absolutely routine. Someone repeatedly calls Doris Day in a spooky
voice and threatens to kill her. She spends the entire movie trying to
get someone to believe her -- her husband, her friend Peggy, her bubbly
Aunt Bea, the police -- and fails. That's it. That's the plot. Except
for the last few minutes when things get a little twisted. A lot of
people evidently saw the explanation coming but I didn't.Oh, of course, the story has to be liberally sprinkled with suspicious
men who might, for one reason or another, have a screw loose in their
heads and a motive in their minds. John Gavin seems helpful and
handsome enough (he smokes a pipe and works in his shirt sleeves,
usually good signs) but he has one scene in which he reminisces about a
horrifying experience he had during the war, trapped in a burning tank,
and his character stares distractedly, ominously, into space. Roddy
MacDowell is a weaselly guy who tries to pry money out of Day. Anthony
Dawson mopes around in the shadows and we don't know who he is or what
he wants. His face is scarred and he looks more openly menacing than he
did in "Dial M For Murder." John Williams basically repeats his
detective role from the same film. Sometimes when I have trouble
falling asleep, I try to force my mind to run through all the times
Williams has played a lawyer, a detective, or an investigator of some
kind, in an attempt to compare the subtle differences in the
performances, but I can never find any. By the time I'm entering Stage
Two sleep I've run out of detectives and the final fading image is of
Williams hawking "the classical collection" of LPs in a TV commercial
-- "Ahh, it's a marvelous collection." Where was I?Oh, yes. Williams has seen all this happen before. The husband a busy
executive, the wife at home bored. Perhaps sexually neglected. Then a
few complaints about naughty phone calls and the husband begins to pay
attention. Aunt Bea believes Doris, at least until she too is sucked
into the sneaky caller's web. Now, you must understand, Rex Harrison as
husband Tony WANTS to help her. Really, he breathes sympathy. But there
is simply no evidence that these threats are coming from anyplace
except Day's imagination. The creepy voice that first calls out to her
from the fog in a deserted park (good scene). The person who pushed her
in front of the bus. A shadow passing her bedroom window up on the
third floor -- or second floor, in London. Come to think of it there's a small hole in the plot somewhere along in
here. Harrison and his girl friend, helpful neighbor Peggy, have
contrived the entire plot. The creepy phone voice comes from a tape
recorder that either Harrison or Peggy play over the phone when they
make the filthy calls. The calls then are pre-recorded, right? So how
is it possible for this scene to take place? Day, Aunt Bea, and Rex are
in the flat when the phone rings. Day begs Aunt Bea to answer the phone
and take the call, just to prove that they're real. Bea answers the
phone and claims to be Day but the caller simply asks, "Why haven't you
called me, Mrs. Preston?" Before she breaks down, Day cries that the
caller realized it wasn't she who answered the phone. Okay. But since
Rex is present in the scene, it means the tape was being played by
Peggy, with whom he is in cahoots. How could such a deceptive tape have
been prerecorded? No one knew until the last second that Aunt Bea would
answer instead of Day. Well, not worth going on about. I may have
missed something. The movie is kind of fun. If I don't look forward to watching it, I
nevertheless enjoy it when I happen to catch it. The score is worth
mentioning too. Nice scene in the pub when Gavin is having his supper
and watching Dawson. There's a tinkling piano, pub-style, in the
background and slowly a more ambitious and menacing low counterpoint
swells up on the sound track, rather neatly done.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0274816/comments</url><from>from Orange Park, FL USA</from><name>Dan Martin (dcmart@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is one of Ms. Day's best performances in her film career up to the
time
(1960) of its release . With an old style English flair for suspense,this
is a thriller that will keep you guessing right up to the climactic
ending.
With Rex Harrison,Myrna Loy,John Gavin,Roddy McDowell and a most memorable
supporting role performed by John Williams as the Inspector.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0274816/comments</url><from>from Orange Park, FL USA</from><name>Dan Martin (dcmart@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is one of Ms. Day's best performances in her film career up to the
time
(1960) of its release . With an old style English flair for suspense,this
is a thriller that will keep you guessing right up to the climactic
ending.
With Rex Harrison,Myrna Loy,John Gavin,Roddy McDowell and a most memorable
supporting role performed by John Williams as the Inspector.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0274816/comments</url><from>from Orange Park, FL USA</from><name>Dan Martin (dcmart@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/midnight_lace/comments.php?reviewid=1406282</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/midnight_lace/comments.php?reviewid=1212907</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117793107.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/midnight_lace/comments.php?reviewid=1804878</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/73158/midnight_lace.html /m/midnight_lace/comments.php?reviewid=1515875</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9B01EFDE1731EF3ABC4C52DFB667838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/midnight_lace/comments.php?reviewid=1388901</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/23796_MIDNIGHT_LACE.html /m/midnight_lace/comments.php?reviewid=1236832</url><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>