<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sink the Bismarck!</original_title><alt_title>Coulez le Bismarck!</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Lewis Gilbert</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
A true WW2 story: the British Navy must find and destroy a powerful German warship.
</synopsis><actor>Kenneth More</actor><actor>Dana Wynter</actor><actor>Carl Möhner</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0060066/comments</url><from>from Hollywood</from><name>jacksflicks</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The British have made war and historical movies with an unrivaled
consistency of quality, and Sink the Bismarck is no exception.  The details
are meticulous, the casting first-rate (except for a hokey
voice-impersonation of Churchill), and the battle sequences marked by
accuracy and fine special effects.This otherwise fine film is marred, however, by the false depiction of one
of the major characters, Admiral Lutjens, commander of the Bismarck.  In the
film, he is stereotyped as the typical Nazi - a Hitler sycophant, careerist
and wild-eyed fanatic.  This was most certainly not the historical Lutjens,
who was by no means a Nazi fanatic.  Lutjens was a naval hero from World War
I, who served out of duty and dedication, not Nazi conviction. (Lutjens
protected Jews under his command, and members of his family were in trouble
for their anti-Nazi views.)  This is at complete odds with his depiction in
Sink the Bismarck, which I find inexcusable, given that the above
information was certainly available to the production.  In fact, an accurate
depiction of Lutjens would have, in my opinion, added interest to the
plot.Nevertheless, Sink the Bismarck is eminently watchable and a fine addition
to any war movie collection, if you bear in mind the above
caveat.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1210625/comments</url><from>from Seattel, WA</from><name>mikestollov</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

A lot of people criticise this film for the wooden acting, but this
ignores
a vital point. In the period the film is set people were a lot more
formal,
especially in the Royal Navy. Such negative comments are on a par with
claims that Shakespearean language is too floral or that George Washington
wore a powdered wig. Honestly I cannot accept any such comments. Anyone
who's seen the God Awful TV movie, "The Junction Boys" will see much more
woodeness.Charting the maiden voyage of the Nazi battleship's Bizmark &amp; her brief
career in the Atlantic, this film lacks modern details now known about
this
episode due to the efforts of divers, namely information gained from the
wreck of the Bizmark itself &amp; investigations of HMS Hood's remains,
famously
blown into pieces by a hit from Bizmark.Also not dealt with is some of the rather more subtle facts of this
period.
Bizmark is touted as "the deadliest warship afloat" but this isn't borne
out
by the facts. The Bizmark chose it's battles very well, avoiding conflict
with Royal Navy warships that could do it actual damage. She was a
commerce
raider, praying on defenceless merchant ships, less powerful warships &amp;
fleeing from anything that could do her harm. The fact that she came up
against warships that could actually do damage to her was down to the
doggedness of the Royal Navy.At first she did prevail, but once more due to the opposition she was
given.
HMS Hood was definitely NOT a good choice for this conflict, she was NOT a
Battleship, she was an old, thinly armoured Battle Cruiser &amp; well below
the
standard of Bizmark, her guns were innacurate &amp; her armour wasn't up to
the
threat she was faced with. The accompanying battleship Prince of Wales was
a
brand new warship, with terrific specifications, but was so new she also
had
teething poblems (her firing control wasn't fully calibrated &amp; some of her
guns had problems that prevented them from firing) &amp; even went into battle
against the Bizmark with civilian ship builders on board who were still
working on her! Hardly surprising then that Bizmark sank Hood &amp; damaged
Prince Of Wales badly. None the less between the two of them they hit
Bizmark three times, knocking out one of her boilers, puncturing her
armour,
so she took on water &amp; leaked fuel, a critical turning point in the
eventual
outcome.When Bizmark was later damaged by aircraft, robbing her of her rudders,
she
was unable to run away &amp; finally forced to come up against "KG5" (HMS King
George The Fifth) &amp; her support fleet, then the truth was revealed.
Bizmark
was good, but against the older, less well specified KG5 she lost heavily,
with enormous loss of life. Bizmark was good, but in a fight with
comparable
forces she was nothing special (yes, she was outnumbered, but by very much
older ships).The confususion of this time is clearly shown, as Bizmark circled
uncontrolably following the air strike, so meaning that sightings sent to
RN
HQ mean that at one point she was thought to be heading away from the
battle
fleet, then towards it.We do see some emotional manipuilation going on, an effort to either
sustain
the narative, or arouse hatred in the audience for the enemy so that we
are
not horrified by the carnage that will soon be unleashed upon them. Royal
Navy ships are shown getting sunk that actually didn't even get hit. Also
Ark Royal Swordfish aircraft are shown getting shot down, when actually
all
returned intact (a fascinating fact, the ancient, obsolete Swordfish from
the aircraft carrier Ark Royal were all the Fleet Air Arm had. The Germans
at the time laughed at the cumbersome, bi-plane torpedo bombers, but they
couldn't hit them! Their anti aircraft guns had predicters on them to
track
incoming aircraft &amp; hit them, but the Swordfish flew so slowly the
predicters couldn't compensate &amp; all the shells missed!).Technical details apart, the naval action is where the movie excels. For
the
last time British movie makers were allowed access to a Royal Navy
Battleship, probably HMS Vanguard, the last RN Big Gun warship. Notice how
the scenes in the Bizmark &amp; KG5 gun turrets are identical! Well they
weren't
going to get this footage from the German Kriegsmarine! However notice
that
the sailors are shown wearing their white, anti flash covers correctly for
once. They should go over the mouth, but rarely do you see this in
films.The acting is superb, considering the period &amp; the generation they came
from. Kenneth Moore plays the part of Cpt Joh  Sheppard (co ordianting the
show down with Bizmark in the London RN HQ) sympathetically, portraying
the
genuine feelings the RN sailors had for the Nazi sailors who'd lost their
lives. (A comment from a sailor of the time "She was the most beautiful
ship
I'd ever seen &amp; we'd come here to sink her"). Later it was known that the
German sailors went throught similar moments after sinking the Hood. The
final seconds of the film show Moore reluctantly throwing Bizmark's
Atlantic
battlefield model into the rubbish. Not covered is the abandoning of the
surviving Germans by the Royal Navy. It is claimed that this was revenge
for
the loss of life on the Hood, where all but 4 were killed. But Lufftwaffe
air attacks against the Royal Naval Forces were a genuine threat, as was
an
attack by German U-Boats who did not hesitate to sink any enemy ship no
matter what was going on. Basically not stopping to pick up survivors was
Standard Operating Procedure whether they were friend or foe, something
that
seems to be forgotten by the German survivors. They blame the Royal Navy,
but the RN never knew if a U-Boat torpedo was on the way, headed for their
valuable ships. It was ultimately the effects of their Nazi Admiral
Doenitz's orders, comander of the U-Boat packs, that lead them to be
abandoned.Carl Mohner portrays the Captain of the Bizmark "Lindeman" with an air of
professionalism, he isn't seen as a Nazi. He is shown as a good warrior,
but
not a Fascist. Karl Stepanek as Admiral Lutchens is shown as a slightly
arrogant, puffed up Nazi. There is some truth here, but later intelligence
releases would explain why Lutchens sent such a long message to Berlin
that
allowed the British to fix his position so accurately &amp; seal his fate. It
wasn't arrogance or a death wish, basically he already believed that he
had
been located by the RN &amp; so had nothing to lose by breaking radio silence
(he was wrong, at that point the RN had no idea where he was). Later
historical evidence shows he was rather more complex that a simple Hitler
toady.The final battle scenes avoid the brutal carnage, later comments from
surviving German sailors tesitfy to the impact of 16 inch shells from the
Royal Navy as they tore the Bizmark to pieces. Basically they describe how
the decks were littered with flesh, "like a butchers shop" as one put it,
from the crew as they were blown to bits by the Royal Navy shells. Given
the
hatred the British still had for the Germans in 1960 when this film was
made
(ask my mother who at the time wept for the loss of the Hood &amp; swore at
German air armadas that dropped bombs on her) this ommision isn't a
surprise, as is the limits of acceptability at the time.Also not covered is the end game, where KG5 pounded Bizmark with broadside
after broadside. This is one of the reasons that the Bizmark aquired the
legend of strength &amp; invicibility. However any naval tactician of the time
would have quickly pointed out a fatal flaw in this part of the action.
Getting in close &amp; sending 16 inch shells into Bizmark was NOT the way to
sink her, the shells would be travelling at a shallow angle &amp; would
explode
in the upper decks. The proper way to do it is to get further back &amp; send
in
shots that come in at a plunging angle, exploding deep in the ship. She
wasn't invincible, she was simply tortured.All in all you have to look a very long way to find a similarly finessed
work charting Naval Warfare. "Battle of the River Plate", "Midway", "The
Cruel Sea" &amp; "Tora! Tora! Tora!" are about the only examples I can think
of.
Intrigiungly they are also open to the criticisms levelled at acting
standard of "Bizmark" but seemingly they don't attract the same. Why this
is
I don't know.Avoid the knee jerk reaction concerning the portrayal of the characters
involved &amp; you have a deep, fascinating portrayal of one of the most
interesting chapters in WW2 Naval History.
For similar adventures try the films mentioned above but NOT the fat-head
2001 "Pearl Harbour" remake, which makes me want to puke.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Kenneth More plays the severe cold and uncompromising Captain Jonathan
Shepard who has lost his wife in an air raid, and whose son is a naval
pilot in the warfare against the Bismarck...'Bismarck' is a super German battleship of World War II that had a
short, but spectacular career...Captain Shepard guides the distinguished campaign from the Admiralty
War headquarters in London: The search, the course, the deploy and the
destruction of the Bismarck under an archetype that said: 'Getting
emotional about things is a peacetime luxury.'The Bismarck's admiral (Karel Stepanek) is a Nazi officer characterized
by emotional instability, presumptuous and overenthusiastic...Sighted and bombarded by British battleships, the Bismarck is
incapacitated and sunk by torpedoes on the morning of May 27, 1941.Dana Wynter is the likable attractive lady naval officer, fitting in
mood and attitude...In the climax of the film and after the naval epic, Michael Hordern,
the Commander-in-Chief of the Home Fleet, turns to his men and says:
'Let's go home, gentlemen!'This exciting sea battle would have been better on a standard screen
than in CinemaScope, as its ships were clearly 'models' using newsreels
footage... Nevertheless, the film is an entertaining hunt, with good
acting.Beside the search and eventual sinking of the Bismarck, I would like to
mention, that the personal drama of the British sailors increase the
intensity of the picture's realism...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The German battleship Bismark was one of the finest warships ever built. 
She carried 8 15-inch guns and a powerful secondary battery and could make
30 knots.  It wasn't one of the biggest or most powerful battleships ever
built.  The Japanese had the Yamato and Mushashi towards the end of the war,
juggernauts with 18-inch cannons.  There's a limit to gigantism of course,
and in the case of battleships it had to do with whether they could fit
physically through the Panama Canal, a concern the Japanese had long put
behind them.  So the Bismark wasn't the sort of sacred monster that sheer
size would make her.  But she LOOKED absolutely great.  Sleek, well
balanced, with her superstructure done the way an architect might have done
it, not an engineer.  She looked built for speed, and endurance too.  For an
example of the opposite trend, take a look at Rodney or Nelson.  More
powerfully armed, with 9 16-inch guns carried in three turrets, all set
forward of the superstructure.  Man, that is one ugly design.  And, more
than that, Bismarck's crew were highly trained and she was equipped with one
of the world's best optical fire-control systems.  It wasn't just luck that
sank the Hood and damaged any smaller ships that go too close; it was good
shooting.  (Her shooting didn't fall off until that final bombardment.) 
Winston Churchill called her "a masterpiece of naval construction," although
not in this movie.  She kept large elements of the fleet pinned down at home
simply by sitting in her protected port and being available.I must have seen this movie a dozen times and each time I begin by wondering
if I'll be able to sit through it again.  (I've got some of the exchanges
memorized.)  I generally make it, though.  It's too good in its own dated
way to pass up.  The model work is not bad at all for its time.  The reviewer who said this
film called for black and white was correct.  It looks cold and frightening
on the North Atlantic.  Almost everything would have been, or at least
seemed, gray even if it had been shot in color.  The peformances are up to
professional standards.  More is a different character here from his usual
jocular one -- frosty, demanding, and no nonsense.  Until finally, overcome
with emotion, he breaks down in an understated scene.  Dana Wynter, his
assistant, spots him and discreetly leaves him alone.  She's too beautiful
to criticize as an actress.  She radiates purity and anima and gently draws
More out of his shell.  Naismith is a familiar face, as are many of the
others.  And there is a running gag in this underground bunker where More is
plotting the Bismarck's demise.  Nobody knows what time it is or, if they
know it's 9 o'clock, they don't know if its morning or evening.  Even the
Germans aboard the Bismarck are lent some humanity by the script writers. 
The cadets look like earnest fresh-faced kids.  The Captain is a practical
man, worried about his ship and his crew.  Only Karel Stepanek, as Lutjens,
belongs in another, much earlier movie, say one made in 1943.  He is well
out of the frame established in the rest of the film.  Stricken with awe
when he gets a birthday greeting from You-Know-Who.  Some of the dialogue is
made up, out of necessity.  Who knows what went on on the Bismarck's bridge,
especially during that last catastrophic shelling?  Back in the bunker, Dana
Wynter looks down at the wooden models on her chart where a dozen British
warships surround the single Bismarck and pound her to pieces.  "I don't
feel like cheering," she says.  Well, "War is all hell."  Maybe that's why
human beings seem to need another one every twenty years or so, to remind
ourselves.  What a waste of great ships, and of good men, on both sides.  And an
argument could even be made that Bismarck's sister ship, the Tirpitz, played
an even more important part in the war simply by staying put and tying down
so many British ships that were needed elsewhere.  Our side "wins," of
course.  Our side almost always wins when we're the side that's funding the
movie.  A lot of viewers will expectably feel relief when the threat
represented by Bismarck is over, but they probably won't feel much like
cheering.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0856650/comments</url><from>from Merriam, Kansas</from><name>Tom Hull</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

For starters, this picture was thankfully filmed in black and white.  This
is only appropriate for gray colored ships shooting it out in the North
Atlantic.  The performers were, for the most part, convincing.  The movie
got a little risky by using a fictional character (played by Kenneth More)
for the lead role, and delving a bit into his personal life.  But it didn't
get out of hand.  The movie takes just the right amount of time in
developing and depicting the important events in the eight day life of the
Bismarck.  I got the feeling that I was actually there and watching these
events take place.  The movie is essentially accurate, based on accounts I
have read in books; including one by the highest ranking German survivor. 
The depiction of the destruction of the British battle cruiser Hood was not
exactly accurate, but I would rank that a minor point.  Getting the ship
used in the movie to blow up the same way the Hood would probably have been
more trouble than it was worth.  The bottom line is the ship was destroyed
and only three crew members survived.This movie is an excellent, no-nonsense portrayal of the short and dramatic
life of the legendary German battleship Bismarck.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9414155/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>roghache</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This movie is a well crafted and gripping depiction of British attempts
to locate and destroy the German battleship Bismarck during World War
II. It is told from the viewpoint of sailors aboard vessels from both
sides and also the British naval command headquarters. I have little
knowledge of naval history so am in no position to comment regarding
historical accuracy.Personally, I found most compelling the strategy and tension within the
Admiralty War Headquarters in London, especially the personal depiction
of the coordinator of this operation. Kenneth More convincingly plays
Captain Jonathan Shepard, who lost his own wife earlier in an air raid
and has a son who is himself a naval pilot involved in the battle to
sink the Bismarck. Shepard's relationship with the lovely but very
professional female naval officer Davis is well captured. There is also
a moving portrait of Shepard's restrained response to unfolding news
regarding his son. Though there is engaging battle drama at sea, it's
the character portrayal of this stiff upper lip British officer that
made the movie for me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3225430/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ebiros2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a little known war time epic movie that should rank with the
likes of "Patton". The story is about the grudge match that's spawned
from sinking of battleship Hood by the German battleship Bismark. A
full blown search for the German battleship by the British navy takes
place to hunt down and sink the Bismark. Acting is first class, and
although the special effects have something to be desired by today's
standard, movie none the less conveys the tension and excitement of
what probably was the greatest and the final naval conflict between
battleships. In recent years Bob Ballard and the Oceanographic
Institute rediscovered the sunken remains of the battleship Bismark
which confirmed the ferocity of the fire power that was exchanged in
this naval warfare. This movie gets mentioned by movie producers of
today when they sight their seminal influence it had on some of their
plot lines, which attests to its production value. The sub plot which
unfolds between Kenneth Moore and Dana Wynter is also written superbly.
A good war time semi documentary that's worth seeing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4327936/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>padutchland-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
and could just watch and enjoy the movie without analyzing it. That's
what movies were originally for - entertainment and enjoyment. I don't
know if the special effects were great for the time or not, but they
looked enough like the real thing for me. Great naval battle scenes and
the acting was perfect for the times portrayed of the 1940's and the
real way that military people are mostly low key in planning
discussions and carrying out their duties. All very believable scenes
with the flavor of the way it really was even in portions that were
added to entertain (when history takes a back seat to entertainment).
Kenneth More showed his versatility in excelling in such a serious part
and Dana Wynter very professional. I don't know why she didn't become a
larger name here in the States with such pure beauty, grace and honest
acting ability. By coincidence I just saw her in another movie In Love
And War where she played a totally different type of part and nailed it
great. Anyway, if you haven't seen Sink The Bismarck, then by all means
give it a gander. It is time well spent for not only those who enjoy
naval movies, but good drama films as well.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
In May 1941 the Royal Navy was stretched to the breaking point. As was
accurately pointed out by Laurence Naismith playing the First Sea Lord,
they are committed heavily to the battle raging for Greece, to
defending the critical base at Malta, and to protecting Atlantic
convoys from America. So when Hitler turned loose his newest and
biggest battleship, the Bismarck, the Royal Navy had not a whole lot to
throw at her. Sink the Bismarck is done in a documentary style with the action taking
place on the high seas in the British ships and on the Bismarck. The
other part of the drama takes place at the war room at the Admiralty
where the fictitious character Kenneth More, a captain who had his ship
shot out from under him by the German commander who is in charge of the
Bismarck. The Bismarck was only out for eight days, but in that time she
annihilated the British cruiser Hood with all but 3 lost. After that it
was a running battle with both planes from the carrier Ark Royal and
ship to ship battles with the Prince of Wales, the George V, and the
Dorcestshire before the Bismarck went down in the Atlantic.There is a side personal drama involving Kenneth More whose son is a
flier on board the Ark Royal and who is missing. WREN officer Dana
Wynter is around to lend a sympathetic ear and there's a bit of a hint
that things might get personal with More and Wynter.The Ark Royal planes did some damage and I notice that the planes flown
off the Ark Royal were ancient biplanes. They did some damage, but
didn't sink the Bismarck themselves. Unfortunately some lessons were
not learned by the British command and the Prince of Wales and the
Repulse were sunk several months later by the Japanese with aerial
bombardment when they reported for duty at the British base in
Singapore. The British did in fact experiment with carriers as the Ark
Royal's contribution in that action and others signifies. I'm willing
to bet Mr. Churchill wished he had a few more carriers like the
Americans and Japanese did. And I'm also willing to bet he was thanking
the Deity the Germans had none.Two things helped popularize the film in America and it did do well on
this side of the Atlantic. I remember a packed house when I went to see
it in theater back when I was a lad. One was the presence and narration
of Edward R. Murrow who as a correspondent for CBS radio reported to
America on the Bismarck story and so many others. His more than FDR's
was the voice of World War II for the American public.The second was that country singer Johnny Horton had a big selling hit
also entitled Sink the Bismarck. Though nary a note of it is heard in
this film that song on the charts boosted sales to Sink the Bismarck
tremendously. Kind of unusual that an American country singer would choose a British
naval action as the subject of a song. But the heroism of all the
members of the Royal Navy and even that of the crew of the Bismarck is
the stuff legends are made of.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
When making a film like, "Sink The Bismark" it benefits the audience
when actual facts of the ship or the events are used in the final cut.
This film does just that. It begins with the Christening and launching
of the impressive German vessel, Bismark. The massive battleship which
could easily cruise at 30 knots became the pride of Germany and quickly
proved her military prowess when encountering the H.M.S. Hood. The Hood
was the pride of the British Royal Navy with her Captain and select
crew of 1,500 men were well seasoned and experienced. Yet on that
fateful day of May 24th, 1941 the two ships came within 15 miles of
each other. After several exchanged salvos, the Bismark with her
compliment of 8 fifteen inch guns completely destroyed the British ship
leaving only three survivors. This disastrous event is but one of the
exceptional battle scenes, superbly recreated by Howard Lydecker and
his special effects crew. To add to the creative storyline are the
actors which give this movie a superior realism. Kenneth More as
Captain Shepard, who along with his naval staff wage war against the
Bismark from their underground command post in war-torn London, where
Edward R. Murrow gives the world a blow by blow account of the
desperate time. Dana Wynter plays Anne Davis, his able assistant. Carl
Möhner is Captain Lindemann, the proud Captain of the Bismark with
Karel Stepanek playing his immediate superior, Admiral Lutjens.
Laurence Naismith plays the First Sea Lord. This a great film and
should honor the Allies who gave so much when the world needed them.
****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
When making a film like, "Sink The Bismark" it benefits the audience
when actual facts of the ship or the events are used in the final cut.
This film does just that. It begins with the Christening and launching
of the impressive German vessel, Bismark. The massive battleship which
could easily cruise at 30 knots became the pride of Germany and quickly
proved her military prowess when encountering the H.M.S. Hood. The Hood
was the pride of the British Royal Navy with her Captain and select
crew of 1,500 men were well seasoned and experienced. Yet on that
fateful day of May 24th, 1941 the two ships came within 15 miles of
each other. After several exchanged salvos, the Bismark with her
compliment of 8 fifteen inch guns completely destroyed the British ship
leaving only three survivors. This disastrous event is but one of the
exceptional battle scenes, superbly recreated by Howard Lydecker and
his special effects crew. To add to the creative storyline are the
actors which give this movie a superior realism. Kenneth More as
Captain Shepard, who along with his naval staff wage war against the
Bismark from their underground command post in war-torn London, where
Edward R. Murrow gives the world a blow by blow account of the
desperate time. Dana Wynter plays Anne Davis, his able assistant. Carl
Möhner is Captain Lindemann, the proud Captain of the Bismark with
Karel Stepanek playing his immediate superior, Admiral Lutjens.
Laurence Naismith plays the First Sea Lord. This a great film and
should honor the Allies who gave so much when the world needed them.
****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1763069</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Above average depiction of infamous WWII battleship Bismark.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/wesley-lovell/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=5200 /m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1312895</url><name>Wesley Lovell</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
63/100
					</rating><comment>A faithful retelling of the real-life naval battle, a colourful portrait in black and white.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1418532</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1264726</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794916.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1806296</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ah-weiler/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9B07E5D7173DE333A25751C1A9649C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1390521</url><name>A.H. Weiler</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=108367 /m/sink_the_bismarck/comments.php?reviewid=1163541</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>