<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Rise and Fall of Legs Diamond</original_title><alt_title>La chute d'un caïd</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Budd Boetticher</director><producer>United States Pictures</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
Jack Diamond and his sickly brother arrive in prohibition New York as jewellery thieves. After a spell in jail the coldly ambitious Diamond hits on the idea of stealing from thieves himself...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ray Danton</actor><actor>Karen Steele</actor><actor>Elaine Stewart</actor><rt_rating>6.5/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>67</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Boetticher viewed his heroes, trapped in the past and doomed to wander,
with no more sentimentality than his outlaws, who try, often
hopelessly, to forget their criminal ways and settle down… His darkest
film of all, however, was "The Rise and Fall of Legs Diamond," in which
the sun-baked desert is replaced by a dark, claustrophobic urban
nightmare… Boetticher's psychopathic hood, played with relentless energy by Ray
Danton, is a totally amoral figure whose lust for power leads him to
destroy even his brother in order to protect himself… Fast, cruel and
violent, the film is one of the cinema's bleakest visions of
unrestrained ambition….
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0752880/comments</url><from>from Western New York</from><name>bmacv</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

The Rise and Fall of Legs Diamond is Budd Boetticher's cold look at a cool
customer.  The low temperature extends to Lucien Ballard's crisply
composed
black-and-white cinematography and to Ray Danton's chilly assumption of
the
title role.  With his `matinee-idol' looks and devil-may-care attitude, he
prefigures another kind of `cool' that would arrive on screen a year or so
later, that of James Bond.Like Bond, Diamond thinks faster than anybody around him; his quick wits
and
ready charm get him out of scrapes as a jewel thief who came down the
Hudson
from Albany to try his luck in Manhattan.  But that luck fails him and he
ends up doing a short stretch; when he gets out, he resolves to steal from
only those who `can't call the police' - other criminals.  And he starts
his
way up in the Arnold Rothstein operation.His fatal flaw is that he cares for nobody but himself, using people
ruthlessly.  The women in his life (Karen Steele, Elaine Stewart and the
young Dyan Cannon) suffer particularly from their sub-zero lover, but even
his sickly brother (Warren Oates) ends up cast out into the blizzard.
Diamond's estrangement increases apace with his sense of his own
invincibility; having survived, against all odds, a spray of bullets, he
convinces himself that he can't be killed.  He's wrong.Though he's right for Boetticher's conception of the part, Danton had less
of a career than he might have.  He appeared in a few late films in the
moribund noir cycle (as the psychotic killer in The Night Runner and as
the
Aspirin Kid in The Beat Generation) but, after this film, worked mostly in
European cinema (by which such names as Fellini, Bergman or Godard should
not be inferred).Boetticher has a few noir credentials as well (Behind Locked Doors, The
Killer is Loose) but seems uneasy in how, on the cusp of Camelot, to spin
this jazz-age tale.  He opts for detachment, structuring the movie as a
choppy series of vignettes - almost tableaux - that don't flow (several of
the incidents clamor for more explanation, but he leaves us to fill in the
missing pieces).  And finally, neither director nor actor gives a sound
accounting of the changes in Diamond: How the winsome scoundrel of the
opening turns into the cold-blooded shark of the finish.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0420823/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Allen J. Duffis (sataft-2)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

For the record, this film is historically inaccurate: not for the events,
but for the true life character portrayals and interactions.For instance, there is no evidence in the record of the time that Arnold
(The Big Bankroll) Rothstein ever formally met with Jack "Legs" Diamond.
Nor
is there any record of Diamond having anything to do with Rothstein's
girlfriend or his gangland assassination.Despite these gaps in historical fact, this is one of the most highly
entertaining ( of the 1960's crop) of films ever made of that era.  In
fact
many film critics hold to the opinion that most, if not all, of the
gangster
films of the sixties, were poor attempts to copy the style and success of
this one. The production is tightly written, well paced and beautifully
filmed by a director (Bud Boetticher) who knew his way around black and
white photography.  And they couldn't have picked a better subject of the
Prohibition Era than Jack "Legs" Diamond.Jack Diamond was not called "Legs" because he worked for a short time as a
dancer, but for the fact that he was initially a highly successful 'snatch
and run' thief in the garment district.  But he did eventually get caught
and served a stint in prison. But forget the historical inaccuracies and
enjoy this never boring gangster film.Ray Danton, one of the most highly underrated actors of his time, gives  a
riveting fast paced portrayal of Diamond that will be hard to surpass.
Not
only is he believable in the outrageous stunts he pulls, but he just as
easily exposes a manic and tragic side to his character as well: all
without
missing a beat.This unusual film also allows you to see some of the screens most
memorable
character actors at their best. But most of all, you get to see two soon
to
be famous actors on their way up.This was actress Dyan Cannon's first film, in a memorable role as the
character,Dixie.  And soon to be veteran character Warren Oates makes his
third appearance in the movies as "Legs" Diamond's brother, Eddie.  A
careful study his early acting skills in this role, clearly defines why he
went on to become one of the most endearing and recognizable character
actors of all time.Trust me on this one, fans.  Whether you like Depression Era gangster
films
or not, you will be constantly entertained by this one.  Don't miss
it!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
In the 20's, the ambitious smalltime thief Jack Diamond (Ray Danton)
and his sick brother Eddie Diamond (Warren Oates) arrive in New York.
Jack meets the dance teacher Alice Shiffer (Karen Steele) and uses
dirty tricks to date her and steal a necklace in a jewelry store. After
spending a period in prison, he asks Alice to work with her in the
dance school during his probation. Then he decides to work as bodyguard
of the powerful gangster lord Arnold Rothstein (Robert Lowery) that
dubs him Legs, with the intention of stealing his illegal business of
bootleg, drugs and gambling. When Arnold is murdered, Legs Diamond
sells protection to the gangs. When he travels to Europe with Alice on
vacation, he sees in the news the changes in New York underworld with
the National Prohibition Act and returns, finding a different city that
he does not understand. "The Rise and Fall of Legs Diamond" is a good gangster movie based on
the biography of the criminal Jack "Legs" Diamond. The gangster is
described as a man that did not love anybody and believed that he could
never be killed, ending his life alone without friends and betrayed by
a lover. This movie was released on VHS in Brazil by Continental
distributor. My vote is seven.Title (Brazil): "O Rei dos Facínoras" ("The King of the Ruffians")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Jack "Legs" Diamond was the alias of John T. Noland (1897-1931) who had
one spectacular career in the underworld of the Roaring Twenties.
Though we are far from seeing the real story of Legs Diamond, Ray
Danton gives us a riveting portrayal of a totally amoral man who uses
and discards people in his rise to the top. Diamond's career and this
film about him is very much a harbinger of stuff like Goodfellas in the
last decade.Right around this time Hollywood took a nostalgic interest in the
gangster era. A whole lot of films like Al Capone, Machine Gun Kelly an
early Charles Bronson starrer, Dutch Schultz Portrait of a Mobster, and
Murder, Inc. among others came out at this time. There was even a good
series from Warner Brothers television that came out called The Roaring
Twenties that starred Dorothy Provine. And of course heading the list
was The Untouchables. The Rise and Fall of Legs Diamond is part of this
trend.This came from Warner Brothers and they certainly had the best gangster
films back in the day. Had this been done back in the thirties, James
Cagney or Edward G. Robinson would have been the star. However the best
guy for the part back then would have been Tyrone Power. That is the
Tyrone Power of Nightmare Alley. Ray Danton's portrayal of Diamond
borrows a lot from Power's Stan Carlisle.This part and Danton's role in the George Raft Story should have made
Danton a star, but it didn't, who knows why. Danton gave up acting and
settled for life behind the camera, directing lots of television shows.Other good portrayals in this are Robert Lowery as Arnold Rothstein,
Warren Oates as Diamond's brother, Karen Steele as his much used and
abused wife, and Frank DeKova in one riveting scene as Lucky Luciano.
DeKova is only identified as the "chairman" in the film as Mr. Luciano
was very much alive when this came out.However the best supporting part is Jesse White's as a gangland rival.
White who normally plays comic tough guys very well really does a fine
job as a rival who Diamond makes crawl for mercy.Good portrayal of the tumultuous Roaring Twenties though not the real
story of Legs Diamond.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I'd never heard a thing about this one before I put it in my video player. I
knew Warren Oates (one of my favourite character actors - 'The Shooting',
'The Wild Bunch', 'Two-Lane Blacktop', 'Bring Me The Head Of Alfredo
Garcia',etc.) was in the supporting cast and that was enough for me to give
it a go. I know absolutely nothing about the real life exploits of 1930s
gangster Jack 'Legs' Diamond, so this movie is more than likely utter
fiction, but hey, I didn't watch it for a history lesson, I watched it to be
entertained, and it certainly did that! It's a terrific picture, very cool
and constantly engaging. Oates plays Legs' sickly "lunger" brother Eddie and
he's very good, as are the three sexy women in Legs' life (Karen Steele,
Elaine Stewart and a young Dyan Cannon). There are also several familiar
faces in the supporting cast that you'll recognize from half forgotten old
movies , but Ray Danton completely steals the film as Diamond. I'm very
surprised after watching this that Danton didn't go on to be a major star as
he is very charismatic and a credible actor. If you like crime movies try
and find 'The Rise And Fall Of Legs Diamond'. It may be obscure but it's a
really good b-picture and not to be overlooked.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12371785/comments</url><from>from Durham NC</from><name>mlraymond</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A well known racketeer of the Twenties and early Thirties, who has
served as inspiration for a novel and a Broadway play, as well as this
movie, Jack "Legs" Diamond is still remembered today. This film is a
tightly written and well played gangster drama, with a surprisingly
strong vein of black comedy running through it. Director Boetticher
said in an interview that he wanted to make a gangster picture unlike
any other, that had a sense of humor, and he claimed to have learned a
lot of funny anecdotes from real hoodlums who had known Diamond, and
incorporated them into the picture. Ray Danton is unforgettable as
Diamond. His startlingly good looks make an ironic contrast with his
ruthless pursuit of money and power. Legs is able to charm any woman
into helping him, and conning other gangsters who think they're smarter
than he is. His deep voiced delivery can be either amusing when he
makes a wisecrack ,or genuinely menacing when it's obvious Legs isn't
kidding about his demands. The other real life mobsters are played
broadly, with actors best known for their comedy roles, including Jesse
White as Leo, Diamond's primary obstacle to overcome. Robert Lowery
portrays Diamond's boss Arnold Rothstein as a cynical and world weary
man, who can get more out of one line of dialogue than pages of it. His
giving an expensive watch to Diamond with the bitterly polite remark "
Just consider it a token of how much I trust you" is a moment that
lingers after the movie is over. Joseph Ruskin is quite sinister in his
role of Matt Moran, Diamond's deadliest enemy. The scene in which they
finally meet for a fatal encounter is a brilliant example of taut,
suspenseful direction. The musical score by Leonard Rosenman is very
effective, with its jaunty main theme that occurs in several variations
throughout the picture. One interesting touch is that the tense, spooky
music that accompanies one of Diamond's early crimes, the burglary of a
jewelry store, sounds remarkably like the planetarium music Rosenman
composed for Rebel Without a Cause some five years earlier. The
Twenties backgrounds are believable and the action scenes are exciting.
The film does falter a bit toward the end, as Diamond seems to go
downhill too rapidly. The filmmakers were obviously trying to mollify
the censors by showing Diamond as getting his comeuppance in an overly
dramatic way, after basically showing him as the hero we've been
rooting for for the greater part of the film. One more observation
should be made: the performance by Warren Oates as Eddie, Diamond's
consumptive younger brother, is very good, and his slightly more
honorable attitudes show Legs up even more as the ruthless , egocentric
criminal he is. This is an excellent movie that should appeal to anyone
who likes the old gangster pictures with Cagney, Robinson, Raft, and
Bogart.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13178622/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>st-shot</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Ray Danton brings a suave cold charm to the title role of this film
about the Roaring 20s gangster. The usually wooden Danton, nattily
attired with a pair of shoulder holsters, cuts quite a figure as he
shoots, seduces and betrays his way to achieve his ambitious goals.Jack Diamond and his handicapped brother come to the big city in search
of a new start as jewelery thieves. This venture get's him jailed but
it fails to dampen his desire for fast cash and he begins to rob crooks
in order to eliminate police involvement. He catches the eye of big
time gambler Arnold Rothstein, fixer of the 1918 World Series. He goes
to work as a bodyguard for Rothstein who is later murdered thus
expediting Leg's rise.Budd Boeticher directs economically, benefiting both pace and story
line as well as Diamond's sharkish style self assuredly delivered by
Danton. He also does a nice job of keeping Diamond's involvement in the
rub out of Rothstein ambiguous (an unsolved murder to this day) as he
attempts to follow the factual outline of his career. In addition
Lucien Ballard's photography gives the studio interiors and exteriors
an extra touch of grit and noir in one of the better gangster pictures
made during a period when the genre was in a bit of a funk.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0932150/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>MStillrage</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Good film. Warren Oates does well, and the photography is superb. A
Scorsese caliber picture, before the Don of Urbana surfaced!! A well
worth watching movie. It has the truth without the shine. It never
slows or gets dull. Amazing for a movie with guys that were unknowns @
the time. Although it's a true story,it is depicted like a newsreel
from the 30's. You feel like Legs himself.He has a contagious ambition,
and he is naive to what new powers exist. He is heartless but always
ambitious. His coldness towards others that are on his side amazes
anyone. He wants to get ahead sooo bad, and he does. The story never
gets dull, and ends with prophecy/look back.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2542703/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edwagreen</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Picture starts out with a promising mission: It was to show the rise
and fall of Legs Diamond. At once, the guy is shown to be a selfish
cad. Ray Danton looks almost glassy-eyed here in his portrayal of the
noted gangster.Jesse White, as Leo, is totally miscast. White sounds like he is almost
ready to do another Maytag commercial. He is totally unconvincing as a
gangster.The picture quickly dissolves into a shoot them up action film. The
characters are not given any chance to develop, especially the part of
Arnold Rothstein.Karen Steele does well in the part of the abused wife. She really
drinks her way down a downward path.Rather weak writing does this 1960 film in. Ray Danton, 5 years before,
you made your film debut as Susan Hayward's ill-fated
attorney-boyfriend in the classic "I'll Cry Tomorrow." You were voted
most promising actor. Then, you began to make films of lower quality
and you were soon washed up as an actor. As far as this film, while we
realize that Legs is portrayed as someone not capable of loving anyone,
it is never fully explained why he turned on his sickly brother.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2542703/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edwagreen</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Picture starts out with a promising mission: It was to show the rise
and fall of Legs Diamond. At once, the guy is shown to be a selfish
cad. Ray Danton looks almost glassy-eyed here in his portrayal of the
noted gangster.Jesse White, as Leo, is totally miscast. White sounds like he is almost
ready to do another Maytag commercial. He is totally unconvincing as a
gangster.The picture quickly dissolves into a shoot them up action film. The
characters are not given any chance to develop, especially the part of
Arnold Rothstein.Karen Steele does well in the part of the abused wife. She really
drinks her way down a downward path.Rather weak writing does this 1960 film in. Ray Danton, 5 years before,
you made your film debut as Susan Hayward's ill-fated
attorney-boyfriend in the classic "I'll Cry Tomorrow." You were voted
most promising actor. Then, you began to make films of lower quality
and you were soon washed up as an actor. As far as this film, while we
realize that Legs is portrayed as someone not capable of loving anyone,
it is never fully explained why he turned on his sickly brother.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-beifuss/</url><url>http://blogs.commercialappeal.com/the_bloodshot_eye/2011/09/legs-diamond.html /m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=2012296</url><name>John Beifuss</name><from>Commercial Appeal (Memphis, TN)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Director Budd Boetticher and screenwriter Joseph Landon are as fast on their feet as their hoofer-turned-gangster protagonist; the efficiency and momentum of their storytelling should be models of inspiration for today's filmmakers.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/boettich.htm#Diamond /m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=2002608</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Strange and often grim gangster film, notable for some off-trail approaches.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/riseandfalloflegsdiamond.htm /m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=1365580</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>An unsentimental and inaccurate Warner Brothers action-packed biopic on ruthless twenties gangster Jack "Legs" Diamond.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-kaplan/</url><url>/m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=1712607</url><name>David Kaplan</name><from>Kaplan vs. Kaplan</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=1400695</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/andy-klein/</url><url>/m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=1376257</url><name>Andy Klein</name><from>Los Angeles CityBeat</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/76774/the_rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond.html /m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=1480862</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=107680 /m/rise_and_fall_of_legs_diamond/comments.php?reviewid=1148550</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>