<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Plunderers</original_title><alt_title>La rançon de la peur</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Joseph Pevney</director><producer>August Productions</producer><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
When four rowdy cowhands ride into a small town and make trouble, no one seems willing or able to take them on, not even Sam Christy, the toughest man in town. But then there is a murder.
</synopsis><actor>Jeff Chandler</actor><actor>John Saxon</actor><actor>Dolores Hart</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8743363/comments</url><from>from Toronto</from><name>worldsofdarkblue</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Juvenile delinquency was a very hot topic in the late fifties and early
sixties. The new scourge of civilization, rock and roll, had
transformed the younger generation into rebels who wanted to cast off
the repressive rules by which they were expected to conduct themselves.
The burgeoning post-war economy was removing the fear that had formed
so much of the older generation's embracement of responsibility and the
ever-quickening pace of materialistic progress was making any prospect
of boredom anathema to the young.This certainly didn't go unnoticed by the establishment who were
understandably alarmed by what appeared to be a rise in youthful
disrespect and hedonism and the war of the generations was taken fairly
seriously for a while. Hollywood quickly realized that this was a very
sexy and saleable topic for entertaining the masses and began churning
out dramas of rebellious youth by the boatload. By 1960 (the year this
film was released) these rebellious youth movies were becoming pretty
repetitive as far as contemporary settings went, so it was a darned
good idea to take the issue and transfer it to a different time - the
old west.It worked rather well, I think. Westerns tend to be fairly simple story
lines for the most part anyway so bringing an aspect of modern juvenile
delinquency into the western was novel enough to spice up both tired
genres a little. I watched it on the late show when I was on a
baby-sitting gig and it made my night. Held my interest all the way and
I enjoyed repeated viewings of it over the next couple of years.It's well acted by all. John Saxon has a great time playing the
quietest but most dangerous gang member and Jeff Chandler gets to be a
bad-tempered hero. As a small and relatively simple movie with a social
message geared to the time of its release it's not really an 8 now, but
I think it deserves a little better rating than it has here so I've
given an extra point or two to help raise the average and I don't think
that's the wrong thing to do at all. It's a decent piece of
entertainment.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0443768/comments</url><from>from Colorado</from><name>Sleepy-17</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Better-than-usual western has interesting premise: Four young
cowboy-hoodlums take over a sleepy town population 50. The whole thing
looks
and feels like a Twilight Zone episode (black and white) without the
fantasy. Two gorgeous women, Delores Hart and Marsha Hunt; a fair
performance from Jeff Chandler; and vivid portrayals by the relatively
unknown youngsters including a promising one by John Saxon. Sleazy early
60's B-Movie fun of the Juvenile Delinquent genre.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"Away All Boats" director Joseph Pevney's "The Plunders" looks like a
cross-between of "Bad Day at Black Rock" and "The Wild One." Basically,
leading man Jeff Chandler is cast as Sam Christy, a former Civil War
officer who has lost the use of his left arm. The loss of that limb--he
still retains the entire arm--serves as a metaphor for his loss of
courage. Like the one-armed Spencer Tracy hero in "Bad Day at Black
Rock," Sam is sullen and filled with self-pity. He lives alone on a
ranch with nobody to take care of him and his relationship with a hotel
owner has gone sour. Four young cowpokes ride into the meager town of
Trail City. They resemble the juvenile delinquent characters on
motorcycles in "The Wild One." In fact, the opening narration sounds
like the cautionary words in the Marlon Brando epic because the
narrator contends that it could happen to any town. These punchers are
fresh out of Dodge City where they blew their wad in no time and don't
have two-bits between them. Tired and ornery, they see Trail City as a
place to square accounts for the raw treatment that they received in
Dodge City. They start out by refusing to pay for a bottle of whiskey at the local
saloon and the town sheriff hauls them into the hoosegow. They spent
the night in jail and agree to leave peaceably until they get out.
Initially, they take $73 worth of clothes from a mercantile store and
follow that up by getting a free room in the hotel. Nobody has enough
courage to curb their wanton urges and the local sheriff buckles under
pressure. Finally, they shoot the poor man down in the street, collect
all the firearms in town and settle back into the saloon. By now
everybody in town is quaking in their boots at the sight of the
vandals. Mike Baron (James Westerfield of "The Sons of Katie Elder")
refuses to serve them in his saloon and William 'Mule' Thompson (Roger
Torrey of "The Nun and the Sergeant")batters him into submission.
Afterward, Sam Christy bucks heads with them and the biggest of the
four roughs him up. Sam exits town and decides to have nothing to do
with the quartet of hellions. Eventually, the young daughter of the
local storekeeper, Ellie Walters(Dolores Hart of "King Creole")prompts
Sam to take another chance at the foursome. Sam rallies the rest of the
townspeople and they stand together and whip the hellions. Sam takes on
the Goliath-like Mule in a knife fight and Ellie turns a six-gun on the
romantically inclined Hispanic gang member, Rondo (John Saxon of "Enter
the Dragon") when he pulls a knife on Sam. In a showdown on the street,
Sam guns down Jeb Lucas Tyler (Golden Globe nominated actor Ray
Stricklyn of "The Return of Dracula")as the rowdy twenty-year old
charges down the street blasting away with two guns. Sam convinces the
rest of the townspeople to let the last one, Davy (Dee Pollock of
"Kelly's Heroes") ride out with the memory of the event to haunt him
forever.Clearly, "The Plunders" is a morality yarn that pits old against young,
weak against strong, and cowardly against brave. Joseph Pevney's taut,
bottled-up direction and Bob Barbash's tip-lipped, intelligent script
make this 93-minute pressure-cooker thriller worth watching, even
though it's pretty predictable. Meaning, you know that Sam Christy is
going to lick these young, immature hellions. Mind you, "The Plunders"
isn't top-drawer entertainment, but it qualifies as above-average
thanks to uniformly fine performances and contemplative pacing. Saxon
looks like he is giving a warm-up act for his treacherous bandit in the
1966 western "The Appaloosa." Saxon has a moment before he dies at the
hands of Dolores Hart when he talks about the prejudice that he has
experienced as a Hispanic at the hands of whites. As usual, Chandler
plays a stern, taciturn man who has to have his cage rattled before he
shows his true colors. The only flaw in his performance occurs during a
fight at his ranch with one of the plunders. Dolores Hart is around for
good looks and everything appears appropriately dusty.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
As a player Jeff Chandler had several westerns to his credit most
notably Broken Arrow where he got an Academy Award nomination. His last
film in the western genre is The Plunderers where he's cast as a
crippled Civil War veteran who is forced to lead his town of Trail's
End in taking a stand against four juvenile toughs.Some people are born leaders and like it or not in tough situations the
job falls to them. John Saxon, Dee Pollock, Ray Stricklyn and Roger
Torrey all come to town and start essentially pushing people around.
They beat up bartender James Westerfield and later shoot down sheriff
Jay C. Flippen who is a tired old man who should have retired from that
job long ago. Flippen is symbolic himself of this post Civil War Texas
town.Chandler is a former cavalry leader in the Civil War and he's like
Lucas McCain in The Rifleman, the one in the town the people look up to
in a moment of crisis. He's as tired as any of the rest of them and
just wishes they would ride away, but when that doesn't happen despite
his physical limitations Chandler steps to the plate.There is a lot of criticism of The Plunderers with some saying this is
just a modern juvenile delinquent story set in the west. That maybe so,
but what was Billy the Kid for instance if not a most murderous
juvenile delinquent. This film is a harbinger of the Young Guns films
or the Lee Marvin classic, The Spikes Gang. The only difference is that
the punks aren't glamorized here. I swear all that was needed was for
Sal Mineo to be cast as one of the punks.The Plunderers was done for Allied Artists which we know was formerly
Mongram Pictures. Back in their day they did their share of B westerns
and the sets were used most notably for The Cisco Kid movies. The
Plunderers is a great deal above the quality of those horse operas and
it's one of Jeff Chandler's better latter day films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4333917/comments</url><from>from Sweden</from><name>mag7bela</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The Plunderers are four youngsters who come to a peaceful little
western town without any money. Actually they're no gunfighters at all
but enjoy staying there getting all for free and watching how they can
get the people more and more frightened. Onearmed Jeff Chandler wants
to stay out of trouble but is increasingly convinced that something
must be done to help the citizens against the troublemakers. Lovely
Dolores Hart is the daughter of the local store owner and the Mexican
youngster Rondo, played by John Saxon, pays a lot of attention to her.
She tries to avoid him but with no success. The dramatic final scenes
include an unusual fight with knives. This is a classic black-and-white
western from 1960 highly recommended. You can easily find resemblances
to Brando's 1954 motorcycle movie "The Wild One".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

Four young hoodlums ride into a tiny town of 50 and the terror begins. The
townsfolk are too old to really fight back and their only hope is for a
man(Jeff Chandler)with only one useful arm to take them on. Predictable,
but
interesting. Chandler is supported by: John Saxon, Dolores Hart, J.C.
Flippen, Marsha Hunt and Ray Stricklyn.NOTE: Hart gave Elvis his first screen kiss in LOVING YOU(1957). She
starred
with him again in KING CREOLE(1958). Hart entered a convent in Connecticut
in 1963.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

Four young hoodlums ride into a tiny town of 50 and the terror begins. The
townsfolk are too old to really fight back and their only hope is for a
man(Jeff Chandler)with only one useful arm to take them on. Predictable,
but
interesting. Chandler is supported by: John Saxon, Dolores Hart, J.C.
Flippen, Marsha Hunt and Ray Stricklyn.NOTE: Hart gave Elvis his first screen kiss in LOVING YOU(1957). She
starred
with him again in KING CREOLE(1958). Hart entered a convent in Connecticut
in 1963.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/plunderers.htm /m/the-plunderers/comments.php?reviewid=1996320</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>The film has been fairly compared to The Wild One.</comment></review></movie>