<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Hypnotic Eye</original_title><imdb_rating>5.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>George Blair</director><producer>Allied Artists Pictures</producer><producer>Bloch/Woodfield Productions</producer><producer>Penguin Productions</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
The city is stricken by a wave of self-mutilations performed by beautiful women who seem to be in a hypnotic trance...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jacques Bergerac</actor><actor>Allison Hayes</actor><actor>Marcia Henderson</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0374584/comments</url><from>from Under a spell</from><name>evilskip</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

The film opens up with a women washing her hair over a lit gas
stove.Naturally her hair catches fire and she has the hairdo from
Hell.This
isn't the first case of self mutilation in the big city.Many women have
been
doing this for weeks.Some have washed their face with sulfuric acid, stuck
their faces into fans etc.Is there a connection?Well if you're the police department with a collective
IQ
of minus six it is tough to figure out.This force couldn't find a donut
shop
with a road map.Yes there is a connection. All of the women have been to
see
a show by Desmond a well known hypnotist.Desmond hypnotizes woman picked by his va va voom assistant(Allison
Hayes).
He also whispers something to them just before he breaks their trance.Hmm,
wonder what that could be?Then he hypnotizes the crowd and makes them do
foolish things which is a giggle.Everybody goes home happy.Sensing a connection before her idiot police detective boy friend does a
young woman allows herself to be put under Desmond's spell.When she goes
home that night Desmond's assistant tells her to take a shower in scalding
water.Luckily old slow on the uptake shows up before she
does.There is a bit of twist ending to this movie.The disfigurements are done
"tastefully"(no gore after all this is 1960).Much is left to the
imagination. The acting is par for this genre.The police are portrayed as such morons you wonder how any crime gets
solved in this city.The movie is padded with lingering scenes of the
audience under hypnotic commands.Even so it is above average.You will look deep into the Hypnotic Eye.You will open your wallet/purse
and send me your money.Told you I had a better use for
hypnotism!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0812757/comments</url><from>from Haddonfield, IL</from><name>GroovyDoom</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This film is a lot of fun, mostly because it is so very bizarre. It's
about a mad hypnotist who leaves a trail of disfigured beauties in his
wake, women who apparently performed acts of self-mutilation while in a
hypnotic trance. I first saw this on TNT when they ran a series called "100% Weird", and
boy they weren't kidding. This is a camp classic, right down to the
period hairdos and the stereotypical characters (the stupid cops, the
beautiful woman in peril, the suave euro-trash magician, the jealous
woman with a secret). It's a painless experience due to the short running time; in fact,
several scenes are obviously padded in order to make the film
feature-length, such as scenes of an entire audience being hypnotized
and a sequence inside a beatnik jazz club that's a real hoot. It's even
got a Scooby-Doo ending involving a character who tears off a false
face. Unbelievable. There's no way you could take it seriously, and no
way you won't enjoy it either.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4969213/comments</url><from/><name>mrb1980</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
In this surprisingly watchable chiller from 1960, a hypnotist Desmond
(Bergerac) gets his entertainment by having beautiful young women
disfigure themselves in pretty graphic ways—setting their hair on fire,
washing faces with acid, drinking lye, putting their faces in
fans—well, you get the idea. With all of this going on, the local
police send a detective and a police psychologist out to solve the
cases.This movie features undoubtedly the dumbest duo of police officers
ever, detective Steve Kennedy and Dr. Philip Hecht. These two guys are
such idiots that their incompetence is fascinating to watch. At first,
they can't decide whether all of these disfigurement cases are related
(duh!) and spend the rest of the movie trying—sort of—to catch the
perpetrator.The many unintentionally funny scenes include Steve's girlfriend
(Henderson) being kissed and groped by Desmond (while Steve blankly
watches from a distance), the first hypnosis scene ("You are the
meanest of all the dogs!!"), the beatnik bar scene, and the final scene
at a theater, where the "secret" is revealed, but only after the
audience is mesmerized into doing pretty outrageous things—like bad
acting.Released during the hypnosis and beatnik crazes of the early 1960s,
this bizarre movie is an interesting time capsule and stars cult
actress Allison Hayes. Be sure and catch Hecht's (Guy Prescott)
jaw-dropping closing line…it's guaranteed to leave you speechless.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0056994/comments</url><from>from Franklin, VA</from><name>mike1964</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Okay, I realize that's not saying much.  However, this is probably the
best
movie Allison Hayes was in (however, I do very much enjoy the Unearthly,
but
Hayes is terrible in that).Plot concerns a hypnotist (Desmond) who is having beautiful young women
mutilate themselves.  I won't give it away, but the suspense is good and
the
movie isn't gory even though the mutilation methods would lead you to
believe so (washing hair in fire, washing face with sulfuric acid,
brushing
face with fan blades, etc).Hayes plays the evil assistant to Desmond and you're really not sure why
she
and Desmond are evil until the Climax.  Not to be missed!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3005125/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>dphelan-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I just heard Michael J Weldon of Psychotronic Video talk about this on
a podcast interview. It reminded me of the first time I saw this on
television ( sometime in the 1960's I guess) on the late night Friday
Chiller show. The woman burning herself, her hair catching fire, etc.
was really terrifying. The film is kind of a B-Movie horror-noir with
the oily continental Jacques Begerac performing that Hypnotic Eye thing
and causing all manner of mayhem and mutilation. Then there was the
wonderful Allison Hayes just 2 years past The Attack of the 5o Foot
Woman giving another great performance and of course, my favorite,
Merry Andrews from TV's How to Marry a Millionaire. They just don't
make them like this anymore. A campy horror classic!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4888011/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon, USA</from><name>Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
My 10/10 rating of course only applies if you're totally into B-movies
from the era of poodle skirts and pompadours; other people will find
"The Hypnotic Eye" worthless. A previous reviewer said that this movie
is practically impossible to find. Fortunately, I can tell you exactly
where to find it: the 1950s/1960s horror/sci-fi section in Movie
Madness, a video/DVD store in Portland, Oregon.Anyway, here's the plot. Perplexing magician Desmond (Jacques Bergerac)
is hypnotizing young women with an "eye" and getting them to mutilate
themselves; for example, one woman sets her hair on fire. Naturally, a
detective starts investigating, and discovers more than he bargained
for.Overall, it's the average campy flick from that period. The only other
cast member whom I recognized was Allison Hayes, better known as the 50
Ft Woman. As for Jacques Bergerac, he also appeared on "The Dick Van
Dyke Show", and as a villain on the old "Batman" TV series. Speaking of
anything, why's his character named "Desmond"? I only know that name
from "Ob-La-Di, Ob-La-Da" and from Desmond Dekker (RIP). The things
that we see in life.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8243414/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>raggtopp93</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
No one under 40 years of age should be allowed to rate this movie. It
was made for the big screen. The tube takes away from the unique
special effects.Todays audience does not appreciate the days of
non-computer effects. As a teen-age female when I saw it at the
theater, I was shocked (wasn't that the point?) at the horror. Crushed
that a gorgeous hunk like Jacques Bergerac could be the bad guy, and
that spiraling "hypnotic eye" was sooo much more memorable when it was
bigger than the audience.It really came out at you, without it being a
3-D movie . Their advertising claimed it could hypnotize the audience.
Well,of course,it couldn't, but it did have an affect of you. It could
not have been the "bad" movie some sites say it was, if I recall him
and the "eye" after 46 years.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15148330/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>calvinnme</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
... and that's too bad since for schlocky horror at its spartan best
you just can't do any better than 50's and 60's vintage films like this
one, Macabre, and From Hell it Came. This was never intended to compete
with the likes of Universal's Frankenstein.The central issue of the plot is that the great beauties of the town
are mutilating themselves. One puts her face in a running fan, another
washes her face with acid, another shampoos with the flames of a gas
stove. None of the girls remembers doing what they did much less why
they did it. Police detective Steve Kennedy is running into a bunch of
brick walls in his investigation when one night his girl takes him to
see a show featuring a hypnotist. The next day the girl that was with
them during the show, and one of the guests that was invited on stage
as a subject for hypnotism, is found mutilated too. The detective and
his girl begin to suspect the hypnotist, but still the questions remain
- why and more so how, since all of the girls were found alone.The film is full of the kind of stream of consciousness dialogue and
wooden acting that was a trademark of Jim Abrahams and the two Zuckers,
except they were doing this kind of thing on purpose often as a spoof
of these kinds of movies, and in these old B horror films it works
well. Plus this old film is loaded with scenes that were knocking on
the door of breaking down the old production code once and for all such
as Desmond the hypnotist putting his subjects in a sexually receptive
trance so that he can make out with them while a deliberate yet passive
Justine looks on vicariously. The film has been splendidly restored by the Warner Archive, and I
highly recommend that copy as everyone else who is peddling DVDs of the
movie is using third rate unrestored copies. Not just for Halloween,
this one is for anytime you're in the mood for a guilty pleasure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2006263/comments</url><from>from North Carolina</from><name>thefensk</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I wish someone would re-release this, or TCM or somebody would show it.
It was just another really bizarre offering from the late fifties/early
sixties. It used to be a regular on the lat Saturday night TV horror
show in my hometown (in Houston the show was called Weird) and this one
fit the bill--really weird.Cinematic excellence? Surely not. But it was offbeat enough to keep
your attention. Even had a debunker who explained away a lot of the
"magic" for the police (and the viewers).The plot does have an interesting twist with the hypnotist's
girlfriend. Sure it didn't win any academy awards but few movies do.I give it a seven because it falls within the genre of movies that are
so bad they are actually good.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0500549/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>ceamc</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
...this movie remains, given the genre, age, and production values,
eminently watchable.Sure, the plot has holes and incongruities one can drive a Mack truck
through, the acting is for the most part wooden - but it all winds up
being part of the fun. And, it stands out for two other aspects.(WARNING: THE FOLLOWING COMMENTS MAY BE CONSIDERED A SPOILER FOR THOSE
WHO HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE!)On the one hand, the sexual content. Not only Desmond's seduction of
Marcia (although he never gets to, er, consummate it - and it's left in
the open whether or not he managed to do so with his other "subjects"),
but also the relationship between him and Justine. And, of course,
there's the rather equivocal character of the Doc. Nothing explicit or
groundbreaking, but again, in context...Second: we're blissfully spared any detailed explanations, of the
one-trauma-fits-all kind, about the origin of Justine's predicament, or
about her hold over Desmond. Maybe the producers just ran out of
celluloid; whatever the reason, it goes against the grain of the
typical Hollywood movie, B- or otherwise.So, if you can get a copy (good luck...), plant tongue firmly in cheek,
turn the IL' suspension-of-disbelief on and just plain enjoy it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0500549/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>ceamc</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
...this movie remains, given the genre, age, and production values,
eminently watchable.Sure, the plot has holes and incongruities one can drive a Mack truck
through, the acting is for the most part wooden - but it all winds up
being part of the fun. And, it stands out for two other aspects.(WARNING: THE FOLLOWING COMMENTS MAY BE CONSIDERED A SPOILER FOR THOSE
WHO HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE!)On the one hand, the sexual content. Not only Desmond's seduction of
Marcia (although he never gets to, er, consummate it - and it's left in
the open whether or not he managed to do so with his other "subjects"),
but also the relationship between him and Justine. And, of course,
there's the rather equivocal character of the Doc. Nothing explicit or
groundbreaking, but again, in context...Second: we're blissfully spared any detailed explanations, of the
one-trauma-fits-all kind, about the origin of Justine's predicament, or
about her hold over Desmond. Maybe the producers just ran out of
celluloid; whatever the reason, it goes against the grain of the
typical Hollywood movie, B- or otherwise.So, if you can get a copy (good luck...), plant tongue firmly in cheek,
turn the IL' suspension-of-disbelief on and just plain enjoy it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>