<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Austerlitz</original_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><country>Yugoslavia</country><country>Liechtenstein</country><director>Abel Gance</director><producer>Compagnie Internationale de Productions Cinématographiques (CIPRA)</producer><producer>Lyre Films</producer><producer>Galatea Film</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
Another of Napoleon's adventures in this epic reconstruction of the battle of Austerlitz, where he had the greatest victory of his career, over the Russians.
</synopsis><actor>Pierre Mondy</actor><actor>Martine Carol</actor><actor>Claudia Cardinale</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0361658/comments</url><from>from Sacramento, CA</from><name>Miyagis_Sweaty_wifebeater (sirjosephu@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Austerlitz (1960) was the battle that made Napoleon Bonaparte not only
one of western civilization's greatest generals, but it solidify his
position as Napoleon I "The Emperor of France". I saw this film many
years ago on video. The colors were washed out and it was cropped big
time. Besides these faults, the movie was great. If there's a movie
that needs to be restored it's this one. A film of this magnitude and
the grand scale it was presented on needs to be shown it is original
glory.NAPOLEON was restored recently. It's only fitting that the film that
the same director spent his entire life on have one of it's sequels be
remastered and preserved in the same way.Highly recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0447092/comments</url><from/><name>delbruk</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

I believe the reason after so many votes that no one has decided to offer
a
review of this film is because it appears so hard to define it as a film.
This is much more a tedious, detailed account of Napoleon's victory at
the
battle of Austerlitz. The film focuses so much on the strategic
underpinnings of the battle that is almost seems more like watching a
risk
or stratego game than a film. From the political maneuvering of how the
French and Russian forces came to the battle to the strategic genius that
was Napoleon this film does not offer much in the way of character
development, acting, or even special effects. What the film does offer is
a
historical recount of how battles were fought in the early 19th century.
The
only interesting cinematic points of interest is to look for a young Jack
Palance as a Russian General and a scene stealing Orson Welles as an
American inventor. Also this was one of the last films directed by the
French "DW Griffith" - Abel Gance.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10879013/comments</url><from>from CGSM, Soseaua Nationala 49</from><name>Cristi_Ciopron</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I will begin by saying that I enjoyed enormously "Austerlitz"'s second
part,that is,the military show as such.The political preamble is
interesting by many things:Pierre Mondy's acting (though a miscast),the
many good cameos (we have Mrs. Caron,Mrs. Cardinale,Mrs. Popesco,
Palance, Marais,Simon,Trintignant,Welles,Pavloff,Jean Mercure in the
same show,and at their best),many well-thought scenes,the
cinematographic thinking of Gance,the script's sobriety in the
treatment of the Bonaparte family (arrogance,vanity,etc.). I cannot but
admire the choice of the bit parts.Many vignettes are ANTHOLOGICAL
(e.g.,the Pope calling Bonaparte a comedian).No cheap jokes.The script is unconventional,dense and considerate. Napoleon appears as
a peevish, tetchy, burlesque, selfish,petulant, aggressive and endowed
man (this portrait is very fair and balanced,and,if ironical and
humorist, it is not at all disrespectful, heinous, outrageous--it is
not a cartoon);his family:a bevy of greedy pushers,arrogant, vain
parvenus, coarse intriguers, cads. The pettiness and the misery do not
lack in Bonaparte's life.His sweetheart is a dowdy.I liked a lot the costumes,the clothes,the uniforms.Gance makes parade before our pleased eyes a series of expressive
figurines,exquisitely molded (Carnot, Talleyrand,Kutuzov, Fulton,Mlle
De Vaudey,Madame Récamier,Weirother,Lannes,Pius VII,etc.,etc.).The women in this movie (Mrs. Caron,Mrs. Cardinale,Mrs. Elvire Popesco)
are radiant and brilliant.The more I think about "Austerlitz",the more I perceive its greatness
and value."Austerlitz" must be tasted,but also thought about,analyzed.
It satisfies both the heart and mind.For me,"Austerlitz" is one of the most amazing,though imperfect,
masterpieces.This movie has its flaws;it also has obvious qualities and is worth
watching .Practically,all the cameos are exceptional,a real feast:first
of all,Marais and Simon,and also Wells,a very young Trintignant,Palance
(it is quite debatable if Palance's histrionic performance is really
that kitsch and tasteless;I think he was just playing Russian,though
his role is that of an Austrian,and he succeeded in creating some funny
moments in the movie;I enjoy what Palance did with his role:it's
buffoonish,but also fun),etc..Marais is a standout,simply astonishing.
The same is true about Jean Mercure (as "Talleyrand") and Polycarpe
Pavloff (as "Kutuzov").Pierre Mondy is an obviously skilled actor,but a miscast as
Bonaparte.His ingrate physique does not help him this way.In the first
part,that of the political rise of Napoleon,Pierre Mondy looks
choleric,roguish,voluntary,brutal,mocking,irascible,clownish enough;but
he can't look inspired,exceptional,larger-than-life.Maybe this is not
Bonaparte,but is a well-made role.Undoubtedly,Pierre Mondy knows his
job;but his performing is,sometimes,theatrical,and rather inadequate
for cinema.A pleasant surprise is "Austerlitz"'s realism and irony,its
lack of idolatry and of inhibitions:we see the Bonaparte family as it
was,a bevy of parvenus and cads.Gance does not incense Bonaparte's holy cards,does not extol him
measureless.On the contrary,the script shows a powerful,able,sharp and
temperate mind.In "Austerlitz"'s first part,that might be entitled "Napoleon's rising"
,some actors play stiffly ,are theatrical and formal,obsolete and worn
out,the movie recalls the scene.But the cameos (Marais,Simon,
Trintignant,Pavloff) bring in a vast amount of exciting and
largehearted acting.I guess the first part of "Austerlitz" was intended as a prologue,a
preparation,a political and historical preface.The society depicted was a theatrical and quite cold one;still,the
THEATRALISM of some of the performances displeases.Even the theatrical
characters must be performed lively.Simon's performance (as "Auboise") simply sweeps away anyone else on
the set;his comic role is a great landmark in the history of cinema.I am a huge fan of this second part of "Austerlitz";its photography is
excellent:a gorgeous looking film .I also enjoyed a lot the cameos from
Marais,Simon,De Sica (flawless!!!),Mrs. Elvire Popesco,Wells,Marchal
(though not very remarkable here).This fresco must be rehabilitated urgently.Any national cinematography would take pride in a movie like
"Austerlitz". But I guess many don't get this film's greatness, nor
Gance's showmanship and taste.Finally,I will add that Bloy held Bonaparte in high esteem;so did
Hegel,Balzac, Stendhal,and even,in his youth,Schopenhauer.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
...and to "Napoleon" whose life Gance transferred to the screen in the
silent era.Sandwiched between two very underrated Gance works ("la Tour
de Nesles" and "Cyrano et D'Artagnan" )it is a return to "real " "true"
history.I will go as far as to write that Gance impressed me much more
when his movies dealt with fictionalized history (the two mentioned
movies,but "j'accuse" too)."Austerlitz has something academic
,conventional.It has nothing of Gance's madness.The first part is a
stream of stars from Martine Carol to Claudia Cardinale ,from Jean
Marais to Orson Welles (in a part which reminds us how Gance was
interested in the development of science through the centuries ,à la
Jules Verne,we find this interest in "Cyrano" and "J'accuse" too).THe
lead is a good actor but he might be ,on an international level, the
least known of them all:Pierre Mondy's name is buried in the cast and
credits and although he is on the screen from the beginning to the
end,his name is not bigger than that of Welles who appears barely five
minutes.Ah fame! The first part has only one sequence where we find
back the inventive Gance:we do not attend the coronation in Notre Dame
;the marechal de Ségur (Jean-Louis Trintignant) tells the whole story
with the model in front of a strange audience:servants ;then the "mamma
" ("pourvu que ça dure!=lets hope it lasts!") ,Napoleon's mother
(Elvire Popesco) enters and her tears begin to flow .Although David put
her in his famous painting she did not attend the ceremony.The second part is more historically interesting ,but if you are not
fond of military strategy ,you may stop yourself yawning.Fortunately a
soldier of the old guard of Napoléon (un "grognard" )played by Michel
Simon brings a bit of life among these troop movements.Last but not least:I have always asked myself why a convinced pacifist
such as Gance (his two versions of "j'accuse" may be the strongest
anti-war films ever)could be so fascinated by a warrior such as
Napoleon.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2575875/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, California</from><name>francophile50</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

My review of this film can be summed up in five words a brilliant work of
art.As described in the previous description the film itself is long and
sometimes tedious.What it fails to mention is that it was created by the
same Director that brought us the Silent film about Napoleon Abel
Gance.The
film is in colour and is very faithful to the feel of Napoleon and the
time
he ruled Europe.It is primarily about the greatest victory Napoleon
achieved
in his career,however it also touches on many of the events in his life
leading up to that moment including his coronation as Emperor of
France.If
you are a student of Napoleon or French history or this time period you
will
enjoy this picture.Shot all throughout Europe in the fifties in many
languages it remains in my opinion as the greatest picture chronicling
Napoleon and his life.The film not only tells a story from his
perspective
but many others as well.It is difficult to find and even more expensive
to
own but I definitely recommend you see it at least once for
yourself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9135710/comments</url><from>from Norway</from><name>MacBobby</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This movie is a huge disappointment. You'd expect the battle of
Austerlitz to be the core subject as the title suggests, but it's not.
Most of the movie is about the Napoleonic era before the battle, with a
pseudo historic perspective. If you know just a little about history,
you'll find yourself yawning most of the time, as Abel Gance tries to
describe the situation for hours, through endless dialogs. Then when
Napoleon is about to be crowned, you think: oh no, not another half
hour just for that scene. Fortunately there's no coronation scene,
but.. worse: it's told! You guess correctly: Gance didn't have the
budget to do it. He might as well just skipped the whole episode. By then you've waited more than 2 hours and still no battle in sight.
At last the battle comes but what you see is a tragic waste. The
tactics and whereabouts of the battle are not shown but told, and you
can hardly understand what's going on. A cavalry charges from right to
left (a couple hundred horses), and you assume it's the Austrian
cavalry. Then you're told that they're defeated by the French, and you
see the same guys charging from left to right (they don't even seem to
have switched costumes). Parts of the battle were filmed in studio,
with ridiculous painted backgrounds. The close combat scenes are
unrealistic at best. Soldiers fall apparently for no reason, and if
nobody told you about the outcome, you wouldn't know who won or lost.
The last scene with the French Army singing the national anthem
completes the cinematographic disaster.All in all, you sit back with the feeling that this movie was conceived
and shot in the early days of movie making, not in 1960: it's not a
movie about Austerlitz, it's the pathetic attempt of an aging man
trying to describe the glory of an emperor he admired. The result is a
boring picture that doesn't even enhance our historic understanding of
the Napoleon era (in spite of Gance's attempts to stick to some
historic details).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4814799/comments</url><from>from Russian Federation</from><name>dkaravaev53</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Concerning depiction of the Russian army in 1805 (historical figures,
uniform, people's manners in the military camp and at the battlefield)
this film of Gance is somewhat of a cabaret performance. Alexandre I is
a kind of a funny mask, Koutouzov - even worse. Russians' uniform and
Cossack dances are acceptable for some carnival but certainly not for
the historical reconstruction. Above all there is an obvious comic
accent in this movie, even in the main episode of the battle. Though
the script is not bad being based on the reliable historical source
(memoirs of the count Segur) the figure of Napoleon is also ridiculous
in some scenes (I wonder why do French actors like to show him as a
character of "comedia del Arte"?). To make my claims more motivated I
recommend you to compare this "Austerlitz" with the appropriate episode
in "War and Peace" by Sergey Bondarchuk - much more dramatic, serious,
large-scaled and true in details.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11280033/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>brad_and_ethan</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Oh great... Another arrogant Frenchmen. So when will YOU ignorant
Frenchmen stop judging Americans? I just watched the dubbed version of
this atrocious film, and I can tell you right now that watching it in
the original French wouldn't make a difference. This movie is MEDIOCRE
at best. All the French comments are biased. Oh, mais oui - it's a
French film so it must be good! WRONG!! Whatever Gance had way back
when when he made Napoleon - he lost it. Napoleon's character is so
dismal in this film. He just struts around with his hands clasped
behind his back, acting like a little child. I know that he probably
had outbursts, but there's little or no attempt to get inside this
man's head/heart and add some depth to him. It's interesting to compare
this film to Waterloo with Rod Steiger. So-so battle scenes with a
lousy drama. The scenes in both films come across as anemic. So
Frenchy, be careful with the films you tout.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11280033/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>brad_and_ethan</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Oh great... Another arrogant Frenchmen. So when will YOU ignorant
Frenchmen stop judging Americans? I just watched the dubbed version of
this atrocious film, and I can tell you right now that watching it in
the original French wouldn't make a difference. This movie is MEDIOCRE
at best. All the French comments are biased. Oh, mais oui - it's a
French film so it must be good! WRONG!! Whatever Gance had way back
when when he made Napoleon - he lost it. Napoleon's character is so
dismal in this film. He just struts around with his hands clasped
behind his back, acting like a little child. I know that he probably
had outbursts, but there's little or no attempt to get inside this
man's head/heart and add some depth to him. It's interesting to compare
this film to Waterloo with Rod Steiger. So-so battle scenes with a
lousy drama. The scenes in both films come across as anemic. So
Frenchy, be careful with the films you tout.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11280033/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>brad_and_ethan</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/austerlitz/review/125964 /m/battle_of_austerlitz/comments.php?reviewid=1689187</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/4
					</rating><comment>If the name of Abel Gance isn't reason enough to rent the film, then how about a cast that includes Orson Welles, Claudia Cardinale, Michel Simon, Vittorio De Sica, Jean Marais, Jack Palance, and Leslie Caron?</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/trevor-johnston/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/78321/austerlitz.html /m/battle_of_austerlitz/comments.php?reviewid=1689186</url><name>Trevor Johnston</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Silent-cinema genius he may well have been, but by this time in his career Abel Gance was creatively a shadow of his former self.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=100686 /m/battle_of_austerlitz/comments.php?reviewid=1689185</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>This lengthy, academic and stilted pageant is made watchable only by familiar faces in the cast.</comment></review></movie>