<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La ciociara</original_title><imdb_rating>7.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Vittorio De Sica</director><producer>Compagnia Cinematografica Champion</producer><producer>Cocinor</producer><producer>Les Films Marceau</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
Cesira and her 13-year-old daughter, Rosetta, flee from the allied bombs in Rome during the second world war...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Sophia Loren</actor><actor>Jean-Paul Belmondo</actor><actor>Raf Vallone</actor><rt_rating>8.6/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Rosetta (Eleanora Brown) is in love with Michele, a student known as
The Professor (Jean-Paul Belmondo)... but Michele is attracted by
Cesira (Sophia Loren) mother of Rosetta...As the Allies were near, and the bombardment more intense, running and
frightened German Soldiers compelled Michelle by the force of arms to
show them the road in order to escape through the mountains...Cesira decides to return to Rome with Rosetta...On their way, completely tired and distressed, they took shelter in a
bombed-out church... There, they looked for some protection... They
didn't know what was expecting them inside the walls of the holly
church, in the shadow, in the darkness...From a sex symbol to a talented actress, Sophia gave the tragic
performance of her life—a mother in despair... Her solemn, profound,
significant face, her tears and hatred, reflected the horror of War...
Her formidable dramatic performance won her an Oscar in 1962... She
also won her critical Awards in Cannes, England and New York..."La Ciociara" (Two Women) is a tribute to a great filmmaker... Sica's
description of the portrait of the misfortune widow and her daughter in
1943 wartime Italy is certainly effective and powerful...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0509769/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I acquired this movie quite a few years a go and only just had my first
viewing and was frankly astonished at Sophia's performance.  It is a
multi-layered rich performance: her anger at men, her absolute devotion to
her daughter, the sadness and acceptance at being a widow of a passionless
marriage to a much older man, her confusion at awakening feelings of
sensuality, her politicization. The last 30 minutes of this movie are
heartbreaking, her horror, helplessness and numbness at what has happened
to
her daughter are some of the most powerful moments I have seen on film.  A
well deserved Oscar and Sophia, you are right up there with the gifted
actors of the past century! 10 out of 10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1198449/comments</url><from>from Plattsmouth, NE</from><name>Jeremy Bristol</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

10/10I'm not sure how much I'm being influenced by my affinity for Isao
Takahata's "Hotaru no Haka"--another great movie about non-soldiers hurt in
their own country--but "Two Women" really sticks in my mind as a terrific
example of normal characters dealing with extraordinary
circumstances.(Possible Spoilers) Some have commented that the rape at the end seemed
forced and that there wasn't enough time afterwards to deal with their
emotions (after all, rape is a horrific, scarring event and there are entire
movies devoted the the aftermath of rape), and at first I agreed.  However,
this isn't a movie about rape or even about war, exactly.  What you have is
the relationship between a mother and a daughter, and how the war almost
broke them apart.  Sophia Loren's character is a fairly strong-willed widow
who doesn't shy away from sex but doesn't seem to enjoy it, either.  She has
a different opinion on how her daughter should act, and she tries to shelter
her daughter from sex and men.  It's a classic case of "Do as I say, not as
I do," taken to an emotional peak not with the rape, but with the very last
scene, when the two women fight about the silk stockings a young man gave
the daughter after the dance.This is an incredible movie that should be available in a higher quality DVD
than the Madacy version.  Anyway, see it and "Hotaru no Haka" back-to-back
to see how WWII affected everyday people from "enemy" countries.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1106800/comments</url><from>from Minnesota, USA</from><name>khann003</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Sophia loren, undoubtedly and unarguably has delivered the greatest
performance in the history of movie. Her performance as the widowed mother
of a teen age girl in this movie that depicted the horrors of the second
great war was absolutely heart-felt and perfect. Rarely can one actor or
actress possibly rise to such occasion to deliver a performance of such
magnitude. It demands pure talent. Full credit to the directing great Mr. De
sica for his creation. Should be watched in its original version to get the
best of it. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1615892/comments</url><from>from boston, ma</from><name>amantsdupontneuf</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

very sad film by vittorio de sica (famed director of "the bicycle
thief.") the first two thirds of the film move slowly, but it's still very
engrossing. the final third of the film is pure cinematic tragedy. sophia
loren won the oscar for best performance for a lead actress in this movie,
and i beleive that she dearly deserved it. prior to seeing "two women" i
had
no idea what a terrific actress she was. her role as the mother desperately
trying to shield her daughter from the horrors of the world is one of the
finest that i have ever seen. this is a truly heartbreaking and beautiful
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Sophia Loren became the first player to win an Acting Oscar for a
foreign language film in Two Women or La Ciociara in her native Italy.
She plays the title role here, the other woman being her daughter
played in La Ciociara by Eleanora Brown.The story here is a relatively simple one, Sophia and Eleanora leave
Rome due to the bombing of Rome just prior to the Allied invasion of
Italy. The political situation is in one state of flux to put it
mildly. In a matter of days, Benito Mussolini was overthrown and
General Badoglio put in charge of the government. But the Nazis
suspecting something was afoot sent in troops and met the Allies in a
pitched 21 day battle at Salerno which like Waterloo was a close run
thing.At one point Jean-Paul Belmondo asks a couple of stray British
paratroopers who landed way up behind enemy lines why the Allies didn't
land in Rome. In fact they almost did land an army there, but
Eisenhower canceled the landing at the last moment and probably saved a
lot of lives doing so.But this isn't about great battles, it's about Two Women just trying to
survive the ravages of war in the best way they can. Sophia decides
their best place is in her old village, south towards Naples. Before
the film ends, she's given plenty of reason to rethink that decision.Sophia was the Best Actress in 1961 for this film and for reasons I
don't understand it was not given any other Oscar nominations,
including for Best Foreign Language Film and for Best Director for
Vittorio DeSica. If La Ciociara has a fault it's that it's Sophia's show totally. The
village characters and that of her one time lover Raf Vallone are left
undeveloped. Only the daughter and young intellectual Belmondo who
falls for the earthy Sophia seem to be on the verge of becoming three
dimensional.The subject matter could never have been done in an American studio
with the Code still firmly in place. I remember back in the day La
Ciociara was shown at the art house circuit and many young juveniles
considered it a mark of daring to get in and see Sophia Loren expose
more than her American films had done up to that time.Sophia Loren deserved that Oscar, every bit of it. And you'll agree if
you see La Ciociara.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0940861/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>LeRoyMarko</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Very bad print (even on DVD), but very good movie. A war film that
focuses more on the people who suffer, instead of telling the story of
those fighting the battle. It's also a movie about love, relationship,
bonding between a woman and her daughter. Sophia Loren's performance is
stellar. Belmondo is also very good. Young Eleonora Brown's performance
gets better during the film. The last 30 minutes of the movie are
poignant. It's heartbreaking to listen to Cesira apologize to Rosetta.
Watch it.Seen at home, in Toronto, on February 19th, 2006.81/100 (***)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
***SPOILERS*** Set in 1943 war torn Italy the movie "Two Women" is
about a mother and daughter leaving Rome for the , what they think,
safety of the countryside and going back to their little village in the
hills and mountains in the Agro Pontino area just north of Rome. Sophia Loren in a somewhat non-glamorous role as Cesira a shop owner in
the Italian capital who's estranged from her husband and is, at the
time that we first meet her, having an affair with local food
distributor Giovanni, Ralf Vallone. Taking care of her shy teenage
daughter Rosetta, Eleanor Brown, Cesira has had enough of the almost
daily and deadly bombing by the USAAF and RAF and leaves the city with
her daughter by train for her home town. There's trouble almost as soon
as the train leaves the city with it being derailed by an Allied air
attack. Leaving the disabled train and on foot both Cesira and Rosetta
make it to the village after they survive an air attack by a USAAF
fighter that killed a farmer who was walking on the same road with
them. After getting to the village things are more or less peaceful, with the
war just an old and bitter memory, with Cesira meeting and falling in
love with the local intellectual as well as socialist young collage
student Michele,Jean-Paul Belmondo, who even young Rosetta takes a
strong liking to. The almost forgotten war slowly catches up with
Cesira and Rosetta and the people at the small village as the Allied
forces break through the German lines and reach the outskirts of Rome.
It soon becomes too dangerous for the village people to stay and they
start to leave and go south to the Italian capital city which is now in
US/Allied hands. Before this happened a squad of German soldiers
entered the town and took Michele with them as a guide through the
dangerous hills and valleys of the Argo Pontino.On their way to Rome the two women, Cesira &amp; Rosetta, stop off at a
bombed out church to get some rest and are later set upon by a group of
French Colonial Moroccan troops. The Moroccans brutally beat and gang
raped them leaving young Rosetta almost mute with fear and shame of
what happened to her and her mother. Getting back on their way to the
Italian capital Cesira &amp; Rosetta are both picked up by a local truck
driver Firindo, Renato Salvatore. Stoping off at a small town outside
of Rome that night Rosetta who seemed to have completely lost her mind,
since she and her mother were raped, sneaks out of the room that she
sharing with Cesira and has an affair with the truck driver. This both
sickened and outrages her already distraught mother. The movie ends
with Cesira getting the terrible news that her lover Michele was shot
and killed by the Germans as we later see both mother and daughter
alone in their small room arm in arm crying and consoling each other as
the movie slowly fades to black.Sophia Loren rightfully who got an Academy Award as best actress for
1961 in the role of Cesira was both feisty as well as touching as the
long suffering Italian mom. The vicious rape scene in the bombed out
church of Cesira and Rosetta was not only graphic and shocking. By
having this outrage committed by the liberating allied troops instead
of the occupying German soldiers it showed that there's nothing good
that comes out of war on either side.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8075900/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>  (tooter.ted@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I gave this film 9/10 while understanding its weaknesses. First, as
others note, the print is the worst I've ever encountered sometimes
turning faces into gray pudding, but the problem was not so great to
keep me from responding fully to the film's power, and I decided to
evaluate the film rather than the print. I have more serious concerns
about events at the film's climax which raise issues which are resolved
too quickly. In fact these issues might be the subject of a whole new
film, and if treated here they would require another hour of play time.
The films hasty resolution of these issues makes important behaviors
seem poorly motivated and unbelievable. However, the issues in question
are not the central issues of the movie. When Cesira apologizes to her
daughter (and at other points) I was left sobbing in spite of the
film's failure to properly address the daughter's final trauma. This is
not a about recovering from trauma. Rather, it is a film about human
fallibility and self-deception or, as Michele puts it, "You can't
escape, not even from yourself." Cesira faults others while never
examining her own behavior. Like those around her, she acts only to
preserve her own immediate interests. At the other extreme. Michele's
idealism prevents him from realizing his own humanity. Only Rosetta
demonstrates the purity to see beyond self-interest, and the instinct
to truly tell right from wrong. Her downfall is the tragedy of the
film. Yet through all of this the film shows us how, when pushed to
extremes, these people are capable of forging deep human bonds. Such
bonds have the power to redeem all as they finally redeem Rosetta. I
can't conclude without adding my own appreciation for Sophia Loren's
extraordinary performance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Italian shopkeeper Sophia Loren flees her war-ravaged city with her
frail teenage daughter for a neighboring village to stay with
relatives, but on the journey home, their lives are cruelly disrupted
when the woman and her child are cornered by lusty soldiers. Loren's
character is sensual and maybe loose, but she's never insensitive and
one immediately feels a connection with her (and you can't take your
eyes off her when she's on-screen). This is a perceptive drama, not so
much a document on the horrors of war as it is a testament to the human
condition, both good and bad, weak and strong. There are some lovely
art-house flourishes and bits of humor dotting the script, but the film
doesn't have a gripping, lasting impact, it doesn't stay with you or
haunt you the way a timeless drama should. Loren passionately emotes
and won a well-deserved Oscar, but the other performances are just
serviceable; she dominates the proceedings. **1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Italian shopkeeper Sophia Loren flees her war-ravaged city with her
frail teenage daughter for a neighboring village to stay with
relatives, but on the journey home, their lives are cruelly disrupted
when the woman and her child are cornered by lusty soldiers. Loren's
character is sensual and maybe loose, but she's never insensitive and
one immediately feels a connection with her (and you can't take your
eyes off her when she's on-screen). This is a perceptive drama, not so
much a document on the horrors of war as it is a testament to the human
condition, both good and bad, weak and strong. There are some lovely
art-house flourishes and bits of humor dotting the script, but the film
doesn't have a gripping, lasting impact, it doesn't stay with you or
haunt you the way a timeless drama should. Loren passionately emotes
and won a well-deserved Oscar, but the other performances are just
serviceable; she dominates the proceedings. **1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=16350 /m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=1926889</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>Rendering an astounding performance as a young widow in Vittiro De Sica's bleak neo-realistic WWII drama, Italian Sophia Loren became the first actress to (deservedly) win the Oscar for a role in a foreign-language film.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-hall/</url><url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=features&amp;Id=2345 /m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=1837815</url><name>Phil Hall</name><from>Film Threat</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>A powerful experience to behold, and one of De Sica's finest films.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/twowomen1961.htm /m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=1521101</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>A bleak but powerful anti-war drama.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=1332394</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Staggering story, outstanding acting, particularly Loren.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lori-hoffman/</url><url>/m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=1638692</url><name>Lori Hoffman</name><from>Atlantic City Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=1341053</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/ddb5490109a79f598625623d0015f1e4/2844d63c1a78667b88256cc600621870?OpenDocument /m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=840916</url><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/don-druker/</url><url>http://onfilm.chireader.com/MovieCaps/T/TW/08723_TWO_WOMEN.html /m/1022238-two_women/comments.php?reviewid=20247</url><name>Don Druker</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>