<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Dama s sobachkoj</original_title><alt_title>La dame au petit chien</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Soviet Union</country><director>Iosif Kheifits</director><producer>Lenfilm Studio</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
In the Nineteenth Century, at the seaside resort of Yalta, the upper class Dimitri Gurov from Moscow meets Anna Sergeyovna walking with her little dog...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Iya Savvina</actor><actor>Aleksey Batalov</actor><actor>Nina Alisova</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2598607/comments</url><from>from Leusden, Holland</from><name>Wout Visser (wrvisser-leusden-nl)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This movie ranks among the masterpieces of Soviet film art.Really everything is good here: the acting, the shots, the timing, the
scenery and its tale. Taken from a very famous short story by Chekhov, one
of Russia's greatest writers. 'Dama s sobachkoj' reflects its very Russian
character well: infinite boredom, caused by life in an endlessly large
country with a harsh climate and a very monotonuous landscape.The plot of this movie is timed at the end of the 19th century, an era
when
in Europe divorce was socially disastrous for your life, status and
career.
For this reason the lovers Sergueevna and Gourov cannot get together, thus
being forced to consider in full the fate of their unhappy marriages and
their missed chances in life.It will not surprise you that the pace of this movie is slow. Maybe too
slow
for Western taste, even back in 1960. Anyway, its slowness provides you
with
plenty of opportunity to enjoy the magnificent shots from this very
Russian
movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
In the Nineteenth Century, at the seaside resort of Yalta, the upper
class Dimitri Gurov (Aleksey Batalov) from Moscow meets Anna Sergeyovna
(Iya Savvina) walking with her little dog. Both have unhappy marriages:
Dimitri has a marriage of convenience arranged by the family when he
was a college boy and Anna married a lackey for love that has gone, and
they have a love affair.When Anna returns to Saratov and Dimitri to Moscow, he has a boring
life at home, spending his time working and going to the club after
hours alone to drink and play cards with his friends. On Christmas,
Dimitri misses Anna and lies to his wife, telling that he has a
business trip to Saint Petersburg. However, he heads to Saratov and he
meets Anna in the Opera House with her husband. Their love kindles and
Anna promises to meet him in Moscow. In a period when divorce would be
unthinkable, Anna and Dimitri are doomed to meet each other in hotel
rooms."Dama s Sobachkoj" is a classy and melancholic love story by Iosif
Kheifits based on a short story by Anton Chekhov. The film is developed
in slow pace, with magnificent black and white cinematography and music
score. Iya Savvina has one of the prettiest faces I have ever seen and it is
easy to explain the initial attraction of Dimitri for Anna. Each frame
is magnificently shot in beautiful planes and details. The DVD released
by the Brazilian distributor Cult Classic is totally restored with
perfect image and sound. My vote is eight.Title (Brazil): "A Dama do Cachorrinho" ("The Lady of the Little Dog")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2213339/comments</url><from>from Sofia, Bulgaria</from><name>insightflow</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The first classic trait of the film which captures the senses, is the
outstanding cinematography - as one viewer notes, in the best
traditions of silent film. Indeed, too much is left unspoken by the
characters. Everything's a delicate and delightful play of fine
sensations - a feast for the intelligent viewer whose thread through
the labyrinth of characters' feelings is often a glimpse, a twitch, and
a seemingly inconsequent line in Chekhov's text. A great burden lies on
the shoulder's of the two main actors, Batalov and Savina. While the
former does a brilliant job, the latter, in my opinion, is classes
underneath. She is fit to play a typical Soviet-era character, not
Chekhov's.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4174632/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tintin-23</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The "Lady with the Little Dog" is arguably Chekhov's best short story,
and probably one of the greatest short stories ever written. I realize
this is quite a statement to make, but, notwithstanding my opinion, it
has been also the opinion of countless literary critics since the
publication of the story. The challenge to faithfully render it on the
screen was indeed a daunting task, but Heifitz, sure of himself, went
ahead with the adaptation of "The Lady with the Little Dog," an
intimidating task, and succeeded. Of course, it did not hurt that
Heifitz had been a great admirer of Chekhov's work since his childhood,
and considered him his mentor. And of course, nobody without a
"velikaya russkaya dusha," a great Russian soul, could have rendered
this work. To a Russian, his soul is something more than what a
Westerner drags to church on Sundays and holidays. It is hard to
explain the Russian soul, but as they say, I cannot tell you what it is
but I know it when I see it.Andrei Moskvin and Dmitry Meskhiyev's black and white photography is
exquisite in rendering the atmosphere of the film, starting in its
opening with the lethargic atmosphere of Yalta, the snowy Moscow
winter, or the pathetic, frozen atmosphere of its conclusion. Heitfitz'
succeeds at reproducing Chekhov's style and symbols. As rapid cuttings
distinguish the story's narrative technique, the camera often jumps to
new scenes without warning. These cuts and jumps through time give a
sense of the suddenness and unexpectedness of Anna and Gurov's illicit
love affair, their falling in love, their settling into their new life,
where much has to be improvised to maintain the relationship. Nature
and the sea are important symbols in Chekhov's work and are portrayed
in the film through lyrical long shots of the sea at sunset and the
nearby hills at Yalta. The two protagonists sit silently, reflecting
from their vantage point on the birth of their love affair, lost in the
continuum of eternity."…Yes, when you stop to think, the whole world is wonderful --
everything, except what we ourselves think and do when we forget the
higher aims of existence and our human dignity" says Gurov.Heitfitz uses a variety of shots appropriate for each scene. Close
shots and close ups emphasize the moments of psychological drama. The
dialogue is, as in Chekhov, minimal, and never more than is necessary.
Only few words convey the emotional complexity of the characters,
preserving the intensity of their feelings.As with Chekhov, the Yalta seduction scene in Anna's room, or any of
the intimate scenes later on, is not shown. In that respect,
Chekhov/Heifitz followed the Russian mores of the time, knowing full
well that had Chekhov dared to innovate, it would have never passed the
censor's pen. One also notes the great care taken with the period
details, such as costumes, carriages, and the physiognomy of the
actors.The acting of the two main characters, Iya Savvina and Aleksei Batalov,
is "on the mark." She is young, fragile, and innocent, and he,
reserved, sophisticated, and aristocratic. Anna was Savvina's first
role. She went on to appear in twenty-seven more films, her last one,
Trotsky, in 1993. Batalov has appeared in more than thirty-four films,
including "Moscow Does Not Believe in Tears" (1979). The other two
lesser characters appear only briefly: Nina Alisova, as Gurov's wife is
sullen, and Pantelejmon Krymov in the role of Anna's husband, indeed
looks like a "lackey." The lyrical music by Nadezhda Simonian, like the
dialogue, is used relatively sparingly. A romantic love theme appears
throughout the film with different tempi, underscoring the different
situations, and in several scene transitions.The themes of this film are love, and the Russian society in the late
19th century. "The Lady with the Little Dog" is a love story between
two people who started in life on the wrong footing, for whatever
reasons, as most of us do. To understand the story, we have to
speculate as to what had happened to these two characters before the
story opens. She is an aristocratic Russian woman, and thus was
destined to marry, for love if she was lucky, but most likely without
love, just to fulfill her role in society, to raise a family and be the
centerpiece of that family. So, Anna followed her destiny. Gurov is an
older aristocrat, from the big city, a well-established member of the
Moscovite society, married with children. He is a man, and therefore in
(relative) control of his life, and as a man of his time, looks down on
women, but at the same time, enjoys their companionship. For that
epoch, at forty years of age, he is at the twilight of his womanizing
years.Anna and Gurov meet and start an intimate relationship, each for a
different reason. Anna wants to escape her boring, dreary small town
provincial life. To Gurov, Anna may represent one of his last chances,
if not the very last, to seduce a young woman who will rejuvenate him,
invigorate his life. His life is turned upside down, as the seducer is
himself seduced, hoisted upon his own petard. But love does not rescue
Anna and Gurov from their stale marriages, nor does it improve their
lives. Of course, divorce at that time and in that society was totally
out of the question. At the end of the film, nothing is said about
their future. It would seem that their relationship may continue, with
their occasional assignations in seedy hotels, a couple caught "…like a
pair of birds of passage. They've been caught and forced into separate
cages." (Anna). Neither of them is brave or strong enough to fly free,
"It seemed that in a little while a solution would offer itself, a new,
lovely life would begin." (Gurov) This short story, which Heifitz rendered flawlessly on the screen, is
among Chekhov's most poignant and lyrical.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8719213/comments</url><from/><name>Fpi</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
In my opinion, there are at least two kinds of melancholia. One has to
do with a low level of passion and few, muddled emotions. Melancholia
could, however, also be about truly passionate emotions of sadness and
longing. There is a huge difference between the two, and they often
seem to be confused. This movie is definitely about the passionate
sadness and longing - at least it communicates some of the most
outrageously passionate longing I've ever witnessed on film. Whoever
thought "fast" automatically means "more passionate" was apparently
dead wrong. There's also something realistic and very human about the
characters. If you've lived for a while you've met people like these,
and you may yourself have experienced (or even dreamt) similar
situations. I felt immense pity for the characters, in my opinion a
great achievement for any movie. Even if it's a film with "love"
playing an important part, I felt it was innovative - this is simply
unique stuff. I'll not give away too much of the story - go see this
outstanding movie for yourself!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10879013/comments</url><from>from CGSM, Soseaua Nationala 49</from><name>Cristi_Ciopron</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
THE LADY … is an exquisite and flawless piece of superior art; ah, you
admirer of cinema, if you fall in love with such movies do not expect,
pray you, to find many others alike. It's a movie of flawless taste—not
even one single false note! On the contrary, the most delicious and
nuanced and fluent harmony …. Oh, such movies disgust you of anything
else—now, think only if it's wise and truly advisable ….It's also the simplest of movies, about love and life; a white flame.
Only the simplest and very best things—nothing peculiar, strident or
whimsical.This is the lightest art; the difficulty of its achievement is proved
by the rarity of such masterpieces. Heifitz did not win a truly
outstanding celebrity; yet, he should have had.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3511584/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (steve@esrati.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I admired the fact that the director paid such close attention to local
detail that he included several scenes to point out the Moslem presence
in Yalta (some 20% of the people are Tartars). There is a scene in
which two touristy looking males order drinks in the hotel and then
stick a pinkie into their glasses. This is a custom among westernized
Turks who wish to follow the Koran's admonition that "the first drop of
alcohol shall not pass your lips." So the first drop is removed. Then
the coachman does his prayers while waiting for the lovers. And a
mother is shown wearing a birka as the children are drilled in their
Russian declensions. My fedora is tipped for him.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Dama s sobachkoy" or "The Lady With the Dog" is an adaptation of the
famous (and rather good) Anton Chekhov short story of the same name.
Director Iosif Kheifits approaches the film sensibly by adapting not
only the story but also many of the sensibilities and characteristics
present in Chekhov's writing.First of all, the pacing: In keeping with Chekhov's short story the
pacing is natural in the way one would relate a truly affecting story
from their life- slowly but also in a sense relentlessly and without
break. Also typical of Chekhov and thankfully not changed in this film
version is the lack of a moral 'message' as well as the subtle
characterization that depends on highlighting character traits rather
than blatantly telling you what sort of character to expect.As a film "Dama s sobachkoy" is definitely impressive with the striking
black and white photography by Dmitri Meskhiyev and Andrei Moskvin
perfectly accentuating the various moods of the film. There's also a
memorable score by Nadezhda Simonyan to add to the film with the main
theme being particularly effective.I'm not sure if I see any real flaws in "Dama s sobachkoy" but somehow
it doesn't come off as a classic. What it does succeed in is becoming
an excellent adaptation of a memorable short story that is pulled off
unusually but very well regardless.8/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3443016/comments</url><from>from London England</from><name>wallner-3</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
They don't make films like this any more. In film you either make it in
the best time honoured classical tradition: logical sequence, irony,
exquisite painstaking set-ups with perfect lighting, costumes, extras,
everything pleasing to the eye and the heart and you find others
watching it with a smile on their faces; or you make it so fast, jump
edits, ramping, so wild that only you know the rules. Well you can do
it the Clint Eastwood way which is the perfectly oiled machine: film
them during the rehearsal. He really belongs to the classical genre.
The problem with the second way is that you can't sit easily through
two hours of a movie made like that. A pop video of two minutes fine,
otherwise you emerge from the cinema with your brain fried and the
stupid expression you get after sitting through three hours of watching
ad commercial festivals. I've done it many times, and it's unnatural,
and not good for you. THE LADY WITH THE LITTLE DOG is a perfect little
story, superbly acted, observed, costumed, directed, lit, everything. A
masterpiece of black and white. It cannot be faulted in any way. It
must have taken ages to do the set-ups, something no one can afford to
do these days; but then with the state paying the salaries, who was
counting? So it was made during the Soviet era: but what is perfect, is
perfect, for all time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1292238/comments</url><from>from Whitstable, Kent, England</from><name>Peter Wright (biggadada@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I must have seen this film when it first came out because it seems so long
ago now, but it made a great impression on me,especially the theme music and
the tune played by the street musician on a clarinet I believe. I am so
pleased to have traced the details at last courtesey of the web. I wonder if
there is a chance I will ever see it once more.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1292238/comments</url><from>from Whitstable, Kent, England</from><name>Peter Wright (biggadada@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I must have seen this film when it first came out because it seems so long
ago now, but it made a great impression on me,especially the theme music and
the tune played by the street musician on a clarinet I believe. I am so
pleased to have traced the details at last courtesey of the web. I wonder if
there is a chance I will ever see it once more.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1292238/comments</url><from>from Whitstable, Kent, England</from><name>Peter Wright (biggadada@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>