<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Murder, Inc.</original_title><alt_title>Crime, société anonyme</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Burt Balaban</director><producer>Princess Production Corporation</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
Based on the true-life book of lawman Burton Turkus, this movie chronicles the rise and fall of the organized crime syndicate known as Murder...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Stuart Whitman</actor><actor>May Britt</actor><actor>Henry Morgan</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Those who comment that Peter Falk elevated this movie to a very
interesting one are right on the money. Falk, in his first role on
screen, definitely plays the most interesting character. Of course,
anyone who is a deranged killer is likely to be the focus of viewers'
attention. However, the actor still has to be convincing and Falk does
a fine job here as "Abe Reles."He's convincing!What made this film fun for me was not only Falk, but seeing a few
other faces I haven't seen in years, such as May Britt, Henry Morgan
and Stuart Whitman. Having watched a few "Night Stalker" TV episodes, I
was still very familiar with Simon Oakland. The above actors were all
very good in here, as was the rest of the cast, except maybe David
Stewart as head crime boss "Lepke." He was too bland for his role.We even get a song from a young Sarah Vaughan and a comedy routine from
Morey Amsterdam!Falk is the undisputed star of the film but second-place, to me, went
to Morgan, who was quietly fascinating as the cop "Turkus."Another nice thing was the DVD which gives us the original widescreen
transfer of the film. There aren't many black-and-white CinemaScope
pictures available for us movie fans to see, so it was pleasure to view
this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0070535/comments</url><from>from Broken Bow, Oklahoma</from><name>helpless_dancer</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Crime czar uses contract killers to take out those who would undermine his
organization. The unfeeling crime boss, Lemke, who constantly complained
about his stomach problems, and his blindly loyal enforcer, Mendy, were
frightening in their deadly lust for power. Peter Falk's portrayal of the
psychotic Reles was chilling with his murderous, take what you can
attitude.
This was a gritty look at the New York underworld during the depression.
The
ending was a tad abrupt, but overall this was a pretty good
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0486888/comments</url><from>from Columbia, South Carolina, USA</from><name>William J. Fickling (wfickling@sc.rr.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Thank God for Turner Classic Movies for digging up obscure stuff like this,
not available on video or DVD, that would otherwise disappear.  Not that
it's that great a movie; it isn't.  There are much better gangster films. 
However, it is notable for two things: it is Peter Falk's debut film, and it
names names, something most gangster films before and after didn't do,
unless the film was set well into the past.  Of course, all the gangsters
whose names are given are conveniently dead:  Abe Reles, Louis "Lepke"
Buchalter, and Albert Anastasia.  A notable omission is Meyer Lansky, who
was alive at the time and thus could have sued for libel.  But a pretty good
overview of organized crime in the 30s and 40s.  Albert Anastasia, by the
way, was the real life model for Johnny Friendly, played by Lee J. Cobb, in
"On the Waterfront."  He was gunned down in a barber's chair while he was
getting a haircut in a New York hotel barbershop in 1957. 
8/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0562813/comments</url><from>from NYC</from><name>luciferjohnson</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Peter Falk's almost scarily authentic performance as Reles steals this
otherwise mediocre account of the real-life Murder Inc., which made
latter-day gangsters like the characters in Goodfellas seem like choir
boys
in comparison. Though allegedly based on the Turkus-Feder book, most of
this
is complete fantasy. The central "love story," the Whitman and Britt
characters, is utterly ridiculous as well as completely fictitious. The
portrayals of Lepke and Mendy Weiss are interesting; the fatso playing
Albert Anastasia is completely mischast.The scene at the end is a copout, evidently for fear of offending the
NYPD.The real story of Murder Inc. would be a fascinating movie, instead of
this
drivel. Even so, this is worth watching because of Falk.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Murder, Inc. was a B picture and I remember seeing it as a lad as the
second part of a double bill back in the days when they had such
things. As I was from Brooklyn the whole story of the gang was
interesting to a 12 year old. Needless to say the neighborhood of
Brownsville had changed quite a bit even in 1960 from 20 years earlier.The film is based on a book by the real Burton Turkus who must have
consented to the dramatic license taken to bring the story of the
taking down of Louis Lepke Burkhalter the only top crime boss to this
day ever to get the death penalty. But the atmosphere of the Jewish
neighborhood of Brownsville in Brooklyn is certainly captured as is the
gang that made the place famous.The film's a good one, not great by any means, but decent enough
entertainment performed by a cast that are well known as competent
players, but no box office draws in this cast. But one of them really
made his own career with this film.Peter Falk got the part of Abe 'Kid Twist' Reles who is one amoral
example of humanity. Like Sammy 'The Bull' Gravano of more recent times
in a career where he participated in a couple of dozen contract
killings, when he's caught he offers to turn state's evidence. The end
he met is part of gangland lore.What Falk did was turn in a performance that so impressed the critics
that he got an Oscar nomination for Best Supporting Actor. Remember
Murder, Inc. was a B film, released with no fanfare so to speak so
Falk's performance got the acclaim it did strictly by word of mouth.The competition that year in this category was pretty good. The others
who Falk was competing against were Jack Kruschen in The Apartment, Sal
Mineo for Exodus, Chill Wills for The Alamo, and the eventual winner,
Peter Ustinov for Spartacus. All of those others were high budget
feature films with studios behind them with accompanying publicity
machinery. Falk may have been there to round out the field, but just
the fact he got there is an incredible tribute to his talent and that
particular performance.Murder, Inc. was not Peter Falk's debut big screen performance, but it
is the one that made his career. The rest of the cast which consists of
such familiar faces as Stuart Whitman, May Britt, Eli Mintz, Morey
Amsterdam, Simon Oakland and Henry Morgan as Burton Turkus perform well
enough, but Peter Falk as Reles will never leave you.Talk about making one's own breaks.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2171244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lastliberal</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
10 years before Peter Falk racked up a trunk-load of Emmy's and many
more nominations for his his work as Columbo, he had two roles that
would stand out in the film world. One was Pocketful of Miracles in
1961, and the other was this film the year before.His performance as the contract killer Abe 'Kid Twist' Reles is the
best thing about the true-life mob story. While most of the other
characters just seem to float through the movie, he was intense ans you
could see the promise that would lie ahead for him.Stuart Whitman, who would get his only Oscar nomination a year later,
was also good as Joey, who got caught up in the rackets. May Britt, who
would leave the movies to marry Sammy Davis, Jr., was also very good as
Joey's wife.The movie seems more like a documentary when it is not focused on these
three characters. As an added bonus, you get to see the legendary Sarah
Vaughan in the movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12371785/comments</url><from>from Durham NC</from><name>mlraymond</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
For anyone who has read the book by Burton Turkus that the screenplay
was based on, the movie is a considerably watered-down version of the
ugly events depicted. But the movie succeeds at evoking the grimy
environment of Brooklyn hoodlums in the late Thirties and early Forties
very well. The leads are adequate and the basic story telling is okay.
But what makes this movie worth seeing is the astounding performance by
Peter Falk as the hit man Abe Reles. He manages to be incongruously
funny, in a way that can genuinely make you laugh, but is absolutely
terrifying at the same time. He plays a hoodlum with a grotesquely
logical sense of values, who sees life and people through such a
distorted lens, that he seems like a creature from another planet. His
performance is so uncannily convincing, you feel as if you need to take
a shower after watching the movie. The only performance I've seen that
comes close is that of Joe Pesci in Goodfellas.Definitely worth seeing
for true crime buffs and gangster movie fans, though not totally
reliable as history.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0276579/comments</url><from>from jersey city, n.j.</from><name>anonymous</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

one of the better gangster movies. peter falk is excellent as abe reles and
a solid performance from vincent gardenia as his lawyer. "Murder Inc. gives
a real account of the back stabbing that accompanies the
underworld. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Almost semi-documentary style tale of true crime mingled with fiction.
A career starter for Peter Falk, who plays Abe Reles, killer for the
mob. MURDER, INC spins a story about notable syndicate boss Louis
"Lepke" Buchalter(David J. Stewart) and his murder-for-hire operations.
Nightclub singer Joey Collins(Stuart Whitman)and his dancer girlfriend
Eadie(May Britt)get tangled into Lepke's web. Dead serious federal
agent Turkus(Henry Morgan) convinces the prolific and specific murderer
Reles to squeal on Lepke and his mob of guns and knives for hire. Morey
Amsterdam plays a not-so-funny funny man that is a victim of Murder,
Inc. Jazz great Sarah Vaughan has a brief part as a nightclub singer.
Also in the cast: Eli Mintz, Joseph Bernard and Vincent Gardenia.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur23533944/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bob-790-196018</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
How much truth there is in this "true story" with "real people" is a
question best left to historians of organized crime. The subplot of
Stuart Whitman ("Joey") and May Britt ("Eadie") as a loving couple
caught up in nasty doings certainly seems like the stuff of fiction. In
any case, this is a low-budget "B" picture with limited resources for
portraying the 1930s setting and documenting the historical events with
authentic detail.The one extraordinary element in the movie is the performance by Peter
Falk as a contract killer. He is not only completely believable in the
role but downright original, giving us a character who is merciless and
vicious yet quick to take offense if anyone finds this objectionable.
He can sound plaintively sincere even as we quickly come to see that he
is incapable of sincerity. He has a host of minor quirks and tics that
are fun to watch.Face it, evil can be fascinating and even attractive, in a disturbing
way. Another example in this movie is the portrayal of crime kingpin
Louis "Lepke" Bucholter by David J. Stewart. While certainly not
achieving the high level of Falk's performance, Stewart shows real
style as the milk-drinking mobster.There is one other bonus in this film: Sarah Vaughan, looking young and
pretty, sings a nice song with that inimitable voice.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur23533944/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bob-790-196018</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
How much truth there is in this "true story" with "real people" is a
question best left to historians of organized crime. The subplot of
Stuart Whitman ("Joey") and May Britt ("Eadie") as a loving couple
caught up in nasty doings certainly seems like the stuff of fiction. In
any case, this is a low-budget "B" picture with limited resources for
portraying the 1930s setting and documenting the historical events with
authentic detail.The one extraordinary element in the movie is the performance by Peter
Falk as a contract killer. He is not only completely believable in the
role but downright original, giving us a character who is merciless and
vicious yet quick to take offense if anyone finds this objectionable.
He can sound plaintively sincere even as we quickly come to see that he
is incapable of sincerity. He has a host of minor quirks and tics that
are fun to watch.Face it, evil can be fascinating and even attractive, in a disturbing
way. Another example in this movie is the portrayal of crime kingpin
Louis "Lepke" Bucholter by David J. Stewart. While certainly not
achieving the high level of Falk's performance, Stewart shows real
style as the milk-drinking mobster.There is one other bonus in this film: Sarah Vaughan, looking young and
pretty, sings a nice song with that inimitable voice.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur23533944/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bob-790-196018</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/felix-gonzalez-jr/</url><url>http://www.dvdreview.com/reviews/pages/2355.shtml /m/1159479-murder_inc/comments.php?reviewid=1651099</url><name>Felix Gonzalez Jr.</name><from>DVD Review</from></reviewer><comment>... the film mixes hard facts and Hollywood romanticism to create an entertaining, if somewhat trifling, piece of violent fluff.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/murderinc.htm /m/1159479-murder_inc/comments.php?reviewid=1127893</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>The best thing about the film was Falk's tough-guy performance.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117793322.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1159479-murder_inc/comments.php?reviewid=1802959</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/73632.html /m/1159479-murder_inc/comments.php?reviewid=1515118</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9405E2DF1031EF3ABC4151DFB066838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1159479-murder_inc/comments.php?reviewid=1388535</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>