<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Der rote Kreis</original_title><alt_title>Scotland Yard contre cercle rouge</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Denmark</country><country>West Germany</country><director>Jürgen Roland</director><producer>Constantin Film</producer><producer>Rialto Film Preben-Philipsen</producer><genre>Thriller</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>Es ist unmöglich, von diesem Film nicht gefesselt zu sein!</synopsis><actor>Renate Ewert</actor><actor>Klausjürgen Wussow</actor><actor>Karl-Georg Saebisch</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0374584/comments</url><from>from Under the guillotine</from><name>evilskip</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This is one of the early West German Edgar Wallace based thrillers.For
some
reason it doesn't get a lot of attention.That is too bad because this is a
crackerjack thriller.After narrowly avoiding the guillotine a master criminal returns to London
and wreaks havoc.Blackmail and murder are the trademarks of the Crimson
Circle.25 people will die in his (or her) spree.A private investigator is called in to help Scotland Yard after 18 people
fall prey to the Crimson Circle. Inspector Parr is deemed to be too old and
behind the times to apprehend the murderer.Parr asks for and is granted
special authority to carry out his plan.However it seemingly backfires in
his face and 7 more people meet their grisly fate.Involved is a neer do well, a young lady of villainous ways, suspicious
police officials and a shady Frenchmen.Who is the Crimson
Circle?The plot is fast paced and there is plenty of action. The cast is up to
the
task and the vehicle is well directed.A nice little surprise awaits at the
end. Well worth seeking out for an evening's entertainment.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Another in the German Wallace cycle involving multiple murders and
blackmail as the result of an execution that went wrong seven years
earlier. Good but not great this film never really added up to much
more than people moving around trying to figure out who the villain was
and to stay far enough on his good side that they didn't end up dead.
To be honest while it isn't a bad movie, its quite good, its very
generic as these things go, blending so much into the mass of German
Wallace films that I started to nod off towards the end. Its not the
fault of the film entirely since I am under the weather, but at the
same time I kind of allowed my self to drift because I sort of felt I
knew where it was going. Worth a look on Late night TV or if you are in
an undemanding mood.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Another in the German Wallace cycle involving multiple murders and
blackmail as the result of an execution that went wrong seven years
earlier. Good but not great this film never really added up to much
more than people moving around trying to figure out who the villain was
and to stay far enough on his good side that they didn't end up dead.
To be honest while it isn't a bad movie, its quite good, its very
generic as these things go, blending so much into the mass of German
Wallace films that I started to nod off towards the end. Its not the
fault of the film entirely since I am under the weather, but at the
same time I kind of allowed my self to drift because I sort of felt I
knew where it was going. Worth a look on Late night TV or if you are in
an undemanding mood.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>