<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Angel Wore Red</original_title><alt_title>L'ange pourpre</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>USA</country><director>Nunnally Johnson</director><producer>Titanus</producer><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><producer>Spectator</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
A clergyman travels to Spain to join the Loyalist side during the Spanish Civil War and finds himself attracted to a beautiful entertainer.
</synopsis><actor>Ava Gardner</actor><actor>Dirk Bogarde</actor><actor>Joseph Cotten</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0359879/comments</url><from>from Pittsburgh, PA</from><name>Eric Chapman (caspar_h@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

A fairly potent script with an interesting plot device at its core (both
believers and non-believers alike chase after a sacred religious relic
during a bloody civil war), undermined by rather bland, pedestrian
film-making. Thus, it's not terribly surprising this was the last film
directed by the prolific screenwriter Nunnally Johnson. He shoots just
about
everything in an overly dark and cramped way making it often impossible to
determine where a scene is set, let alone what is going on or even who is
in
it. This may have been intentional, with the absence of light meant to
convey the spiritual darkness in which the country of Spain was submerged
at
the time, but it comes off as crude and makes for rough viewing. There's
something strange about the sound as well; there are few if any
sufficiently
lit close ups and it seems as if some of the actors' voices have been
dubbed. Vittorio DeSica's character, for instance, comes across a bit like
Truman Capote playing General Patton. Joseph Cotten pops up every now and
again, as a cynical, gravel-voiced newsman, (in fact, he also narrates)
but
you never ever really see his face and there is something disembodied
about
his entire presence. It's all a bit unsettling.Nonetheless, if you can endure its flaws, the movie raises some thought
provoking questions on the nature of faith and religion in times of
strife,
and Dirk Bogarde is quite impassioned as the troubled priest. Ava Gardner,
however, is noticeably past her prime as Bogarde's love interest, and her
character isn't adequately fleshed out.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14840331/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>alanrhobson</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This film has an abiding place in my film canon, for one very good
reason.It isn't a great film, as both the other IMDb reviewers have gone out
of their way to stress (although some of their criticisms were a little
unfair. I thought, for example, that Joseph Cotten fared better than
they say). However, it is virtually the only entertainment vehicle I
have ever seen - including film, TV, radio, newspaper, magazine - that
dares to show the truth about the left-wing
Republicans/anti-Nationalists in the Spanish Civil War.The Spanish Republicans have been lionised for decades for their
allegedly heroic struggle against fascism (although it is actually a
moot point to what extent Franco's Nationalists were fascist). However,
this film is brave enough to show the truth - that the Spanish
Republicans singled out religious targets and many harmless middle
class targets and killed or persecuted them. It also dares to show the
truth that the Republicans ran the areas they controlled along
Stalinist lines. Which is not surprising, given the links with
Communists and Stalinist Russia that some of them had.The file deserves enormous credit for showing this, and it is a shame
that no-one has pointed this out on IMDb - until now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19799182/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>hopkinshughes</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Though far from perfect, I could watch this movie again, and perhaps
even more than that. It's a fascinating movie, for one thing, pairing
two of the most beautiful people who ever lived, in a story with real
depth, or at least the promise of real depth, which says a lot in a
world where 99 movies out of 100 don't even try. Imagine, complaining
that at 37, Ava Gardner was "past her prime." It is wonderful to see
Bogarde, whose roles usually had him sneering worldly-wise ironies,
showing heartfelt passion for the good and the true. It is equally
wonderful to see Gardner in a role far more suited for her than the
calculating charmer or the tormented playgirl. She never seemed to be
really trying until this one, where perhaps the part touched something
deep in her. Their chemistry was superlative, their love scene one of
the greats of all time, in my view. That this portrayal of a love that goes beyond time and place occurs in
the context of one of the most astonishingly wicked and absurd wars of
all time is another sublimity that seems to have whizzed right by all
but one of the previous reviewers. Hemingway showed only that Robert
Jordan thought the war was absurd, he didn't show its absurdity, which
director Nunnally Johnson managed to do here in both direction and
dialog, and against great odds. Like another of my favorites, Viva
Zapata, this movie is a flawed masterpiece, better by far than 100
polished banalities. Blame its flaws on the trials of filming in 1960
(still stuck in the 50s), on sloppy editing, on the meaningless title,
and the inevitable hurdles that writers and directors have to overcome
in the complicated and difficult art of film-making, truly daunting in
the case of this film. (Imagine attempting to film a love story between
a priest and a prostitute in 50s Sicily?!) Don't blame the the actors,
the director, or the beautiful and poignant story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0108786/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Tom May (joycean_chap@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

I thought this film was rather lacking in both narrative and film-making
technique. The script is far from awful, but also far from interesting in
the most part. As the previous reviewer says, the lighting, choice of shots
etc. was jarring and obscured characters (Joseph Cotten, who indeed
established no presence at all in this film partly due to this). The
historical period examined is a curious if comendable choice, and while the
general details are correctly conveyed, no attempt is really made to discuss
the issues in much depth. Good to see neither of the two sides particularly
favoured, although such a commitment might have added at least some drama.
Drama is scant in the film, with a few scenes written as exposition,
delivered in a way just as stilted.The film actually has a rather good and eclectic cast for 1960, although the
talents are ill used. Finlay Currie, Vittorio De Sica (well, seemingly in
the main part a director), Dirk Bogarde (not yet of the stature achieved in
films like "The Servant" and "Accident"), Joseph Cotten and Ava Gardner are
all of some talent. De Sica's character who does indeed speak in a rather
un-Italian, mid-Atlantic accent, which either suggests dubbing or a
remarkably odd decision somewhere along the line - the character is
portrayed as a Spanish patriot. The character's endless minor disparaging
comments about modern warfare are mildly amusing in their
frequency.
I wouldn't say Ava Gardner is at all "past her prime" in this film, at about
37. Her performance is actually quite good, although lacking some
credibility, and there are some pretty reasonable quiet scenes between her
and Bogarde. Her beauty seems to have matured well, although the murky,
technically below-par direction doesn't help this to show. Bogarde seemed
quite good at times, but far from indelible or memorable in this role.I would say this film is reasonably watchable and far from abject, but it is
largely far from gripping or interesting.Rating:- **/***** 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"The Angel Wore Red" is a 1960 film that takes on the subject of the
Spanish Civil War. It stars Dirk Bogarde, Ava Gardner, Joseph Cotten,
Vittorio de Sica, and Finlay Currie. The Spanish Civil War is not an
easy subject and unfortunately, the film only partially succeeds with
Nunnally Johnson's script and under his direction.A priest, Arturo Carrera (Dirk Bogarde) gives up the priesthood just as
the war is starting and finds himself on the run from the Spanish
Republicans, who accused the priests of indoctrinating their followers
against them. Arturo slips into a cabaret in order to hide and meets
Soledad (Gardner), an entertainer. Eventually, he falls for her, and
both of them wind up being arrested. Meanwhile, both sides are
searching for a sacred relic that is believed to have miraculous powers
- it is said to have helped defeat Napoleon. The Bishop entrusted it to
someone before the cathedral was destroyed. Each side wants it for its
own reasons.This is a very dark film - darkly photographed, and the sound is
strange. I am glad someone else mentioned that it seemed as if it was
dubbed. I could easily believe it was in Italian originally and dubbed
in English, though that wasn't the case. The acting is excellent. Movie
priests always look so darn good - Bogarde makes a handsome, romantic
and gentle priest and gives a dynamic performance as a man who hasn't
lost his faith in God, only in the church as a way to serve man. Ava
Gardner is well cast. Some comments state she was "past it" etc. -
though she looks older than Bogarde, which really doesn't make any
difference, she also looks appropriate for the role she plays -
Spanish, someone who's been around the block more than once, likes the
nightlife and is not wealthy. She is not particularly well
photographed, and in spots where she is, it's obvious that her beauty
hasn't faded. All anyone has to do is see her in 1964's "Night of the
Iguana" to realize what great beauty she still had. Vittoria di Sica
plays General Clave; it's an odd performance, which is fitting because
the man he plays is odd. Joseph Cotten to me is completely wasted as a
news journalist in this movie and seems just inserted into the film.
He's excellent, but the performance comes from nowhere.In the end, "The Angel Wore Red" doesn't give us much understanding of
the conflict, and the viewer feels almost as if he or she is entering
in the middle of something. We're actually entering in the beginning of
the Spanish Civil War, but nothing leads us up to it. Props to Johnson,
however, for taking on such a weighty subject.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19799763/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vespatian75</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Despite some obvious flaws I regard this film as a major achievement.
The first obvious problem is the dubbing. Vittorio De Sica, a great
actor is dubbed in English by a run of the mill voice over technician.
The film suffers from being a joint Anglo/American- Italian production.But it is one of the most mature treatments of a political historical
theme that I have ever seen. Neither the loyalists nor the Franco led
rebels are spared. Both are essentially brutal totalitarians. The
Catholic Church is not spared either. Churchmen are showed to be so out
of touch with their flock as to be almost comical, and yet when finally
knocked off their pedestal they recover their Christianity. Dirk Bogard
gives a subtle and brilliant performance as the tortured young priest.
Ava Gardner is perfect as the cynical and yet innocent prostitute. It
is actually to her advantage that she played this role at 37 rather
than ten years earlier. She would simply been too overpoweringly
beautiful to have been fully creditable in the part. Aldo Frabrizzi's
part may be too reminiscent of his role in Open City especially at the
end. Vittorio De Sica seems to have been doing an imitation of Claude
Raines in Casablanca. It would have been good to have heard those two
great actors in their native Italian. Joseph Cotton as the one eyed
jaded reporter gives a broad yet compelling interpretation. The films
failings pale in comparison to its overriding importance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19799763/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vespatian75</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Despite some obvious flaws I regard this film as a major achievement.
The first obvious problem is the dubbing. Vittorio De Sica, a great
actor is dubbed in English by a run of the mill voice over technician.
The film suffers from being a joint Anglo/American- Italian production.But it is one of the most mature treatments of a political historical
theme that I have ever seen. Neither the loyalists nor the Franco led
rebels are spared. Both are essentially brutal totalitarians. The
Catholic Church is not spared either. Churchmen are showed to be so out
of touch with their flock as to be almost comical, and yet when finally
knocked off their pedestal they recover their Christianity. Dirk Bogard
gives a subtle and brilliant performance as the tortured young priest.
Ava Gardner is perfect as the cynical and yet innocent prostitute. It
is actually to her advantage that she played this role at 37 rather
than ten years earlier. She would simply been too overpoweringly
beautiful to have been fully creditable in the part. Aldo Frabrizzi's
part may be too reminiscent of his role in Open City especially at the
end. Vittorio De Sica seems to have been doing an imitation of Claude
Raines in Casablanca. It would have been good to have heard those two
great actors in their native Italian. Joseph Cotton as the one eyed
jaded reporter gives a broad yet compelling interpretation. The films
failings pale in comparison to its overriding importance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19799763/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vespatian75</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>