<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Subterraneans</original_title><alt_title>Les rats des caves</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Ranald MacDougall</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>These are The Subterraneans Today's Young Rebels - Who live and love in a world of their own this is their story told to the hot rhythms of fabulous jazz!</synopsis><actor>Leslie Caron</actor><actor>George Peppard</actor><actor>Janice Rule</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1099586/comments</url><from>from Cape Town, South Africa</from><name>Bruno Morphet (Bruno.Morphet@tequila-cape.co.za)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Reviled by the original Beats, most notably Allen Ginsberg, and
now virtually unobtainable in video form (let alone DVD) from any
source, The Subterraneans has been derided as a Hollywood
hatchet job bearing very little resemblance to the Kerouac book on
which its based. The plot is simple, disillusioned writer, George
Peppard, explores the 'subterranean' depths of San Francisco's
North Beach district circa 1959 looking for anybody who will share
his jaded perspective on life and finds romance amongst the
Beatniks in the form of slightly touched Leslie Caron (original
book's black female love interest is replaced by a French girl for
Hollywood palates). Script is similarly lightweight, with intermittent
nods to the language of the Beats and a clumsy attempt to
re-create the famous Ginsberg "Howl" reading, but nevertheless
the movie as a whole is stangely compelling in a historical sense,
not as a faithful representation of Beat culture, but rather as a view
on how the Beats were commoditized and became 'Beatniks'. If
you have an interest in the popular culture of the time, daddio, then
like, seek this flick out, if you're a serious Beat scholar, stay
away.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3460221/comments</url><from>from Alexandria, Virginia</from><name>JAtheDJ</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I just viewed this film for the first time. Janice Rule and Leslie
Caron are excellent given the superfluous material; George Peppard is
stiff and unconvincing.If you take this film literally, the Beats represented party-loving,
self-serving hedonists, rebelling against society with no particular
purpose. In fact, the Beats and their literature provided a needed
counterpoint to the conformity and staid complacency of American life
in the 1950s. They were the forerunners of the Hippies, for sure.Despite a shallow story line, the film is of historical interest as to
how Hollywood (and maybe mainstream America) viewed the Beat generation
in 1960, when the film was released.The music is absolutely marvelous - it's great to see and hear jazz
giants like Gerry Mulligan (also in an acting role), Art Pepper, Art
Farmer and Shelly Manne.A true period piece, worth seeing - once.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15433874/comments</url><from>from Hungary</from><name>jay-fogelman</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
If this film is hard to get a hold of, it's probably because anyone
involved in it has tried to buy up and destroy the prints. Never mind
the faithlessness to Kerouac -- this is about as close to the spirit
and vision of Kerouac as Howdy Doody is to Shakespeare -- the script
provides ample opportunities for the humiliation of actors,
opportunities which, unfortunately are exploited to the full. George
Peppard is miscast as a soul-searching intellectual writer, but seems
to have the soul of a soft, fluffy robot. Roddy MacDowell doesn't speak
his lines, but declaims them. The otherwise charming Leslie Caron has
the depth of a neurotic paper doll. It's a kind of exploitation film:
instant beatnik, just add intelligence. My compliments to anyone who
can watch this for five minutes without cringing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9659469/comments</url><from>from Bulgaria</from><name>timeonlyknows</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
A piece of art!This is what describes the movie best.It's about a love
story between two very different of a kind people.But the thing that
grabbed me most was the good play of the actors which by the way were
given much material.Not like most movies which are made today this one
relays most on the dialogue.It is not what they say,it's how they say
it!I must say as a really big fan of old movies that this one has made
me a big impression,it was very enjoyable to just watch how all those
actors really becoming their characters!George Peppard did well but a
little unconvincable,but Leslie Caron was the one how got me convinced
that there was love somewhere in the movie...These are The
Subterraneans Today's Young Rebels - Who live and love in a world of
their own this is their story told to the hot rhythms of fabulous jazz!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2780485/comments</url><from>from Albania</from><name>Benzyl</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Hooray I thought, another San Francisco movie that TnT shows from time
to time and I can't think of a better place to set a beat generation
based production than here. The good news is that there is plenty of
location shots set around the North Beach/Telegraph Hill exteriors but
bad that most of the interiors are the usual Paramount style back lots
that just oozes, well, not authenticity anyway. the acting style is
labored and theatrical almost like pantomime and if you think of a less
plausible West Side Story with the singing removed you would be pretty
close to what can be seen here. The acting particularly from the female
lead is over the top whiny and mostly unsympathetic making this a movie
to watch but with the sound turned down.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1308744/comments</url><from>from Copenhagen, Denmark'</from><name>sonny_p</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

Tasteless adaption of a great beat novel.
The big MGM studio setup is not suited for a story like
this.
A low budget B/W Noir style, would have suited the story
better.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5816032/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Enoch Sneed</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
There are good bad films and bad bad films - this is a skin-crawlingly
embarrassing bad film. It starts with a title text about "Bohemians"
who gather in Greenwich Village, London's Soho, the Left Bank in Paris,
and San Francisco.We then see George Peppard playing a frustrated would-be author
shouting at his typewriter and telling his long-suffering mother he is
hungry for life and needs to discover its meaning.After this the film goes downhill as George encounters a group of
Beatniks who gather in a place called the "Catacombs", call each other
"man", have very intense relationships and meditate on the cosmic.This is just a joke. A caricature of existentialism, 'beat culture' or
whatever you want to call it. It also marks the point where young
people starting taking themselves too seriously, felt they had
"Something To Say" simply because they *were* young and that they knew
how to put things right. Sorry, chaps, the world's a s**t-house and
that's it. Dear San Francisco, if you think *this* is a youth movement,
wait until you see what 1967 has in store.Why this should be a Turner "Classic" Movie is beyond me (unless we're
talking about some sort of "classic age" of movie-making). MGM was
responsible for enough true classics for this piece of bilge to be
quietly forgotten.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5816032/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Enoch Sneed</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
There are good bad films and bad bad films - this is a skin-crawlingly
embarrassing bad film. It starts with a title text about "Bohemians"
who gather in Greenwich Village, London's Soho, the Left Bank in Paris,
and San Francisco.We then see George Peppard playing a frustrated would-be author
shouting at his typewriter and telling his long-suffering mother he is
hungry for life and needs to discover its meaning.After this the film goes downhill as George encounters a group of
Beatniks who gather in a place called the "Catacombs", call each other
"man", have very intense relationships and meditate on the cosmic.This is just a joke. A caricature of existentialism, 'beat culture' or
whatever you want to call it. It also marks the point where young
people starting taking themselves too seriously, felt they had
"Something To Say" simply because they *were* young and that they knew
how to put things right. Sorry, chaps, the world's a s**t-house and
that's it. Dear San Francisco, if you think *this* is a youth movement,
wait until you see what 1967 has in store.Why this should be a Turner "Classic" Movie is beyond me (unless we're
talking about some sort of "classic age" of movie-making). MGM was
responsible for enough true classics for this piece of bilge to be
quietly forgotten.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5816032/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Enoch Sneed</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>