<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Dark at the Top of the Stairs</original_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Delbert Mann</director><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In Oklahoma in the 1920s, Ruben Flood loses his job as a traveling salesman, when the company goes bankrupt...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Robert Preston</actor><actor>Dorothy McGuire</actor><actor>Eve Arden</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10408116/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>jpdoherty</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Based on the Purlitzer Prize-winning play by William Inge Warner Bros.
THE DARK AT THE TOP OF THE STAIRS (1960) was adapted for the screen by
Harriet Frank Jnr. and Irving Ravetch. Produced for the studio by
Michael Garrison it turned out to be a fairly engaging and entertaining
melodrama thanks in no small measure to the well rounded direction by
Delbert Mann and solid performances by a committed cast. Although
unavoidably static, because of its theatrical origins, it nevertheless
was nicely photographed in Technicolor by the great Harry Stradling and
gorgeously scored by the studio's legendary Max Steiner.Set in a small town in 20's Oklahoma the story concerns the ups and
downs of the Flood family. An average family trying to get on with
their everyday lives. The head of the household is patriarch Rubin
(Robert Preston) who because of the changing times suddenly loses his
job as a saddlery salesman and keeps it a secret from his devoted but
angst-ridden wife Cora (Dorothy McGuire). Cora is also mother to their
shy and withdrawn teenage daughter (Shirley Knight) and their equally
withdrawn adolescent son who is constantly afraid of the dark at the
top of the stairs.Wonderfully acted throughout Preston gives a flamboyant portrayal of
the irascible but well meaning Rubin and McGuire was never better as
the ever worried and brow beaten Cora. Her performance is sensitive and
heartfelt. Also fine is Shirley Knight in her Oscar nominated role as
the young girl who's heart is broken much too early in life when she
falls for the ill-fated Jewish boy Sammy Golden (Lee Kinsolving). But
stealing the show is the entrance of Eve Arden as Cora's droll sister
Lottie who arrives on a visit with her hen-pecked husband Morris (Frank
Overton). "I just can't stand the sound of her voice" he confides in
Rubin.Complimenting the whole production is the lovely music by Max Steiner.
Full of exquisite themes this is one of the composer's most captivating
scores. The main theme, first heard under the titles, is a beguiling
waltz. Rubin's theme is a jaunty march-like piece while the theme for
Cora is bluesy and reflective. But the highlight of the score is the
ingenious little theme he wrote for the teenage lovers. Scored for
Harmonica and strings it gives their scenes together a gentle and
persuasive charm. The piece became somewhat popular in the early
sixties when a cover version was recorded by the Percy Faith Orchestra.
Evidently trying for another hit with a Steiner tune after that
orchestra's runaway smash with the composer's "Theme From A Summer
Place" the year before.THE DARK AT THE TOP OF THE STAIRS has never been released on DVD or VHS
for that matter. Perhaps this accounts for it being without a
reputation. Pity it's not better known but when it is seen the movie
stands up well and all because of its fine production values, its
memorable performances, its adroit direction and all wrapped up neatly
in a gorgeous and unforgettable musical score.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0278043/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Alec West</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I was fortunate to find someone who'd saved this film on videotape so I
could archive it on DVD. It is one of the more profound films to come
out of that period and one which stands the test of time.Rubin Flood (Robert Preston) is a victim of progress. At middle-age, he
finds himself losing his job because his boss faces bankruptcy. With
the coming of automobiles, no one wants the horse-related leather goods
he used to sell. Cora Flood (Dorothy McGuire), his wife, is a victim
too. Forced to 'make due' with little money even before Rubin lost his
job, she must also face the problems of a her daughter, Reenie (Shirley
Knight), as she transitions from adolescence to young adulthood ... and
the problems of her son, Sonny (Robert Eyer), as he transitions from
childhood to adolescence.Times are tough for the entire Flood family. But, they must come to
terms with their problems of love, timidity, suspected infidelity,
religious prejudices and the changing times in which they live. While
the gadgets may have changed, the problems modern families face are no
different than theirs ... making this film one that I think should be
'required' of all high school students to view.I rate this film 10 out of 10 ... and rate Warner Brothers 'zero' for
taking a 'dog-in-the-manger' attitude toward releasing this gem on home
video. Preston, McGuire, Knight, and Eyer ... not to mention Lee
Kinsolving (Sammy Golden), Eve Arden (Aunt Lottie) and Angela Lansbury
(Mavis Pruitt) all turn in stellar performances in their roles. Kudos
go to Shirley Knight who was nominated for an Oscar in the film and Lee
Kinsolving, who only appeared in one more film and a handful of TV
shows before his untimely death at age 36. And special kudos go to
William Inge (stage play writer), Harriet Frank, Jr. (screenplay
writer) and Delbert Mann for his masterful direction of an enduring
work.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0270026/comments</url><from>from warren michigan</from><name>Joseph Harder</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

     Robert Preston will be forever remembered as "The Music Man"-and well
he should be. However, he gave many other fine performances, and one of the
best was as Rubin Flood in The Dark at the Top of the Stairs.Dwight McDonald
once wrote an essay mocking "Ingeland and Kazanistan", and he may have had a
point. At the same time, the series of films based on William Inges plays
includes some of the best dramas of the fifties and early sixties..still,
perhaps the most underrated period of Amnerican film.This  film is not just
an example of sentimental "americana". Though set in the past, it is not an
exercise in simplistic nostalgia. Instead it reveals the sexual repression,
Anti-Semitism,and snobbery which poisoned American life in the early part of
this century.However, it does not simply look at the past from a standpoint
of smug superiority. Instead, it suggests the dignity and inner strength of
these people, as they struggled with economic and moral uncertainty.It has a
superficially "happy' ending', yet it is still a sad and troubling portrait
of the fragility of quotidian existence.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4935417/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bbboomer49-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie years ago and fell in love with it. I have hunted for
the video but unfortunately there isn't one. I was lucky enough to find
it playing on TV several years ago and taped it. Although I am happy to
have what I do, I think it's a shame it is not available for the Robert
Preston fans out there. It is a movie that was before its time. It hit
on topics that were seldom talked about publicly in the time setting.
Topics hinted at but not openly discussed like they do in this film.
Robert Preston did a remarkable job as the character, Rubin Flood. Your
heart went out to him because you could see through his strong, always
looking for the positive, family provider roll. The fear and
uncertainty he faced each day as the head of his family and his aging
prospects at being successful in the eyes of his family. The film has a
glorious mix of humor and drama. Unforgettable!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0466277/comments</url><from>from Sao Paulo, Brazil</from><name>Vicente Adorno (vicenteadorno@uol.com.br)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I've only seen this film two times. The first one was when I was a
teenager,
in the early 60s, and the other one was on TV, not so long ago. As it had
happened in the first time, viewing "The Dark at the Top of the Stairs"
again gave me the same feeling: in spite of being a very American movie in
all its aspects, it has a strong and universal appeal because it deals
with
people with flesh and blood, not puppets or flat characters. But what I
consider appalling is the callousness of movie distributors who haven't so
far given us the chance to see and buy this little gem either in VHS or
DVD.
According to the reliable Halliwell's Film Guide, this was produced by
Warner Bros. Why don't they release it now in either of these formats, or,
better still, in both? Maybe they lack what this movie is plentifully
supplied with, that is, "a real feeling for the people and the place", in
Halliwell's words.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0115314/comments</url><from>from Mayland</from><name>lew-11</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Angela tends to play baddies - and she is good at it. In the Manchurian
Candidate she was a black widow spider and praying mantis combined - with
lipstick. In this movie, she is young and plump and wholesome and pretty -
and in one scene with Robert Preston where they share a single kiss, she
is
more desirable than all the millions of boobs on the Internet.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1508189/comments</url><from>from NEW MEXICO</from><name>MARCI WATSON (mwatson@wnmt.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I'm known as a soft touch when it comes to the films I enjoy but this
movie
also touched and affected my two teenage sons who accidentally were caught
up in it while I was watching it. It is very poignant especially the
religious prejudice and the pain &amp; destruction it caused.  This is a
tasteful story of first love, love lost and love re-discovered.  The
characters are wonderful. I hope to have an opportunity to tape it or even
better to purchase it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0216535/comments</url><from>from Oregon, USA</from><name>rickert</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

One of the most simple yet moving of William Inge's plays is presented
here
with some of the finest American actors to grace the screen.  This is
American cinema at its greatest.  Anything else I could say would sound
even
more trite.  If you can find this film (it's never been released on video
as
far as I know) give it a try.  I was able to tape it off of Encore once,
and
I am forever grateful that they aired it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1910387/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>solrac4100</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A Family trials and tribulations in '20s Oklahoma. Preston gives a
poignant portrayal of a husband who chooses the warmth of another woman
over his cold wife and familial duties. He tries to compensate for his
own lack of self-esteem by cheating on his patient wife (Dorothy
McGuire).Preston's "other woman" is played by Angela Lansbury. His
daughter falls in love with a Jewish boy who commits suicide due to
anti-Semitic pressure. Meanwhile, young Sonny must come to terms with
the evil he imagines to exist in the dark at the top of the stairs. An
emotional but wonderful movie and very well performed by Dorothy
McGuire,Angela Lansbury and Robert Preston.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0638989/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>lora64</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Events take place in a small town atmosphere. Rubin (Robert Preston), being
a family man, faces the bleak fact of losing his job when business takes a
downturn, and at middle age it's not so easy for him to cope. His wife Cora
(Dorothy McGuire) as well as their two children, each have needs of their
own. When Rubin goes off for four days and returns to argue and confront his
wife with his needs, she in turn reveals what is troubling her, money, that
they seem to argue over all the time. Sounds very familiar!I think Robert Preston turns in a fine dramatic performance and fits the
role perfectly. His next film was to be The Music Man so he obviously
carried over all that dynamic energy to a musical, a very versatile
man.Eve Arden, as Lottie, is always too talkative, seeming to wonder aloud on
every thought that comes into her head. Eventually she pours out her
troubles to Cora while on a visit and this bonds them closer as sisters
since both are having difficulties in their marriage.Mavis (Angela Lansbury) is very friendly to Rubin, almost becoming the
"other woman" but he's not really ready to cross that line. She's a very
understanding and wise lady as it turns out later.It's interesting to get a glimpse into the lives of each character, young
and old -- a slice of life, you might say, and to observe the prejudices of
the day as they are played out. I think in many ways we've learned to be more tolerant in our
time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0638989/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>lora64</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Events take place in a small town atmosphere. Rubin (Robert Preston), being
a family man, faces the bleak fact of losing his job when business takes a
downturn, and at middle age it's not so easy for him to cope. His wife Cora
(Dorothy McGuire) as well as their two children, each have needs of their
own. When Rubin goes off for four days and returns to argue and confront his
wife with his needs, she in turn reveals what is troubling her, money, that
they seem to argue over all the time. Sounds very familiar!I think Robert Preston turns in a fine dramatic performance and fits the
role perfectly. His next film was to be The Music Man so he obviously
carried over all that dynamic energy to a musical, a very versatile
man.Eve Arden, as Lottie, is always too talkative, seeming to wonder aloud on
every thought that comes into her head. Eventually she pours out her
troubles to Cora while on a visit and this bonds them closer as sisters
since both are having difficulties in their marriage.Mavis (Angela Lansbury) is very friendly to Rubin, almost becoming the
"other woman" but he's not really ready to cross that line. She's a very
understanding and wise lady as it turns out later.It's interesting to get a glimpse into the lives of each character, young
and old -- a slice of life, you might say, and to observe the prejudices of
the day as they are played out. I think in many ways we've learned to be more tolerant in our
time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0638989/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>lora64</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/dark-at-the-top-of-the-stairs-the-1/ /m/the-dark-at-the-top-of-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1975566</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>This version of William Inge's family melodrama is verbose and lacks subtlety, but the acting is good, especially Shirley Knight who received her Oscar nomination.</comment></review></movie>