<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Pepe</original_title><alt_title>Pépé</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Mexico</country><country>USA</country><director>George Sidney</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><producer>Posa Films</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Musical</genre><synopsis>
The young Mexican Pepe's beloved horse is sold to Hollywood star Ted Holt, leading to Pepe's journey to Hollywood to get the horse back, and Pepe's encounter with half the stars working in Hollywood at the time.
</synopsis><actor>Cantinflas</actor><actor>Dan Dailey</actor><actor>Shirley Jones</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Now any film with as many stars as they gathered together for bit parts
as Pepe will automatically get me watching it in any event. There's no
way I'd give this a bad review. But in terms of the film itself, it might well have been oversold back
then. Cantinflas got rave notices for his performance as Passepartout
in Around the World in 80 Days, but failed to win audiences in the
English speaking world. So this time Cantinflas played the title role
and Columbia Pictures gathered together just about every star who had a
free minute or so to appear in this. When you consider that Around the
World in 80 Days was also such an all star extravaganza, did any other
performer in history ever command such support?Not that he didn't deserve it. In Latin America, especially in his
native Mexico, Cantinflas was a national icon. I think that it was no
accident that all these stars wanted to appear with him, it certainly
would boost their market value in the Latin American area to be
identified with him.Seeing this film again 46 years after it first came out and I did see
it in the theater back in the day, I was struck with how similar the
Pepe character was to Forrest Gump. Tom Hanks who got an Oscar for his
performance of someone as guileless as Pepe also during that film ran
into as many famous folks as Pepe managed to. Columbia cheated a little bit by going to Las Vegas for part of the
story. This was the height of the Rat Pack era and a whole lot of the
cast from Ocean's 11 took time from filming that to do some ring-a-ding
walk-ons here. There are some nice musical numbers. Shirley Jones is in good voice
singing the title song. A real treat is Cantinflas, Dan Dailey, and
Maurice Chevalier doing a reprise of Mimi. My favorite though is a star
that appears only by voice, but Judy Garland's The Faraway Part of Town
which is heard over a radio should rank as one of the best songs she
ever sang.Seen almost a half a century later, I'd say Pepe was undeservedly
panned by the critics back then and is worth looking at whenever it
gets broadcast.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0326706/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>shinquiz</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

It seems as if the 195-minute print of this all-star oddity has forever
been
pulled from circulation. However the remaining 157-minute version is quite
long enough. This movie has always been made fun of, but as misguided as
it
is, it is still entertaining, if only because it is so crammed full of
guest
appearances.Here's who you get: Greer Garson trying to buy a prize horse; Edward G.
Robinson playing himself though he is seen here as a famous film producer;
Ernie Kovacs as an immigration inspector; William Demarest as a studio
gate
keeper; Zsa Zsa Gabor reading a copy of "The Interns" to promote
Columbia's
upcoming film version; Bing Crosby signing Cantinflas's tortilla and
joining
him in a few lines of "South of the Border"; Jay North playing Dennis the
Menace; Billie Burke hitting Charles Coburn with a slingshot; Jack Lemmon
dressed as Daphne from "Some Like It Hot" in a bizarre sequence involving
a
parking lot; Andre Previn at the piano while Bobby Darin sings a terrific
number called "That's How It Went, All Right"; Michael Callan, Shirley
Jones, and Matt Mattox doing a sizzling dance called "The Rumble"; Judy
Garland (heard but not seen) singing "The Faraway Part of Town" on the
radio; Ann B. Davis playing her "Shultzy" character from "The Bob Cummings
Show" but here assigned to working as Edward G. Robinson's secretary;
Donna
Reed making cutesy banter with Dan Dailey about her then-current TV
series;
a trip to the Sands Casino in Las Vegas where we see Peter Lawford and
Richard Conte standing around in the lobby, Sammy Davis Jr. doing
impressions to "Hooray for Hollywood", Frank Sinatra and Dean Martin
gambling, Cesar Romero hanging out at the slot machines, a dejected Jimmy
Durante losing at cards, and Joey Bishop saying "son of a gun"; Hedda
Hopper
boarding a plane; a ghastly sequence in which a miniature Debbie Reynolds
drunkenly dancing with Cantinflas on Dan Dailey's desktop to "Tequila"; a
delightful moment when Dailey and Cantinflas join Maurice Chevalier in
dancing to "Mimi"; Janet Leigh being surprised in the bathtub the same
year
as her "Psycho" shower; Tony Curtis getting pushed into an indoor pool;
and
Kim Novak giving advice on buying a wedding ring.Somehow I find this hodgepodge strangely irresistible.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3819245/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>pepes</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Now that I have read some put downs, I need to respond.This movie 'PEPE' (1960) George Sidney, was just what tens of thousands
of other movies is, and are supposed to do, that is to give you an
escape.Give you an escape from everyday blaze. It's funny, musical, short on a
fabulous plot but wonderful to watch especially if you like to dream
that maybe some small unknown would be able to brush elbows with the
stars of the era, and save his ('son' as he says) to boot. What's so
bad about that?? I'm sorry "Mario Moreno Reyes" Cantinflas did not get a fair shake from
Hollywood he had such potential. In my book this is a must see.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3573636/comments</url><from>from San Juan, Puerto Rico</from><name>josem1999</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
It's really hard to rate this movie. On the one hand, it's a true time
capsule of 1960..every mega star is here..including practically the
whole rat pack. On the other hand , this is a an extremely corny movie
about a man and his donkey.What is really painful to watch is what the movie does to the
Cantinflas persona. In his Mexican movies, he is street smart but with
a sentimental side. Sort of a Mexican Little Tramp. In his Mexican
movies this persona became more and more sentimental and less street
smart as years went by. But nothing can prepare you for this movie. In
it, the Cantinflas persona becomes a virtual moron. He is such an
ignorant fool it is almost painful to watch.I remember seeing this movie with my grandmother and mother at the old
Radio City theater in Santurce. I was a boy expecting a Cantinflas
movie and was surprised to see a movie like this. Still I have fond memories and I feel that the movie deserves a DVD
release. In fact this movie doesn't even show up on AMC or TCM. And its
a shame because this movie is an interesting way to go back to 1960.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4641088/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gaby01575</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This movie might be pointless, meaningless fluff but it was
entertaining enough to warrant a DVD release. I remember seeing a much
shortened version on late night TV a long, long time ago and laughed
myself silly, especially at the scene w/ Jack Lemmon in drag trying to
make it to a dental appointment in between takes of a "Some Like It
Hot" kind of movie, while Cantinflas, mistaken for a carhop, wreaks
havoc in the parking lot w/ Lemmon's girlfriend's Jaguar. "There goes
my girl's car!", he exclaims and then as the car crashes, "There goes
my girl!". By the way, I don't think the preceding was a spoiler. It's
fun to enjoy mindless entertainment from time to time, too bad it had
to be at the expense of the talented Mario Moreno/Cantinflas who was
presented as a racial stereotype. If you can get past that, there is a
whole parade of stars who were THE stars during that period which, I'm
sure, we all look back to w/ nostalgia. If only for nostalgia's sake, I
vote for a DVD release of this movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15651776/comments</url><from>from Egypt</from><name>ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
It's pure magic. Despite anyone tries to convince you not. When I was
14-year-old this movie was among my top 5. Who can resist many stars,
bright dances, droll sketches, great music, and so sizzling girls from
the good old 1950s as well ?! You can say it got a thin plot. But as
whole I discovered that that was the point ! It's a variety show. (Cantinflas), the Mexican comic star, wasn't that
hot name in America. And the way to achieve that was by putting him in
the middle of Hollywood hall of fame, through delightful colorful
episodes with a plot (somewhat) like kind of (Charles Chaplin)'s tales
yet about a man and not a kid.. but a horse. And for me all of that
worked magically.I believe the TV at the moment was hitting the movies' industry badly.
So Hollywood had to fight back with its heavy artillery. You can sense
that rightly with Cantinflas's first American movie 4 years ago (Around
the World in 80 Days). The many cameos of the stars, the episodic feel,
and the international backgrounds all were the cinema's desperate
weapons at its war. And Cantinflas's second American movie wasn't away
from that. Still the parts that really entertained me much were Maurice
Chevalier's Mimi, the bar's erotic dance, Dean Martin's cameo, and the
scene of Cantinflas with Edward G. Robinson near the end as a walking
broken heart (Cantinflas lost that year's Golden Globe of the best
actor for Jack Lemmon in The Apartment). so it is a funny, sexy, and
touching show.The title song is one of few songs move my feeling to the highest
degree. It's holy for me. Aside from perfect music, I ranked it as the
best song ever made about the beauty of simplicity, the smiling clown
in our life, or just the beauty of being simple smiling man. This was the end of the musicals' age on-screen, and to tell you the
truth Pepe isn't a great musical itself, though it managed to give the
good emotions that any great musical used to deliver. And remember
folks; this was nominated for 7 Oscars. Best Art Direction-Set
Decoration, Best Cinematography, Best Costume Design, Best Sound, Best
Editing, Best Original Song (Faraway Part of Town), and Best Music;
Scoring of a Musical Picture. It's surely better than many musicals I
watched from Hollywood's golden age.George Sidney's movies that I saw till now are all an absolute treat.
Plus something else, the women in his movies are all sexy. So sexy at
the least! It's clear that this man loved the showgirls along with the
cabaret's dancing so much. And by the way I began to believe that
(Sidney) was slightly having a passion for the butts (the good female
butts!). Yes, you can believe that when you watch for instance his way
of focusing on the dancing girl with Dailey (after Chevalier's number).
And certainly in other movies like his next (Viva Las Vegas) and (The
Swinger) !I know it gets weird at places (the dance as small people) but again
this is a show with various spectacles, and this trick wasn't popular
only, but was kind of dazzling back then also. However still boring for
a big fan of the movie like me! Plus I couldn't stand Dan Dailey most
of the time. But still the final scene was the worst thing; it
abstracted the Hollywood happy ending yet in the wrong way. It's a rare document about Hollywood at the end of the 1950s. You may
catch on its value after experiencing Hollywood of the 1970s where
movies like (That's Entertainment) were produced just to recall days
like these! Although now it isn't among the top 5, but as this show was
ultra-satisfying for me in my childhood, IT IS as satisfying after. So
bad that it didn't serve its lead to be a Hollywood star. However Pepe
(the movie, the character and the song) are real stars in my memories.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2673557/comments</url><from>from Miami, Fl</from><name>William Bradley (webillbradley@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I have fond memories of this movie.  I remember along with my brother
Alan,
begging our parents to take us to the drive-in to see Pepe.  I don't know
anyone who did not like Cantinflas.  With the advent of DVD, I don't know
why this title has not surfaced.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1597256/comments</url><from>from California, USA</from><name>david</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Cantinflas meets every star in Hollywood, in an attempt to
recapture the 80 Days magic.  No such luck.  Cantinflas was
asked to carry Pepe and simply wasn't up to the task, though it's
perfectly acceptable all-star entertainment.  Cameos by Tony
Curtis, Janet Leigh, Dean Martin, Ernie Kovacs, and particularly
Kim Novak, help make it more than watchable.
In a way it's better than 80 Days, since Kim wasn't in that one.  I
stayed around for the next show to see Kim's cameo again.  In
those days you could remain in the theatre on one paid admission
for as long as you wished.In San Francisco, PEPE played at advanced prices, on continuous
showings, no reserved seats.  On March 14, 1961 I spent nearly
seven hours in the St. Francis Theatre on Market Street.  PEPE
runs 195 minutes.  Us Kim Novak fans are durable, and loyal -
she's still one of my favorite stars.  Wow. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218191/comments</url><from>from Portsmouth, Rhode Island</from><name>JD-50</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Edward G. Robinson, Dan Daily, &amp; Cantinflas (as Pepe) were very convincing
in their major rolls in this movie.  The guest star list was enormous and
included just about everyone who was hot in Hollywood.  My favorite was
Bobby Darin during his zenith.
This movie is like a time capsule from 1960 and would make a great addition
to a collection of family entertainment videos. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1062365/comments</url><from>from Warwick, Pa.</from><name>Teenie-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I agree with many other comments posted here about this film about why
it should never have been given a poor rating by critics. I was ten
years old when this film was released and wanted to see it but never
did until today. I saw it on TCM and boy, what a real treat to have
seen so many of the old stars that have since left us but their talent
and memories still linger in our minds and hearts. I never knew that
Shirley Jones was a dancer until the scene where Dan Dailey is filming
a dance sequence with her and another dancer and Bobby Darin is singing
the story. This is when talent was talent, compared to some of the junk
they call talent today.Cantinflas could have truly been called the Mexican Charlie Chaplin,
with his character so reminiscent of The Little Tramp yet unique in his
own little way. He definitely did not get the credit that he deserved.Take the kids away from the raunchy cartoons and violence and rent this
one for a family viewing night. They will get a kick out of Pepe's
horse and his little donkey. I plan to purchase a copy for myself to
keep in my collection for viewing on a rainy day. This is one of my
all-time favorites.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1062365/comments</url><from>from Warwick, Pa.</from><name>Teenie-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I agree with many other comments posted here about this film about why
it should never have been given a poor rating by critics. I was ten
years old when this film was released and wanted to see it but never
did until today. I saw it on TCM and boy, what a real treat to have
seen so many of the old stars that have since left us but their talent
and memories still linger in our minds and hearts. I never knew that
Shirley Jones was a dancer until the scene where Dan Dailey is filming
a dance sequence with her and another dancer and Bobby Darin is singing
the story. This is when talent was talent, compared to some of the junk
they call talent today.Cantinflas could have truly been called the Mexican Charlie Chaplin,
with his character so reminiscent of The Little Tramp yet unique in his
own little way. He definitely did not get the credit that he deserved.Take the kids away from the raunchy cartoons and violence and rent this
one for a family viewing night. They will get a kick out of Pepe's
horse and his little donkey. I plan to purchase a copy for myself to
keep in my collection for viewing on a rainy day. This is one of my
all-time favorites.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=16168 /m/pepe/comments.php?reviewid=1922265</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Despite the cameos of over 30 movie stars and big budget, George Sidney's gimmicky comedy, starring Mexican actor Cantinflas who goes to Hollywood to take care of his horse, is one of Hollywood's biggest flops of the 1960s. </comment></review></movie>