<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The World of Suzie Wong</original_title><alt_title>Le monde de Suzie Wong</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><country>USA</country><director>Richard Quine</director><producer>World Enterprises</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Robert Lomax tired of working in an office, wants to be an artist. So he moves to Hong Kong to try his hand at painting...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>William Holden</actor><actor>Nancy Kwan</actor><actor>Sylvia Syms</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The setting is Hong Kong in the late fifties… The film tells the story of a bittersweet love affair between an
American architect who has decided to try painting and a wonderful
Asian girl who uses with vigor and diligence her essentially dirty
trade in a turmoil of mischievous fantasy… Suzie Wong (Nancy Kwan), attracted to Robert Lomax (Holden), offers to
be his "steady girlfriend," but a world-weary Lomax informs her that he
has had enough of love and wants only to paint… Paint he does, and the irresistible hooker, appointed as a model,
appears in his work in a variety of poses… A compassionate Lomax
suddenly realizes he loves her and takes her as his mistress… There are comic moments in Richard Quine's movie concerning the lies
Suzie relates to win the respect of her prostitute friends and her
drunken admirer, Ben (Michael Wilding). Nancy Kwan in her film's debut displays a large range of feelings,
alternating hardness, affection, and affinity…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2439952/comments</url><from>from Omaha, NE</from><name> (jmikew797@cox.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Today there are many "chick flicks."  The World of Suzie Wong is the
quintessential "romance for guys."There are two parallel themes in this film: 1) the "Pygmalion" theme,
which
was old when George Bernard Shaw's play first appeared in 1913.
Pygmalion,
in classical legend, was the king of Cyprus who fell in love with his own
sculpture.  Hence the theme of beginning with a raw material (in this case
a
woman of no great position or education) and to some degree transforming
her
into she whom you might adore.Some may object to this theme carrying racist overtones, but in my view
the
reverse is true.  The very fact that in this type of romantic union the
protagonists are of unequal social position means that the man is
attracted
to the woman because of her human qualities, not because of any advantage
she can provide to him in terms of social status or wealth.  In fact, a
man
who loves such a woman is often looked down upon socially, which is
present
in this story.  The object of Robert Lomax's love is Susie Wong for who
she
is as a woman and how she makes him feel, and he gladly, even cynically
disregards the disparagements of those who do not approve.2) Theme number two is the enchantment of the East.  This is magic stuff
for
those so smitten, and once smitten, these is no cure.  In this way, this
wonderful story (novel and film) is understated.  It is barely believable
that Lomax's attraction to Suzie would start from nothing and grow so
slowly
to compelling strength.  This mixture of desire and fascination is more
likely to stormily seize a man's heart, but "Robert meets Suzie-falls
crazy
in love-marries Suzie" would make for a ten-minute film, and that just
wouldn't do, would it?It's also an interesting commentary on the film makers of the fifties that
when they wanted to tell the story of interracial romance they had to
attenuate the effect.  Both Nancy Kwan and France Nguyen (in South
Pacific)
were of mixed parentage.When a guy with Quixotic romantic notions (which Lomax clearly has, or he
would not be in Hong Kong trying to paint professionally) beholds the
lovlieness of a Nancy Kwan in those subtle, but oh, so sexy silk dresses
(cheongsam in Cantonese, Qipao [shee pow] in Mandarin), he sees a vision
of
feminine loveliness he thought could only exist in the Platonic realm of
the
form.  He sees perfection.  He is enchanted.  There is no cure save to
have
this woman for his own or death.  This enchantment your humble
correspondent
knows first-hand, and therefore connects deeply with Robert and
Suzie.The World of Suzie Wong is so very romantic, and the themes explored here
are enduring.  I love the novel -- I love the film.  I can't imagine
anyone
but William Holden playing Lomax.  This role belongs to
he.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3651251/comments</url><from>from VA., U.S.A.</from><name>woolrich2-1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
American William Holden, as former architect turned struggling artist,
Robert Lomax, a cynic who's "pushing forty," arrives in 1960 Hong Kong
to make a valiant effort for his art. He's never been there and has no
idea what to expect. On the ferry boat to Kowloon, he has a sort of
altercation with the very young &amp; attractive Nancy Kwan, who claims to
be named "Mei Li," a very proper young lady about to enter into an
arranged marriage set up by her wealthy father. Shortly before
reluctantly introducing herself, she also almost manages to have Robert
arrested by claiming he's a purse snatcher, which, judging from her
mirthful expression, she does for the sheer entertainment value of the
situation.Robert, completely lost and not particularly wealthy, soon makes his
way to the Wan Chai district, and, in his naivete as American abroad,
fails to realize he's entered the main prostitution district in the
city. His journey to the seedy hotel where he sets up shop as artist
would be one of the highlights of the film: Robert's amazement and
confusion at the bustling, vibrant city that has become his new home
come across nicely. In many ways, the brilliant cinematography and
camera work turn the city of Hong Kong itself into the unacknowledged
third star of the film. However, it's a very different Hong Kong than
now: very much a British colonial post, and, in segments of the
neighborhoods, almost a Third World city.Unfortunately, once Robert reaches the hotel, the movie loses much
realism, and we've plainly entered a 1950's Hollywood set version of
Hong Kong, complete with cartoonish prostitutes and Brit sailors on
leave. It turns out that prim-and-proper Mei Li's none other than "very
popular" Wan Chai "girl" Suzie Wong. There are some very dated scenes
that follow, although actress Jacqui Chan's charming in an off kilter
way as bar girl Gwennie Lee. Nancy Kwan vamps and spouts much pidgin
English and says "for goodness' sake" about 500 times in a row.
Fortunately, Robert, Suzie, and the camera eventually hit the streets
of actual Hong Kong again.Then, something odd happens with this film, bit by bit. The movie
focuses more and more on Robert and Suzie as a couple, and, bit by bit,
Suzie becomes less of a stereotypical bar girl and more and more of a
human being who behaves unexpectedly. It turns out that she has
developed a persona for herself, a very manipulative, successful one,
that's given her an edge in a very harsh city for abandoned young
women. She has an active fantasy life, that's enabled her to separate
herself psychologically from the more sordid aspects of what she's done
in order to survive. Robert too, becomes less and less Joe Gillis, Jr.
(for those of you who've seen Holden in SUNSET BLVD. from a decade
earlier), a one-note, crabby cynic with a paternalistic attitude
towards Suzie, and more and more a human being who's in love. He shows
this most plainly when he finds out that Suzie has an infant son, and
Robert accepts little Winston affectionately as his own. In a complex
way, Suzie, and also little Winston, act as muses for Robert, and his
own art becomes more inspired and interesting because of them. Suzie
also benefits from her love for Robert and shows some real emotion for
him rather than her usual play acting.This is where I find the movie interesting, as it depicts, much more
realistically than one might expect in 1960, the dimensions of a
biracial, bicultural couple's life together. Although Robert has made
contact with the British elite in the city and needs them for patronage
for his art, he's never really comfortable with them or their
patronizing, mildly racist way of observing the Chinese. Kay O'Neill
(actress Sylvia Syms), the daughter of a well-placed British banker,
falls for Robert, but he doesn't really feel any emotion for her as he
does for Suzie. Of course, she can't believe Robert would really prefer
Suzie to her. When he announces he's thinking of marrying Suzie, Kay's
father says that, of course, he could never hire someone in those
circumstances. The rest of the Brits more talk around Suzie than to her
whenever she's present. Likewise, most of the Chinese, while polite
with Robert, don't know quite what to make of him, either, and he seems
to do better either with Suzie as intermediary or because her friends
help him along. It's obvious too that sometimes cultural miscues cause
Suzie and Robert to misunderstand one another. This leads to the
beginning of the climax of the film, which is somewhat tragic. No doubt, this has been a controversial film. In the past, many
Asian-American studies professors seemed to grow livid at the mention
of it. This was supposed to be the ne plus ultra (or maybe the nadir,
instead) for stereotypical portrayals of all Asian women as submissive
little China doll characters or bar girls. There is some of that there
(although much less than in most other 1950's-early 1960's American
films), but, as I'd noted, the interesting thing's how the stereotype
turns out to be a fake, something created for the advantage (if that's
the word) of the heroine for relating to foreigners. It's also
interesting how the genuine romance, one based on a sort of mutual
respect between Robert and Suzie, becomes more important. Most
interesting of all's the portrayal (that mostly rings true) of a
biracial, bicultural romance between two human beings. As someone
involved in such a relationship for many years, I found myself giving
the film an extra star for this "rightness" alone.Plus, if nothing else, this movie's a terrific time capsule/travelogue
of Hong Kong, as it was never so brilliantly captured elsewhere on
screen in that era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2081542/comments</url><from>from Heraganahalli, India</from><name>Herag Halli</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
If there was one beautiful face on the screen that mesmerized me in
1960--it was Nancy Kwan as Suzie Wong in "The World of Suzie Wong".
Forty five years later, I bought the DVD and I treasure this movie as
much as I did in 1960. This was the time when Stars were Stars and
beauty was not skin deep. Nancy Kwan stole the scenes from her
"Permeanent boy friend, Lobert!" (Chinese version of Robert!). William
Holden who was at the peak of his career at that time gave a subtle but
memorable perf. There is more romance in this movie than "Casablanca"
and "Sound of Music" combined. The location is beautifully captured,
with background music embellishing the landscape. This was produced by
Ray Stark and masterfully directed by Richard Quine. This was when
Hollywood was the glamor capitol of the world and artistry and talent
took higher billing. This movie is an attestation to the fact, that-you
make good movies, people will see them no matter what, when and where.
The movie was a visual treat, with an old fashioned romance and an
innate beauty that the newer movies will never capture. "To who it may
concern," Why can't Hollywood make more movie's like this?-"For
Goodness Sake"!!!.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1422160/comments</url><from>from Hong Kong</from><name>Katie</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

AT LONG LAST I saw The World of Suzie Wong at my school library today. You
just have to see it to believe it. It is a shame that it takes an outsider
(Hollywood) to capture the exotic beauty of the old-time Hong Kong. (With
Love Is a Many-splendored Thing as the forerunner) I have never seen Hong
Kong photographed in a flattering yet realistic light. Nancy Kwan ignites
the screen with such charm and grace which Asian actresses seriously lack
today. All through the film I smile whenever I see her. I love her
chemistry
with William Holden..yet another favorite of mine...Hong Kong is blessed to
be immortalized by this exquisite romance.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0624493/comments</url><from>from Bozeman, Montana</from><name>L K Moore</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

When Nancy Kwan turned her beguiling eyes on William Holden in this 1960
[risque for the time] movie I felt weak in the knees.
I was 13 and in my little home town of Miles City, Montana I was far
removed
from the type of life depicted here. The plot though very understandable
featured tough realities to depict. Kwan's beauty seemed vibrant, fresh and
full of innocense, how could she play a prostitute? [Her spectacular
performance kept me spellbound throughout the movie and I knew THEN that
girls must be much more complex than my heretofore 13 year old male pysche
could imagine.] The obvious age difference between William Holden and Kwan
was a hurdle few professional actors and actresses at the time could have
so
skillfully surmounted, they were superb, they sizzled then they were
tender,
then they were angry. I count this film in my top-ten ALLtime for these and
a number of other reasons.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3480595/comments</url><from>from Sugar Land, Texas</from><name>ust2006</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I remember watching this movie years ago on TV one night and absolutely
being mesmerized by the lovely Nancy Kwan..When I noticed it was
available on DVD I rented it one evening and was again totally
captivated by Nancy..Back in the sixties, Nancy Kwan was the biggest
Asian star around! She made her debut in this lavishly filmed
production and what a debut! She exudes an incredible amount of sex
appeal yet there is an innocence about her that is very charming in
this film! I've read that this film was criticized for negative
portrayals of asians....but if you just look within the context of the
story, I think it's a powerful love story..which is what it was meant
to be! The locales are fantastic..William Holden is wonderful and the
supporting cast is full of colorful characters!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0885866/comments</url><from>from Ile-de-France / Paris Region, France</from><name>Nicholas Rhodes</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Long before "Pretty Woman", "Maid in Manhattan" and "In the Mood For Love"
were dreamed up, we have this beautiful film from the fifties which is the
meatiest of them all.True the film is a bit long, but this does not detract from the general
impression it gives to the spectator.The dialogues are sublime, the technicolor is wonderful and both
protagonists are very beaufiful actors. I saw this on TV and would dearly
love to have it on DVD ( chance would be a fine thing !!! ) to have a better
sound quality for the dialogues.For pure unadulterated romance and passion, this film is hard to
beat.
One gets the impression that it was rather ahead of its time when it came
out.Lastly, those frightening landslide sequences close to the end are really
impressive, and the "baby's funeral" also leaves a bitter taste in the
mouth.A truly magnificent film, seemingly little known today, and which would gain
from being made better known to the general public .......
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4908105/comments</url><from>from Singapore</from><name>celia c</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A romance between an American artist and a Chinese prostitute, this
show can't be truly appreciated by those unfamaliar with the Chinese
cultures/way. Some find the behaviour of Suzie Wong in this show
appalling in some scenes, the part where she seems proud that Robert
hit her. In those day in the Chinese culture it is portrayed as a sign
that the man cares about you, not so with American culture. I love the
part where she gave her hard earned money to Robert because his
paintings were not making money, his reaction proofed that he did love
he, wanting to provide and not be provided for. I gave this show a 9/10
because the only fault i can find with it is the scene where she finds
her son dead, i felt that she didn't act like a mother would when she
found her son dead. Not enough emotion, William Holden did a fanstastic
job as the artist. Charming yet dependable. Overall one of my
favourites to date.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0220554/comments</url><from>from Lucas Buck, NC</from><name>Doctor_Bombay</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

There was a time when late night TV meant Johnny Carson and a cloud of dust,
the other two networks scrambling locally with ‘Million Dollar Movie'
packages. It was a time when broad appeal movies like `The World of Suzie
Wong' flourished on TV-start with a basic romance, add exotic settings and
just a hint of comedy.William Holden was never more a leading man than in this film. Take all the
dynamic sex appeal he exudes in Network, and turn the clock back some 15
years. He is commanding.This quirky little comedy hits all the right spots, with Nancy Kwan
absolutely stunning as the Won-Tsai Girl, Suzie. Beautiful Hong Kong
landscapes are just the cherry on top of this sweet deal. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0220554/comments</url><from>from Lucas Buck, NC</from><name>Doctor_Bombay</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

There was a time when late night TV meant Johnny Carson and a cloud of dust,
the other two networks scrambling locally with ‘Million Dollar Movie'
packages. It was a time when broad appeal movies like `The World of Suzie
Wong' flourished on TV-start with a basic romance, add exotic settings and
just a hint of comedy.William Holden was never more a leading man than in this film. Take all the
dynamic sex appeal he exudes in Network, and turn the clock back some 15
years. He is commanding.This quirky little comedy hits all the right spots, with Nancy Kwan
absolutely stunning as the Won-Tsai Girl, Suzie. Beautiful Hong Kong
landscapes are just the cherry on top of this sweet deal. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0220554/comments</url><from>from Lucas Buck, NC</from><name>Doctor_Bombay</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/world-of-suzie-wong-the-1960-2/ /m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1985868</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>Though stereotypical, this interracial romantic melodrama was one of William Holden's most popular films</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1403747</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1373012</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117796477.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1730646</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/64820/the_world_of_suzie_wong.html /m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1474082</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C01E5DB1030EF3ABC4952DFB767838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1394695</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sharon-mizota/</url><url>http://popmatters.com/film/reviews/w/world-of-suzie-wong.shtml /m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=1337041</url><name>Sharon Mizota</name><from>PopMatters</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movieline.standard8media.com/reviews/world_of_suzie_wong.shtml /m/world_of_suzie_wong/comments.php?reviewid=263411</url><from>Movieline</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>