<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ma Barker's Killer Brood</original_title><imdb_rating>5.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Bill Karn</director><producer>Screen Classics Inc.</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Ma Barker and her four sons terrorize the 1930s South and Midwest with a string of kidnappings, robberies and murders, and even get to work with such famous criminals as John Dillinger and Baby Face Nelson.
</synopsis><actor>Lurene Tuttle</actor><actor>Tristram Coffin</actor><actor>Paul Dubov</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0108408/comments</url><from>from Jersey City, NJ</from><name>Paul Curtis</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This film is terrific fun!  It makes up for its tiny budget with wild,
over-the-top performances (Lurene Tuttle was sweet-voiced Effie on the Sam
Spade radio show...WHAT a DIFFERENCE!), extreme violence (one part where
they set a guy on fire gets shown TWICE!) and goofy, quotable
dialogue.This is the kind of movie The Addams Family would watch with their
kids.With these things in mind, viewers looking for an accurate, historical
picture will be disoriented, or at least disappointed.  This is definitely
not a good source for American History term papers.  It is intended as a
source for giggly thrills, and is a good one. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3303692/comments</url><from>from sparks, nevada</from><name>shepardjessica</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

This film is a fairly inaccurate representation of Ma Barker, but is great
fun with some very strange scenes.  The slapping of the one son is a
crack-up.  Lurene Tuttle (Sheriff Chambers' sweet wife in PSYCHO) is
incredibly vicious and driven as the matriarch of this ignorant brood of
miscreants.  A 5 out of 10.  Best performance = Lurene Tuttle.  A lot of these cheapo
exploitation flicks of the 50's and 60's are loaded with strange
performances and interesting cinematography.  This is available on cheap DVD
and well worth a look.  I waited years to find this one.  Give it a
shot!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9929801/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>wjrprezhistorian</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I agree -- it was low budget schlock at its worst -- but I enjoyed it!
I enjoyed seeing a Young Don Grady (of TV's My Three Sons fame) as one
of the kids in the beginning of the film...Lurene Tuttle was quite
'campy' in her portrayal of 'Ma.' I only knew her from her days as the
older nurse on the late 1960's TV series 'Julia' (starring Diahann
Carroll).I'll tell you how much I enjoyed this picture, I had gone to see a
movie based on a Tony Award winning play earlier in the day, something
that I had been looking forward to seeing, but I was thoroughly
disenchanted and disgusted with it.At least, with 'Ma', I did not expect HIGH expectations of it, but I
enjoyed it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6972563/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vosamis-1</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
It's true, Ma Barker really did nothing, other than as the man said,
provide a house of refuge for her admitedly killer brood. She never had
a gun in her hand (the billboard for the movie shows her blasting away
with a "tommy" gun) and would not even have known how to fire one (she
was not bright). Ma Barker never was charged with a crime, and was
never arrested. She was shot by Hoover's "G Men" in I think 1935, and
they had to justify he murder somehow, so they just made up the story
of her being a criminal master mind. Anyhow, this movie stinks, not
just because it is fake, but from what the young man above said so
well, that it is just a junky movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630861/comments</url><from>from Mountain Mesa, California</from><name>rsoonsa (rsoonsa@bandbbooks.com)</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

Supposedly based upon the life of Ozark matriarch Ma Barker and her four
felonious public enemy sons, this meanly made low budget example of
drive-in
movie schlock actually treats several incidents in the real-life career
of
the notorious Barker/Karpis Gang which was very active during 1931/35
from
the Midwest into Southeast U.S., but so contorts the truth in order to
create a lurid melodrama that a viewer is alienated from the proceedings,
especially in light of obvious cut-rate production values.  Al Karpis was
the confirmed master hand behind the Gang's string of sinful successes
whereas the factual Ma Barker, although enjoying holding open house for
various fugitives, only travelled with her family and was patently
incapable
of organizing more than luncheons, whereas in this poorly scripted
travesty
Lurene Tuttle as a tommygun wielding sadistic sociopath performs a raft
of
maniacal actions, including running over a policeman twice, all while
planning the Gang's adventures and serving up heist advice to respectful
triggermen such as John Dillinger, Machine Gun Kelly and Baby Face
Nelson.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630861/comments</url><from>from Mountain Mesa, California</from><name>rsoonsa (rsoonsa@bandbbooks.com)</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

Supposedly based upon the life of Ozark matriarch Ma Barker and her four
felonious public enemy sons, this meanly made low budget example of
drive-in
movie schlock actually treats several incidents in the real-life career
of
the notorious Barker/Karpis Gang which was very active during 1931/35
from
the Midwest into Southeast U.S., but so contorts the truth in order to
create a lurid melodrama that a viewer is alienated from the proceedings,
especially in light of obvious cut-rate production values.  Al Karpis was
the confirmed master hand behind the Gang's string of sinful successes
whereas the factual Ma Barker, although enjoying holding open house for
various fugitives, only travelled with her family and was patently
incapable
of organizing more than luncheons, whereas in this poorly scripted
travesty
Lurene Tuttle as a tommygun wielding sadistic sociopath performs a raft
of
maniacal actions, including running over a policeman twice, all while
planning the Gang's adventures and serving up heist advice to respectful
triggermen such as John Dillinger, Machine Gun Kelly and Baby Face
Nelson.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630861/comments</url><from>from Mountain Mesa, California</from><name>rsoonsa (rsoonsa@bandbbooks.com)</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>