<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Conspiracy of Hearts</original_title><alt_title>Les conspiratrices</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Ralph Thomas</director><producer>Rank Organisation, The</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In wartime Italy nuns in a convent regularly smuggle Jewish children out of a nearby internment camp...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Lilli Palmer</actor><actor>Sylvia Syms</actor><actor>Yvonne Mitchell</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3192976/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, USA</from><name>marcosaguado</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I saw it when I was 8 years old, I'm almost 40 now and I always
remember this movie. Catholic nuns in France, hiding Jewish children in
their convent during the occupation. Lilli Palmer, I remember her face
vividly. There must be a reason, but I can't find a copy of that film,
not even on video. Maybe, I should keep the memory as it is, rather
than jeopardizing it by seeing again, today. I couldn't sleep after I
saw it. I think I lived that film. It happened to me another time, when
I was around the same age. A Spanish movie, MARCELINO PAN Y VINO.
Strangely enough, both films have religious roots and take place within
the walls of convents and monasteries. I wonder what that means.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3162457/comments</url><from>from Cary, North Carolina</from><name>Richard Rohrer (donriccardo)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw this film when I was young, and I have never forgotten it.  There
are
certain scenes of compassion and courage that have been with me ever
since.
The decision to do the right thing in spite of the consequences is upheld
in
the portrayal of the nuns, the priest, the rabbi and even the soldiers
ordered to shoot the nuns. The lesson that to be good and godly means to
personally involve oneself in direct,compassionate intervention on behalf
of
those in need is clearly shown and lauded, as is the truth that love and
compassion can know no ethnic nor religious boundaries.  It is a good
movie,
especially for the young. I would hope that it could be made available for
purchase.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1612270/comments</url><from>from New York City</from><name>gelashe</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie as a little girl with my mom. I was too young to
understand or appreciate it. I got the opportunity to see it in my
twenties and never forgot it. The last time it was shown, I taped it
and have never seen it on T. V. again.The courtyard scene at the end is what I remember most. Other memorable
scenes are: the nuns hiding the children at the bottom of the farmer's
wheelbarrel while a Nazi officer stabs a pitchfork into it to make sure
it is really garbage underneath, the German nun who was angry at hiding
the children at the beginning, later winds up saving one of them by
hiding her under her habit and the beginning of the film when the nuns
asked a little girl her name, and she replies "Jew Dog". She said she
had been called that so many times by the Germans that she forgot her
real name, and at Yom Kippur when the children read the names of their
families who are all dead. This is a wonderful movie. It is a shame it
is not available on video or shown on cable.Lily Palmer as the Mother Superior is outstanding especially noting her
beauty.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10186390/comments</url><from>from Berkshire United Kingdom</from><name>bobmorgslu</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I first saw this movie in 1960 when I was 10 and was taken to see it
with my mother on our weekly Monday night visit to the Cinema. I didn't
go out of choice, It was just for me and my mother to get out of my
Fathers way so he could get on with jobs about the house. I can't
remember many films that I saw at that time but this was one of the few
that stuck in my mind. I suppose it was that I could identify with the
Children as they were about my age and that it was about the war. Those
of us born in the 40's and 50's grew up with stories about the war. It
was certainly a topic for discussion I'm our household as my Father had
been a radio operator in the RAF from 1939 onwards.I can remember being deeply moved and disturbed by it even at that
young age especially at the climatic ending. Since then I have seen it
on TV as it occasionally pops up on UK TV often in the afternoons. The
last time it appeared about 18 months ago I took the opportunity to
record it on Video. I watch it when I need to renew my faith in mankind
as it proves that even in the darkest times, there are people who will
risk all for others and their beliefs and that goodness eventually
triumphs over evil.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3320540/comments</url><from>from Perthshire</from><name>philphoto</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

My Mother took me to see this film at the Lowestoft Odeon around 1960
(I was 8) . Why I remember it is that the Cinema Manager told my Mother
that the film was on its first screening in the UK even before London
(dunno why) and there would be a surprise after the film. The surprise
was the Actor Ronald Lewis who came on stage . Unfortunately some of
the audience hissed him which put him off a little-he said 'Im one of
the Good Guys' or words to that effect but then gave us an interesting
talk about making the film. I didn't understand the movie at the time
really but seeing it this afternoon was the first time since then. The
film showed the Italian troops in a good, professional light when our
Dads at the time told us that they had 'chased them all over North
Africa'

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1355003/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>sol-</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
An appropriately solemn and always very compelling Holocaust era film,
it is quite competently acted, especially by the child actors and
actresses, who give off realistic and believable performances. In
particular, Rebecca Dignam stands out as a child who the nuns take a
special liking to. The plot line sounds rather ordinary but it works
well, providing a fine and interesting tale. The film is, however, a
bit too melodramatic, and on top of that it ends unrealistically. But
for what it is, it is very good. Based on a story by Adrian Scott, it
went credited to Dale Pitt due to blacklisting, but either way Robert
Presnell Jr.'s screenplay is generally fine.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7633029/comments</url><from>from Coleraine, N.Ireland</from><name>Feckart</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I worry that at some time in the not too distant future the extent of
the evil perpetrated during the 1930s and 40s will be forgotten. Watch
this film and remind yourself that unless all good people stand strong,
every day and every hour, these sort of events will keep happening,
over and over again.In this shocking (certainly for 1960), depressing, heart-breaking,
uplifting and surprisingly honest movie, we see that it is only through
individuals taking personal responsibility for their actions that we
can have any hope of building a world fit for our children.When I see films like this, and read the positive response from
reviewers on IMDb, I still have some hope for the future.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0622738/comments</url><from>from Weatherford, Texas</from><name>mterr53851 (mterr53851@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie when it first came out..as a ten year old it grabbed
me because of my deep abiding respect for the Nuns . I went to a
Catholic school in 1961 with a much better view of what the Sisters
stood for...this is a great movie and yes it is too bad it's not on VHS
or DVD ..and I don't know why no-one in the movie business is not
pushing the issue to put this movie on tape for public
distribution...the same goes with "Something is Out There" another
great made for TV movie..and a few other made for TV movies...come on
Movie industry wake up and fly right the "BUYING" public is out here
waiting!!! Can ya hear the Thunder??
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0220020/comments</url><from>from Florida</from><name>Phlicker</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Because, as this movie shows, people ARE good.I saw it when I was only ten, and to all intents and purposes, "Conspiracy
of Hearts" seems to have vanished from the surface of the
earth.One scene sticks in my mind after all these years.  One of the newly
arrived
Jewish refugees (a girl) is given bread to eat.  "You can't eat that," a
boy
from elsewhere warns her.  The nuns protest that there is nothing wrong
with
the bread.  The girl takes a bite and is chewing it when the boy whispers
in
her ear.  We see the girl's mouth open, and the partially chewed bread is
expelled.  Why?POSSIBLE SPOILER (not of the movie -- just of the scene)What the boy has told her is: "It's Yom Kippur."The movie was quite suspenseful and very involving.  If you ever get the
chance to see
"Conspiracy of Hearts," by all means jump at it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10768443/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>inspire_wisdom</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Please can this beautiful film regarding Christian suffering and the
understanding of standing for principles of truth be re-released on
DVD. Even though I am not a Catholic Christian, but of another part of
the family of Christ, I attended a Catholic school and I just feel this
a really beautiful film.May God Bless all those Christians that risked
their lives to save Jews and the weak in Nazi Occupied Europe. I feel
these kind of films must be shown to an ignorant generation of people
that have forgotten the horrors of World War 2. The wish of those that
gave their lives in World War 2 for freedom and peace is that "We don't
forget".Even if we look at the World now there is still genocide still
taking place against vulnerable people just because they are different
or speak different.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10768443/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>inspire_wisdom</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Please can this beautiful film regarding Christian suffering and the
understanding of standing for principles of truth be re-released on
DVD. Even though I am not a Catholic Christian, but of another part of
the family of Christ, I attended a Catholic school and I just feel this
a really beautiful film.May God Bless all those Christians that risked
their lives to save Jews and the weak in Nazi Occupied Europe. I feel
these kind of films must be shown to an ignorant generation of people
that have forgotten the horrors of World War 2. The wish of those that
gave their lives in World War 2 for freedom and peace is that "We don't
forget".Even if we look at the World now there is still genocide still
taking place against vulnerable people just because they are different
or speak different.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10768443/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>inspire_wisdom</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>