<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Devi</original_title><alt_title>La déesse</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>Satyajit Ray</director><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Devi focuses on a young woman, who is deemed a goddess when her father-in-law, a rich feudal landlord, envisions her as the Goddess Kali.
</synopsis><actor>Chhabi Biswas</actor><actor>Soumitra Chatterjee</actor><actor>Sharmila Tagore</actor><rt_rating>7.6/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0097928/comments</url><from>from San Jose, CA</from><name>Rex Michael Dillon (misterdillon@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This film was made in 1960. This is interesting because it is highly
doubtful that the same film could be made in India today, in spite of
India's massive film industry. The film does a great depiction of the
crisis faced by people struggling to be modern yet encumbered with the
traditional systems and the specter of having been colonized. The younger son is ready to walk away from the bondage of traditional
and as he sees, the superstition of the traditional life. Of course, he
is reaping the benefit of life as a high caste. His young wife becomes
the Devi - the embodiment of the goddess. This film also works well for
its psychological content for the way we see the father project his
desires onto those around him, and the choices faced by each character.
In light of the fundamentalism worldwide - Christian, Muslim &amp; Hindu -
it is hard to image that this film could be made today in India since
it leans to a skeptical view of Darsan and the goddess.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0198397/comments</url><from>from Montreal, Canada</from><name>Daniel Yates</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

"Devi" is one of Satyajit Ray's most compact films.  At 93 minutes,
it
is his shortest feature, and the story is one of his simplest to describe.
In the 1830's young woman, Doya, lives in a mansion with her father and
extended family.  Her husband works far away, but plans to have Doya move
with him soon.  On day Doya's father drops to her feet and proclaims that
she is the reincarnation of the Goddess Kali.  At first Doya is skeptical,
but when a sick boy seems to be cured in her presence, she too comes to
believe that she is the Goddess.  Despite her husbands attempt to take her
away from the house, she stays.  When she is not able to cure a second
sick
boy, her nephew, she cannot handle the pressure, and despite her husband's
pleas, runs away into the mist.Yet despite the seeming simplicity of the story line, "Devi" is a
complex work.  Aesthetically,  Ray is able to use the space in an
incredibly
evocative manner.  In the beginning of the film the interiors of the
mansion
are shot in a relatively open manner, and there seems to be a lot of space
to move around.  As the film progresses, the shots get tighter and there
seems to be less space.  This contrasts with all the exterior sequences,
which are shot using a greater degree of long shots.  Yet, this is not a
simplistic visual statement by Ray that suggests that the indoor are
confining while the outdoors represents freedom.  In fact the outdoors too
is confining, for along with the open space come oppressive mists and
clouds, as well as the tendency to have the characters draped in shadow.
It's as if Ray is saying there is nowhere for these characters to go, no
escape from their fate.At the end of the film, when Doya runs away, she is enshrouded in
mist,
leaving it ambiguous as to what will happen to her, and certainly
suggesting
that she has not found escape.  Although in most plot summaries it is
stated
that Doya dies in the end, that did not seem to be case with the print
that
I saw.  Perhaps the other writers were thinking of the original story.  In
any case, by having Doya run away into the mists, Ray makes a more
powerful
statement than if he were to have her simply die.  By dying, we know that
although this was the tragic result of her father pressuring her into
believing she was the Goddess, she has found some release.  By having Doya
running away into the mist, Ray creates a much more chilling conclusion,
for
we know that Doya might never be able to undo the damage that has been
done.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2840174/comments</url><from>from London city (UK)</from><name>Edi_Drums</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
So evocative are the facial expressions and gestures of the characters
(in both dramatic display and awkward suppression), and so expressive
the use of music and camera angles, that the spoken word seems
necessary only to keep the story moving along. Long periods of silence,
with only stirring music or even just the background sounds of everyday
life, give the scant dialogue secondary importance. It is testament to
the power of the self-contained plot.At the close of the film, we see Uma (the faithful husband) beholding
Doya in an ethereally-sunlit bedroom. She is in despair. We can be
forgiven for thinking that he is seeing her ghost, or even that the
film is about to take a far-fetched, fantastical turn. But no, the
director is simply bombarding us with flooding light: the film ends
moments later with Doya's panicked flight into the mist.As a climax to gradually-escalating tension through the film, the
ending feels both open to interpretation, whilst also having a dark,
sobering finality. In fleeing, Doya may succeed in liberating herself
from her situation and regaining her individuality. On the other hand,
it could be a crazed act of desperation condemning her to inescapable
turmoil and suffering, now irreparably damaged by the effects of her
'deification' - the religious superstition and fanaticism set in motion
by her father-in-law, but which has spread so quickly through the
community.This film, in its slow-paced but mesmerising simplicity, is sublime. In
2001, forty-one years after its release, the lead actress Sharmila
Tagore discussed the film (in an interview with Nasreen Munni Kabir):"I was only fourteen when I acted in Devi, so we did the filming during
my summer holidays. Sometimes the lighting took a long time to set up,
and dealing with the physical tiredness of sitting still, I found
myself fitting into the character. I BECAME the character. The key to
that kind of performance is not to think: it is to suspend thought, and
just to be. I had to empty my mind of everything and just allow Doya to
take over. She is not a thinking person, but a feeling person. It is
all filmed in close-ups, so the face begins to haunt the viewer."Something once happened on set when we were filming in a studio in
Calcutta. In a scene where the girl is sitting there, everybody
worshipping her as Devi, a very old man came and prostrated himself
before me. It was such a strange, eerie experience. I immediately
understood how Doya must be feeling."To accept it all as real(istic) you have to understand nineteenth
century Bengal. Patriarchy was paramount. Orthodoxy and superstition
were also very deeply entrenched. At the same time though, rationalism
was just beginning to raise its head, but it was too timid to confront
the strong orthodoxy: the father was the head of the family. Nobody
could question him. ("Please your father and you please the gods",
remarks the brother in law.)"All Ray's films are culturally specific, and yet they have a timeless
quality. You can watch Devi in any era and relate to it, depending on
your own experience and your own evolution. I watch the film now and
still see things I missed then."I would say that it is one my best performances. It was a complex role
to play, a challenge. It definitely remains my favourite film."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3847551/comments</url><from>from Ronn Ives/FUTURES Antiques, Norfolk, VA.</from><name> (futures@exis.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Devi" (Hindi, 1960): Directed by Satyajit Ray, and banned in India
until the intercession of Nehru, this is the story of a lovely 17 year
old wife, who is suddenly labeled as a "Goddess" (while her husband is
absent to complete his final exams in college), due to a dream
("vision") by her father-in-law. What follows is a fascinating,
multi-angled look at the transitional Indian culture (and MOST
cultures, frankly). Is this any different, any worse, or any more
desperate than seeing the face of Jesus in a grilled cheese sandwich or
the grain of a wooden door? Is her overnight change in status unique?
Are the people who have confused motives, hopelessness, or malleable
minds any less vulnerable here and now? The quality of the video copy I
viewed was rough – a copy of a copy of a copy – yet even then, the
power of Ray's vision shines through. This is a serious, beautiful,
insightful, tragic film. (It has something of a "cousins" relationship
to the film "Anchoress".)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6519738/comments</url><from>from London, United Kingdom</from><name>Jag85</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
After watching Satyajit Ray's The Apu Trilogy (1955-1959), which are
now my favourite films of all time, I was looking forward to watching
Devi, the next film Ray directed after The Apu Trilogy. Although I
couldn't feel the same kind of emotional connection with the characters
in Devi that I felt in The Apu Trilogy, this film was thought-provoking
and very intriguing to watch.Devi dealt with a serious issue in Bengali society at the time in a
mature manner and Ray's direction and cinematography for this film was
just as superb as The Apu Trilogy. It starred Soumitra Chatterjee and
Sharmila Tagore once again as a married couple, like in Apur Sansar
(the final part of The Apu Trilogy). However, whereas it was Soumitra
who played the lead role in Apur Sansar, this time it's Sharmila who
plays the lead role in Devi. Her performance was very subtle for the
first half but her delusional performance towards the end was very
convincing. Overall, I'd highly recommend this movie to any Satyajit
Ray fan.8/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0428246/comments</url><from>from Arlington County, Virginia</from><name>mazumdar</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

WARNING -- PLOT DISCUSSED -- Umaprasad is a modern man. He argues with his
wife, Doyamoyee, about the value of a modern education when she asks him
not
to leave her at home for his college in Calcutta. (Doyamoyee is 17 and the
two have been married for four years. They seem still to have the
attraction
of newlyweds for each other -- yes, it can happen, even with an arranged
marriage!) Why do you need to go away for this kind of education, she asks
him. Umaprasad's father is a good and learned man; he never needed that
kind
of an education and he has always done his duty to his family and to god.
Doyamoyee and the father, a widow, have great regard for each other and
while Umaprasad is away in the metropolis, the father's regard for his
young
daughter-in-law grows, slowly, to what we might consider an extremely
pathological level. Is there some sexual tension behind this astonishing
behaviour? It's always possible. But don't be misled; this film is not in
any way about sex or perversity. All the outward manifestations of
affection
are very proper and correct in a Bengali context. (A foot massage given by
a
young wife to her father-in-law is not considered an erotic act, rather a
dutiful one.) This film is about the nature of devotion and duty. The
father's level of devotion becomes dangerous to everyone in the
household --
for Doyamoyee, for Umaprasad, and for Umaprasad's elder brother Taraprasad
and his wife Harasundari and their child. Umaprasad doesn't agree with his
father, Taraprasad probably doesn't, Doyamoyee probably don't either. But
what can be done? The father's devotion is perfectly logical in the
context
of tradition. How can Umaprasad speak against it? It will take courage.
But
courage to do what, destroy his own father? There is a complex web of
duties
involved. How will Umaprasad do his duty to his father? his wife? Has the
childless Doyamoyee failed in her duties to her husband? How will
Harasundari do her duty to her father-in-law as well as to her husband and
to her young son? All these questions are implied. As usual, director
Satyajit Ray applies a subtle hand -- given an extraordinary situation,
what
would you really do? How would you really behave? To westerners,
Umaprasad's
reaction to his father's actions may be unbelievable. This is perhaps a
difference in place in time. Put yourself in his shoes -- devotion must be
respected and duty must be done.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20464595/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>princebansal1982</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Devi explores the psychology behind faith. Most Indians still believe
in reincarnations and avatars. We still want to believe in miracles and
spiritual-gurus who proclaim themselves to be God or his prophet still
number in plenty.Sharmila Tagore plays Doyamoyee, a kind hearted girl who is married to
Umaprasad. She is loved by everybody in the household especially her
father-in-law Kalikinkar Roy and her nephew. Father-in-law likens her
appreciative nature to that of his own mother.The real trouble starts when he see Doyamoyee as a goddess in his
dreams. The very next morning he falls to her feet and proclaims her as
a goddess. Doya who is really a child as well a traditional Indian wife
who is not supposed to argue with her elders, doesn't dares to protest.
The person who could protest, which is her husband is away and unaware
of what is happening in the house. Only person who protests is her
sister-in-law who knows her much better than her father-in-law and
writes to Umaprasad to come back.Initially Doya thinks that she is not a Devi, but when a sick boy is
miraculously cured, her own judgement is clouded.This movie is a little atypical for Ray. It is a psychological and
claustrophobic movie like Persona but still having its grip on reality.Cinematography is excellent and there are few powerful scenes. After
Jalsaghar Chhabi Biswas again gives an amazing performance as
Kalikinkar Roy.This is second movie of Sharmila Tagore, and she has the
most expressive face I have ever seen. While in the movie she is
supposed to be 17 she was actually 14 while filming of the movie. While
she did scores of movies in her long career, this is her most memorable
and haunting performance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0286381/comments</url><from>from California, USA</from><name>Ven-3</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Excellent film. Captures the essence of religious superstition verses
spirituality. Shot in glorious black and white the film is essentially about
a 17 year old bride ( played by Sharmila Tagore)whose atheist husband goes
away for further studies leaving her with his family in a rural town in
Bengal.
Her devout father-in-law, who is an ardent worshipper of the goddess Kali,
has a vision that his daughter-in-law is actually an incarnation of the
goddess. The devoted daughter-in-law, initially, plays along for the
fear of
hurting his feelings but as the movie progresses she gets caught up in the
ritualistic practices and starts to believe that she is actually the
goddesses incarnate. I have actually seen things like that happen and I
think Ray captured the mass hysteria of an entire town very well. The
struggle between the son who is a spiritual man but is not superstious and
his father is well portrayed. Over all an excellent film, not on par
with the
Apu trilogy however.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0502794/comments</url><from>from virginia</from><name>pat (edsapir@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

'Devi' is so good I went out and bought the whole 'Apu Trilogy.' Which was
expensive, and I'm poor. 'Devi' is so good that I've watched it enough
times
to be able to mouth along to it in Bengali, and I don't speak Bengali.
"Khoka khotay?" "Aaaa... cheko ta." (I'm now learning Bengali because I
love
this movie so much!)There is such an intricate web of relationships between the characters,
that
it reminds me of Macbeth. The story is very specifically about the Indian
culture (it's revealing investigation into Hinduism could have happened
nowhere else) but its tale of strife between generations is something
anyone
can understand and feel.If you would like to talk about this film, please email me! "Namoskar."
(I'm
pretty sure that means 'goodbye!')
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449070/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Sid Debgupta</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The direction is taut, but the plot is thin on the ground,
and the ending leaves something to be desired. Best part
of
the movie is undoubtedly the couple of Shyama sangeets
thrown in.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449070/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Sid Debgupta</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The direction is taut, but the plot is thin on the ground,
and the ending leaves something to be desired. Best part
of
the movie is undoubtedly the couple of Shyama sangeets
thrown in.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449070/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Sid Debgupta</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/devi.htm /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=2005567</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>Ray's lyrical images reflect on how the fervor of Hinduism can sometimes lead to misplaced worship.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://online.tvguide.com/newsearch/detail.aspx?tvobjectid=124686&amp;more=ucmoviereview /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=1535116</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Ray shows compassion and insight, telling the story in a subdued but fascinating manner.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/mem/movies/review.html?title1=&amp;title2=Devi%20%28Movie%29&amp;reviewer=&amp;v_id=13486&amp;pdate=19621008&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=1388897</url><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment>A haunting experience, and should have been, coming from afar from a man born to make movies.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>/m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=1264405</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>F5 (Wichita, KS)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Lacks the enraptured rhythms of The Apu Trilogy, but engrossing all the same.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/2659_DEVI.html /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=30570</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>One of Satyajit Ray's greatest early films (1962), full of sensuality and ironic undertones.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/edward-guthmann/</url><url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/1995/09/22/DD38900.DTL /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=30571</url><name>Edward Guthmann</name><from>San Francisco Chronicle</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>It's a film that bears all the hallmarks of Ray's best work: gracefulness, exquisite pacing and composition, love for his characters and a deep regard for the power of silence to tell a story.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=1407469</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/65365/devi.html /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=1474518</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102755 /m/devi/comments.php?reviewid=1147352</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>