<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Seven Ways from Sundown</original_title><alt_title>Les sept chemins du couchant</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Harry Keller</director><producer>Universal Pictures</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
Audie Murphy is again the kid who puts on a badge to catch the bad guy, skillfully played by Barry Sullivan...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Audie Murphy</actor><actor>Barry Sullivan</actor><actor>Venetia Stevenson</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2805771/comments</url><from>from Fort Lauderdale, FL</from><name>triassic4</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I will not take up space by reviewing what other Viewer's comments have
already unanimously echoed -- this is a greatly overlooked and
EXCELLENT Western 60's film (as are quite a few of AUDIE MURPHY's
films). What I ask of UNIVERSAL DVD Productions is to .... PLEASE WAKE
UP ... and to please release some of AUDIE MURPHY's films onto DVD! Did
you know that almost NONE of his films have ever even been released
onto VHS ... or ... DVD!! How absurd!! The ONLY times I have ever been
able to even see these films were (recently) on TMC (a GREAT Channel!!)
and several years ago on AMC (before they "sold out" to the Corporate
conglomerates and SAVAGELY BUTCHERED their films with gross
"commercialization" -- which is pretty SAD for a Company that boasted
and prided itself in FILM RESTORATION and PRESERVATION!!). Here are a
few of AUDIE's FINE Western titles which I offer to UNIVERSAL for
consideration: SEVEN WAYS FROM SUNDOWN, HELL BENT FOR LEATHER, GUNS OF
FORT PETTICOAT, COLUMN SOUTH, and RIDE CLEAR OF DIABLO. Thankfully, at
least a few of his films ARE available on DVD ... and you should check
them out or buy them -- you will NOT be disappointed: DUEL AT SILVER
CREEK, NIGHT PASSAGE (with JAMES STEWART!), and NO NAME ON THE BULLET.
These films can stand right up there and beside any of the other
Classic Western Films!! Thanks for reading.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
One source I regard as essential when it comes to Westerns is a book by
Phil Hardy called " The Western " and forming volume 1 of the Aurem
Encycopedia of the cinema .It lists genre movies by year with potted
critical reviews .Except that it does not give this robust and unusual
little movie its own review relegating it instead to an appendix where
it is mentioned but not singled out for comment Bad error from a normally reliable writer because this is a most
enjoyable movie .Murphy plays a neophyte Texas Ranger with the somewhat
cumbersome name of Seven Ways From Sundown Jones .He is sent in company
with a grizzled veteran to track down Jim Flood a charismatic and
freethinking outlaw .Jones captures Flood but not until his partner is
killed and he begins the task of returning Flood to captivity .Flood
turns out to be a likable man and a friendship develops between the
two men whose journey is interrupted by bounty hunters and Indians
before reaching its climax at Rangers headquarters Sullivan is outstanding as Flood and Murphy is more than competent as
the Ranger and there is a strong supporting cast Check this out .Its well made ,well acted and well written .It should
not be forgotten or overshadowed by other bigger movies
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1035465/comments</url><from/><name>shoshone</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Murphy's character is a model of dedication to his duty who is determined
to
get the job done come what may.  He is fully aware that Sullivan, although
his prisoner, always has the upper hand and is only the prisoner because he
allows it.  A mutual respect and friendship of sorts develops between the
two.  Sullivan's obliging and engaging manner baffles Murphy who learns to
trust him along the way, at one stage even accepting his prisoner's word
that he won't try to escape.  The end is inevitable and we see that
although
justice has to be done, it can leave a bitter aftertaste in ones
mouth.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1116241/comments</url><from>from brighton, ma</from><name>telegonus</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Everyone should see at least one Audie Murphy western in his life. This one
is as good as any. Audie's a lawman charged with bringing  elegant bad guy
Barry Sullivan back to town in order to have him hanged. The problem is
that, for all their difference, these two men become friends; and in time
good friends. Sullivan teaches Audie a thing or two about life, and Audie
gives Sullivan a lesson or two in morality. These guy complement one
another. The dialogue is, for a low-budget western, often quite good.
Everything happens as it should. The ending, while not a shocker, truly
resonates, and makes us think about what we have just seen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Audie Murphy is a rookie Texas Ranger assigned by Ranger Lieutenant Ken
Tobey to accompany John McIntire to track down and apprehend noted
badman Barry Sullivan. McIntire is killed, but Murphy takes him and
they have one interesting journey back.The film is kind of The Comancheros in reverse with a younger Texas
Ranger bringing back an older outlaw. Like Stuart Whiteman with John
Wayne, Sullivan is full of tricks and charm, but Murphy is up to it.The whole film like The Comancheros depends on the chemistry between
Murphy and Sullivan and they do it have it. It makes watching Seven
Ways from Sundown good fun and you don't think about some glaring plot
holes and some rather specious character motivation for the main and
supporting characters. The title comes from the fact Murphy's dad numbered rather than named
his children. And Murphy's mom embellished the numbers with some
additions, One for the money, Two for the show, etc. Hey it could happen. I was in Fort Polk, Louisiana back in 1971 with a
guy named John Twenty Five in basic training. Having seen this film in
the theater way back when it was always on my mind during that rather
grueling period of my life with Mr. Twenty Five.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1483872/comments</url><from>from Michigan</from><name>Utopia1776</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Seven Ways From Sundown Jones (Audie Murphy) must bring in outlaw Jim
Flood,
who tries to win Jones over to his side with charm and a fun loving
personality.  Does Jones put friendship over justice?  Does Flood
underestimate the green lawman?  Watch and see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218006/comments</url><from>from S. Paulo, Brazil</from><name>tmwest</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This is a better than average Audie Murphy western. Murphy is a ranger
whose task is to capture an outlaw (Barry Sullivan). After the capture,
a certain friendship starts developing between Murphy and Sullivan.It
is a dangerous relationship for Murphy. Jim Flood(Sullivan) is a killer
who will stop at nothing to get his way. Murphy's hardest choice will
be not to let this friendship interfere in his deliverance of Flood to
justice. Seven Days From Sundown is the peculiar name of Murphy's
character. He comes from a family where each one of the brothers had a
numerical name. The first was called "One For The Money" and the second
"Two For The Road". Directed by Harry Keller who was very familiar with
westerns both as an editor and director.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
When the movie begins,"Seven" looks like a clueless kid ,cmpletely
immature;and it is all to the credit to Audie Murphy,the most decorated
soldier in WW2,to give this kind of performance.The first meal with the
girl's mother makes him look like the son of the house.His mission is actually an initiation :he is in need of a father /big
brother ;first Sgt Hennessy ,then Jim Flood will play the role :the
scene when they play poker with beans is revealing:and if you do not
think it is,check out the last line .Flood is actually a complex
man:not really a hero,for he committed a crime,but far from being a
villain,who gives his knife to a kid (the key to his character is
perhaps his absence of child .At the end of the movie,when Seven has
grown into a man and is about to marry the girl,he lets himself killed
for his mission of a father is over
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
When the movie begins,"Seven" looks like a clueless kid ,cmpletely
immature;and it is all to the credit to Audie Murphy,the most decorated
soldier in WW2,to give this kind of performance.The first meal with the
girl's mother makes him look like the son of the house.His mission is actually an initiation :he is in need of a father /big
brother ;first Sgt Hennessy ,then Jim Flood will play the role :the
scene when they play poker with beans is revealing:and if you do not
think it is,check out the last line .Flood is actually a complex
man:not really a hero,for he committed a crime,but far from being a
villain,who gives his knife to a kid (the key to his character is
perhaps his absence of child .At the end of the movie,when Seven has
grown into a man and is about to marry the girl,he lets himself killed
for his mission of a father is over
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>