<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Rat</original_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Yugoslavia</country><director>Veljko Bulajic</director><producer>Jadran Film</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis/><actor>Antun Vrdoljak</actor><actor>Zlatko Madunic</actor><actor>Ljubisa Jovanovic</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6550289/comments</url><from>from Boston</from><name>SDQ</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I watched this film without knowing what it was going to be about. It's
thrown together with an American B movie 'This Is Not A Test' in a
collection that I picked up at the local library for killing some time.
The two films both deal with the horrors of the atomic weapon era. The
story has been pointed out by others here so I won't summarize that,
but it was quite an interesting contrast to see the two back to back.
Atomic War Bride is made with many implicit and explicit allusions to
the European intellectual and literary traditions, while addressing the
new issue of atomic weapons of mass destruction, that was going to soon
become one of the earliest strong signs of globalization. I don't mean
to get into 'This Is Not A Test' here, but the point is that those
traces of intellectual thought make a serious difference between these
two films. While the American one is not much more than a basic and
crude take on the questions of authority and irony, this one covers a
wide range of issues about the relationship between the individual and
the society, the relationship between the individual and the state,
questions of violence and love, absurdity, freedom and group
psychology, and more. All in all, I guess, this is a nice little film
that makes you think again and again, without necessarily claiming to
be an intellectual film. It is, after all, an absurd comedy about war
and the question of optimism against the harsh realities of the human
nature. I found it well worth the watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0102677/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>John Seal</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
It's hard to believe this fascinating and bleak Yugoslavian plea for
peace ever got an American release, but apparently it did. Set in an
unnamed country, the film features future director Anton Vrdoljak as
John Johnson, an eternally hopeful young man whose wedding day is
spoiled by the outbreak of war against another unnamed nation. Drafted
into the military, John goes through basic training with his cousin
Jack Jackson, his friend Louis, and a guy called Pete Peters. (The
unimaginative English dubbing also has the temerity to include a
character called Andy Anderson.)He soon finds himself locked in an air
raid shelter, where a giant TV screen broadcasts an address from the
nation's president in which he proudly announces the launching of
nuclear weapons against the enemy. When the citizens of the shelter
decide to march on the government in protest, our hero is arrested for
treason. Shot amidst realistic smoldering wreckage, Atomic War Bride
proudly wears its anti-war politics on its sleeve, not surprising
considering the neutral stance taken by Marshall Tito during the Cold
War. A fascinating and worthwhile curio.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3867949/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>sleuth1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
For anyone who grew up in the 60's and faced the Cuban Missle crisis,
this movie brings back the thoughts and feelings of the time. The world
of two young people in love on their wedding day, are thrown into a
Candide-Like whirlwind of change, challenges and the unknown. Our world
today has forgotten the fear of every school child of that time, who
ducked under a school desk, covering their heads with a schoolbook to
stop the atomic radiation. This dark and honest look into their lives
is a clear reflection of what we will face if we cannot overcome the
same obstacles to peace that they faced in the movie. Funny and
downright silly slapstick comedy in many scenes of the film is artfully
juxtaposed with the harsh realities of the evil forces at work in this
world. Everone must see this film so that they can understand the true
nature of war, and what we can do to try to change the ultimate outcome
of any war caused by the unreasonable pursuit of power for the sake of
power, by those using the justifications provided by the cloak of
government compartmentalization and self justification based on the
supposed wishes of the masses. God bless John Johnson and Maria!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0952932/comments</url><from>from Saint Louis, Missouri</from><name>harshman-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Quite the dismal little film. It concerns a couple, who are blonde hair and
blue eyed like everyone else in this Scandinavian future, who decide to get
hitched just as the unnamed country they live in goes to war with another
no-name country. The man of the couple, John Johnson (Anton Vrdoljak) gets
shoved around and beaten down just about as much as any man can in a film,
and yet still maintains his iron will and sunny disposition. I won't spoil
the end, but it's pretty nihilistic. Watch it ONLY if you're in a good
mood.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0952932/comments</url><from>from Saint Louis, Missouri</from><name>harshman-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Quite the dismal little film. It concerns a couple, who are blonde hair and
blue eyed like everyone else in this Scandinavian future, who decide to get
hitched just as the unnamed country they live in goes to war with another
no-name country. The man of the couple, John Johnson (Anton Vrdoljak) gets
shoved around and beaten down just about as much as any man can in a film,
and yet still maintains his iron will and sunny disposition. I won't spoil
the end, but it's pretty nihilistic. Watch it ONLY if you're in a good
mood.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0952932/comments</url><from>from Saint Louis, Missouri</from><name>harshman-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>