<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Gallant Hours</original_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Robert Montgomery</director><producer>Cagney-Montgomery Production</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
A semi-documentary dramatization of five weeks in the life of Vice Admiral William F. "Bull" Halsey...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>James Cagney</actor><actor>Dennis Weaver</actor><actor>Ward Costello</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Helped in fact by an astonishing physical resemblance to Admiral
William F. Halsey that audiences today can't appreciate, James Cagney
in his next to last film before retirement makes a very believable and
strained Bull Halsey recollecting those harrowing weeks during the
seesaw battle for Guadalcanal. If one is looking for battle scenes and lots of blood and gore skip
this film. If one however would like to see a study about the strain of
command than this film is ideal. Cagney drops all of the mannerisms
that we normally associate with him in playing Admiral Halsey. It's a
restrained and mature performance.The Gallant Hours is also a tribute to the men of our fighting forces
in the Pacific who took and held on to the key island of Guadalcanal in
the Solomons and halted the Japanese in the Southwest Pacific Theater
of Operations. Director Robert Montgomery did the film in documentary style and at
times you feel like you're in the brain of Admiral Halsey, weighing
each decision he makes with him. The familiar voice you hear narrating
is that of Montgomery who was no longer acting and now was mostly
concerned with production and with political work for the Republican
National Committee.The Gallant Hours is a fine character study of one of America's
greatest naval heroes and should not be missed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0493618/comments</url><from>from San Antonio, Texas</from><name>magneta (magneta@idworld.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is a surprisingly engaging war film, considering there are no
action scenes. The movie is well-acted, although Dennis Weaver's
"Chester" accent is a bit over-the-top. Cagney is superb as Admiral
Halsey, in my opinion his best role ever. His understated pain in
ordering only a 'routine' search for his missing son is beautiful, and
the heart-to-heart with Roy Webb over the day's combat losses is a
textbook lesson in the responsibilities of command. The use of the
off-screen narrator in lieu of subtitles to present the Japanese side
of the issue is tremendously effective; one wishes it had been used in
other films as well. Although there are no combat scenes in the movie,
the suspense is palpable as the command staff lives the battle through
the air-to-air and ship-to-ship transmissions of men fighting for their
lives.For the war movie or history buff, or the die-hard Cagney fan, this is
a fine movie!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3188037/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>nelliebell-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

When in the days that pass this life that we live,if you happen to come
upon
this film keep it,view it,and know truly that this is what is meant by the
golden age of Hollywood.This is not about the roaring twenties or the
1940s
or in fact anything that you can touch.It is a film that involves a time
when we in our resolve as a sovereignty were to be attacked by surprise
and
while unable to provide front line support sufficient to deter such
unwarranted aggression we did what we could to figure out how to do what
we
had as yet been unable to do and that is stop the Japanese.Our military
history will recognize that the defense of Guadalcanal will be recognized
as
a perimeter that was held and cleared at great cost.However,the ability of
the Marine Corps to hold were aided by the very gallant efforts of our
Navy
and so many others that though Guadalcanal was the focus of our
efforts,the
reader might do well to look up Defense of the South Pacific.This was in
fact when we started to take back what was a very high cost to
relinquish.Names like battle of savo island,The straights of Iron Bottom
Sound,the Solomons,The Tokyo Express,you will learn just how drama can
unfold on the silver screen without running up a 300 million dollar
tab.This
film is about a ordinary man in Admiral William Halsey who at a very
critical time in our efforts in the South Pacific took command of our
defenses and in a matter of speaking light a fire and proceeded to defend
and ultimately defeat the aggression of a dangerous and superior force in
the Japanese.This film is not to go past when you come to it.I am
personally
pleased that where I was a youngster when I first viewed this very fine
film, fortunately it has been made available through videotape(VHS)and
maybe
those that know better would know that these are the films we truly care
for.This is in defense of the Gallant Hours, it would do well as a fine
package in Digital Versatile Disc.I do not think you can do any better a
movie than The Gallant Hours.I can not recommend a picture any more highly
than I than  this film.A moving tribute to a very ordinary man who said
that
he would get the credit for the work that was started by others.A worthy
movie going experience.It might be well to know that there are subtle ways
by which this movie becomes a picture worth saving and it is emphasized in
the following words,"I knew a lad who went to sea and left the shore
behind
him,the lad was me and now I can not find him.Away,away,away he went and
left the shore behind him."A do not miss.Sincerely
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0472846/comments</url><from>from Indianapolis, IN, USA</from><name>AnthonyM-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This classic film is about Admiral Halsey's leadership of the US forces in
the South Pacific during the early part of World War II. The film is more
about leadership than warfare. Combat is not depicted on screen, so this
film would not appeal to those who seek lots of action. I strongly
recommend
the film, especially to  history buffs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Straightforward black and white World War II battlefield biography
about U.S. Navy Admiral William F. 'Bull' Halsey with zero combat
scenes makes it a rough going 116 minutes despite an outstanding James
Cagney as Halsey. Dennis "Chester" Weaver—minus his limp from
"Gunsmoke"--played his aide. Warning: if you watch this respectable war
film, prepare yourself for a male chorus cooing behind the scenes in
reverence. After the first 10 minutes, that cooing gets pretty thick.
Director Robert Montgomery, who fought in World War II in the European
Theater of Operations, reenacts everything in a semi-documentary style
and adds to the film's overall sense of credibility. Nevertheless, this
Hollywood epic ought to be a regular film on the History Channel
because it doesn't deviate from the facts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10312321/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Lawrence Farrington</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This film is a leadership tutorial masterpiece. As a substitute high
school math and science teacher, I have run this to conduct leadership
laboratories. Additionally, the theme composition that opens the film
is marvelous. I have tried to reconstruct the lyrics (had trouble
understanding last verse lyrics) so that I could present the
composition for adoption by the U. S. Naval Academy Mens' Chorus. Any
help along these lines would be appreciated. I have attempted to locate
survivors of Ward Costello, its composer, without success...for any
necessary permission.The most memorable scene is between Halsey (Cagney) and the candidate
of air group commander (Richard Jaekel), when Jaekel says, "I thought I
was alone." Cagney replies, "You were and you always will be."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2683539/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>johnmcd7</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A war film without action makes this picture almost unique. The message
is that wars are fought with character as much as gun fire. Cagney's
performance is subtle and deeply felt. One scene in particular in the
final half hour should be watched carefully: a 45-second shot of Cagney
sitting at his desk with a cup of coffee as the consequences of his
decision run through his mind in the form of off-screen battle sounds.
The camera patiently draws in on his face, as his expression grown more
grim. Cagney's expression and eyes have a power that burns through the
screen like a magnificent still life summing up the enormous
responsibility of command. Also, the choral music throughout adds a
great weight and sense of secular reverence to the tone of the film. In
a way, "Gallant Hours" is comparable to "Command Decision," in that it
takes us, as one other viewer put it, behind the scenes of battle.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Robert Montgomery directs this brief, but informative study of Adm. William
F. 'Bull' Halsey Jr. in the Pacific during WWII. James Cagney is super as
the highly decorated and revered Fleet Commander. Stoic, stern, confident
and compassionate...Cagney in one of his best film performances.Supporting cast is a mix of veteran actors and younger stars: Walter Sande,
Les Tremayne, Dennis Weaver, Richard Jaeckel, James Yagi, Robert Burton and
Ward Costello.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Arrgghh!! Whether or not this is a good film, I am surprised that most
of the reviewers don't mention the god-awful men's chorus that
inappropriately drones on and one with even greater solemnity than a
Biblical epic!! It's horrible and annoying--and undermines much of the
film. Why this was chosen for the soundtrack I have no idea, as it
grates on the nerves like no other soundtrack I can recall! Yes, it's
that bad and after a while it sounds almost like bees swarming--I kid
you not! Aside from the demoniacally-inspired chorus, the next thing
you'll probably notice is the unusual style of the film. Instead of a
typical bio-pic, this one is told in a semi-documentary style--with
very serious narration punctuating various vignettes of a very small
portion of Admiral Halsey's life. This small cross-section of his life
consists of just five weeks!! So, it's hard to exactly call this a
'bio-pic' as it would seem to imply more than just a tiny portion of
the subject's life.The film is also surprisingly different from what you'd expect because
the telling of the story is very straight-forward and without
adornment. Simple and direct seem to be the motto for this film...and
have a male chorus that sounds worse than cats begin tortured.If you want a film version of all of Halsey's life or a warts-and-all
film, this is not the movie for you. However, it is very competently
made and worth seeing...even with the evil chorus from Hell--though I
AM deducting two points for this!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Samuel Morison, the official U. S. Navy historian for World War II,
disapproved of Admiral William F. Halsey, calling him "a sailor's
admiral," whereas Halsey's superior, Ernest King, was "an admiral's
admiral." This is probably because Morison was a Boston Brahmin and
believed that salty language and flagrant self display should be
avoided. Maybe it endeared you to the enlisted men but it was
undignified. You should also be elegantly modest and not given to
flashy pronouncements like "Attack -- repeat -- attack," and "Kill
Japs. Kill more Japs." The story begins with Halsey's retirement in
1945, having a last cup of coffee, served by his loyal Fillipino
steward, Manuel, whose name Cagney pronounces Manual, as in
"Instructor's Manual." Cagney asks Manuel which campaign he thinks of
most often. Manuel concentrates and finally replies, "Guadalcanal."
WHAM. Into a flashback of Halsey's miseries and triumphs in
Guadalcanal.But if the viewer expects a lot of slam-bang combat and heroic
trumpets, he doesn't get it. Instead we see a quiet black-and-white
account of Cagney's playing the most famous American Admiral of the
war, during the months of battle on the island and on the sea around
it. Not a shot is fired. There is hardly a ship or an airplane in
sight. All the combat is off screen. There are few outdoor shots. The
director, Robert Montgomery, sticks close to Cagney, follows him from
room to room as he is haunted by the decisions he must make, or as he
tries to avoid the five hypodermics waiting for him in the doc's
office. It's a straightforward story that adheres to its subject. There
are no women's roles in the film, and we learn virtually nothing about
Cagney's home life.How does Cagney play it? Pretty well. It's his least mannered
performance. He never shouts or jabs his forefinger at anyone. He wears
glasses and looks dumpy. And he moves slowly, slightly bent, as if
burdened with a responsibility that weighs him down like a stone. With
his eyebrows darkened, he even LOOKS quite a bit like Halsey.The script treats the character with respect, just as it treats the
Japanese officers, of whom we see a little bit. Halsey is shown as
thoughtful, a little skeptical of any good luck, generous with praise,
practically flawless, in fact -- except for that business with the
syringes, which he finally stands up to. The film was released ten
years before "Patton" established a genre, or pseudo-genre, of heroes
who had, as John Wayne once put it, "the Yuman feeta clay." Halsey is
presented as a plain old hero, and the film more or less fills in the
blanks about what KIND of hero he was. By the end, with the exception
of having to make risky decisions that are forced upon him by
circumstance, we are left to conclude that he was the kind of hero that
might just as easily have been a contemplative monk. The movie is a
little slow at times.The traditional iron-hard heroic features are missing. At one point,
Cagney even says that, since two people in a row have suggested "the
admiral might change his mind," that maybe he actually SHOULD change
his mind. But then he has to go and vitiate the point by adding, after
a pause, that "you don't change your mind. You just go in a different
direction." Oh, heck. And here I was, hoping we'd see a leader who was
capable of admitting mistakes, adapting to circumstances, and actually
changing his mind.And, man, did Halsey have reasons for admitting mistakes. What a
different movie it would have been if, at the beginning, Manuel had
replied, not "Guadalcanal," but something like, "I always think about
the typhoons, Admiral," or, "How about the battle of Leyte Gulf?"
However, okay, the world was not ready, and if you must cover only one
campaign out of the many that Halsey was involved in, it might as well
be a victory.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Samuel Morison, the official U. S. Navy historian for World War II,
disapproved of Admiral William F. Halsey, calling him "a sailor's
admiral," whereas Halsey's superior, Ernest King, was "an admiral's
admiral." This is probably because Morison was a Boston Brahmin and
believed that salty language and flagrant self display should be
avoided. Maybe it endeared you to the enlisted men but it was
undignified. You should also be elegantly modest and not given to
flashy pronouncements like "Attack -- repeat -- attack," and "Kill
Japs. Kill more Japs." The story begins with Halsey's retirement in
1945, having a last cup of coffee, served by his loyal Fillipino
steward, Manuel, whose name Cagney pronounces Manual, as in
"Instructor's Manual." Cagney asks Manuel which campaign he thinks of
most often. Manuel concentrates and finally replies, "Guadalcanal."
WHAM. Into a flashback of Halsey's miseries and triumphs in
Guadalcanal.But if the viewer expects a lot of slam-bang combat and heroic
trumpets, he doesn't get it. Instead we see a quiet black-and-white
account of Cagney's playing the most famous American Admiral of the
war, during the months of battle on the island and on the sea around
it. Not a shot is fired. There is hardly a ship or an airplane in
sight. All the combat is off screen. There are few outdoor shots. The
director, Robert Montgomery, sticks close to Cagney, follows him from
room to room as he is haunted by the decisions he must make, or as he
tries to avoid the five hypodermics waiting for him in the doc's
office. It's a straightforward story that adheres to its subject. There
are no women's roles in the film, and we learn virtually nothing about
Cagney's home life.How does Cagney play it? Pretty well. It's his least mannered
performance. He never shouts or jabs his forefinger at anyone. He wears
glasses and looks dumpy. And he moves slowly, slightly bent, as if
burdened with a responsibility that weighs him down like a stone. With
his eyebrows darkened, he even LOOKS quite a bit like Halsey.The script treats the character with respect, just as it treats the
Japanese officers, of whom we see a little bit. Halsey is shown as
thoughtful, a little skeptical of any good luck, generous with praise,
practically flawless, in fact -- except for that business with the
syringes, which he finally stands up to. The film was released ten
years before "Patton" established a genre, or pseudo-genre, of heroes
who had, as John Wayne once put it, "the Yuman feeta clay." Halsey is
presented as a plain old hero, and the film more or less fills in the
blanks about what KIND of hero he was. By the end, with the exception
of having to make risky decisions that are forced upon him by
circumstance, we are left to conclude that he was the kind of hero that
might just as easily have been a contemplative monk. The movie is a
little slow at times.The traditional iron-hard heroic features are missing. At one point,
Cagney even says that, since two people in a row have suggested "the
admiral might change his mind," that maybe he actually SHOULD change
his mind. But then he has to go and vitiate the point by adding, after
a pause, that "you don't change your mind. You just go in a different
direction." Oh, heck. And here I was, hoping we'd see a leader who was
capable of admitting mistakes, adapting to circumstances, and actually
changing his mind.And, man, did Halsey have reasons for admitting mistakes. What a
different movie it would have been if, at the beginning, Manuel had
replied, not "Guadalcanal," but something like, "I always think about
the typhoons, Admiral," or, "How about the battle of Leyte Gulf?"
However, okay, the world was not ready, and if you must cover only one
campaign out of the many that Halsey was involved in, it might as well
be a victory.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>