<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Heller in Pink Tights</original_title><alt_title>La diablesse en collant rose</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>George Cukor</director><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Story of theatrical troupe that travels through the Old West.
</synopsis><actor>Sophia Loren</actor><actor>Anthony Quinn</actor><actor>Margaret O'Brien</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is George Cukor's sole attempt at a western. As is typical of
Cukor, instead of doing a western like Ford or Hawks or Curtiz as a
look at men fighting men against pure nature backgrounds we have Cukor
looking at the coming of culture to the West (here in the acting troop
led by Anthony Quinn and Sophia Loren), and how it is doomed to triumph
over the individualist (here Steve Forrest, a desperado who ends up
accepting his defeat). It is not a great western (Ford and the others
were better at that type), but it a worthy exception to the rule (Ford
did deal with culture twice, using Alan Mowbray in "My Darling
Clementine" and "Wagon Master" as a fading Shakespearean - although he
pulls himself together in the second film). Cukor loves the theater
(his one film noir, "A Double Life" is set in a theater in New York
City). Here some of the most interesting things are the company
rehearsing (in one scene they are putting on Offenbach's "La Belle
Hellene"). But what is most interesting is their guaranteed show
stopper - "Mazeppa".It was a popular play in the middle 19th Century, based on an incident
of the wars between Peter the Great and Charles XIV of Sweden. Mazeppa,
a "hetman" of the Ukranian Cossacks, was captured by his enemies, tied
naked to a wild horse, which was released into the forest. Mazeppa died
as a result. The play was a big success for Adah Mencken, a poet and
actress who was prominent in the 1860s on both sides of the Atlantic,
and was briefly married to John Heenan, the leading heavyweight champ
of America (bare knuckles days). To tittle-late the men in the audience
she wore skin colored clothing, so that it looked like she was naked.
Sophia Loren puts on similar (pink colored) tights - hence the films'
title - and does the scene on a real horse and a moving stage. It
certainly is interesting to see a brief glance at a 19th Century
dramatic highlight, even if it seems rather silly to us today.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12449122/comments</url><from>from New Zealand</from><name>M. J Arocena</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The look alone is worth the trouble. Rich, colorful, slightly baroque.
Sophia Loren is as good as when she's directed by a great actor's
director, this time is not Vittorio De Sica but George Cukor and her
timing, her intention as a character is total perfection. Her sympathy
is not merely believable but contagious and sympathy was Loren's secret
weapon. True, it's not your Ford or Hawks western if anything it's
closer to Sergio Leone with a slightly more refined if not feminine
sensibility. The showdowns here are not of gun powder but of love
power. The Art Direction is superb and the film shouldn't be dismiss
because it doesn't fulfill the rules of the genre. This is a Cukor film
and that in itself makes it a cut above most movies. Anthony Quinn is
also traveling unknown territory very successfully. Eileen Heckart is,
as usual, a scene stealer: "She's only sixteen!, only sixteen, do you
hear?" she shouts trying to protect her most valuable asset, her
daughter, played by Margaret O'Brien wanting to be accepted as a 20
year old. An extra plus for film lovers is a glimpse of Ramon Novarro
one of the biggest stars of the silent era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218006/comments</url><from>from S. Paulo, Brazil</from><name>tmwest</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is a western made by George Cukor, who would not dream about
making a western unless it would really be about something else. This
one is about show business and I can understand how anybody working in
entertainment would identify strongly with it. Anthony Quinn leads a
theatrical troupe formed by Sophia Loren, Margaret O'Brien, Eileen
Heckart and the legendary Ramon Novarro through the west. They are
pursued by creditors and are really living on the edge. Loren, using
her charms, is a big help, but this is hard for Quinn who is in love
with her to accept. They come to a town and are going to perform
Offenbach's 'La Belle Helene', but the owner of the theater thinks the
townspeople will never accept a young woman leaving her old husband for
the young Paris. Instead they do the opera 'Mazeppa'. Loren gets
involved unwillingly with a gunfighter, Steve Forrest, who seems so
tough compared to Anthony Quinn, but as the film goes along we start
learning how much courage the whole troupe must have to remain in show
business. An unusual film, with a lot of meaning.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
For the only western in the film credits of George Cukor he sure
couldn't be faulted for the source of his material. This film is taken
from one of the books by the great western novelist Louis L'Amour. It
concerns the escapades of a traveling theatrical troupe in the west
headed by Anthony Quinn with the leading lady being Sophia Loren. This
was her only trip to the American west on film also.Theatrical people did not exactly have the same kind of prestige back
in those days as they do now. We first meet our players fleeing across
the state/territorial boundaries of Nebraska and Wyoming evading a
sheriff with a writ. They arrive in Cheyenne and get themselves
involved with the villainous doings of Ramon Novarro and his hired
gunman Steve Forrest. After Forrest does a couple of jobs for him, Novarro tries a
doublecross maneuver similar to the one Laird Cregar tried on Alan Ladd
in This Gun For Hire with the same sorry results. Forrest of necessity
joins the theatrical troupe and both get an opportunity to use their
respective skills to help each other out of some tight spots.This film had potential to be better. Maybe in the hands of someone
like George Marshall or John Ford it might even have become a classic.
George Cukor was not the director for it. The film marked the last feature film appearance of both Ramon Novarro
and Edmund Lowe. Novarro did do some television work until his tragic
murder in 1968. Here he's a smooth and polished villain. Edmund Lowe
does quite well as an old ham actor which at that point in his life was
I'm sure one easy role for him.Heller in Pink Tights is enjoyable enough, but no classic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0864661/comments</url><from>from Marin County, California</from><name>kirksworks</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Director George Cukor's only western, this is about a traveling stage
show that keeps getting into trouble because of the escapades of their
leading star, Angela Rossini, deliciously played by Sophia Loren, quite
fetching as a blonde. She is top billed along with Anthony Quinn. It
also stars an adolescent Margaret O'Brien (a child in "Meet Me in St.
Louis"), whose mother does not want her to grow up.  I thought O'Brien
was as charming in this as she was in "St. Louis."  I had never seen "Heller" in its complete form, never in any quality
print, and this DVD looks great.  I'd only seen edited for TV versions,
and that made it hard to follow.  Seeing this DVD release surprised me.
 The film is top notch Cukor, ranking as one of the most entertaining
westerns of the 1960s. The director also got a full- blooded and
emotional performance from Loren, perhaps one of her most natural, and
the director even held the reins on Quinn, who could overdo his roles
on occasion. Actor Steve Forrest also has a well-integrated part, and his character
appears at just the right moments to thrust the story forward or change
its direction.  Ramon Novarro (Judah in the silent "Ben-Hur," opposite
Garbo in "Mata Hari") appears on screen for the last time, effectively
playing a conniving banker.  If you go into this film with an open
mind, I think you'll find that it is funny, exciting, romantic and
often surprising. I never knew where it was going, and that made it
refreshing. You'll probably also enjoy the wonderfully visualized
period atmosphere in stunning Technicolor. There's also a fine score by
Daniele Amphitheatrof, a far too unappreciated composer.Give this film a try. You'll probably have a good time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0258737/comments</url><from>from Canberra, Australia</from><name>David Atfield (bits@alphalink.com.au)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

This film is really very badly directed - which is amazing given Cukor's
excellent filmography.  He rarely focuses the attention of the viewer where
it should be - and seems obsessed with close-ups on Sophia's eyes.  I wonder
if Carlo Ponti interfered a lot here - as Sophia is rarely out of shot, to
the detriment of the other characters and the film.  This is one of Sophia's
worst performances - she seems to be struggling with her lines - although
she looks good blonde.  The excellent supporting cast is wasted - even
Anthony Quinn is allowed little screen time.  Eileen Heckhart is allowed
even less time, but it's interesting to see child actress Margaret O'Brien
in a rare adult role.  Her little girl voice is jarring however.  The only
reason to see this film is to witness the final performance of the legendary
Ramon Novarro.  He is splendid and stylish as the villain - a great lesson
in screen acting, although again we don't see enough of him.  Is there a
story about the making of this film?  I wonder if Cukor had to battle the
Ponti-Loren partnership and was forced to give too much screen time to
Sophia.  What a mistake!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This film is introduced with the words: "When the great American
frontier was resounding with the names of such gunman and outlaws as
Wyatt Earp, Jesse James, Bat Masterson and Doc Holliday - a beautiful
and flirtatious actress swept through the west with her theatrical
troupe. A 'hellion in pink tights,' she was the toast of every
settlement from Cheyenne to Virginia City - and became a legend of the
old west. This is her story." And, after a creative title sequence, we
meet beautiful actress Sophia Loren (as Angela "Angie" Rossini) in a
blonde wig, running lines with co-star Anthony Quinn (Thomas "Tom"
Healy)...As the theatrical troupe arrives to perform in Cheyenne, Ms. Loren and
ruggedly handsome Steve Forrest (as Clint Mabry) exchange mutually sexy
glances. However, Loren decides to remain faithful (at least
temporarily) to Mr. Quinn. Their relationship is threatened when Loren
loses herself to Mr. Forrest in a poker game. When Loren, Quinn and
company are suddenly run out of town, Forrest joins them, protecting
his "property." They are threatened by bloodthirsty Native American
Indians and respectable gangster Ramon Novarro (as De Leon). Forrest
helps with the Indians, but has trouble with Mr. Novarro...Loren and Quinn are okay, but surprisingly lack chemistry as a couple.
Despite his lower billing, Forrest comes across as more like the
story's leading man. The supporting cast is very strong: Novarro, a
former "silent screen" idol, is exceptional as the main villain; former
child star Margaret O'Brien and Eileen Heckart are a delightfully
naughty mother/daughter duo; and Edmund Lowe (as Manfred "Doc"
Montague) is a bonus, in his last acting appearance. Director George
Cukor and his team make it very stylized, with an emphasis on garish
color. The film's jarring attitude was later common on television.******* Heller in Pink Tights (1/1/60) George Cukor ~ Sophia Loren,
Steve Forrest, Anthony Quinn, Ramon Novarro
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5677059/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>aj989</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The film is the story of an acting troupe (Anthony Quinn, Sophia Loren,
Eileen Heckart, Margaret O'Brien) who run into various monetary and
Indian problems as they travel across the Western United States.George Cukor, who directed this film, supposedly never liked how the
usual western looked. They lacked color, according to him, and in
"Heller in Pink Tights," Cukor set out to remedy that. The film is full
of vivacious color. From Eileen Heckart's orange hair to Sophia Loren's
platinum blonde wig and the various pieces of clothing that they wear.
Visually the film is quite arresting. It mixes such loud, bright colors
with the colors of such a rigid and tough landscape.While the use of color is certainly interesting, the film never gets
quite as far. The story is entertaining, but in a silly way. The
chemistry between Loren and her two love interests (Quinn and Steve
Forrest) is non-existent. She also looks totally uncomfortable with the
blonde wig she is saddled with. Eileen Heckart is fun as the loudmouth
actress/stage mother to O'Brien's character, and Anthony Quinn is his
usual "dramatic" self."Heller in Pink Tights" certainly is a different kind of Western. I
just only wish the film's story would have been as interesting as its
use of color.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
In Old West Wyoming, a traveling troupe of dramatic actors is on the
run from bill collectors; a cocky gunslinger comes to their rescue once
the caravan hits hostile Indian territory--sticking around to settle a
bet with the beautiful leading actress, whom he's smitten with. George
Cukor western, adapted from the novel "Heller With a Gun" by Louis
L'Amour, has a shaky beginning, a not-bad first act, but absolutely
nothing to offer after the first 50 or so minutes. Sophia Loren, in
peculiar blonde and red wigs, has a charming early scene getting
herself into a poker game (bluffing with 4 sevens), and there's also a
stunning, beautifully accomplished sequence wherein the dramatists give
an action-filled performance in a packed theater (complete with Loren
riding through the crowd on a horse). Still, Anthony Quinn's
relationship with Loren never catches fire, and Sophia and Steve
Forrest create little chemistry. This may be due to Cukor's direction,
which has no magic (and he's particularly insulting to the Indian
tribe, who hoop and holler over the left-behind costumes like a bunch
of drunken rowdies at a frat-house). A disappointment overall, though
small sections of the picture give hint it may have been a fascinating
effort under different circumstances. *1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
What an average, ordinary movie. And by average and ordinary, I mean
dull. The plot revolves around a traveling show in the old West. The
group runs afoul of Indians, sheriffs, and killers as they seek to make
their fortunes. Sophia Loren is the star and is in almost every scene,
but not even she can save Heller in Pink Tights from achieving nothing
more than mediocrity. Anthony Quinn is also top billed, but he is
terribly underutilized and looks like he's just going through the
motions. The chemistry between the pair is non-existent. The only
bright spot in the cast is Eileen Heckart who, as usual, steals every
scene in which she appears. Director George Cukor shot Heller in Pink
Tights in the most gaudy of color schemes that hardly seems natural
give the time period in which the movie takes place. An exploding paint
store wouldn't produce this much color. I'm not sure what Cukor was
going for, but he failed at almost every turn.In short, this one should be reserved for Cukor or Loren completists
only.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
What an average, ordinary movie. And by average and ordinary, I mean
dull. The plot revolves around a traveling show in the old West. The
group runs afoul of Indians, sheriffs, and killers as they seek to make
their fortunes. Sophia Loren is the star and is in almost every scene,
but not even she can save Heller in Pink Tights from achieving nothing
more than mediocrity. Anthony Quinn is also top billed, but he is
terribly underutilized and looks like he's just going through the
motions. The chemistry between the pair is non-existent. The only
bright spot in the cast is Eileen Heckart who, as usual, steals every
scene in which she appears. Director George Cukor shot Heller in Pink
Tights in the most gaudy of color schemes that hardly seems natural
give the time period in which the movie takes place. An exploding paint
store wouldn't produce this much color. I'm not sure what Cukor was
going for, but he failed at almost every turn.In short, this one should be reserved for Cukor or Loren completists
only.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/h/HellerPinkTights.html /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1842864</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Cukor never loses sight of the theatricality which infuses both the fanciful incarnations of the saltimbanques and the genre conventions of the Western</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/cukor.htm#Pink /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1748236</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Strange mix of show-biz saga and Western, inventively styled.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/hellerinpinktights.htm /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1554061</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>It's one of the rare Westerns that explores the barnstorming troupes in the Old West of the 19th-century.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/heller-in-pink-tights-1/ /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1524345</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>More a comedy about showbiz that Western per se, Cukor's foray into the horseopera genre, based on Louis L'Amour novella, stars Sophia Loren as the leading lady of a troupe touring the frontier.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117791583.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1806857</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/71905/heller_in_pink_tights.html /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1482242</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9902E2DE143DE333A25754C1A9659C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/heller_in_pink_tights/comments.php?reviewid=1389932</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>