<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Sinister Urge</original_title><imdb_rating>2.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Edward D. Wood Jr.</director><producer>Headliner Productions</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
A flunky for a porno movie ring starts murdering the smut films' lead actresses.
</synopsis><actor>Kenne Duncan</actor><actor>Duke Moore</actor><actor>Jean Fontaine</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0797612/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>madsagittarian</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

What a night.  The stuff of which legends are made.In 1995 in beautiful downtown Toronto, when Tim Burton's mighty biopic ED
WOOD went into second-run, one of our rep cinemas had a
never-to-be-forgotten quadruple bill of films by everyone's favourite
cross-dressing auteur.  JAIL BAIT, BRIDE OF THE MONSTER, NIGHT OF THE GHOULS
preceded this, the final programme of the evening, and perhaps Ed Wood's
final masterpiece (well, for his "legit" non-porn movies anyway).  From the
expected pimply nerdy geeks to one dignified old gentleman who said that
they SHOULD have given Mr. Wood a star in front of Grauman's, this, the
least seen of all of Wood's pictures from his "classical" period, was a real
crowd pleaser.THE SINISTER URGE is a must for anyone with even a passing interest in the
films of this precious Gonzo genius, or, like myself, who have a strange
attraction to works made by people who eke out an existence way way way in
the back alleys of Tinseltown.  This riotous "expose" is classic Edward D.:
long scenes which don't go anywhere (including an extract from his
uncompleted JD epic- HELLBORN), priceless dialogue which waxes profundity
about everything and nothing, and a strange attempt at morality while also
delivering whatever exploitation elements that unsuspecting people paid to
see.  My favourite bits include: 1) the long scene where the two hardworking cops out to bust the porn ring
must explain to an anonymous taxpayer who comes to the station, and tell him
exactly why they are spending his hard-earned tax dollars on such a
seemingly trivial matter; this scene wouldn't even pass the green light in a
pre-production meeting for an educational film, however with typically
Woodian panache, the taxpayer leaves afterwards shaking his head in
amazement over the great public service these man are performing.  Once
again, within his ridiculous subplots, Wood slyly inserts bits where you
realize how subversive his scenarios really are. The ever-critical
writer-director is simultaneously praising and damning these intrepid cops
for a seemingly superfluous service-- remember, only two years later the US
government spent a huge wad of the taxpayers' money to decipher the lyrics
to "Louie Louie" because the song was considered to be corrupting the minds
of impressionable youngsters.2) the director's cameo appearance; since one of the main subplots concerns
some knife-wielding loony who attacks women in the park (apparently looking
at semi-clad girls in magazines drove him to his social deviance), the two
cops talk about sending an undercover male officer in drag to the park and
foil the psychotic pervert (right here, the audience knowingly began to
applaud), and in the next scene, there is Mr. Wood in a dress and mop wig
trying to ferret out the guy in the park.  A cameo appearance to save some
money instead of hiring another bit player?  In most likelihood, a good
excuse for the eccentric auteur to insert his personal baggage-- a Brechtian
cry for identity.3)  a bizarre climax, featuring a decapitated head in someone's
bushes!Man, they sure don't make them like this anymore.  Seeing THE SINISTER URGE
is like a breath of fresh air.  As much as PLAN 9, GLEN OR GLENDA and BRIDE
OF THE MONSTER are important works of this pioneering independent filmmaker,
the stories about their creation, and their dialogue is cited so often that
perhaps they no longer seem new.  It is great to see this, and also JAIL
BAIT, and appreciate the charms that even his under-hyped works
have.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0861465/comments</url><from>from Queens, NY</from><name>InzyWimzy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I really think smut gets a bad rep.  This Ed Wood schlocker attempts to
correlate the smut racket and the ills of society's problems.  Well, at
least back in 1961.  Of course, this isn't shown so well and Ed delivers his
usual bland scenes of dialogue where the characters are trying to further
progress the story.  Or were they trading borscht pie recipes?  Well this
all adds up to a movie that seems like a 10 hour skin grafting
session.Is it bad?  Of course, no question.  Or was it made out to be that way? 
After seeing Ed Wood's works, it looks like his actors are giving serious,
genuine performances, but there's a sense that they're having fun with it
(that is until Ed explained how he was going to pay them).  Characters
galore range from crazed psychotic who really intimate with a switchblade to
9 fingered wonder Harvey B Dunn who adds new meaning to `giving the bird'.  
Some scenes are so kampy, it's funny.  An interview with naïve actress
really had me laughing  when the interviewer slyly explains what type of
film they'll be shooting.  Also, a group of teeners (aka more of Ed's
extras) witness a fight break out for no reason!!  To try and explain the
hilarity of this scene would not do it justice.   Count how many desk scenes
there are till your wall paint starts peeling!  And that Kline, can he steal
a scene or what?Ah, but let's not forget Jean Fontaine as Gloria.  Her grating voice really
adds a menacing presence (I will never look at a leotard the same way ever
again).  Maybe smut wasn't the problem and Gloria was the root of the
problem?  Well, that or her seal tight ensemble displayed throughout the
movie! Listening to Gloria's logic and way of reasoning makes me realize
that caning may not be such a bad thing after all.  And her great line
"Dirk? No, that can't be Dirk. Uh-uh. No, that's not Dirk. No" is well worth
the price of admission. There's so much more like shooting on the smut set of scantily clad (?)
actresses, abrupt jump cuts, a police raid (HA HA HA), the Syndicate….oh
man, some directors wish they could create movies with the flair Ed Wood
had.  I'm starting to see method in Ed's madness.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2721657/comments</url><from>from brooklyn NY</from><name>sol1218</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
One of Ed Wood Jr. lesser known works about the smut racket where Wood
himself has a cameo role in it. Not as the cop in drag with a tight
womens wool sweater, which would have been more like it for Wood, but
as a smut peddler having it out with his rival at a pizza joint that
fronts for a porno distribution site. With a number of young women found dead in and around a local park
their deaths are connected to a local smut ring headed by Gloria
Henderson. Things get real bad for Gloria when the cops take into
custody her top smut photographer Jaffe together with all the canisters
of porno films, that he hid in his closet. Leaving her racket on the
verge of being shut down not just by the cops but by the syndicate who
are bankrolling her smut operation.The weak link in Gloria's smut business is one of her enforcers Dirk
Williams who becomes so hopped up and morally corrupted by having a
hand in her smut racket. Dirk he goes bananas when he sees porno films
and pictures that he's peddling supplied by Gloria's right-hand man in
her business the former legit Hollywood film maker Johnny Ryde. Dirk's
uncountable urge for sex and violence is touched off just by the sight
of smut photos and that drives him to commit rape and murder. The local
cops know all about Gloria's operation but need solid proof and
evidence to put her,together with Johnny Ryde, out of business. In the
end it's Gloria herself who provides all the rope that they need to
hang her without Gloria even knowing it. Director Ed Wood does the best he can to show the evils of pornography
and how it effects naive and innocent young girls who come to Hollywood
looking to make it big in the motion picture industry. Only ending up
getting talked into making porno films by the likes of Gloria and
Johnny Ryde to just pay off their bills. We see the tragic story of
Mary Smith who ended up making smut films and photos for Gloria and
finally fell victim to Dirks sinister urge. When he caught Mary alone
in the park, by the duck pond, and ended up raping and murdering her.
We also see in the movie "The Sinister Urge" how difficult it is to
arrest the likes of Gloria Henderson and make the charges of the crimes
she committed stick.Admittedly a laughable venture, which of his movies aren't, of Wood's
because of the cheap budget and in some cases non-actors in it. The
movie "The Sinister Urge"is still years ahead of it's time thanks to
the foresight and vision of it's director Ed Wood Jr, in showing the
evils and horrors of the then, in 1961, underground and illegal smut
business in and out of Hollywood. That destroyed the lives of thousands
of young girls like Mary Smith in mind as well as body.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4955511/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ragreen259</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Don't fall into the evil world of pornography!This movie is classic Wood. For some reason, I have a hard time seeing
it as being made in 1961, however.It's great going through, looking for how many errors due to budget
constraints there are, continuity errors, all the usual. Add to this
the stiff acting and memorized lines, and you're all set. I enjoyed
this movie, and see new stupid errors in it every time I watch it, it
can supply you with hours of entertainment. Don't expect Ben Hur, but if you enjoy Ed Wood, or haven't seen
anything else by him but want a classic example of his work, this is
one you'll want to see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1690893/comments</url><from>from Spokane, WA</from><name>counterrevolutionary</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

Some people believe that Ed Wood knew exactly what he was doing: that he
*intended* to make "bad" movies in order to make people laugh. There are
plenty of good reasons not to buy into that theory, and THE SINISTER URGE is
Exhibit A.PLAN 9 FROM OUTER SPACE, GLEN OR GLENDA, and BRIDE OF THE MONSTER are
endearing in their goofy lunacy. This one, though just as bad as the rest of
Wood's oeuvre, is mostly just plodding and dull.Not that there isn't entertainment to be had here, at least for the bad
movie connoisseur: my personal favorite is the obvious use of pre-existing
(and completely unrelated) footage, shoehorned in on the waste-not want-not
principle and "justified" through the use of atrocious dubbing and risible
expository dialogue (which takes place *after* the inserted scene, making it
even more ludicrous). But that's not the sort of thing calculated to make a mainstream audience
roar with laughter.I can imagine someone trying to make a movie like PLAN 9. I can't imagine
anyone trying to make a movie like this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0207491/comments</url><from>from haddonfield, nj</from><name>jay kauffman</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

absolutely hysterical film about the porn industry. brassy blonde (jean
fontaine has to be seen to believed) runs a porn industry that frankly isn't
very exciting. the combination of bad writing and bad acting exerts a strange
fascination. never dull.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Edward D. Wood Jr (or E.D. Wood credited for the film) is practically
revered today as a filmmaker forgotten and neglected in his time as
just another Shlock-Meister of B-movie (or Z-movie) cinema. His legacy
is now, well, being the ultimate in bad schlock kind of movie-making,
where you can almost see the sets about the tear at the seams, the
actors going through their lines like they know they won't get any pay
for it, and camera-work (and perhaps editing too) that becomes jarring
in the worst possible ways. While the Sinister Urge, Wood's last 'real'
film before diving deep into obscure porn directing (ironic considering
the film's subject here), does not have a kind of classically bad way
about it like Plan 9 From Outer Space. That film has since become a
kind of cult classic where the actor in place of the late Bela Lugosi
in the film, the various props and sets (including the 'saucers'), and
horrendous narration becomes most of the ironic fun. The Sinister Urge
in comparison doesn't have that impressive ambition to be something
more than it can never be, as this film is nothing more than an
under-cooked 'warning' film about porn movies, and the people who may
kill to be apart of them.The Sinister Urge is 71 minutes long, which doesn't overstay its
welcome (though one may try and define 'welcome' with an Ed Wood
picture) as a film with many static camera angles and very few moments
of ingenuity. One of those- the scene where the brakes don't work with
the car- is ironically successful, as it really shouldn't be at all
workable as a scene, but as a little piece of suspense it could be
worse. Most of the rest of the picture isn't so lucky- again, many,
many actors who seem like they are not only content to not become
stars, they're almost doomed to be in pictures like Wood's. Often the
performances are wooden, but of course part of the real problem with
watching such actors is the often silly dialog. It tries to be
'realistic', but Wood has no gripe with stopping somewhere to have a
character (usually the lead cop character) to lay out a dull speech
about the message of the story. On top of the story not really being
too coherent, anyway, the director's method of the 'cut, print,
perfect' method can be seen quite often with some laughable mistakes
abound.Now, does all of this make the Sinister Urge as astoundingly, amusingly
bad as Plan 9? Not really; there's nothing too memorable about how the
film is bad here, unless you're a die-hard fan of the director. He does
try here and there to keep some storytelling merit, with his style
being so uncomplicated and static it shows his ambition. But the lack
of talent overcomes everything else, not to mention the cardboard-sided
points of the film. It's also not too unworthy of the Mystery Science
Theater 3000 treatment either, which has now made the film available on
DVD. The commentary is spot-on usually and funny, though as with Plan 9
you may still want to make wisecracks on your own. That's Wood as the
mustached guy who fights at the Cafeteria in one scene.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Even by Ed Wood's standards, The Sinister Urge is a miserable movie.
Everything you would expect to find in an Ed Wood film is here – a
ridiculous plot, bad acting, stilted dialogue, poor editing, and bad
set design. Most of the "action" takes place behind a desk on an all
but barren set as two policemen drone on an on about nothing. There's
one scene that must be seen to be believed involving a "taxpayer" who
shows up to demand to know what the police are doing. They give Mr.
Taxpayer a good lecture about the dangers of pornography and how it
leads to all sorts of other crimes including murder, kidnapping,
jay-walking, terrorism, and ripping tags off mattresses. It's a hoot!But as I've said before when discussing Ed Wood's movies, even with all
the problems, there's a love for the art form that you can see just
under the surface. Ed Wood wasn't the most gifted filmmaker and he
often worked in less than stellar conditions, but there's no denying
his love of movies. He just didn't have the wherewithal to make a
"good" one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2081575/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>warterra</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
After years of hearing how awful Ed Wood films are this example of his
work really didn't seem so bad.I expected epic continuity errors, little to no plot and extremely low
budget filming. However the worst thing about this film turned out to
be just how dull it was. Unless you're watching the MST3K version
you'll find this movie very boring.The continuity errors are there, but you can overlook them if you
choose to. The story moves, albeit slowly, plot elements are there, and
the story wraps up, but in a rather unbelievable way. It may be low
budget, but the wooden acting hurts this movie far more than the
budget. The sets, car crash, and fight scenes seem about on par with
60's TV.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"The Sinister Urge" is proof if any was ever needed that Ed Wood was a
completely and utterly inept writer and director. He does, of course,
have a surprising number of fans who actually like some of his work
("Bride of the Monster", I have to admit, isn't really all that bad of
a film), but "The Sinister Urge" is so chock-full of Ed Wood clichés
(redundant dialogue, amazingly bad acting, and taking hypocritical
preaching to a whole new level are but few of the features of this
film).I've seen "The Sinister Urge" several times in its "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" version, which features some of the funniest and most
seemingly random riffs in the history of that show- one scene features
Mike and the bots breaking into song... but I won't spoil that for you.
Tonight I watched this film without their aid and it is a prime example
of complete cinematic incompetence. From start to finish the script is
unbelievably bad, not even in an earnest "Plan 9" sort of way- there's
only the occasional laugh here, unless you can find humor in something
so pathetically horrid. Similarly, Wood is incapable of even a second
of flair in his direction of the film.There are people in this world who will tell you with a straight face
that this is a fine film, an indictment of the seedy world of
pornography (oh let's face it, compared to what we have going now, the
porn industry in 1960 was one big huge convent). These people are
absolutely, unequivocally NUTS. One only has too look at Wood's
filmography to see that he had already written several smut films,
including notorious early nudie Western "Revenge of the Virgins", prior
to this film's release."The Sinister Urge" is one of the most boring, plodding, miserable
excuses for a film in all of cinema. I'm not a big fan of picking on Ed
Wood, to be honest, but this is proof (along with the many other films
of his that aren't widely known) that Wood is an astoundingly
incompetent director.1/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"The Sinister Urge" is proof if any was ever needed that Ed Wood was a
completely and utterly inept writer and director. He does, of course,
have a surprising number of fans who actually like some of his work
("Bride of the Monster", I have to admit, isn't really all that bad of
a film), but "The Sinister Urge" is so chock-full of Ed Wood clichés
(redundant dialogue, amazingly bad acting, and taking hypocritical
preaching to a whole new level are but few of the features of this
film).I've seen "The Sinister Urge" several times in its "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" version, which features some of the funniest and most
seemingly random riffs in the history of that show- one scene features
Mike and the bots breaking into song... but I won't spoil that for you.
Tonight I watched this film without their aid and it is a prime example
of complete cinematic incompetence. From start to finish the script is
unbelievably bad, not even in an earnest "Plan 9" sort of way- there's
only the occasional laugh here, unless you can find humor in something
so pathetically horrid. Similarly, Wood is incapable of even a second
of flair in his direction of the film.There are people in this world who will tell you with a straight face
that this is a fine film, an indictment of the seedy world of
pornography (oh let's face it, compared to what we have going now, the
porn industry in 1960 was one big huge convent). These people are
absolutely, unequivocally NUTS. One only has too look at Wood's
filmography to see that he had already written several smut films,
including notorious early nudie Western "Revenge of the Virgins", prior
to this film's release."The Sinister Urge" is one of the most boring, plodding, miserable
excuses for a film in all of cinema. I'm not a big fan of picking on Ed
Wood, to be honest, but this is proof (along with the many other films
of his that aren't widely known) that Wood is an astoundingly
incompetent director.1/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>