<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Flesh and the Fiends</original_title><alt_title>L'impasse aux violences</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>John Gilling</director><producer>Triad Productions</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
Edinburgh surgeon Dr. Robert Knox requires cadavers for his research into the functioning of the human...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Peter Cushing</actor><actor>June Laverick</actor><actor>Donald Pleasence</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
With this seemly arrogant but honest message showing on the screen, the
film opens at a dark Edinburgh cemetery where two vicious figures lift
a cadaver from its grave... "The Flesh and the Fiends" tells the true
story of William Burke and William Hare, corpse-suppliers to the
ambitious surgeon and university professor Dr. Robert Knox. From what
I've read in factual biographies and works of reference (yes, I find
this stuff so intriguing that I study it on the side), the screenplay
is rather accurate and faithful when it comes to the basic re-telling
of the murder cases. Burke and Hare's modus operandi as well as their
negotiations with Dr. Knox really were this clumsy and unscrupulous
while Knox damn well knew about the suspicious methods of the two, but
he couldn't care less as long the study-objects he received were fresh
and supplied regularly. I reckon that writer/director John Gilling then
added some fictional elements to his film, like the characterizations
of the main roles, since Hare's persona is almost blackly comical and
Dr. Knox' attitude is stubborn and typically obnoxious like nearly
every scientist in horror cinema. Still, the escalation of the tragedy
is truthfully illustrated with Burke and Hare getting into the
body-snatching business coincidentally at first, but quickly
specializing in it because of the good cash money and eventually even
converting to murder in order to deliver the most 'quality'."The Flesh and the Fiends" isn't just a great historical film, it also
is a praiseworthy horror achievement with a uniquely grim atmosphere
and very convincing acting performances. John Gilling terrifically
revives a 19th century Edinburgh with its low-perspective inhabitants
(drunks, beggars and thieves...) and ominous bars and alleys. The
murders are very mean and cold-heartedly illustrated (the death of a
young unintelligent boy, strangled amid squealing pigs is particularly
unsettling) which probably makes this film the most disturbing of the
entire 50's decade. Peter Cushing is excellent in the – for him –
familiar role of brilliant doctor but it especially are Donald
Pleasance (hypocrite and self-centered) and George Rose (a
simple-minded killer) who impress as Hare and Burke. The supportive
roles are somewhat stiff and they bring forward redundant sub plots,
like the romantic interactions between Knox' daughter Martha and her
doctor-lover Geoffrey. The typically Scottish accents are a joy to
listen to and the eerie black and white photography emphases the
already very chilling tone. This movie is still incomprehensibly
underrated and unknown. Maybe because it's not a Hammer production or
maybe because the substance was considered controversial for a long
period of time. Fact remains that this old shocker is far better than
most contemporary horror gems and everybody who has an interest in the
obscure should urgently check it out!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1609501/comments</url><from>from Wakefield, England</from><name>Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The late '50s was one of the most important periods in the evolution of
horror cinema - especially the British horror film, which was
undergoing a radical new wave of gory Technicolour entries such as
Dracula, The Curse of Frankenstein and The Mummy. Two men who were
thrust into super-stardom thanks to these movies were Peter Cushing and
Christopher Lee, perhaps the finest horror actors ever to grace the
genre. The Flesh And The Fiends (a.k.a Mania) is a 1959 chiller, shot
in black and white, with Cushing in the main role. The black and white
photography harks back to the style of the older horror films from the
'30s and '40s, but the story is quite disturbing and includes some
pretty grisly scenes more in line with the contemporary hunger for
explicit blood and guts. And, while Christopher Lee might for once be
missing as Cushing's co-star, Donald Pleasance proves himself to be a
wonderfully adept replacement.In 19th Century Edinburgh, a respected lecturer in anatomy, Dr. Knox
(Peter Cushing), goes about his work and outwardly seems to be the
perfect gentleman. However, he keeps a dark and disgusting secret from
his niece Martha (June Laverick) and her lover Dr. Mitchell (Dermot
Walsh). Knox secretly buys corpses from a pair of unscrupulous local
grave-robbers named Burke (George Rose) and Hare (Donald Pleasance).
With these dead bodies, Knox carries out secret anatomical studies.
Burke and Hare, realising that they're onto a lucrative line of
business, begin to murder victims rather than simply digging up the
bodies of the already-dead so that they can keep the doctor stocked
with corpses. This spate of murders doesn't seem to concern Knox too
much, even though he suspects that Burke and Hare are the culprits....
so engrossed is he in his experiments that he is happy to turn a blind
eye. Eventually Burke and Hare are captured for their crimes, the
latter testifying against his accomplice to save his skin (though he is
later pursued and blinded by a hateful mob), while - most disturbing of
all - the cruel and calculating Dr. Knox is ultimately pardoned for his
own part in the affair.The Flesh And The Fiends is a very impressive horror film, in which
Knox is shown to be the real monster by the way he uses his wealth and
intellect to exploit the impoverished Burke and Hare. While Burke and
Hare's motive is merely to make money, Knox manipulatively allows them
to shoulder all the risk by carrying out the grave-robbing and murders
that will get him his corpses. The scenes of squalor and filth are very
powerfully captured, and the scenes showing dead bodies being dragged
from their earthy graves are extremely provocative for the time.
Cushing is outstanding as usual, and Rose and Pleasance make a
genuinely creepy pair of resurrectionists. Though it might not be the
gore-fest that modern audiences seem to demand, The Flesh And The
Fiends is a gruesome treat for those who remember what old-style horror
flicks were all about.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I'll leave it up to others to debate whether 'Mania' (a.k.a. 'The Flesh and
the Fiends') is technically a horror movie. While dealing with horrific
events, and told in a fashion with plenty of creepy moments, I would still
say it isn't horror myself. Whatever you classify it as it is a seriously
underrated thriller with strong performances from an above average cast.
Director John Gilling went on to make the Hammer classic 'The Plague Of
Zombies' later in the 1960s, and stars Peter Cushing ('Twins Of Evil') and
Donald Pleasence ('Halloween') both made a strong impact on the horror
genre, so fans will be interested to see this for those reasons alone.
Cushing is excellent as the stubborn and driven Dr. Knox who needs a steady
supply of corpses to dissect, and Pleasence plays the slimy William Hare,
who along with his equally creepy colleague William Burke (George Rose),
gleefully fills that need. The only problem is that Burke and Hare have no
qualms about where the corpses come from, or whether they need a little
"help" along the way. Burke and Hare were real body snatchers, but I have no
idea just how historically accurate the events depicted in this movie are.
But it certainly is entertaining and worth watching for the terrific
performances by Cushing, Pleasence and Rose, and also for Billie Whitelaw
('The Omen') who has a small but important supporting role as the love
interest for one of Dr. Knox's medical students (John Cairney - 'Jason And
The Argonauts').
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0865972/comments</url><from>from Chyby, Poland</from><name>HumanoidOfFlesh</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Peter Cushing plays the doctor who needs bodies in this fine adaptation
of the Burke and Hare grave robbing case.Donald Pleasance and George
Rose are both excellent as the infamous grave robbers.The film is truly
atmospheric-full of packed bars,foggy streets and deep shadows-and the
performance by Peter Cushing is simply amazing-Cushing is probably one
of the most recognizable faces in the horror genre.The film has an
eerie cinematic style reminiscent more of films from the 1940's than
1959.The first half of Gilling's story moves extremely slow,but the
second half has some gruesome murder scenes.A must-see for fans of
British horror!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0443294/comments</url><from>from Limerick, Ireland</from><name>Darren O'Shaughnessy (darren shan)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Peter Cushing plays a lecturing doctor in 19th century Edinburgh who
must buy fresh corpses to teach his students about the mysteries of
anatomy. While the emphasis is on the doctor and the moral dilemmas he
faces, Pleasance and Rose steal the show as Burke &amp; Hare, no-goods who
hit on the idea of providing their own, surprisingly fresh corpses ...This is an unbelievably vivid horror tale, gruesome and perverse, years
ahead of its time. It has some weaknesses, and a most peculiar ending,
but Cushing and Pleasance give two of their best ever performances,
Rose matches them, and a young Billie Whitelaw is memorable also.
Despite being a film from the 50s, this is absolutely NOT for the
squeamish! An overlooked minor masterpiece, every bit as important to
its genre as PSYCHO or NIGHT OF THE LIVING DEAD.Trivia: Although "Psycho" is widely credited with being the first film
to feature the actual sound of a stabbing taking place, if memory
serves me right, this one might have beaten it to the punch by a year
... I'd be grateful if anyone else could confirm this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Aside from Jack the Ripper and Dr. Crippen, the Burke and Hare Case of
Scotland (1827 - 28) is the most popular subject for true crime films set in
Great Britain.  The three best known versions of this story in film are Val
Lewton's THE BODYSNATCHER, the present film (MANIA), and THE DOCTOR AND THE
DEVILS (based on a play by Dylan Thomas).  They all stick to the basics,
which are that a prominent Edinburgh doctor buys bodies from two men
(supposedly "Resurrectionists" - grave robbers - but actually murderers)for
his anatomy classes.  In terms of following the story, MANIA is closest to
the actual facts of the Burke and Hare case, even down to the final victims
(i.e. Daft Jamie).  The three central actors are Cushing (as Knox), Rose
(ironically himself a murder victim a quarter century later - as Burke), and
Pleasance (as Hare).
All three give good performances.  A gruesome story, with some occasional
good black humor touches.  Daft Jamie dies because he threatens to go to the
police unless he is paid off.  In watching him walk away, Rose says to
Pleasance what he makes of that threat.  Pleasance answers, "It means Daft
Jamie isn't as daft as we thought!"
The authors of the screenplay included the so-called comuppance of Hare, who
turned "King's Evidence" against his partner (which is why only Burke
hanged).  According to legend Hare was blinded by a gang who recognized him
(though not with a torch but by casting him into a lime
pit).  Actually, it is more likely he died peacefully in old age, but life
is not always fair.  The film also ends making it look like
Knox
has been forgiven.  Well, his students did forgive him (he was a brilliant
instructor of anatomy), but he was driven out of his city, his country, and
ended his day in London working in a clinic (and also being a showman of
some Ojibbaway Indians touring England)!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The Flesh and the Fiends is similar, in a lot of ways, to the Val
Lewton produced Robert Wise film, The Body Snatcher, but for some
reason; this one has flown further under the radar. It's odd, because
despite the greatness of the other film; The Flesh and the Fiends is a
lot better, and has the added malevolence of being based on a true-life
story. The film takes place in Edinburgh, and director John Gilling
does an excellent job of ensuring that the city looks as foreboding as
possible, and the perfect home for a story as macabre as this one. The
film follows the idea of having to break eggs to make an omelette, and
sees Doctor Robert Knox buying corpses from a couple of murderous grave
robbers in order for him to have subjects, from which new surgical
procedures can be ascertained. The real stars of the show, however, are
the graverobbers themselves; Burke and Hare. They begin their careers
by simply taking bodies from graves; but once they realise how
lucrative the business of selling cadavers is, they soon resort to
making a few corpses of their own...The biggest name in the cast is the one belonging to the great Peter
Cushing. Cushing has shown throughout his career that he is capable of
a number of different roles, and his role here is one of the best he's
had. He gets to sink his teeth into the character of Doctor Knox. In
fact, this man isn't a world away from Cushing's world-beating turn as
Doctor Frankenstein in Hammer's classic series, which explains why
Cushing is so good at it. George Rose and Donald Pleasance give the
film its extra dimension in the roles of the graverobbers. Rose is
good, but it's Pleasance who really stands out in this film. Seeing him
in a role like this is actually quite heartbreaking; as here we see how
great he can be, rendering his roles in films like Halloween even more
of a waste of time. The plot plays out from a number of different
angles, ensuring that there's always enough going on around the central
plot to ensure that the film never dries up and becomes boring. It's
strange that a film of this quality could fly straight under the radar;
but somehow it has. However, copies of this are out there; and it
definitely is well worth tracking down!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4636501/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Matthew Janovic (myboigie@earthlink.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is quite possibly the finest British horror-film ever made--except
that it is entirely-true. The Flesh and the Fiends is nothing-less than
a fairly truthful accounting of the original 'bodysnatchers,' Burke and
Hare who resorted-to-murder after running-out of 'fresh' corpses for a
Dr. Thomas Knox, of Edinburgh, Scotland. It is a scandalous-story that
would never have been possible were it not for antiquated
religious-notions that it was unholy to disinter the dead--even if
approved by the deceased and their survivors--for the purposes of
medical-inquiry. Shot in an shadowy-expressionist black, there are few
films that top this in the horror-canon. Hammer had some great films,
but this is really the capper. Burke and Hare just wanted money to
drink and whore. In the squalor of early-industrial Britain, there were
precursors to Jack the Ripper, and Burke and Hare could have taught
Jack a few-lessons. Britain's early-industrial poverty spawned rampant-licentiousness,
disease and violence. When human-life is considered worthless, you get
a tendency for crime and murder of this type. Groan all-you-want, but
these were the fruits of a form of gross economic-inequality that
prevails today. And for those who don't know, Great Britain in the
1820s was the time of Charles Dickens. Dr. Knox was one of numerous
aristocratic-doctors of his day who had to resort to the employ of
bodysnatchers to obtain fresh-cadavers for his anatomical-research.
Because of this, Flesh and the Fiends is also a tale of
scientific-ethics--with a wrongheaded-ending! Dr. Knox was definitely
aware at some point that Burke and Hare were murdering human-beings for
money (this all paid-handsomely at the time), to provide him bodies. It
doesn't get much darker than this. Would we even bat-an-eye today? In
Houston (circa 1960s-1970s), the coroner's office was selling the
cadavers of homeless Black men to the Department of Energy for
radiation-experiments. Today, there are organized-crime groups who
snatch-organs from the living and the dead for the highest-bidders!
Egads, bodysnatching never-ended.The film: it was produced by a tiny
independent English studio called 'Independents-International', and is
regarded as their best-film.Directed by Hammer-director John Gilling, it was also a minor-hit, and
is easily one of Peter Cushing's best-performances. Also noteworthy, is
Donald Pleascence's performance of the deadly Hare, which is very
nuanced. Cushing's performance is also nuanced, illustrating the
moral-dilemma that Knox must have felt utilizing the kind-of cadavers
Burke and Hare provided him. How can you lose with a movie that has him
and Peter Cushing?! Everything about The Flesh and the Fiends is
convincing, even for such a low-budget thriller. The original-negatives
of the film were located in the 1990s, so most of the editions on DVD
are superb, and contain the 'Continental version' that has plenty of
flesh (and fiends) on-display. What a wild-romp, and yet what a
chilling-parable of the abuses-of-power in a rotten-era of
human-history. It's sad how things aren't very different. You could do
worse than to watch this on those cold, Autumn-nights. This is a movie
for true horror-lovers who realize horror is of human-origin. Be-sure
to check the Brooksfilm (Mel's old-company) version of this story, 'The
Doctor and the Devils' (1985). It's pretty good, too, though
not-as-good as this. When I saw it as a kid, I thought it was about
Jack the Ripper!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0081778/comments</url><from/><name>Jason-38</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

THE FLESH AND THE FIENDS followed in the wake of the success of Hammer
Films' early successes. Although not actually a Hammer Film Production, it
shares many stylistic points with Hammer. However, the script is a largely
accurate version of the history of the body snatchers, Burke and Hare, and
their main customer, Dr. Robert Knox.Although there are memorable performances in this film, it is Peter
Cushing's work as Dr. Knox that ultimately stands out. During the 1820's
in
Edinburgh, Scotland, Dr. Knox illegally bought cadavers from Burke and
Hare.
In spite of every reason to be suspicious of Burke and Hare, Dr. Know
persisted in obtaining cadavers from them for medical lectures. To Dr.
Knox,
the training of competent doctors took precedent over ethical
considerations.In a remarkable scene in the denouement, a little girl in the street begs
alms from Dr. Knox. Cushing tells her that he doesn't have any money with
him, but if she will step over to his house he will give her some. The
little girl politely declines the offer, saying, "Oh, no, you might be Dr.
Knox." Cushing's unspoken response is truly unforgettable. It makes you
realize that Peter Cushing was
really a fine actor. What a pity his talent was too often wasted in
pictures
that were beneath him.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2378994/comments</url><from>from U.S.</from><name>macabro357</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

(aka: MANIA)This is sort of a variation of the Val Lewton film, THE BODY SNATCHER (1945)
starring Boris Karloff with the original story written by Robert Louis
Stevenson.  This version is quite good (although I still prefer the earlier film) with
an effectively creepy atmosphere that has the look of a Hammer flick, even
though Hammer Studios didn't participate in this one.Peter Cushing plays a medical professor who employs grave robbers (Donald
Pleasance and George Rose) in order to steal freshly buried corpses for his
medical anatomy classes.  The robbers get greedy for more money so they
start killing people in order to supply more fresh corpses.  At first it's
done without the doctor's knowledge, but then when some evidence turns up
casting doubt upon the whole affair, he turns a blind eye about it and
doesn't seem to care.We all know justice prevails in the end although I thought the last minute
of the film where Cushing restores faith in his students, looked a little
too down-pat to me.  But only the lower classes suffer the consequences
while the upper class gets off scot-free, right?The Image DVD has both the censored UK version and the Continental version
that contains scenes of barmaids with their tops slipping down exposing
their breasts.  You can also tell because the quality of these deleted
scenes is grainer that the film as a whole.  I guess they needed something
racier for the continental audiences to watch, although Billie Whitelaw gets
to keep her top on.  Bummer.  The widescreen b/w print is in fair condition with some bad splices and
flaking in some scenes, but it's a vast improvement over the old Sinister
Cinema VHS tape that was floating around a few years back.  Other extras
include posters and stills.    6 out of 10

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2378994/comments</url><from>from U.S.</from><name>macabro357</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

(aka: MANIA)This is sort of a variation of the Val Lewton film, THE BODY SNATCHER (1945)
starring Boris Karloff with the original story written by Robert Louis
Stevenson.  This version is quite good (although I still prefer the earlier film) with
an effectively creepy atmosphere that has the look of a Hammer flick, even
though Hammer Studios didn't participate in this one.Peter Cushing plays a medical professor who employs grave robbers (Donald
Pleasance and George Rose) in order to steal freshly buried corpses for his
medical anatomy classes.  The robbers get greedy for more money so they
start killing people in order to supply more fresh corpses.  At first it's
done without the doctor's knowledge, but then when some evidence turns up
casting doubt upon the whole affair, he turns a blind eye about it and
doesn't seem to care.We all know justice prevails in the end although I thought the last minute
of the film where Cushing restores faith in his students, looked a little
too down-pat to me.  But only the lower classes suffer the consequences
while the upper class gets off scot-free, right?The Image DVD has both the censored UK version and the Continental version
that contains scenes of barmaids with their tops slipping down exposing
their breasts.  You can also tell because the quality of these deleted
scenes is grainer that the film as a whole.  I guess they needed something
racier for the continental audiences to watch, although Billie Whitelaw gets
to keep her top on.  Bummer.  The widescreen b/w print is in fair condition with some bad splices and
flaking in some scenes, but it's a vast improvement over the old Sinister
Cinema VHS tape that was floating around a few years back.  Other extras
include posters and stills.    6 out of 10

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2378994/comments</url><from>from U.S.</from><name>macabro357</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>