<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The City of the Dead</original_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>John Llewellyn Moxey</director><producer>Vulcan</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
A young coed (Nan Barlow) uses her winter vacation to research a paper on witchcraft in New England...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Patricia Jessel</actor><actor>Dennis Lotis</actor><actor>Christopher Lee</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is the story of a college student who goes to do research in a small
town and promptly runs into strange goings on. Its not giving anything away
to say that the events involve witches of the not particularly friendly
variety.This movie creeps me out. Even if I hear the music in another room my skin
crawls. I don't know what it is but there is something about it that does
not sit well with me. Eerily filmed in suggestive black and white this film
looks like a half remembered nightmare, perhaps a clearer version of
Begotten.I dread the prospect of ever seeing this again, despite owning several
versions of it. (Hey, a good fright film has to be treasured)10 out of 10.Remember keep the lights on while you watch this. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

'Horror Hotel' (sadly the copy I bought has this tacky title, which is the
only thing I can fault about it) really surprised me at just how creepy and
atmospheric it was. I was expecting some camp fun, but it is actually a very
effective and inventive movie for such a cheap effort. The story sucks you
in, and the acting for the most part is above average. Christopher Lee is
billed as the star, which isn't exactly true, but he is excellent in his
scenes, and Patricia Jessel is even better in a very enjoyable duel role. I
also admire how director John Moxey (his movie debut. He also went on to
make 'Circus Of Fear') was able to conjure up a spooky New England town with
basically just a few sets and some fog. A great example of imaginative low
budget horror movie making at its best! Highly recommended to fans of
'Carnival Of Souls', and 'Black Sunday'. 'Horror Hotel' isn't a great an
achievement as either, but it shares some similarities in style and feel.
This is one extremely underrated movie!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0958628/comments</url><from>from Valencia, Spain</from><name>peace63</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I saw this as a Creature Feature movie in New York back in the early
1970s when I was a young kid. It was one hellaciously scary movie. I
have never seen this movie again on television, and I bought the DVD to
see if it was as good as I remember it. Like Manster, it has aged very
well.The effects and the mood are excellent. The harsh black and white makes
the shots much starker than they would be in color. The close-ups of
the faces of the vengeful crowd in the opening scenes creates a grim
mood which drives the movie. Horror Hotel has some outstanding scares.
It takes no prisoners, and like some of the best horror movies, nobody
is guaranteed to survive.The head witch, Elizabeth Selywn is awesome. Patricia Jessel plays two
roles. One as the original Selwyn witch who is burned at the stake in
1692, and then as the proprietor of the Hotel, Mrs. Newless. In both
roles she personifies evil, and her evil laugh is one of the scariest I
have ever seen. Sadly, Ms. Jessel passed away in 1968 when she was
still young.Christopher Lee has a supporting role. He starts off as a kindly
college professor and as the movie unfolds we discover that Lee knows a
lot more than he shares. His evil glares are better than a ton of
special effects. The actors that play the good characters do not stand
out much except for Ann Beach, who plays the mute girl that keeps
trying to help the potential victims. The best roles and the best
acting is in the hands of the coven of witches. The climactic
confrontation that ends the movie is not just terrifying, but it is
also full of drama, suspense, and great special effects (for 1960). The
director, John L. Moxey should be given credit for making an excellent
film. He was also the director of many movies and such TV series as The
Night Stalker, Kung-Fu, Mannix, Mission Impossible, and more.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3718339/comments</url><from/><name>Godzilla444</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

What a corker! This is one of those must have halloween movies. If only
to see our beloved Mr Lee doing an American accent. This is a prime
example from Moxey (The Night Stalker) of why most colleges do not
teach witchcraft. There are certain things which having a reasonable
knowledge of horror movies, one does not do. 1, Do not study the occult, as it will lead to many terrible things.2, Do not study the occult if Christopher Lee is your lecturer, as he
is Dracula.3, Do not go to ancient towns to study the occult if Christopher Lee
has advised you that it will help your studies, as he may have sinister
motives and be Dracula.Dracula does not appear in this film but Mr Lee casts an equally dark
shadow over this films proceedings, slowly drawing in both characters
and audience with his fantastic Christopher Lee-ness. Although saying
that the movie is of a high enough caliber that Mr Lee serves to add to
the flavor of this great movie, rather than being the only reason to
watch. A must have for all whom are drawn to horror flicks from the old
school.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1360747/comments</url><from>from Kentucky</from><name>Backlash007</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Strangers rarely come to Whitewood...and for good reason.  For it's
inhabited with witches and warlocks...and Christopher Lee!  He's absolutely
menacing in his role of Professor Driscoll.  Horror Hotel (aka: The City of
the Dead) is a just an old fashioned horror story, it's even kind of creepy.
 I think this one is all about the atmosphere; a dark and rickety hotel
located in an aging New England town that boasts an excellent use of fog
that would make John Carpenter envious.  It's something to be seen.  Horror
Hotel is slightly dated, but not too shabby.  After all, "the basis of
reality is fairy tales, and the basis of fairy tales is
reality"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0812757/comments</url><from>from Haddonfield, IL</from><name>GroovyDoom</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Some witches are just bad to the bone. Elizabeth Selwyn is one such
witch, and she's executed in a witchly fashion for it. Right before
she's burned at the stake, she vows revenge on her tormentors, which is
probably a fairly typical thing to do when a bunch of people are
burning you alive. Despite the fact that flames usually do nothing good
for the complexion, Elizabeth apparently manages to return with all her
witchly beauty as an immortal being who haunts the town of Whitewood,
and her equally immortal coven lives there with her among the
perpetually foggy streets. She and her cohorts are in the habit of
sacrificing young girls on holidays that witches hold sacred, and she
runs a spooky inn as a lure for this purpose. This is an unfortunate reality for our damsel in distress, naive
college student Nan Barlow, who goes to Whitewood to research the
existence of witchcraft in its history. She learns the difficult way
that old habits die hard, and our favorite witch, with the sly
pseudonym of Mrs. "Newlys", is all too happy to welcome her to her
creepy hotel, which is a lot like the Hotel California--you can check
in, but you can't check out.In a "Psycho"-esque change of protagonists halfway through the film,
Nan's brother traces her to Whitewood when she turns up missing, and
pretty soon everyone involved is on a collision course with the
nastiest witch in Whitewood.Oh, and Christopher Lee, too."City of the Dead", which also exists with the title "Horror Hotel"
(which sounds a lot like something in a traveling carnival), is a
deliciously spooky flick. Nobody's going to jump out of their seats
watching this one, but it does have some excellent photography,
especially in black &amp; white, and the sets are truly eerie. Fans of more
modern horror films will ultimately be disappointed, but genre
aficionados will find this wicked black &amp; white fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3760433/comments</url><from>from Exeter UK</from><name>Tim Groombridge</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Having not taken much time to watch older movies of this genre, I was
pleasantly surprised by how comprehensive the film was.Black and white photography rarely seems to look this good, and has
been one of the things that has turned me off such films before now.
The visuals in City Of The Dead are so sharp and foreboding that they
serve to accentuate the small town paranoia perfectly.In terms of the characters, Patricia Jessel as Mrs Newlis and
Christopher Lee as Prof Driscoll, are supremely sinister, whilst
Venetia Stevenson as Nan Barlow, is hopelessly deserving of the viewers
compassion as the witches prey!I've come to love this film, not just for the sake of the film itself,
but because it proved me so wrong in my assumption that most movies of
this type/age are dull, it's incredibly watchable and tense.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1924433/comments</url><from>from Northfield, MN</from><name>Troy Ros (Rastacat1@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I first saw this movie in the mid 70's late one Saturday night on
Sinister
Cinema in Portland, OR and it kind of scared the crap out of me. They
replayed it about a year later and same thing: It scared the crap out of
me.
I have now seen it 6 or 7 times over the years including twice in the
last
few months with the VCI Entertainment version of the dvd.The movie doesn't scare me like it used to, but it still amazes me how it
transports me into it's own world of the fog shrouded town of Whitewood,
Massachusetts. The story itself is common enough: A woman (Patricia
Jessel)
is burned at the stake for witchcraft and she leaves a curse on the
people
of the town as she is consumed by the flames. Forward 300 years to the
present day and we have Nan Barlow (Venetia Stevens) as a self determined
college student who decides to write a paper on witchcraft. Her
professor,
Alan Driscoll (Christopher Lee), gives her directions to the town of
Whitewood where 300 years earlier an alleged witch was burned at the
stake.
She goes to the town and after a few days disappears. Her brother then
goes
to the hotel where she was last seen, and runs into all kinds obstacles,
not
the least of which is the innkeeper of the Whitewood Inn, who just
happens
to look exactly like the witch burned 300 years earlier, and also
Christopher Lee who happens to be a long ago resident of
WhitewoodThere is an old, blind priest who stays in his church despite the fact
that
he has no congregation. His granddaughter, Betta St. John (Patricia
Russell), who seems to not be a witch, and has just returned to the town
to
take care of her grandfather, runs the local used book and antique store.
She had befriended Nan before she disappeared and is now working with her
brother, Dennis Lotis (Richard Barlow), to try and find out what happened
to
Nan.Of course they run into the witches along they way and there is a
showdown
of sorts. The strength of this movie is in it's crisp acting and smart
script. Especially notable are Patricia Jessel, Christopher Lee and
Venitia
Stevens. Despite it's low budget, the director, John Llewellyn Moxey, has
made an altogether unforgettable film. This ranks right up there with
other
unique horror movies such as Carnival of Souls (1962), The Wicker Man
(1973), The Thing From Another World (1951), and Village of the Damned
(1960).The VCI Entertainment release is just what this movie has needed for
years.
An excellent transfer at 1.66:1 with two extra minutes of footage added
from
previous video and dvd releases. There is a commentary by director John
Llewellyn Moxey and another separate commentary by Christopher Lee. There
are also three interview segments with Lee, Moxey and Venetia Stevenson.
Pretty impressive extras for a 40 year old low budget movie.The commentary by Christopher Lee is interesting in that he has not seen
this movie since it came out 41 years earlier. He is watching it with an
interviewer from VCI who knows more about what is going on in the movie
than
Lee does. But Lee's ability to recall information about people and give
anecdotal information is unsurpassed. He is literally a walking, talking
encyclopedia of info on people he has worked with over the years.This is one of my prize dvd's and I really cannot recommend it highly
enough. The VCI version lists for around $25 but I have seen it cheaper.
There are also several basic versions without the extras (or extra
footage)
of the movie along with another movie on one dvd. Most notably the
Diamond
Entertainment version where it is packaged along with Carnival of Souls
for
under $10. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0732762/comments</url><from>from Bayonne, NJ</from><name>modrock62</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A true masterpiece and a perfect example of how imagination and desire can
overcome a small budget in film making! "Horror Hotel", aka, "City Of The
Dead" is one of my all-time favorite horror classics. Beautiful black and
white photography, a stock pile of atmosphere, a literate script, terrific
acting and chills galore! I have seen this gem many times, first when I was
very young and caught it on the Late Show. It has had an effect on me
everytime I see it. The plot seems familiar I am sure, a witches cult is
operating in a small New England town but there is much more then that! From
Christopher Lee to the chilling witch hunt and stake burning of the opening
to the climatic battle with the coven in the graveyard. Outstanding! Mist
and fog drown this small town and what strikes me most is that this entire
production was studio bound!!! no location shooting, all done in a studio
and it comes off without a hitch!
I happen to have a copy of this film on video that I cherish. It's not a
newly remastered, pristine copy. It's a copy that seems to have been copied
from a television broadcast and I love it! It looks grainy, old, had pieces
of hair and dirt on it and I wouldn't trade it for the world. It brings back
great memories of films shown when I was young in the 60's and 70's and adds
an extra dose of charm and atmosphere to the film. A true classic and one I
highly recommend!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0605857/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>marquis de cinema</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

1960 was a year in which three horror films on a similar subject matter
known as The Haunted Palace, Horror Hotel, and The Mask of Satan were
released.  The locales are worthy of Lovecraft.  The opening scene is
inspired by the pre credits sequence of Mario Bava's debut, The Mask of
Satan(1960).  Horror Hotel(1960) has an Italian flavor with its atmosphere
and mystery.  Whitewood like Dunwich is a cursed and unsavory little town. 
An underrated horror flick of the 1960s.  Patricia Jessel gives a commanding
and menacing performance as Elizabeth Selwyn.Christopher Lee gives an excellent turn as the mysterious Professor Alan
Driscoll.  One of his best roles in a non hammer horror film besides Horror
Express(1972), The Whip &amp; the Body(1964), and The Wicker Man(1974).  Comes
after his famous roles for Hammer studios in Curse of Frankenstein(1957),
Horror of Dracula(1958), and The Mummy(1959).  About a young student who
goes off into an old New England town to investigate the phenomen of
witchcraft.  After she disappears her brother looks for her with sinister
results.  There are tads of Dennis Wheatley in Horror Hotel(1960).  John
Moxey films the horror with finesse.Professor Alan Driscoll in a way i alike the character of Mocata.  The scene
where the boyfriend of the missing girl crashes into a tree after seeing the
image of Selwyn burning and laughing is something out of The Devil Rides
Out.  Christopher Lee does a good job in hiding his rich British voice.  May
be the influence for Lucio Fulci's Paura Nella Citta Dei Morti Viventi/City
of the Living Dead(1980) and Dario Argento's Inferno(1980).  For example
Inferno(1980) uses a couple of this film's plot device.  An intriquing line
in Horror Hotel comes from Christopher Lee in the early first half when he
says, "The basis of fairy tales is reality, basis of reality is fairy
tales".  Seems to implie that legends and myths are based on something
true.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0605857/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>marquis de cinema</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

1960 was a year in which three horror films on a similar subject matter
known as The Haunted Palace, Horror Hotel, and The Mask of Satan were
released.  The locales are worthy of Lovecraft.  The opening scene is
inspired by the pre credits sequence of Mario Bava's debut, The Mask of
Satan(1960).  Horror Hotel(1960) has an Italian flavor with its atmosphere
and mystery.  Whitewood like Dunwich is a cursed and unsavory little town. 
An underrated horror flick of the 1960s.  Patricia Jessel gives a commanding
and menacing performance as Elizabeth Selwyn.Christopher Lee gives an excellent turn as the mysterious Professor Alan
Driscoll.  One of his best roles in a non hammer horror film besides Horror
Express(1972), The Whip &amp; the Body(1964), and The Wicker Man(1974).  Comes
after his famous roles for Hammer studios in Curse of Frankenstein(1957),
Horror of Dracula(1958), and The Mummy(1959).  About a young student who
goes off into an old New England town to investigate the phenomen of
witchcraft.  After she disappears her brother looks for her with sinister
results.  There are tads of Dennis Wheatley in Horror Hotel(1960).  John
Moxey films the horror with finesse.Professor Alan Driscoll in a way i alike the character of Mocata.  The scene
where the boyfriend of the missing girl crashes into a tree after seeing the
image of Selwyn burning and laughing is something out of The Devil Rides
Out.  Christopher Lee does a good job in hiding his rich British voice.  May
be the influence for Lucio Fulci's Paura Nella Citta Dei Morti Viventi/City
of the Living Dead(1980) and Dario Argento's Inferno(1980).  For example
Inferno(1980) uses a couple of this film's plot device.  An intriquing line
in Horror Hotel comes from Christopher Lee in the early first half when he
says, "The basis of fairy tales is reality, basis of reality is fairy
tales".  Seems to implie that legends and myths are based on something
true.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0605857/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>marquis de cinema</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-biodrowski/</url><url>http://cinefantastiqueonline.com/2007/08/22/hollywood-gothique-horror-hotelcity-of-the-dead-review/ /m/horror_hotel/comments.php?reviewid=1739824</url><name>Steve Biodrowski</name><from>ESplatter</from></reviewer><comment>It sports what may be the best, most terrifying (happy) ending ever seen in a genre fear fest - a genuine tour-de-force so powerful in its imagery that it almost single-handedly erases any reservations one has about the rest of the movie.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/daniel-eagan/</url><url>/m/horror_hotel/comments.php?reviewid=1292678</url><name>Daniel Eagan</name><from>Film Journal International</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment>Not as scary as you'd like</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/horror_hotel/comments.php?reviewid=1186743</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Cheesy horror that looks like a TV show.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=3781 /m/horror_hotel/comments.php?reviewid=276394</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
70/100
					</rating><comment>It may seem a somewhat trite and corny affair when compared with today's definition of 'horror movies,' but this one has the market cornered on atmosphere.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/mem/movies/review.html?title1=&amp;title2=Horror%20Hotel%20%28Movie%29&amp;reviewer=&amp;v_id=23149&amp;pdate=19630620&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/horror_hotel/comments.php?reviewid=1389875</url><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>