<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Adua e le compagne</original_title><alt_title>Adua et ses compagnes</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Antonio Pietrangeli</director><producer>Zebra Film</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis/><actor>Simone Signoret</actor><actor>Marcello Mastroianni</actor><actor>Sandra Milo</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342532/comments</url><from>from San Francisco Bay Area</from><name>joehardy-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Here is a wonderful example of Italian realism from 1960 that I'd never
heard of until this week--and I'm 65 years old and a big fan of this
genre.
It was shown in San Francisco as the only "classic" film in a festival of
recent Italian cinema.  It deserves a wider audience.  How can a film that
stars Simone Signoret and Marcello Mastroianni remain so obscure?  This
story of four prostitutes forced to fend for themselves when a new law
closes the bordellos of Rome reminds one of "Bicycle Thief" or "The
Organizer," in its gritty social realism, but there are scenes of
happiness
and humor too.  They pool their savings to open a trattoria, but find they
cannot get a license.  A prominent fixer with connections obtains the
license for them, on condition that they conduct their old business
upstairs
and pay him an exorbitant monthly fee.  The women are not anxious to turn
tricks for a living any longer and find joy in running the restaurant. The
women long to settle down--one has a child, another meets a man who loves
her.  Only one is tempted to return to her old life. Signoret, the major
character here and as wonderful as ever, falls for Mastroianni, a glib car
salesman, hustler and womanizer.   While the trattoria is a success, it
does
not bring in the kind of money demanded by their "patron," which leads to
conflict.  The resolutions of their individual stories develop alongside
that of their collective story.  In this genre, happy endings are not a
staple.  Grim reality is, however.  We can feel great sympathy for these
women, but we know that such people are too often bound by destiny, given
the realities of power--who has it and who hasn't--and the attitudes of
society.  All this drama is accompanied by a terrific jazz soundtrack,
which
is unfortunately not credited.  The black-and-white cinematography is
first
rate.  The closing scene in the rain ranks among the all-time
unforgettable
film endings.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0835751/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>esteban hernandez</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I will never be tired of seeing "Adua e le compagne", this black and
white film is a jewel of Italian cinematography with a plot easy to
understand, and excellent acting of four women, French star Simone
Signoret, then-young Sandra Milo, Gina Rovere and Emmanuelle Riva, all
playing the role of prostitutes who wanted to incorporate themselves
honestly to the society. Their acting was seconded by the experienced
and charismatic Marcello Mastroianni in the role of a typical Italian
tricky pigeon and lover. Italy of the 50s had the problem of
prostitution, and mafia was around it together with some "gentlemen" of
the corrupted local administration always looking for licenses, permits
and other documents in a tricky way to facilitate the work of the
prostitutes who at the same time had to pay heavy sum of money to the
above-mentioned gentlemen. The director Antonio Pietrangeli was able to
show clearly where the problem was and who were promoting the dirty
business of prostitution. In addition, youth does not last forever and
the same happened with the beauty of the prostitutes. The film also
shows this fact convincingly. The DVD of this film exists but only in
Italian, and it would be good to have it in other languages (English,
Spanish and French at least).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4944007/comments</url><from>from Greenwich - London</from><name>christopher-underwood</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Very fine, gloriously black and white, very well acted drama involving
four girls who decide to pool their resources and run a restaurant
together when their brothel is closed down. There are so many moments
where this could easily have become sentimental and doesn't and is much
to the director's credit that this looks so good throughout. The jazz
soundtrack is a great help as are the snatches or 'real life' - the
steam trains rushing below car dealer Mastroianni's window, the fine
moment in the main street when he passes off Signoret's failing car to
another whilst slipping her into one more. But the best of all such
sequences is the final shot upon the cobblestoned street in the pouring
rain and without a cloying close-up, we all know exactly what the
facial expression is. As I say all the acting is good but Signoret
particularly puts in another excellent performance where she ranges
from sexy to sad and energetic to dejected, but perhaps best of all her
verbal onslaught upon 'the landlord'.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2567136/comments</url><from/><name>writers_reign</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This has to be something of an oddity - a 'Continetal' film about four
hookers with NO nudity and No sex. Quite a trick but Pietrangeli pulls
it off with the help of a fine cast led by Simone Signoret - by now no
stranger to the oldest profession having played hookers in Dedee Of
Anvers and La Ronde - as the eponymous Adua and Marcello Mastroianni as
the waste-of-space she falls for. All four of the hookers - Caterina
(Gina Rovere), Lolita (Sandra Milo) and Marilena (Emmannuelle Riva) are
the other three - are excellent and contrive not to LOOK like what they
are or rather were for the story begins when the Italian government
closed the legal brothels effectively putting them out of work. They
pool their money and open a restaurant and make a decent stab at
leaving their old lives behind them but problems mount up in the form
of red tape requiring a 'patron' to unravel. Such a patron is found and
he's more than happy to do the necessary with the proviso that in the
fullness of time, say two months, the girls revert to their old trade
via turning tricks in the upstairs bedrooms of the restaurant. For
various reasons only one of the four is happy with and prepared to do
this and so the film has a realistic rather than a conventional happy
ending. Signoret towers above the others and even Mastroianni seems
lacklustre in comparison but it remains an engrossing film and well
worth seeing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2567136/comments</url><from/><name>writers_reign</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This has to be something of an oddity - a 'Continetal' film about four
hookers with NO nudity and No sex. Quite a trick but Pietrangeli pulls
it off with the help of a fine cast led by Simone Signoret - by now no
stranger to the oldest profession having played hookers in Dedee Of
Anvers and La Ronde - as the eponymous Adua and Marcello Mastroianni as
the waste-of-space she falls for. All four of the hookers - Caterina
(Gina Rovere), Lolita (Sandra Milo) and Marilena (Emmannuelle Riva) are
the other three - are excellent and contrive not to LOOK like what they
are or rather were for the story begins when the Italian government
closed the legal brothels effectively putting them out of work. They
pool their money and open a restaurant and make a decent stab at
leaving their old lives behind them but problems mount up in the form
of red tape requiring a 'patron' to unravel. Such a patron is found and
he's more than happy to do the necessary with the proviso that in the
fullness of time, say two months, the girls revert to their old trade
via turning tricks in the upstairs bedrooms of the restaurant. For
various reasons only one of the four is happy with and prepared to do
this and so the film has a realistic rather than a conventional happy
ending. Signoret towers above the others and even Mastroianni seems
lacklustre in comparison but it remains an engrossing film and well
worth seeing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>