<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Key Witness</original_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Phil Karlson</director><producer>Avon Productions (II)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
An average Los Angeles citizen witnesses a gang murder when he stops to use a telephone. Aware that he is the only witness against them...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jeffrey Hunter</actor><actor>Pat Crowley</actor><actor>Dennis Hopper</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0692247/comments</url><from>from Boulder, Colorado</from><name>reelguy2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Key Witness verges on the point of hysteria, and lacks credibility
throughout, but it's still a riveting drama, directed by Phil Karlson in
typically tough fashion.Most of the performances are over-the-top, but as the witness to a gang
stabbing, Jeffrey Hunter gives a standout performance. Without overacting,
he brings plenty of energy and intensively to his role, playing an Everyman
driven to the breaking point by the mob terrorizing him and his family. Next
to Brainstorm (1965), this is his best work.Although the film may infuriate you with its pat ending, you shouldn't be
bored for an instant.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1665171/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jefbecco</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I think that people miss the historical aspect of this movie. It was
1960 and Hollywood was just figuring out how to make a "real" and
gritty crime drama. Yes the film is bizarre - Father Knows Best meets
The Wild Ones or The Blackboard Jungle. The average scriptwriter
probably wasn't real familiar with the daily life of street criminals
and the language would have gone right over their head.But the movie shows the by 1960 crime was becoming more of a concern
for the average middle class American family. People were starting to
learn that their safe, secure little worlds, weren't and that the crime
of the "lower class" neighborhoods was moving into their daily life.By
1970 middle class America would be much sadder and wiser, but this film
shows that crime was a concern in during the good old days of President
Ike.Basically it's an interesting look at the time.It's one of the few
older movies I've come across in which there is a reference to a
character, even a villain, using Cocaine. Yes the thugs are too clean
and they don't look like they smell. As a cop I can tell you the one
thing that movies don't convey is the smell of that world. How can
they?The only movie that I can think of that came the closest was
"Training Day".Don't compare this movie to modern productions, it isn't fair.
Overacting and melodramatic scripts were normal and expected. Just
watch shows like Star Trek,Route 66, The Big Valley and The Fugitive.
Those shows were over the top by our standards, but not back then.It
isn't that bad.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1899407/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>rg mccreary (bwanabe)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Very rarely shown, I was fortunate to have seen it at its release.Several dozen onlookers witness a daring gang murder, but only LA
businessman Fred Morrow agrees to testify. His family is tormented by
the youthful thugs, the police being unable to protect them from the
gang's attacks and ever increasing violence. Will Morrow hang tough and
perform his civic duty or will he recognize his mistake and develop
amnesia, thereby allowing one of B-movie Hollywood's most brazen
killers to go free? The theme music ("Ruby Duby Du"), written by
Charles Wolcott, is absolutely haunting, and is far and away my
favorite instrumental.Jeffrey Hunter, Dennis Hopper, Pat Crowley, Johnny Nash and Susan
Harrison make for a top-notch cast.Four years after its release I met a person who likewise considered
"Key Witness" his favorite movie. Forty-two years later we remain best
friends.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7194258/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>hop2hop4</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Pretty good movie and relative to the times. But It was the song "Ruby
Duby Du" that I remember. Its one of those tunes that once it gets into
your head you can not stop it. I remember it being played throughout
the movie but that was 46 years ago; maybe it was just the play on the
radio and of course; bought the 45 as well. It was a hit song at the
time. The gang leader's girl was named Ruby. As far as the film, story,
itself; I remember the impression that movie gave me was one of
helplessness or "how to fight such a terrible gang of young people".
After all, its just a dad and his family. This was a movie about young
thugs and a family. I could relate to the family but was frightened by
the cold heartlessness of the gang. I remember the scene where the gang
had entered the family's home and scratched the words "Key Witness" on
the roof of their automobile inside the attached garage. That scene,
for me, started the scary meanness threaded throughout the rest of the
story. And oh yes, "the circle" with the father in the middle and
finally one of the gang members went back-to-back with the dad as the
movie's second hero. As I recall the daughter kinda liked that boy.
Only the "Ruby Duby Du" song helped ease the tenseness for this 11 year
old in 1960. I downloaded that song just a couple of years ago. Pretty
cool dad...daddy-o.Al
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1313418/comments</url><from>from TeXas</from><name>Tiger_Mark</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I really enjoyed this film. However, I enjoy all films of this particular
genre. Black and whites film from the late 1950's/early 1960's. Plenty of
hip looking individuals with snappy lingo. The detectives wear hats and the
punks are bad news. It reminds me of "Blackboard Jungle" or some Stanley
Kramer film.The story is about doing the right thing, even when the wrong
thing is much easier to do. Moreover, you get to see a young Dennis Hopper
do his early version of Frank Booth from "Blue Velvet." Good stuff in a
retro kind of way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2925760/comments</url><from/><name>BrentCarleton</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
While it's true that the plot is frequently hampered by preposterous
turns, this emerges as a genuinely harrowing thriller, largely owing to
Jeffrey Hunter's conviction in the title role, as well as comely
Patricia Crowley's interpretation as his panicked suburban wife.It is to director Karlson's credit that he can take the improbable and
still draw one in, such as the scene where Mr. Hunter's young son is
shot by one of the thug's on the school playground--and one goes quite
limp with horror.And for all those doubting the veracity of witness retribution--try
reading the daily newspapers.However, Cinemasope is inappropriate for such an intimate story, and
the cinematographer here is usually incapable of effectively composing
for such a wide frame.Look for Ted Knight in a bit as Dennis Hopper's defense attorney.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0455019/comments</url><from>from Out there in the dark</from><name>mackjay</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
A rather disappointing minor entry, "Key Witness"(1960) directed by
none other than PHIL KARLSON (of the superb "Kansas City Confidential",
"Scandal Sheet" and "99 River Street"), is a Cinemascoped-up
second-rate b-movie. Utterly conventional in most ways, this film is a
let down from start to finish. Its worst offense is what might be
called the "pulled punch"--all scenes of action or violence are done
through editing away from the actual moment, then cutting back to its
aftermath. The whole film just seems like a routine exercise. On the
good side: the jazz score by Charles Wolcott--listenable, if a bit
repetitive.In the cast--Jeffrey Hunter: giving here what may be among his better performances.
He seems emotionally involved in his noir situation as the victimized
witness to a stabbing.Pat Crowley: bland as his near-hysterical wifeFrank Silvera: best performer in the film, as a tenacious police
detectiveThe Thugs are played by:Dennis Hopper--not one of his better moments, overacted out the wahzooSusan Harrison--miscast (too delicate and nice) as the moll, yes THAT
Susan Harrison of "Sweet Smell of Success" and the barrel-bottom
ballerina from 'The Twilight Zone'Johnny "I Can See Clearly Now" Nash: not at all bad for a
singer-turned-actorJoby Baker: staple of TV and movies from this period, actually does an
interesting turn as a jive-talking junkie-typeTed Knight: uncredited as Hopper's lawyer.A must-see for Karlson, Hopper and Hunter completest.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0864454/comments</url><from>from Hollywood, CA</from><name>jimddddd</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
By the late 1950s film noir was dead but the juvenile delinquent
thriller, originally inspired by the novels of Hal Ellson from ten
years earlier ("Duke," "The Golden Spike," etc), was thriving on the
B-movie circuit. But MGM and producer Pandro Berman, perhaps hoping to
repeat their 1955 success with "Blackboard Jungle," tried to blow "Key
Witness" up into an A-movie, widescreen Cinemascope, "Rebel Without a
Cause" alumni (Hopper, Corey Allen), and all. Though the plot relies on
sometimes ridiculous turns (in one maddening scene, a deputy runs into
a courtroom interrupting testimony) and the characters are mostly
cartoons (Muggles certainly lives up to the first syllable in his
name), director Phil Karlson's decision to shoot on the streets of Los
Angeles keeps everything moderately realistic. The opening scene, set
in a hilly slum neighborhood just north of City Hall in the Chinatown
area (though it looks like old Bunker Hill and is referred to as "East
L.A." in the film), immediately puts the viewer into the middle of the
action and the period. If this film had been shot on a soundstage, as
"Blackboard Jungle" was, it would have fallen apart within the first
ten minutes, but once again L.A. saves the day. If you love the
atmosphere of on-location films from this era, you'll enjoy the
sensation of sitting through "Key Witness."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2666766/comments</url><from>from Chicago - Atlanta</from><name>eman_groove</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie really had me laughing and rolling in my lounge chair. The
corny lines and predicaments the main characters were faced with let
you know how advanced the screenplay writer was in the 50's &amp; 60's. The
so-called "hip-talk" was so funny that I know the actors probably had
to do several takes to keep from laughing at themselves saying the
lines. This movie believe it or not touches on the urban social
conscience of the world too.I thought Key Witness was interesting. The characters were of different
genders, race, class and creed. It also also gave you an understanding
about life in East L.A. during the late 50's &amp; early 60's. If Key Witness was re-made to reflect the times of today, the following
actors should be cast in the character roles: Mr. Morrow - David
Hasslehoff or Rob Lowe, Mrs. Morrow - Christina Applegate, Cowboy -
Brad Pitt, Apple - David Alan Grier or Micheal Beach(Third Watch), Ruby
- Christina Applegate, Carmen Electra, Madonna or Melissa Milano or
Melissa Rivers (first acting gig) Muggles - Brad Pitt, Vince Vaughn or
Colin Ferrell, Det. Turno - Obba Obatunde, Giancarlo Espisito, Charles
S. Dutton, Magician - Vince Vaughn . The plot would be the same only
updated to reflect the times. Its a classic for any young filmmaker to
use as a guide and training tool. Check it out!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6454530/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>sun-mines</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I put a copy of "Ruby Duby Du" on YouTube.com. I don't know how long it
will last because I don't have the copyright. Tags: Wolcott.Now, I don't appreciate this minimum length for comment being 10 lines
of text. It's a waste of my time and your time.I thought by now IMDb would have wised up.So, I'm really sorry to have to do this to you all, but just to make
IMDb happy, here's a little part of a little poem by my Dad:"We do not know why the tear drop fell, and he would not like it so,
But from his eyes I'll theorize he was looking into Hell.A Hell of his own making, he knew where the trail had turned, Without
his help the die was cast, and so the bridges burned.High in the Hills of Tranquility sits a hawk on a lonely byrne. Broods
he not in senility, but for a love who will never return.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6454530/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>sun-mines</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I put a copy of "Ruby Duby Du" on YouTube.com. I don't know how long it
will last because I don't have the copyright. Tags: Wolcott.Now, I don't appreciate this minimum length for comment being 10 lines
of text. It's a waste of my time and your time.I thought by now IMDb would have wised up.So, I'm really sorry to have to do this to you all, but just to make
IMDb happy, here's a little part of a little poem by my Dad:"We do not know why the tear drop fell, and he would not like it so,
But from his eyes I'll theorize he was looking into Hell.A Hell of his own making, he knew where the trail had turned, Without
his help the die was cast, and so the bridges burned.High in the Hills of Tranquility sits a hawk on a lonely byrne. Broods
he not in senility, but for a love who will never return.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6454530/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>sun-mines</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>