<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La caperucita roja</original_title><imdb_rating>5.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Mexico</country><director>Roberto Rodríguez</director><producer>Películas Rodríguez</producer><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis/><actor>María Gracia</actor><actor>Manuel 'Loco' Valdés</actor><actor>Santanón</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0372846/comments</url><from>from DVD Drive-In</from><name>Casey-52</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

LITTLE RED RIDING HOOD was available at a film convention I went to and
out
of curiosity, I bought it. It was the funniest thing I had seen in years!
Not intentionally funny, mind you, but funny! The little girl is so
obnoxious, everyone loves her, the perfect little girl. You just wanna
ring
her neck! The wolf is a man in a raggedy old HIDEOUS suit that stalks
around
"menacingly" with his sidekick, a skunk (a man in a HIDEOUS skunk suit!).
When Little Red sings, her voice is that of an adult opera singer! With a
giant spider who's "angry", the wolf's cave that looks like a giant jack
o'
lantern, and a bunch of comedy relief that isn't comedy and certainly
isn't
relief for the atrocity of this thing! Get this movie now!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15166517/comments</url><from>from Nazareth, PA United States</from><name>islandsnvrcry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
this movie is basically flawless. as a CHILD, i watched the English
version and was enthralled by it, and at the same time very creeped out
by the incredibly and shockingly sexual predator/stalker character of
the Wolf. Anyone who has seen this film as a child can tell you it is
an emotional roller coaster on multiple levels. The music, the rustic
scenery in "half color", and the emotions just take you to another
world; an outsider who is just waiting to see the protagonist come to
an end, with the evil being so pungent and in our face, with you
completely unable to do anything about it. You constantly fear for
riding hood and the villagers because you know what is coming for them.
its very shakespearan.As an ADULT, the movie is the most hilarious thing you will perhaps
ever see in you're life, for various reasons, primarily the corniness
and high levels of non realism. It is worthe minutes upon minutes of
laughter. However, It is also possible to take the film very seriously;
just note the above mentioned characteristics of the wolf. Strong other
gender and age related issues are also prevalent throughout the film;
its a matter of viewing it as styalistic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6168271/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>traveller-samurai</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I am disagree with some comments of the users of this movie because of
the very bad dubbing of the movie. We have to remember that, for a
Mexican movie, this one is on the standards of this time (beginning of
the sixties) and it had to be see it more as a theatrical way than a
movie.The most appreciated character on this movie and the next two had been
made is Manuel "Loco" Valdes because he was in his top moment as
comedian and actor, so he develop a very funny and unoffensive wolf
that became the pivotal of this and the next two movies.Maybe for me, this movie is now not more than a lot of sugar on screen
(currently I am 27), but for the time I saw it (around 20 years
before), this series of movies became a very nice experience to see on
Mexican TV.This movie is good for kids that wants to imagine that the characters
are real even that they look so unreal on screen, but forget to hear it
dubbed in English, the Spanish version is better.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0802132/comments</url><from>from Westchester, New York</from><name>rdh7182373</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

In 1959, K. Gordon Murray released "Santa Claus" which he
purchased
from the Mexican Azteca studios. He released it in the U.S. with an
ineptly
dubbed English soundtrack and it became a surprise hit.  Murray's 'high
concept' was to book it to theaters
as an exclusive "Childrens Matinee".  It would only play
afternoons
in selected theaters rather than evening performances like Hollywood
features. For about a decade, Murray and his imitators released Mexican
and
German imports using this release pattern.In the sixties my parents took me to see some of his
pictures on weekends. There is nothing quite so bizarre as to see these
movies on a large screen.  Everything is magnified.  The shabby costumes,
the out of synch dialogue, rediculous songs, endless zooming and
characters
running into the camera lens. You can see the eyebrows and mascara of the
comedian playing the wolf through an obvious hole in the costume.
Sometimes
the lips move while they're talking, other times they don't. When the girl
sings her theme song, a grown woman's voice comes out of her mouth.  The
skunk babbles incoherantly in every scene drowning out the other dialogue.
The continuity is choppy since Murray removed shots and scenes from the
original Mexican version. It plays like a low budget horror film rather
than
a children's fantasy.  All of these elements made for a very disorienting
and grotesque moviegoing experience. Yet I must admit, I found it
memorable.I recently purchased a VHS of the original spanish language version, "La
Caperucita Roja".  While still strange, the continuity is more coherant
and
less choppy.  The skunk does not babble as much and a little girl's voice
is
used for the theme song. I have no idea where Murray got his first scene
in
the American version of Little Red Riding Hood and Freckles arguing since
it's not in the Mexican version.Murray also released three sequels to this picture.  The strangest is
"Little Red Riding Hood and the Monsters".  In one scene, the girl rips
out
the chest hair of an ogre and stuffs it in his mouth. There's nothing
quite
like a K. Gordon Murray Children's Matinee!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4364000/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bkball4me</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw the movie when I was a kid back in Mexico. It was a total hit
back then along with "Pulgarcito". I was so fascinated with her
sweetness and her costume that my dad bought me the 45" record of this
movie. For too long I was none other than Caperucita Roja, until I
replaced her for a movie star a couple of years later. If by any chance
you are lucky to have this movie, I recommend that you have the mind of
a child of the 60'S and to watch it and to remember that everything was
magic,incredible, pure, innocent, perfect, It just has all the
ingredients to make us laugh, be sad, to dream and to believe that
goodness always overcomes darkness. A 100% BEAUTIFUL AND RECOMMENDED
MOVIE WITH NO DOUBT!!! (p.s. Guess what I just bought from one of these
auctions?.... you're right; the record my Dad gave me 38 years ago and
also some originals Lobby Cards from the movie!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4364000/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bkball4me</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw the movie when I was a kid back in Mexico. It was a total hit
back then along with "Pulgarcito". I was so fascinated with her
sweetness and her costume that my dad bought me the 45" record of this
movie. For too long I was none other than Caperucita Roja, until I
replaced her for a movie star a couple of years later. If by any chance
you are lucky to have this movie, I recommend that you have the mind of
a child of the 60'S and to watch it and to remember that everything was
magic,incredible, pure, innocent, perfect, It just has all the
ingredients to make us laugh, be sad, to dream and to believe that
goodness always overcomes darkness. A 100% BEAUTIFUL AND RECOMMENDED
MOVIE WITH NO DOUBT!!! (p.s. Guess what I just bought from one of these
auctions?.... you're right; the record my Dad gave me 38 years ago and
also some originals Lobby Cards from the movie!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4364000/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bkball4me</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>