<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Morgan il pirata</original_title><alt_title>Capitaine Morgan</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>André De Toth</director><producer>Adelphia Compagnia Cinematografica</producer><producer>Compagnie Cinématographique de France</producer><producer>Lux Film</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
A Welsh pirate raids up and down the Caribbean, battling the Spanish, the English and other pirates.
</synopsis><actor>Steve Reeves</actor><actor>Valérie Lagrange</actor><actor>Ivo Garrani</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1791493/comments</url><from>from california</from><name>non_sportcardandy</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

During my school years this was the movie I viewed more times(4 1/2) at the
theaters than any other.Although a steve reeves fan I was all set to make
fun of this movie with my brother before viewing it,maybe I was too use to
seeing him run around in sandals(Steve Reeves not my brother)and thought his
playing the part of a pirate was kind of hokey.Fifteen minutes into the
movie I accepted his playing a mortal and really started to enjoy this
movie,actually the movie got real interesting earlier than that with the
first appearance of Valerie Lagrange.Wow!The rest could have the blondes,
this dark haired beauty was my type.First there was Annette,Gina ,Sophia and
now Valerie,finally there would be Lucianna(that's my wife and leading
lady).The romantic pairing of Reeves and Lagrange is fairytale like and
probably had much to do with my repeat viewings that were an escape from the
blah events of reality.Still though this is top adventure/action
entertainment with a nice musical score.Like many Italian movies a few
laughs are mixed in with all the action.The biggest one probably being when
one pirate changes his mind about baring from the waist up before dueling
reeves,seem as though his built wouldn't compare well with the champion body
builder.There are nice scenes of impressive ships at sea to go along with
the battles,pillaging and plundering.An epic without the long duration that
causes squirming in the seats.In this film is also another big star of
european adventure films-Chelo Alonso,she no doubt is appealing to many of
the viewers also.The way I see it,if a person doesn't like this movie it's
because they don't like pirate movies period.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0963568/comments</url><from>from sterling hts, michigan</from><name> (mhrabovsky1@home.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

It is a shame that "Morgan the Pirate" is not shown or recognized more by
action fans. It is very hard to find this film on any tv station -
including
cable or video stores.  Steve Reeves gives his very best acting job in this
venerable pirate tale.....also, an oddity is that Steve has to pursue the
lovely Dona Inez, the daughter of the governor of Panama, throughout the
film.....she makes Reeves work very hard to make a conquest of her.   In
other Reeves tales the women begin swooning over him very early.  Morgan
the
Pirate has great action scenes, with good closeups of some beautifully
reconstructed pirate ships.   The costumes are quite historical, with
Reeves
decked out in a slew of pirate regalia as the film progresses.  The music
sets off this swashbuckler to a great extent.  Best music score around for
this pirate tale.  Reeves survives a mini mutiny among his own pirate
group,
spearheaded by a jealous cohort captain who Steve outduels in an excellent
action sequence early in the film as Reeves establishes his authority as
the
overall leader of the pirates.  Some lovely women to look at in this film,
and Reeves does not appear overly muscular for the role.Plenty of pirate fighting and a good romantic ending for Captain
Morgan.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Henry Morgan(Steve Reeves) is an English slave who's bought by the
Panama governor(Ivo Garrani)'s daughter named Ines(Valerie Legrange).
They fall in love and then he's condemned. When he finds himself in a
galleon , bursts a rebellion and he becomes pirate. Meanwhile Ines is
kidnapped in island of Turtle , but she's freed. Then ,Morgan decides
to take the city of Panama, the location strongest fortified from
Spanish empire.The film is a nice pirates-adventures movie, lavishly produced.This
classic story of romantic adventure come to life enriched by
Technicolor cinematography in charge of Tonino Delli Colli(usual
cameraman of Sergio Leone and Pasolini) and adapted magnificently to
the screen. Overwhelming battle ships and sword-play and full of
villainy, romance ,swashbuckler and heroism. Usual dancing scenes in
charge of a gorgeous and erotic Chelo Alonso. Steve Reeves is cool as
the pirate hero who encounters dangerous situations while trying
retrieve his lover . Reeves acted as a corpulent hero in several
movies, starring historic and legendary characters, such as ¨Romulus¨
in Romulus and Remo ; ¨Phillipides¨ in Giant of Marathon; ¨Eneas¨in The
war of the Trojan and The horse of Trojan ; ¨Glaucus¨ in The last days
of Pompei and ¨Hercules¨ in the Queen of Lydia. The motion picture is
well directed by Andre De Toth and Primo Zeglio. Andre De Toth is a
classic director , Western habitual(Indian fighter, Man in the
saddle,Ramrod,Last of Comanches, The stranger wore a gun), but also
made Peplum(Gold for the Caesar, The Mongols).The film is partially based on historical events, as Henry John
Morgan(born Welsh 1635, dead Port Royal, Jamaica 1688) was a known
corsair , at death of pirate Edward Mansfield was appointed chief by
the buccaneers. He conquered Providence island or Saint Catalina. Later
he sacked the city of Panama, violating the truce between Spain and
England. For that reason was imprisoned , bu the king Charles II freed
him and named him governor of Jamaica.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10236499/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>limeres</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Along with "The Thief of Bagdad, one of Reeves' best flicks. It has a
great story, perfect casting, authentic locations, rousing action and
pretty music score. Reeves' presence and the strong romantic theme add
quite a bit of appeal to the genre. Check out the sword fight on
Tortuga Island, a classic. The whole family will love this.Having seen this flick at the Saturday matinée when I was an
impressionable young lad, it's hard to imagine anyone duplicating this
role in a more convincing way than Reeves, but someday perhaps
Hollywood will revisit the story of Morgan the Pirate, it's certainly
worthy of a remake, if they could find someone with half the presence
of Reeves to play the role.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1546152/comments</url><from>from Colorado Springs</from><name>TheVid</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This pirate vehicle for muscleman Reeves is an effective change of pace
from
his sword-and-sandal adventures, and similar to his heroic,
action-oriented
version of THE THIEF OF BAGHDAD.  The extraordinary participation of
Chelo
Alonso gives this minor epic a big boost, as she,
once again, provides a lively, exotic dance number amidst Steve's pec
flexing.  Enjoyable.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2568038/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>ptb-8</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw this in 1962 when I was 7 years old at a kids matinee in our
local crummy cinema THE EMPIRE  in the suburb of BOTANY in
SYDNEY AUSTRALIA. It made me the man I am today, with a completely mesmerising
afficianado for old cinemas and the use of colour in old
films.Years later it was re run with hilarous voice overs at late shows but
the film still was such good fun and quite well made that even
making fun of it didn't detract. It is actually quite good.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5031062/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>loufalce</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Before you write it off as just another el cheapo Italian made "peplum
epic", take the time to watch it.Reeves is in fine form in title role
and he does manage to create a believable character. The film is also
fairly factual in how he began his career and the raid on Spanish
controlled Panama at the end of the film actually happened in 1671.
Film features fine color photography, good atmosphere, and realistic
looking 17th. century costumes. There is a very exciting and well
staged sword duel on the beach, beautiful women {including the
voluptious Chelo Alonso} a great musical score and, for once the ships
are authentic looking life size replicas and not the usual bathtub toy
boats that too pirate movies feature. There's also a funny sequence
where Morgan's men-dressed as woman capture a Spanish treasure galleon.
I remember watching it on the Channel 9 "Million Dollar Movie" {in the
New York area} in the early 60s when it would be shown at 7.30 and
11.30 every weekday night for a week. I must have watched it 5 times!
It was a fun movie then. I recently got to see it on VHS and it is
still how I remembered it. Of course it does not have a "Pirates of the
Caribbean" budget, but it is not as overblown as those films. No
supernatural events or fantasy elements, just a well made and exciting
pirate film that delivers on all levels. Steve Reeves best role-even
when compared to "Hercules". His films are long overdue for a comeback.
I hope it happens soon! This guy really deserves it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0382004/comments</url><from>from CARDIFF, WALES</from><name>ALAN MOUNT</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This was one of the very best Steve Reeves movies and probably contained
his
best acting performance.Events in the life of the Welsh pirate who
eventually became governor of Panama are vividly brought to the screen by
veteran director Andre de Toth.The action sequences are frequent and quite
well staged and the swordfight on a beach with Reeves and a pirate rival is
at least 10 times more exciting than the so-called classic similar
duel(little more than a tussle really) between Flynn and Rathbone in
"CAPTAIN BLOOD".All in all,"MORGAN THE PIRATE" is a spirited romp and I was
pleased to find it so after seeing it again today for the first time since
1962.It is truly time that  Reeves and his movies are rediscovered and
appreciated by a new audience.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
***SPOILERS*** One of movie strongman Steve Reeves best and most
sensitive performances as the English pirate Henry Morgan. The daring
young man who took upon himself to destroy the Spanish Empire with his
band of jolly Roger Buccaneers in a series of hit and run battles on
land as well as at sea.Things didn't start off that good for Morgan with him being sold into
slavery by the Spanish after capturing him from a sunken English
galleon. It was Morgan's Greek-god like physique and good looks that
had the daughter of the Governor of Panama's daughter Dona Inez,
Valerie Iagrange, fall heads over heels for the big hunk by buying him
at a slave auction in town. Put in charge of the royal stable Morgan
made the mistake of getting a little too close, like enveloping her
with his massive arms, with Dona, a horse lover, when she went to see
the latest colt of her prized stallion. Condemmed to a life as a slave
rower on a Spanish galleon Morgan starts a mutiny among the slaves on
the boat who take it over throwing its Spanish crew overboard. Joing up
with the pirates on far off Torluga Island Morgan starts his personal
war against the Spanish using them and their ships as his attacking
naval task force.Non stop action with Captain Morgan causing havoc all across the
Caribbean for the Spanish with his hit and run tactics that has them or
the Governor of Panama Don Jose Guzman, Ivo Garrani, offer as much as
50,000 docket's, pieces of gold, for Morgan's head. During the action
Morgan's buccaneers capture the governor's daughter Dona Inez who start
to suffer for a serious case of Stockholm syndrome. Thats in Dona
falling madly in love with her capture Captain Morgan, whom she was
nuts about earlier in the movie before her capture, to the horror of
her outraged father Governoer Guzman who want's her boyfriend dead!In the end Morgan is double-crossed by his fellow Englishman and
comrade in arms Sir Thomas Modyford, Givlio Bosetti, who after signing
a secret peace treaty with the hated Spanish ratted out Morgan's
brilliant battle plan to attack Panama City from the west, Pacific
Ocean, not east, Atlantic Ocean, as the Spanish expected him to. With
his navy now at the bottom of the Caribbean Morgan whips his men into
action by launching a ground attack, with thousands of buccaneers,
using the local cattle as human, or animal, shields on the surprise
attack on Panama City. ***SPOILERS*** Action packed final with Morgan and his men breaching
the Panama City walls and having it out with the Governor's men on
their own turf making mincemeat out of them. Morgan himself gets a
bonus besides capturing Panama City, the richest city in the Americas,
by rescuing Dona who was being held against her will there by her pop
"The Gov" or Governor. And later, after the film "Morgan the Pirate was
over, Morgan would end up living out his final years as he Governor of
Panama City which he and his men captured from the Spanish.P.S I was at first surprised to see Steve Reeves' clean shaved but he
then grew his famous beard back within the first half hour of the
movie. It may have been the heat and humidity of the Caribbean that
cased Reeves to later again shave off his beard and never has it grow
back for the remainder of the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0893724/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name> (hans101067@altavista.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a good pirate film for kids.I don't think anybody,including
Reeves,thought that he was a great artist,but it's a fun picture.Vaguely
inspired by "Captain Blood",this has very little to do with the real Henry
Morgan.It also has aspects of "The Adventures of Robin Hood "as well.Chelo
Alonso,straight from her adventures in the Follies Bergere is simply
exquisite.A funny sequence has Reeves strip to the waist for a duel with
the
paunchy Armand Mestral,who,when viewing his rivals superb physique,shrugs
in
chagrin.Ripping good fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0893724/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name> (hans101067@altavista.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a good pirate film for kids.I don't think anybody,including
Reeves,thought that he was a great artist,but it's a fun picture.Vaguely
inspired by "Captain Blood",this has very little to do with the real Henry
Morgan.It also has aspects of "The Adventures of Robin Hood "as well.Chelo
Alonso,straight from her adventures in the Follies Bergere is simply
exquisite.A funny sequence has Reeves strip to the waist for a duel with
the
paunchy Armand Mestral,who,when viewing his rivals superb physique,shrugs
in
chagrin.Ripping good fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0893724/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name> (hans101067@altavista.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>