<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Era notte a Roma</original_title><alt_title>Les évadés de la nuit</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Roberto Rossellini</director><producer>International Goldstar</producer><producer>Dismage</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis/><actor>Giovanna Ralli</actor><actor>Renato Salvatori</actor><actor>Leo Genn</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4965002/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>tentender</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Can no one have seen this important Rossellini film? Astonishing it is
to be the first to comment in these "pages" on a work by one of the
major directors of world cinema (and for the second time -- no one else
had commented on "Vanina Vanini" either). Apparently this 145 minute
film (that is how it clocked in at the showing I attended) received
very little distribution, and, though it is excellent, it is not hard
to see why this was so. Its story of three Allied soldiers, one
English, one American, one Russian, on the loose in an
as-yet-unliberated Italy, is short on wild excitement, but filled with
interesting detail and human warmth. Giovanna Ralli is marvelous (and
would have been a marvelous Vanina Vanini, if only...) in a complex and
emotional role. Peter Baldwin and Renato Salvatori are winningly
handsome young men (and are rather lookalikes), and Leo Genn and Sergei
Bondarchuk provide solid acting. Rossellini's use of the zoom to make
possible "intercutting without cuts" is used to great effect in this
film, and the scene in which the spy/informer eavesdrops on the
confessional is especially masterful. One of Rossellini's last films
before he decided to devote himself exclusively to the small screen,
this film is sober, serious, worthy, and, withal, not lacking in value
as entertainment. Postscript: I've now had a chance two years later
(December 2008) to re-view this film, thanks to a new (and very
inexpensive) DVD region 1 release. My second viewing has led me to
revise (upward) my evaluation of this beautiful film. Yes, it's long,
and seems episodic, but, as in Chekhov's plays and (odd pairing, I
know) McCarey's "The Bells of St. Mary's," on second viewing the
connections between the episodes are profound and satisfying. The
Lionsgate DVD (paired with a second little-known Rossellini feature,
"Dov'e la liberta) is a real bargain (available for under $15). The
print appears better than that on the region 2 UK disc (see screen
captures at DVDBeaver.com), and, though the titles are in French (this
is a Franco-Italian co-production) the title itself is given in
Italian, unlike that on the UK version. Running time is 2:13.5,
compared to 2:08 and change on the region 2 disc (accounted for by the
PAL speedup). Subtitles are excellent and unusually thorough. My
previously stated running time of 145 is confirmed by Jose Luis
Guarnier within the text of his Praeger Film Library monograph from
1970 (though his filmography gives 120 minutes!) There is a strange
mis-match in the editing in the first attic scene, which may indicate
some foul play. I can't recall any specific missing scene, though.
Details aside, this really is a great film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
An user complained that Rossellini's movies are overlooked today;he is
completely right.Although the Italian New Wave was never so hard and so
nasty as their French counterpart on former colleagues,it nevertheless
cast a shadow over them.On the European board ,there are plenty of
messages about Fellini,Antonioni,Pasolini (and Godard,Truffaut ,Rohmer
and co)whereas Rossellini (and De Sica,the great Luigi Comencini)are
almost always absent.He also complained about the cuts in Rossellini's works;however,what
was intolerable in "Vanina Vanini" (the first part of which is
thoroughly incomprehensible) is not so important in "Era Notte a Roma"
. My copy has a running time of about 130 min and that's enough,for I
think that it's overlong and even full of filler."Era Notte" tells the story of three escaped prisoners during WW2: a
Russian,an English and an American.It's also the story of an Italian
girl who helps the peasants to get rid of their burdensome guests in
exchange for food.She's not a resistance fighter (as his fiancé is) but
she will prove herself very human in spite of her weakness.Rossellini displays respect for the audience: every character speaks
his own language ,which gives the movie much more substance than ,for
instance ," Uomo della croce " in which everyone spoke Italian.My
favorite scene is the Christmas celebration with a very moving "Auld
Lang Syne" sung by people from four different countries.It cannot be
considered one of Rossellini 's masterworks but its several moments of
brilliance make it a must for Rossellini's fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12654879/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>simon-1303</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I like a lot of Rossellini, but there is the odd clinker. Here's why:it's not sure if it's propaganda, documentary or drama, or all three ;
it's set in a blackout, so it's more unrelieved grey than black and
white; it's largely set in tenement garrets, though some odd scenes
elsewhere; there are few attractive compositions, except repeated shots
of the Rome skyline; it has national clichés instead of characters:
impulsive American, reserved Brit, bad German, good German, bad
fascist, emotional Italian etc. ; the characters enter and leave the
film almost at random ; the dramatic scenes aren't, they stop and start
abruptly and are poorly linked; plot developments seem to come out of
nowhere; the interesting things often happen off screen; characters'
behaviour is often reckless to the point of incredulity.Apparently rewritten, screenplayed, edited and scored on the hoof, with
a great deal of family involvement,and I'm afraid it shows. sorry for
being so negative.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14241946/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>parsifalssister</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Although it has its faults, as described in the review above, it is
also a complex, intelligent document of the war. With Rome as a
symbolic backdrop, three POWs arrive into the safe, but reluctant arms
of a smuggler, and hide during an unspecified time just before the
Allies reach the City.All of the characters speak in their own tongue, which is the
complicated part, but it is not without its sense of authenticity in
the circumstances. But even with these language and cultural barriers,
the main characters create several dynamic exchanges.The pace is slow; the color bleak; the dialog often abbreviated; the
relationships in doubt; yet, ultimately, we come to understand the
forest of emotion we all experience during crisis, and war is among the
most severe of crises.The Italian female lead is engaging and the British Major congenial.
The Italians are splendid as both collaborator and rescuer. The Germans
play a less significant role, but they remain the fodder for how
choices are made of who will live or die, even as the war draws near to
the end.The last 20 minutes are spellbinding as those choices are crystallized
and strengthened by honesty, integrity and treachery.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14241946/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>parsifalssister</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Although it has its faults, as described in the review above, it is
also a complex, intelligent document of the war. With Rome as a
symbolic backdrop, three POWs arrive into the safe, but reluctant arms
of a smuggler, and hide during an unspecified time just before the
Allies reach the City.All of the characters speak in their own tongue, which is the
complicated part, but it is not without its sense of authenticity in
the circumstances. But even with these language and cultural barriers,
the main characters create several dynamic exchanges.The pace is slow; the color bleak; the dialog often abbreviated; the
relationships in doubt; yet, ultimately, we come to understand the
forest of emotion we all experience during crisis, and war is among the
most severe of crises.The Italian female lead is engaging and the British Major congenial.
The Italians are splendid as both collaborator and rescuer. The Germans
play a less significant role, but they remain the fodder for how
choices are made of who will live or die, even as the war draws near to
the end.The last 20 minutes are spellbinding as those choices are crystallized
and strengthened by honesty, integrity and treachery.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/escapebynight.htm /m/era_notte_a_roma/comments.php?reviewid=1964962</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>Stylishly filmed in black-and-white, and effectively mixes together neorealism, film noir and didactic lessons in patriotism.</comment></review></movie>