<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Private Lives of Adam and Eve</original_title><alt_title>La vie privée d'Adam et Ève</alt_title><imdb_rating>3.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Mickey Rooney</director><producer>Albert Zugsmith Productions</producer><producer>Fryman Enterprises</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>It's Fantabulous!</synopsis><actor>Mickey Rooney</actor><actor>Mamie Van Doren</actor><actor>Fay Spain</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0683496/comments</url><from>from Adelaide, Australia</from><name>MuggySphere</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

I don't care what everyone else said but I liked this film.Sure it's silly with the dream sequence in the middle andalternates between black and white and color, but it's
god
a sense of fun about it. It's also got some really nice
looking
ladies and Eve manages to walk in a skirt that looks almost
too
tight to fit into. LOL.....  Sure the film didn't win or for that matter deserve to win
awards
for production or such but it's fun.... I had fun watching it
and
it just felt like there was a sense of fun in the story.6/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0293302/comments</url><from>from Long Beach, Ca</from><name>Kenny-36</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
It's been years since I saw this movie, but I thought it was wonderful.
It's about a group of travelers that get stranded in a storm and start
talking about the creations with each traveler becoming a character in
the creation. While there's some religious overtones this is a comedy
and playing the devil is Mickey Rooney. The Devil (Rooney) trying to
get Adam and Eve to take a bite of the apple. Dressed as the snake, his
tail splashing in the water of a river and then dressed as an umpire. I
can't remember what was said, I just remember I was laughing a lot and
it was late at night. If you have the chance I suggest you watch this,
it's worth your time. As it was said above this movie didn't win any
awards, but I liked it and would buy it if they put it on DVD.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6663146/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>afainca75</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie when I was 6 or 7 and it enchanted my young mind. In
my polluted older age mind the enchantment remains. (I would love to
see it again, but I can't find it anywhere.) I recall that several
people are on a bus and have to stop and take refuge in a church on the
side of the road because of a severe thunderstorm. They spend the night
in the church and one of the people on the bus has a dream about the
Garden of Eden. Some of the people on the bus are characters in the
dream; Mickey Rooney, the bus driver, is the devil. If anyone who reads
this knows how I can get a copy of it, please email me with the
information - afainca75@hotmail.com.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0827419/comments</url><from>from California</from><name>laffinsal</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This is one of the very strangest films I have ever seen. Several travelers
are en route to Reno, when thunderstorm causes them to take refuge in an
abandoned church. Falling asleep, the two leads dream they are Adam and Eve
in the garden of Eden. The "Eden" sequence, up until the "expulsion" is in
color. The first twenty minutes of the film are actually pretty decent, and
seem to build up to something good, but the dream sequence in "Eden" is
just
too silly for words. The sight of Mickey Rooney playing the Devil in a
padded snake suit is alone worth watching the film for. Paul Anka sings the
theme song and has a rather minor role in the film. Also noteworthy is
Tuesday Weld who does not appear in the dream sequence, but who sparkles
during her screen time. The film ends with Eve requesting a pickle from Ad.
A definite must-see!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1163639/comments</url><from>from mission, ks</from><name>eminges</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

This movie is so wrong on so many levels: Paul Anka opens sitting on his
$400 hot rod and steering with his feet, Martin Milner and Mamie Van Doren
walk into the closing credits with all their marital problems solved on her
announcement that she's pregnant, sanitized by her expressing a desire to
eat pickles.  In between lies a virtual encyclopedia of every snickering,
simpering, leering last-gasp-of-the-fifties nudge-nudge battle-of-the-sexes
cliche', somehow made all the worse by strictly G-rated language and less
exposed flesh than an Iranian quilting bee.Anyone ever caught expressing the slightest nostalgia for anything about the
Fifties except beatniks and early rockers should be strapped down, Prisoner
655321 style, and forced to watch alternating showings of this excrescence
and Sex Kittens Go to College.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Very peculiar comedy is alternately clever and lame... but ultimately
it succeeds in providing some mild amusement. It's hard to fathom why
it was so soundly condemned in its day, perhaps making a surreal comic
travesty out of part of the Bible was just too far ahead of its time.
It is certainly far less irreverent than "The Life of Brian." Some
sequences (such as the devil's playing piano and having a barbecue) may
have provided the inspiration for such scenes as the Herod scene in
"Jesus Christ, Superstar." Another thing that might have irritated the
bluestockings is the fact that Adam, Eve, and Lillith are definitely
hot, Milner looking better out of his clothes than he ever looked in
them. It's kind of like a sexy, live action Flinstones, altogether
harmless and amusing. Catch the cave scene where A&amp;E quarrel over
moving the boulders (furniture)and the one in which the devil convinces
Eve to cut her long hair (strategically pasted to her breasts) only to
reveal a leaf -pattern bra underneath! It's full of little comic gems
and some funny dialog regarding the pair's living conditions and social
standing. Eve: "If I had a mother, I'd go home to her!" Adam: "Don't be
silly...I AM your mother!"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14623715/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ockid44</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie as a kid and I cannot remember much about it. But I do
remember Mickey Rooney and I thought he was hilarious. I remember
Milner playing Adam. I remembered him because he starred in TV series
Route 66.The movie caught my attention as a child because I went to church
regular and I was very familiar with the Biblical Adam and Eve story.Like I stated, I cannot remember much but I have always wanted to see
the movie again. It was corny but fun.I would love to buy a copy of it to see if the movie would be just as
funny as it was years ago.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2950940/comments</url><from>from Denver, Colorado and Santiago, Chile</from><name>lazarillo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a VERY strange movie, co-directed by cult director Albert
Zugsmith and actor Mickey Rooney, that was barely released back in the
day and has never appeared on legitimate home video. The "frame" story
involves a motley assortment of characters taking a bus trip to Reno,
Nevada when they're cut off by a flash flood and have to take refuge in
a church. The movie then slips (for no apparent reason) into a long
"Wizard of Oz"-type dream sequence where two of the characters,
conveniently named "Adam" () and "Eve" (Mamie Van Doren), re-live the
Garden of Eden adventures of their namesakes, with two other
passengers, a loud-mouth promoter (Mickey Rooney) and his sultry wife
(Fay Spain), becoming, respectively, "Satan" and his consort "Lilith".
(Va-va-voom actress/model June Wilkinson also appears as another female
minion of Satan).The Garden of Eden story is a lot more goofy than funny, the heights of
the (mostly unintentional) hilarity reached when Rooney appears in a
snake costume, which kind of looks like a bad papier-mache snake has
unsuccessfully tried to swallow a chubby, washed-up child actor. What's
particularly strange though is that the Garden of Eden sequence only
utilizes four of the eight passengers on the bus. Paul Anka is
apparently only there to warble a couple of lame songs. But "the Velvet
Fog" himself, Mel Torme, is completely wasted both as an actor and a
singer. You wouldn't think you'd really need a sixteen-year-old Tuesday
Weld (playing a teen runaway) when you have Van Doren, Spain, and June
Wilkinson in the cast, but even in an abortive role, the vixenish Weld
manages to out-sexy--and definitely out-act--all of her older, more
voluptuous co-stars (SHE should have played Eve). Then there's the
elderly but lecherous bus driver who narrates everything (and says at
one point of Weld's character, "They used to call her 'bobby socks',
but now they call her 'baby sex'").I didn't find this completely un-entertaining just because of the
unusual cast and just because it's so damn weird. It's definitely a
throw-back to a bye-gone era when the mostly male movie audience was an
unapologetic mixture of chauvinists, big-breast fetishists, and dirty
old men. Ah, the good old days!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17271122/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>unclebuzz1966</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
For years this was panned as a turkey (including Leonard Maltin's Movie
Guide which awarded this trip to Eden the infamous BOMB!) I have a
great fondness for this completely whacked, fantasy-adult comedy.
First, the film opens with what appears to be the trailer for the film
but is actually a funky introductory segment. Then we launch right into
Paul Anka's opening title track - which is a swinging little number.
The film makes no bones that this is intended to be an "adult comedy"
with loads of double entendres and Mickey's leering, over-the-top
portrayal of Nick Lewis a.k.a. "the Devil." But the true fruits are to
be savored in producer Albert Zugsmith's Eden where the fabulous Mamie
Van Doren strolls the garden in the tiniest fig leaf bikini yet seen in
an American studio release. (And this was two years before Ursula
Andress' famous bikini intro. from "Dr. NO.") I just wish Universal
would re-strike a new print for DVD release because the current copies
yield a Spectracolor that has turned, much like Eve's apple, bloody
red. "Adam and Eve" is a pleasure - albeit a guilty one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1410530/comments</url><from>from San Pablo, CA</from><name>spost8260</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
So this movie is silly? It has plenty of charm and light heartedness!
It's innocent and funny. It's really worth a look especially if you're
a (female) Martin Milner fan! You can find this on video currently at
www.thevideobeat.com It was worth the purchase because it had been so
long since I had seen it and it was only more charming since I've
become older. Mickey Rooney as the devil? Can you imagine Andy Hardy in
a padded snake suit? I found that extremely hilarious, just that alone!
I'm not really a fan of Mamie Van Doren, so her part is difficult to
watch (though I'm sure she would be a sight for the male audience). All
in all, the cast is excellent, the story is sweet. I honestly can't
understand why the decency brigade tagged it...I know things were
strict growing up, but there's really nothing dirty at all about
it...unless you have a really filthy mind?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1410530/comments</url><from>from San Pablo, CA</from><name>spost8260</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
So this movie is silly? It has plenty of charm and light heartedness!
It's innocent and funny. It's really worth a look especially if you're
a (female) Martin Milner fan! You can find this on video currently at
www.thevideobeat.com It was worth the purchase because it had been so
long since I had seen it and it was only more charming since I've
become older. Mickey Rooney as the devil? Can you imagine Andy Hardy in
a padded snake suit? I found that extremely hilarious, just that alone!
I'm not really a fan of Mamie Van Doren, so her part is difficult to
watch (though I'm sure she would be a sight for the male audience). All
in all, the cast is excellent, the story is sweet. I honestly can't
understand why the decency brigade tagged it...I know things were
strict growing up, but there's really nothing dirty at all about
it...unless you have a really filthy mind?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1410530/comments</url><from>from San Pablo, CA</from><name>spost8260</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>