<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La dolce vita</original_title><alt_title>La douceur de vivre</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Federico Fellini</director><producer>Riama Film</producer><producer>Gray-Film</producer><producer>Pathé Consortium Cinéma</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Journalist and man-about-town Marcello struggles to find his place in the world, torn between the allure...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Marcello Mastroianni</actor><actor>Anita Ekberg</actor><actor>Anouk Aimée</actor><rt_rating>9.1/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>98</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0455019/comments</url><from>from Out there in the dark</from><name>mackjay</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
LA DOLCE VITA is an episodic film, but that is a feature of much of
Fellini. In several of his films, Fellini builds meaning in this way:
not with a single continuing plot, but with a series of smaller stories
that add up to a total collection of interconnected ideas.Maybe the secret (if there is one) of LA DOLCE VITA's appeal is that
it's so darned interesting all the time. This especially applies to the
plot concerning Steiner. Steiner is the key figure in the film, apart
from Marcello himself, who is Fellini's and the viewer's counterpart.
What Steiner represents to Marcello is of prime importance. The young
reporter sees the older man as a perfected, idealized version of
himself. He longs to emulate Steiner and is convinced this man knows
how to live life fully. There is irony aplenty in the entire Steiner
narrative. When Marcello brings his wife to the Steiner party, they
meet a few interesting, but mostly insufferable pretentious
'intellectual' types. (the famous Fellini 'careless' post-dubbing of
dialogue in this scene particularly amusing: it seems to add to these
characters' disconnection from a true self, as though they don't even
realize what they are actually saying). Steiner himself associates with
these people, yet does not truly seem to be one of them. He feels
trapped by his own pretentious circle of intellectuals. When Marcello
tell him how much he envies and admires him, Steiner replies:"Don't be like me. Salvation doesn't lie within four walls. I'm too
serious to be a dilettante and too much a dabbler to be a professional.
Even the most miserable life is better than a sheltered existence in an
organized society where everything is calculated and perfected."This gives Marcello much to contemplate for the rest of the film. And
Steiner's subsequent suicide confirms the deep suspicion growing within
the protagonist that all of existence, as he himself has known it thus
far, is fundamentally absurd and meaningless. For this reason the film
is existential in its outlook. Marcello is the modern, urban human,
trapped in an absurd universe. But Fellini, seems not fully despairing
in his outlook. Consider, for example, the significance of Marcello's
interaction with the blonde girl in the cafe--she represents a simpler
life away from the city and the over-complications of modern existence.
Many viewers have missed the fact that it is this same girl who waves
to Marcello on the beach in the film's final scene: she waves and is
telling something he is never able to hear, so he waves once, and turns
back to the empty, inebriated crowd as they speculate about the
unknowability of nature, embodied by a monstrous, bloated fish.LA DOLCE VITA is a great film for the way it pulls some viewers in and
forces them to contemplate the actual content of what they are seeing.
The main theme is one it shares with films of Antonioni: modern man has
become disconnected from the natural world and he suffers because of
it. LA DOLCE VITA's visual style is poetic, some of its characters are
more than compelling and hard to forget, and its musical score by Nino
Rota is among the most memorable of all time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1531451/comments</url><from>from usa</from><name>shoolaroon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I first saw this movie probably over 25 years ago when I was quite a bit
younger.  At that point I enjoyed it for its party scenes, sense of joy
and
life and vitality and....Marcello Mastroianni.  Now that I'm older myself
and have just recently seen the movie again, I find that I have a much
deeper understanding of it.  Maybe it takes some age to find some meaning.
In a nutshell, Marcello is at a crossroads in his life, he's unable to
settle down or move foreward into any direction - he's a diletante with
aspirations but no real goals.  He's wrapped up in himself and in
projecting
rather dreamy ideals onto other people.  But as he keeps projecting on to
others he comes to find in each situation that he doesn't really know the
person and they are a mystery and probably a disappointment to him.
certainly steiner is the biggest disappointment and disillusions him to a
degree that he is apparently lost to a life of corruption and decadence as
a
result.  but it's not that these people are difficult to understand to
someone other than marcello - i think we can see that anita ekberg's
character really is just a big good-natured blond and not the mysterious
goddess marcello makes her out to be; his father is again - the typical
traveling salesman and perhaps not the paternal figure that marcello would
like him to be. his amour maddelena lives up to her name even as marcello
starts believing himself in love with her - he's literally seduced by
nothing more than an image he creates in his own mind. his friend steiner
seems to have it all to marcello and to be the renaissance man that he
would
like to be - but, of course, he is dissatisfied and disturbed and we see
what the end is.  the only one whom marcello forms a somewhat realistic
connection with is his girlfriend whom he treats badly and neglects
despite
her obvious love for him.  he refuses to actually work on the one
relationship that he could actually succeed at - he would rather dream
about
possibilities than actualize something.marcello cannot communicate with others because he cannot see them as the
people they really are - he just sees them as projections of his own
needs,
aspirations, desires and goals.  when he finds out what they're really
like,
he either turns away or falls apart. this is an outstanding movie - 10 out
of 10 and beautifully photographed.  if you don't get it now, try again in
10 years - it will wait for you to catch up.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0852256/comments</url><from>from Charlottesville, Virginia</from><name>Mark (mhh3f)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

To appreciate this film you need to appreciate film.  I'm saddened that so
many have commented negatively on it and cast dispersions upon those who
enjoyed it.  It is not Titanic, or Armageddon.  It is a long film that
attempts to show more than a hackneyed plot about some simple people.  It is
a beautiful exploration about life that does not preach or try to tell you
what to think.  I understand why many are frustrated with it.  It seems to
go nowhere at times, but thats the point.  And most importantly the scenery
on this trip to nowhere is beautiful.So, if you are the type that does not like to watch films that are art, do
not watch this.  Watch Coyote Ugly.  It will entertain you.  Other films to
avoid:  Last Year at Marienbad, The Seventh Seal, The 400 Blows, etc.  Go
see something with a gun on the cover instead.For those who like a challenge rather than simple escapism, this is a film
that engages you.Different films for different people.  People seem very threatened when they
don't like a film that is widely regarded as a classic.  The reason is
simple, it's not your kind of film.  But don't assume its a film for no one.
Makes sense right?

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0323948/comments</url><from>from Dobbs Ferry, NY</from><name>Robert Hirschfeld (boberich@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I just saw a new print of this wonderful film after not having seen it
for maybe 20 years and it is still spellbinding. Fellini sums up an era
and an attitude here, and succeeds in doing something that ought to be
impossible: he makes a full and meaningful film about empty and
meaningless lives. Mastroianni seems to have been to Fellini what
DeNiro has been to Scorsese--a perfect embodiment of a personal vision.
What a wonderful actor he was--brilliant in his youth and in his age.
Many other performers are hardly less fine here, and the cinematography
and composition are stunning throughout. There are so many indelible
images from this film, images that have become iconic over the decades:
Ekberg in the Fontana di Trevi, the statue of Christ flying over Rome,
the astonishing, candlelit procession at the castle, to name a few. It
seems plot less and yet it isn't plot less at all; Marcello's ultimately
fruitless search for meaning, a search that he abandons in the end, as
he stares across a slight and yet unbridgable abyss on the beach at a
lovely young girl who seems to possess the knowledge and understanding
that is denied to him. I'm astonished at the number of people who don't
get this movie, who seem to think that Fellini expects us to admire the
bizarre characters who people the film, or who think that a movie about
worthless individuals must be a worthless movie, or who don't seem to
understand that movies that are full of what become clichés usually do
so because they capture an important vision. Fellini made several
exceptional films: 81/2, La Strada, Amarcord, and The Nights of Cabiria
come to mind, but La Dolce Vita may be, when all is said and done, his
masterwork.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1592694/comments</url><from>from Biloxi, Mississippi</from><name>gftbiloxi (gftbiloxi@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
LA DOLCE VITA presents a series of incidents in the life of Roman
tabloid reporter Marcello Rubini (Marcello Mastroianni)--and although
each incident is very different in content they create a portrait of an
intelligent but superficial man who is gradually consumed by "the sweet
life" of wealth, celebrity, and self-indulgence he reports on and which
he has come to crave.Although the film seems to be making a negative statement about
self-indulgence that leads to self-loathing, Fellini also gives the
viewer plenty of room to act as interpreter, and he cleverly plays one
theme against its antithesis throughout the film. (The suffocation of
monogamy vs. the meaninglessness of promiscuity and sincere religious
belief vs. manipulative hypocrisy are but two of the most obvious
juxtapositions.) But Fellini's most remarkable effect here is his
ability to keep us interested in the largely unsympathetic characters
LA DOLCE VITA presents: a few are naive to the point of stupidity; most
are vapid; the majority (including the leads) are unspeakably
shallow--and yet they still hold our interest over the course of this
three hour film.The cast is superior, with Marcello Mastroianni's personal charm
particularly powerful. As usual with Fellini, there is a lot to look at
on the screen: although he hasn't dropped into the wild surrealism for
which he was sometimes known, there are quite a few surrealistic
flourishes and visual ironies aplenty--the latter most often supplied
by the hordes of photographers that scuttle after the leading
characters much like cockroaches in search of crumbs. For many years
available to the home market in pan-and-scan only, the film is now in a
letterbox release that makes it all the more effective. Strongly
recommended.Gary F. Taylor, aka GFT, Amazon Reviewer
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0923228/comments</url><from>from brasil (giras@ig.com.br)</from><name>guimo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

(first of all, sorry my poor english)
Who, in this entire world, drunk as a horse in the middle of the night,
never discovered the meaning of life, that it can be so easy and joyfull
that hurts.
This happens with a certain frequency. The big problem is, after all that,
to face all the thoughts and conclusions in a sober monday morning, when
everything is just real, concious and above all that sincere.
This is the the big question and problem of Marcello Rubini, a reporter of
a
gossip magazines who has to deal with the fact that he tastes the same
poison he spreads by leaving in a group of people which he sucks his
living.In a moment he is directing his papparazzi and, in the next, he is running
away from them.
He flows between all kinds of social circles and the only impression he
gives is that it doesnt matter what kind of craziness you are getting into
everything is a big cliché. From the mainstream world of a gorgeous
actress
who feels able to express opinions about everything (and we buy it),
passing
throught the religious world of the faith, and also an intellectual circle
that gives a fake impression of freedom, everything turns out to be an
escape.
That blonde girl appears as a stroke of pureness and sincereness,
something
we should really look for, but we just dont.
In the case of Marcello's life, writing is the solutions he always
substitute for vain experiences. Something he likes and that he needs a
young girl to tell him that.
That litlle cute girl is a person Marcello would like to be, someone who
faces the soberty of a monday morning with hopeness and
happiness.A masterpiece.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Long considered a major filmmaker, Federico Fellini established his
reputation through an insistence on the interest-value of his own
fantastic and idiosyncratic vision of the world… In so doing, however,
he repeatedly lays himself open to charges of egomania, self-indulgence
and superficiality; certainly much of his work, if visually
extraordinary, is hyperbolic, naïve and incoherent…This film about the hedonistic, amoral life of Rome's "beautiful
people" is really a series of startling episodes held together by a
character played by Marcello Mastroianni, a gossip columnist who is
himself caught up in the aimless, scandalous "sweet life."Filled, like all Fellini films, with stunning, bizarre images and faces
and marked by the director's wild comic imagination, the film was
widely condemned as "vulgar, witless, and intellectually bankrupt" and
lavishly praised as "a cultural and social document, as well as an
exciting entertainment.""La Dolce Vita" moves from one shocking sequence to another… It is a
sprawling epic satire on what Fellini considered the spiritual malaise
of modern society… It followed a journalist employed by a scandal
magazine around a Rome obsessed with orgiastic parties, voluptuous film
stars and the commercial marketing of religion… While its images are
flamboyant—a statue of Christ flying above Rome suspended from a
helicopter, Anita Ekberg dancing in the Trevi fountain, a kitten on her
head—the film's despairing tone often rings meaningless, even though
Mastroanni's compulsive womanizer, never glamorized, fails to achieve
redemption…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0736738/comments</url><from/><name>drednm</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Long, episodic film by Federico Fellini about the conceits and facades
of life: fame, intellect, sex, friendship, despair, innocence, etc.Marcello Mastroianni is perfect as the shallow tabloid reporter who
joyfully follows around Rome a blonde movie star from Sweden (Anita
Ekberg) as she prowls around the city's bars and bistros. He is also
having an affair with a woman (Anouk Aimee) while his girl friend
(Yvonne Furnaux) seems to be going nuts.But as Marcello moves through the city following the movie star, the
miracle of the virgin, a few parties, etc. we see that his life is very
empty because the things he reports on are meaningless drivel. We see
that fame and fortune and the trappings of success are meaningless.Marcello starts to realize that the movie star is a vapid airhead, the
miracles are a sham, and his friend's (who seemed quite happily
married) ghastly murder and suicide show the futility of life itself.The Fellini themes are common to many of his films, but what makes La
Dolce Vita so memorable are the cynical tone, the Nina Rota music, and
the string of terrific visual images.The opening scene is of a helicopter hauling a gilded plaster statue
through the air across Rome. The flying saint is a bizarre image but
serves to set up the movies which is all about images and events that
are never what they seem to be.Notable are the scenes of statuesque Ekberg in that terrific strapless
black dress with the voluminous skirts as she swishes around dancing
and eventually wading through a city fountain. The party scenes are
also notable. The first because of the intolerable intellectuals who
sits around and talk and talk but never do anything. The last party has
the indelible image of Mastroianni "riding" a drunken blonde woman as
though she were a horse. The final image of the giant dead fish is
quite unsettling as it symbolizes their bloated lives.Fellini is brilliant in filling scenes with odd people as extras,
usually hideously dressed or wearing ugly glasses. The "gallery" of
people who inhabit the city is one of grotesques, vapid fashion slaves,
the rich, hangers on, etc.A long film, but highly recommended and very memorable.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2420383/comments</url><from>from Dallas, Texas</from><name>Lechuguilla</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Mostly because of the terrific high contrast, B&amp;W visuals, and the
evocative music, this is the only Fellini film I have seen that I have
somewhat enjoyed. I recommend it, but not without reservations. It's a
complex film with many textured layers of meaning. And, in typical
Fellini fashion, it rambles and it meanders.Deviating from standard three-Act structure, Fellini's story consists
of roughly eight episodes, all starting at night and ending at dawn,
more or less. Each has its own crisis. And the only thing that unites
these episodes into a coherent whole is the story's protagonist,
Marcello (Marcello Mastroianni). In his job as a journalist and overall
observer of human nature, Marcello encounters people in high society
who seem outwardly happy and self-fulfilled. On closer examination,
however, these people are empty, hollow, alienated, emotionally adrift
and vacant.A good example is the starlet Sylvia (Anita Ekberg), a glamorous
figure, but she's all image and no substance. "La dolce vita" is the
first film that uses the concept of "paparazzi", which implies the
importance of "image", separate from substance.Throughout the various episodes Marcello sees these "images" of
happiness, of contentment, but the images are deceptive, elusive,
unreliable. In one episode, two "miracle" children "see" the Madonna.
"The Madonna is over there", shouts one child. The crowd chases after
her. But the other child who "sees" the Madonna runs in the opposite
direction. Happiness, self-fulfillment, religious visions ... they're
all a will-o'-the-wisp. And so, the film conveys a sense of pessimism
and cynicism.The film thus has deep thematic value. It caused a scandal when it was
released, and was banned by the Catholic Church, apparently for
appearing to be anti-religious.Yet for all its deep meaning, "La dolce vita" can be a trial to sit
through. Somewhere in the second half I began to lose interest. I don't
have a problem with Fellini's deviation from standard plot structure. I
do have a problem with a director who doesn't know when to quit. This
film goes on for almost three hours. A good edit, to delete all the
fat, would have tightened up the story and rendered it more potent. As
is, it's too strung out, too stretched, too meandering.If the viewer can persevere, there's enormous cinematic art in this
film. And helped along by Nino Rota's music, the film is wonderfully
evocative, at times stylishly melancholy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1570107/comments</url><from>from Lao People's Democratic Republic</from><name>damien-16</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I've seen this film regularly since 1971.  In theatres, on TV, on video,
on
DVD.  It doesn't age.  If anybody ever needed proof that Fellini was a
genius, this is it. La dolce vita remains the most touching statement
about
the human condition I ever saw on film.  Everybody remembers the
magic-realistic image of Anita Ekberg in the Trevi fountain, and a truly
amazing image it is.  But the film is much more than a slightly
surrealistic
sketchbook of emotionally empty jet setters. It is more existentialist
than
any book by Sartre or Camus.  The final sequence is simply devastating.
We
are all Marcello.  Since over 30 years this is my number-one
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1570107/comments</url><from>from Lao People's Democratic Republic</from><name>damien-16</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I've seen this film regularly since 1971.  In theatres, on TV, on video,
on
DVD.  It doesn't age.  If anybody ever needed proof that Fellini was a
genius, this is it. La dolce vita remains the most touching statement
about
the human condition I ever saw on film.  Everybody remembers the
magic-realistic image of Anita Ekberg in the Trevi fountain, and a truly
amazing image it is.  But the film is much more than a slightly
surrealistic
sketchbook of emotionally empty jet setters. It is more existentialist
than
any book by Sartre or Camus.  The final sequence is simply devastating.
We
are all Marcello.  Since over 30 years this is my number-one
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1570107/comments</url><from>from Lao People's Democratic Republic</from><name>damien-16</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/wesley-lovell/</url><url>http://www.cinemasight.com/review-la-dolce-vita-1960/ /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=2003840</url><name>Wesley Lovell</name><from>Oscar Guy</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>A lovely Italian palette that questions if we can settle down to a life of struggle without having first lived life at its best.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/matthew-connolly/</url><url>http://www.slantmagazine.com/film/review/la-dolce-vita/5551 /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1989624</url><name>Matthew Connolly</name><from>Slant Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>What is happiness within the film's world? Fellini offers no easy answers. </comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-fear/</url><url>http://newyork.timeout.com/arts-culture/film/1488885/la-dolce-vita /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1988998</url><name>David Fear</name><from>Time Out New York</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Everything has changed, and nothing has changed. How sour it still is.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rick-mele/</url><url>http://www.askmen.com/entertainment/movie/la-dolce-vita.html?t=1266435143 /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1871349</url><name>Rick Mele</name><from>AskMen.com</from></reviewer><rating>
93/100
					</rating><comment>Along with his later 8 1/2, La Dolce Vita is regarded as one of acclaimed Italian director Federico Fellini's best-loved and most influential films. The '60s-set tale of one man's struggle with the so-called "sweet life" stars Marcello Mastroi</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>http://www.colesmithey.com/capsules/2009/04/la-dolce-vita.html /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1815806</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>Daily Radar</from></reviewer><rating>
A+
					</rating><comment>The satire on display is so simultaneously subtle yet blatant that the movie itself is intoxicating.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fran-hortop/</url><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102866&amp;section=review&amp;page=all#reviewnav /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1814073</url><name>Fran Hortop</name><from>Film4</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>In spite of its thematic ugliness, this is a stunning-looking trawl through the Italian capital, with Ekberg's impromptu paddle in the Trevi fountain still the films enduring image.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pablo-villaca/</url><url>/m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1812453</url><name>Pablo Villaca</name><from>Cinema em Cena</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Mágico e inesquecível, representa não apenas um fascinante estudo de personagem, mas também um mergulho dilacerante na fragilidade humana. E Ekberg tornou-se, para sempre, uma das maiores personificações de sensualidade oferecidas pelo Cinema.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/ladolcevita.htm /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1653349</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>It's winsome because of the stylish cinematography, which fills the screen with mind-blowing bizarre visuals.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/dolce_vita/articles/1638858/experienced_as_a_series_of_bizarre_vignettes_a_headlong_rush_into_the_heady_air_of_romes_via_veneta__its_swank_nightclubs_and_seedy_gigolos_the_perfume_of_fame_and_the_stink_of_money/ /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1638858</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
94/100
					</rating><comment>...experienced as a series of bizarre vignettes, a headlong rush into the heady air of Rome's Via Veneta , its swank nightclubs and seedy gigolos, the perfume of fame and the stink of money.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/shawn-levy/</url><url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/109611339371980.xml /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1630920</url><name>Shawn Levy</name><from>Oregonian</from></reviewer><comment>Films don't get more essential than this.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117790493.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1630919</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>Perhaps many spectators will squirm at the three-hour length of the film or of some of its sequences (though director Federico Fellini cut some 30 minutes from his final print), yet others will never notice they've sat that long.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/2801_DOLCE_VITA /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1630918</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>The film was hugely successful and widely praised in its time, though it's really nothing more than the old C.B. De Mille formula of titillation and moralizing.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-villarreal/</url><url>http://www.azstarnet.com/allheadlines/159530.php /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1561828</url><name>Phil Villarreal</name><from>Arizona Daily Star</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>Federico Fellini's "La Dolce Vita" operates on so many levels that it's tough to know where Fellini is coming from or where he's headed, regardless of how many times you've watched his film.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://online.tvguide.com/newsearch/detail.aspx?tvobjectid=103408&amp;more=ucmoviereview /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1535186</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>After what we've seen of decadence during the past three decades or so, La Dolce Vita now seems tame, but people wasting time in nightclubs, dancing in the fountains of Rome, and just generally hanging out seemed a bit of a shock in 1960.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/65620/la_dolce_vita.html /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1475799</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>There are perhaps a couple of party scenes too many, and the peripheral characters can be unconvincing, but the stylish cinematography and Fellini's bizarre, extravagant visuals are absolutely riveting.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/la-dolce-vita-2/ /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1407019</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>Made at the peak of Fellini's career, La Dolce Vita provided the first look into Rome's decadent cafe society, boasting superlative performances from Marcello Mastroianni, Anouk Aimee, Anita Ekberg, and others.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>http://www.somethoughtson3daysofthecondor.com/reviews/la_dolce_vita.htm /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1401143</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>F5 (Wichita, KS)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>My heart wants to tell you that it's a great film, but my head fights it. I can settle it by saying that it's important, and that its joys outnumber its missteps.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ethan-alter/</url><url>http://www.nycfilmcritic.com/display_film.php?id=122 /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1367013</url><name>Ethan Alter</name><from>NYC Film Critic</from></reviewer><rating>
4.5/5
					</rating><comment>This remains a landmark movie that should be seen by every self-respecting movie buff.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1349991</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Primo Fellini!</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steven-snyder/</url><url>http://movies.zertinet.com/Classics/ladolcevita.htm /m/dolce_vita/comments.php?reviewid=1348956</url><name>Steven Snyder</name><from>Zertinet Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>What's incredible about Federico Fellini's work is its sense of life. Never once does this movie feel constructed or contrived, but rather appears to be unraveling before us, unscripted and uninhibited.</comment></review></movie>