<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Bramble Bush</original_title><alt_title>Le buisson ardent</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Daniel Petrie</director><producer>United States Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A handsome and successful young doctor returns to his home town in New England to see his dying friend for one last time...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Richard Burton</actor><actor>Barbara Rush</actor><actor>Jack Carson</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0043975/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ronnie</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
No, not Elizabeth Taylor but a veteran actress just as beautiful and
talented, maybe more so, a tall, trim brunette with deep-set brown
eyes, lovely skin, and a great smile. She's the best thing in this post
"Peyton Place" (1957) soap opera, very expressive as a dying man's wife
who falls in love with his doctor (Burton). The picture features Angie
Dickinson as a nurse who passively adores Burton, but she's already
involved with a corrupt lawyer (Jack Carson). A murder results in a
courtroom trial at the end. The drama tends to jump around a lot, but
is bolstered by exceptional jazz and traditional musical score by
Leonard Rosenman, and attractive imitation New England locations, in
color.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
When you have the classical training that Richard Burton had you can
make some of the worst tripe sound as profound as the classics. But
even he had trouble with The Bramble Bush which is a third class ripoff
of Peyton Place.Burton is cast as a doctor in The Bramble Bush gone back to his Peyton
Place like New England town on a consultation. A good friend from
childhood, Tom Drake, is dying of incurable Hodgkin's Disease and he'd
like for Burton to put an end to him in a humane manner. So would
Drake's wife Barbara Rush so she can move on. Burton helps with her
problem as well.And he's also helping nurse Angie Dickinson with her situation as well.
Angie's involved with bottom feeding lawyer Jack Carson and later on
bottom of the ocean feeding city editor Henry Jones learns about the
two of them. Angie would much prefer Burton and Burton obliges as best
he can.James Dunn's character is totally unexplained. Burton has a visceral
hatred for him because he found him in bed with his mother back in the
day as a kid. But why Dunn is trying to push himself in Burton's
company is totally up in the air. Dunn does a good job as an alcoholic,
sad to say in real life as well. What might have been an interesting film on euthanasia instead becomes
a trashy soap opera in The Bramble Bush. A whole cast of some really
good players is wasted here.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3426380/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lauriejane</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I was 15 years old in 1960 when this flick was released (or escaped). I
attended it on a blind date set up by my girlfriend, Carla. My date was
a serious and proper young man who wore a suit and tie. Known for my
teenage highjinks, I had assured my girlfriend that I would behave like
a proper young lady. The complex tear jerking plot and multiple
characters seemed to enchant the audience at the theatre on Hollywood
Blvd. but kept me on the verge of laughter which I desperately
attempted to stifle as the film went on...and on...and on. People were
clutching handkerchiefs and sniffing back tears during the final
courtroom scene when, at the sudden appearance of yet one more
anguished character and one more unlikely plot twist, I gave in to a
fit of teenage giggles. The scolding from my girlfriend, my date and
offended members of the audience only increased my laughing fit which
took on a life of its own, eventuating my removal by ushers who had to
lift me out of my seat by the armpits and drag me screaming with
laughter down the aisle into the lobby. Later, when I explained to my
father why my girlfriend was no longer speaking to me and my date had
ended early, he asked, "What was the movie?" He was a screenwriter and
interested in such things. When I told him, he said, in a hushed, awed
tone, "No wonder you laughed. That was the worst picture ever made."
Instead of lecturing me about my improper social conduct, he commended
me for having good taste in films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3426380/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lauriejane</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I was 15 years old in 1960 when this flick was released (or escaped). I
attended it on a blind date set up by my girlfriend, Carla. My date was
a serious and proper young man who wore a suit and tie. Known for my
teenage highjinks, I had assured my girlfriend that I would behave like
a proper young lady. The complex tear jerking plot and multiple
characters seemed to enchant the audience at the theatre on Hollywood
Blvd. but kept me on the verge of laughter which I desperately
attempted to stifle as the film went on...and on...and on. People were
clutching handkerchiefs and sniffing back tears during the final
courtroom scene when, at the sudden appearance of yet one more
anguished character and one more unlikely plot twist, I gave in to a
fit of teenage giggles. The scolding from my girlfriend, my date and
offended members of the audience only increased my laughing fit which
took on a life of its own, eventuating my removal by ushers who had to
lift me out of my seat by the armpits and drag me screaming with
laughter down the aisle into the lobby. Later, when I explained to my
father why my girlfriend was no longer speaking to me and my date had
ended early, he asked, "What was the movie?" He was a screenwriter and
interested in such things. When I told him, he said, in a hushed, awed
tone, "No wonder you laughed. That was the worst picture ever made."
Instead of lecturing me about my improper social conduct, he commended
me for having good taste in films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3426380/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lauriejane</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117789495.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/bramble_bush/comments.php?reviewid=1806442</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/68378/the_bramble_bush.html /m/bramble_bush/comments.php?reviewid=1481894</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C01E3DE1E38E333A25756C2A9649C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/bramble_bush/comments.php?reviewid=1389778</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>