<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Classe tous risques</original_title><imdb_rating>7.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Claude Sautet</director><producer>Mondex Films</producer><producer>Les Films Odéon</producer><producer>Filmsonor</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Abel Davis is a criminal, hunted in Italy. The police are closing in, so he and his pal Raymond arrange to flee back to France with Abel's wife...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Lino Ventura</actor><actor>Sandra Milo</actor><actor>Jean-Paul Belmondo</actor><rt_rating>8.3/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12350949/comments</url><from>from Israel</from><name>urigafni</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Odd one should be able to stumble into "Classe Tous Risques" only by
chance; it should be on any "best of film-noir" list, including IMDb's.Lino Ventura is as good as ever; knowing of his dire, delicate family
situation gives extra weight to his almost expressionless face and
brief dialogues. Belmondo's restrained performance under Sautet's firm
direction only shows what a wonderful actor he could - and should -have
been."Classe Tous Risques" is utterly mininal, dry and cold, without
Melville's artistic scenery, pretty faces and fancy cars. It is almost
film-noir meet neo-realism. Davos' few, hard words to his children
describing their life of secrecy from there on get a hold on your
throat to the end of the film. The final sentence of the film - a voice-over telling of Davos' end in
no more than ten dry, sombre words - leaves you with a hard punch in
the stomach.A true jewel in the great crown of French film-noir.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The film Classe tous risques directed by Claude Sautet was not a film,
to be honest, I had ever really heard of until the Film Forum in NYC
said that they would have a 2-week screening of the film, with new
English subtitles. When I also read that it was in the vein of the
classic French crime films ala Jean Pierre Melville, I jumped at the
chance to check it out (at best it would rank up with his great works,
and at worst I would get some good popcorn in a great theater). It was
well worth the admission, as Classe tous risques is one of those kinds
of French films that is just waiting to be re-discovered (or discovered
for the first time). With terrific, tense diligence, Sautet keeps the
suspense at a tight pitch for the first forty minutes of the film,
keeping a good (if not great) middle section, and then ending it up
with what is always expected with these films, but with fascinating
motivations by way of the characters. With a film in the vein of this
sort, you know how it will end, but it's the cool, observant journey
that counts.The film features a performance with some real truth and honesty, amid
the "old-school" criminal's code, by Lino Ventura as Aldo, who at the
start of the film (one of the best beginnings to a film in this genre
and country) steals a hefty amount of money with his partner in crime).
When there is a sudden, ugly twist of fate on a beach late one night,
Aldo is again on the run with two little kids. He gets the aid of Eric
Stark (Jean-Paul Belmondo, a role in tune with Le Doulos only with a
smidgen more humanity and charisma), who is also a thief and drives him
into Paris. But there are some problems with some of Aldo's old
business partner's, and one old score may be just the right ticket. A
couple of times the plot may seem to be leisurely, but it isn't. Like
Melville, Sautet doesn't allow any fat to his story, and it's a very
tightly structured film, with some good doses of humor here and there
(I was sometimes grinning at the audacity of the criminals in the
beginning chase sequence, and also with a particular woman who had a
finicky thing with her cat and a fish).Along with a fine score by the great George Delerue, exceptional
cinematography, and a mood that is seldom met let alone matched now
adays, Classe tous risques is a reminder of that bridge between the
real old-school film-noir, and the latter day crime films. Gangsters in
these new sort of "thug-life" movies have a 1000th of the class and
honor of the thieves in this film, and is a second banana to the works
of Melville and Jules Dassin (a compliment I assure you). That it has a
good realistic, moral edge helps as well.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239636/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Dziga7</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I saw this film at Telluride Film Festival in 1997, where one of
the screenwriters, José Giovanni, was being honored.  It ranks
highly as a great noir-crime-drama, incredible performances by
Belmondo and Lino Ventura.  The attention given to every
character, and complex psychological portrayals, detailing
loyalty, treachery, love, and hope, are tremendous.  It is an
excellent drama, an excellent thriller, and an excellent film.
Up there with the best of Melville.  (The title in English 'Class all risk,' in French 'Classe tous risques' is word-play on 'Classe Touriste,' meaning
'Tourist Class'.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I have just watched on Italian TV the excellent crime drama CLASSE TOUS
RISQUES (1960; aka: THE BIG RISK), directed by Claude Sautet and
starring the late Lino Ventura (in one of his best roles) and a very
young Jean-Paul Belmondo. This film came out at the tail end of a string of French gangster
thrillers of the 50s, the most famous of which was, of course, Jules
Dassin's seminal DU RIFIFI CHEZ LES HOMMES (1954; aka: RIFIFI). I
haven't watched RIFIFI in a long time but I plan to acquire the
Criterion DVD some time or other. In fact, I have only postponed it,
really, because of the reported audio-synch problem present on the
disc's first pressings and, being a non-U.S. resident, Criterion's
policy dictates that no defective discs delivered outside Region 1
territories can be replaced! Still, in light of THE BIG RISK, I may
risk it [sic] all the same! When the film came out it converged with a spate of Nouvelle Vague
releases including Jean-Luc Godard's A' BOUT DE SOUFFLE (1960; aka:
BREATHLESS) starring, of course, Jean-Paul Belmondo himself. It is easy
to assume that his characterization in THE BIG RISK is nowhere near as
iconic as his Laszlo Kovacs in Godard's film, but after all his is a
supporting role (albeit pulled off with confidence and charm) and he is
all too obviously overshadowed by the underrated Ventura, who dominates
the film from beginning to end. Ventura was a regular in gangster films
of the period: he was in Jacques Becker's masterful TOUCHEZ PAS AU
GRISBI (1953; aka: HANDS OFF THE LOOT!) playing the main villainous
role and in which he conducts an effective vis-à-vis with nominal star
Jean Gabin, but he then took the lead for Jean-Pierre Melville's
magnificent thriller set in WWII, L'ARMEE' DES OMBRES (1969; aka: ARMY
OF SHADOWS). Incidentally, next week Criterion will release Melville's BOB LE
FLAMBEUR (1955) and I hope they can put their hands on other films by
this French master, notably LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES (1950), from the play
by Jean Cocteau; LE DEUXIEME SOUFFLE (1966; aka: SECOND BREATH), also
starring Lino Ventura; LE SAMOURAI (1967), his undisputed chef
d'oeuvre; the aforementioned L'ARMEE' DES OMBRES and LE CERCLE ROUGE
(1970; aka: THE RED CIRCLE). It is worth noting that the last two may
very well be future Criterion DVDs. For the record, I have recorded
ENFANTS, SAMOURAI, ARMEE' and CERCLE (which I have yet to watch) off
French TV, along with the atypical LEON MORIN, PRETRE (1961) and the
little-seen LE DOULOS (1962; aka: THE FINGER MAN), both of which star
Jean-Paul Belmondo. To go back to THE BIG RISK, it was dismissed at the time as
old-fashioned in light of the Nouvelle Vague, though the few stylistic
touches it has are effective exactly because they are sparse and
unexpected. After an explosive start, the film relaxes its grip for the
first half in order to establish plot (somewhat unusual in its emphasis
on the domestic problems of gangsters) and characterization
(particularly in eliciting audience sympathy for the lone anti-hero).
The plot does have its improbable turns: for example, Belmondo's and
Sandra Milo's characters are a bit too good to be true, aiding Ventura
without batting an eyelid (despite the obvious danger involved) just
minutes after making his acquaintance, while the ending is a bit of a
letdown (the film is abruptly interrupted and the plot resolved with a
hurried voice-over explanation)...but Ventura's solid performance as a
man betrayed, quietly desperate at first but driven eventually to
sudden eruptions of violence, holds the film firmly together and makes
THE BIG RISK a classic of its kind. Other films by Claude Sautet I have watched are LES CHOSES DE LA VIE
(1969), MAX ET LES FERRAILLEURS (1971; aka: MAX AND THE SCRAP-MONGERS),
CESAR ET ROSALIE (1972), all on Italian TV, and VINCENT, FRANCOIS, PAUL
ET LES AUTRES (1974), which I have recorded off French TV. All of these
are low-key yet very interesting and thought-provoking films, aided a
great deal by a superb selection of actors (Michel Piccoli in CHOSES,
MAX and VINCENT; Romy Schneider in the first three titles; and Yves
Montand in the last two). VINCENT, FRANCOIS, PAUL ET LES AUTRES is
perhaps Sautet's best film: it co-stars Serge Reggiani, Gerard
Depardieu (one of his first), Marie Dubois and Stephane Audran (an
extended cameo, really, but effective nonetheless).As I have said, I wish that some of the films I mentioned by Claude
Sautet and Jean-Pierre Melville, including of course THE BIG RISK, will
one day be released on DVD. Supplements for such films may be hard to
come by, I guess, but a quality print in the Original Aspect Ratio with
a transfer to match are the least we could expect for them. I know that
some of the above-mentioned films are already available on French
Region 2 DVD but unfortunately most of them do not carry English
subtitles. Although I do have quite a basic knowledge of the French
language, I am still not fluent enough to get by without any subtitles.
However, I would very much like to read your opinions of French Region
2 DVDs and will affect a search through the Mobius archives for that
purpose, though I may still have to post my queries about particular
French DVDs which I am interested in purchasing in a new thread in this
Forum in the near future.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

"Classes tous risques" is one of the best "gangsters" films noirs France
has
ever produced.Perfect cast :Lino Ventura,a young Jean -Paul Belmondo (who
made "a bout de souffle",Godard's thing, the same year),Marcel Dalio and a
fine supporting cast ;brilliant script by José Giovanni -who also wrote
"le
trou" Becker's masterpièce the same year!What a year for him!;wonderful
black and white cinematography by Ghislain Cloquet.And taut
action,first-class directing by Claude Sautet,who surpasses Jean-Pierre
Melville .Whereas the latter films gangsters movie with metaphysical
pretensions,which sometimes lasts more than two hours,Claude Sautet
directs
men of flesh and blood,and the presence of the two children adds moments
of
extraordinary poignancy which Melville has never been able to generate
.And
Sautet avoids pathos,excessive sentimentality:the last time Ventura sees
his
children,coming down in the metro (subway)is a peak of restrained
emotion.Ventura portrays a gangster whose die  is cast when the movie begins.He
thinks that he can rely on his former acquaintances ,but they are all
cowards -we are far from manly friendship dear to Jacques Becker ("touchez
pas au grisbi" ) which Melville was to continue throughout the
sixties-sometimes abetted by mean women (the film noir misogyny par
excellence),living in a rotten microcosm,ready to inform on -we are far
from
Jean Seberg's simplistic behavior in Godard's "opus"-.Cloquet works wonders with the picture:the scene on the beach in a
starless
night when the two children see their mother die after the shoot-out with
the customs officers is absolutely mind-boggling.There's a good use of voice-over,which Sautet only uses when
necessary;thus
,the last lines make the ending even stronger than if we have attended the
scenes.Claude Sautet had found a good niche ,and he followed the "classes tous
risques" rules quite well with his follow-up "l'arme à gauche" (1965)
which
featured Ventura again and made a good use of a desert island and a
ship.Had
he continued in that vein,France would have had a Howard Hawks.In his
subsequent works ,only "Max et les ferrailleurs " (1971)
showed something of the brilliance he displayed in the first half of the
sixties.He had become ,from "les choses de la vie" onwards,the cinema de
qualité director who used to focus on tender-hearted bourgeois
in such works as "Cesar et Rosalie" (1972),"Vincent François ,Paul et les
autres" (1974) or "Mado" (1976) 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3128276/comments</url><from>from Philadelphia</from><name>Dickhead_Marcus_Halberstram</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Classe Tous Risques (The Big Risk) is repeatedly recommended every time
I look up a Jean-Pierre Melville film that I had to give it a watch as
soon as possible. Since I've been discovering Melville and seemingly
working backwards through his filmography, it would be easy for me to
mistake this as one of his films, but it was made in 1960, by Claude
Sautet, before Melville would come and stake his claim on french
neo-noir.Classe Tous Risques has two of the best lead men of the time, Lino
Ventura and Jean-Paul Belmondo. Ventura plays Abel, a gangster exiled
in Italy with his wife and two kids, who wants to come back to Paris
because the police are closing in on him. After a roaring and fast
paced opening with a big surprise, Abel eventually gets hooked up with
Eric Stark (Belmondo) who wants to get into the criminal underworld.
Stark becomes Abel's chauffeur and eventual only friend in an
underworld that turns it's back on Abel after everything he's done and
been through. The film shows the the duality of the two men, the older
Abel at the end of his time after tragedy strikes him, and the younger
Eric starting off the same way Abel did, falling in love with a
beautiful woman who sticks with her man despite the world they are a
part of. It never ends pretty for them, or their loved ones. Its one
thing to see a individual criminal come to his demise, its different
when he has loved ones he risks taking down with him.Much like Melville's film, the seemingly simple story gets more
subtlety complicated as it goes along. As usual, as what I feel with
Melville's films, it left my head spinning (in a good way) and dying to
re watch it again to pick up what I missed the first time. Classe Tous
Risques is a definite keeper.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2042633/comments</url><from>from Queens, NY</from><name>noralee</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
"Classe tous risques" feels like the granddaddy of "The Sopranos" in
mixing the criminal and the domestic, and of the buddy film to feel as
contemporary as "Reservoir Dogs."Even as these gangsters are affectionately entangled with wives,
children, lovers and parents, they are coldly ruthless, and we are
constantly reminded they are, no matter what warm situation we also see
them in. They can tousle a kid's hair - and then shoot a threat in cold
blood. The key is loyalty, and the male camaraderie is beautifully
conveyed, without ethnic or class stereotypes, even as their web of
past obligations and pay backs narrows into suspicion and paranoia, as
the old gang is in various stages of parole, retirement, out on bail or
into new, less profitable ventures. An intense accusation is of sending
a stranger to perform an old escape scenario. It is a high point of
emotion when a wife is told off that she's not the one the gangster is
friends with, while virtually the only time we hear music on the
soundtrack is when he recalls his wife.Streetscapes in Italy and France are marvelously used, in blinding
daylight to dark water and highways, from the opening set up of a pair
of brazen robbers -- who are traveling with one's wife and two kids.
Rugged, craggy Lino Ventura captures the screen immediately as the
criminal dad. And the second thug is clearly a casually avuncular
presence in their lives, as they smoothly coordinate the theft and
escape, in cars, buses, on boats and motorcycles, in easy tandem. This
is not the cliché crusty old guy softened with the big-eyed orphan;
these are their jobs and their families and they intersect in horrific
ways.The film pulls no punches in unexpectedly killing off characters,
directly and as collateral damage, and challenging our sympathy for
them, right through to the unsentimental end, which is probably why
there was never an American remake. It seems so fresh that it's not until Jean-Paul Belmondo enters almost
a third of the way into the film, looking so insouciant as a young
punk, that one realizes that this is from 1960. Sultry Sandra Milo has
smart and terrific chemistry with him, from an ambulance to an elevator
to a hospital bed.While the Film Forum was showing a new 35 mm print with newly
translated subtitles, it was not pristine. The program notes explained
that the title refers to a kind of insurance policy and is pun on
"tourist class."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2630196/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>Prof-Hieronymos-Grost</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Career criminal and crime boss, Abel Davos (Lino Ventura) has been on
the run for more than 10 years, hiding out in Milan, Italy. In his
absence, he has been sentenced to death in his home country of France
for his crimes. Disillusioned with his life in Italy and with the
police there closing in on him, he decides to return to his old
stomping ground in Paris. Sending his wife Therese and two young sons
ahead to Nice, Abel and his next in command Raymond Naldi do one final
heist, to fund their new lives back in France. The heist proffers a
meagre half million francs, way less than their sources had suggested,
despite this and with the police in chase they both make it to Nice,
where they hideout briefly. After stealing a pleasure boat from a
local, they aim to make it to San Remo a tourist spot where they will
blend in more readily, but they are stopped by armed customs officers
on a deserted beach, a shoot out ensues and Therese and Naldi are both
killed. A now wounded Davos with two kids in tow is going to be easily
spotted by police, so he calls on his old friends in Paris to send
help, but they have moved on since their old friend went into hiding
and are not too inclined to take a risk themselves, so they send small
time thief, Eric Stark (Jean Paul Belmondo) to rescue him. Davos is
disgusted that such a lowly thief is sent to his aid, despite the fact
he hits it off immediately with the charming Stark, he sets out to find
out why he has been snubbed, but their betrayal doesn't stop there.Classe Tous Risques (aka the Big Risk) was written for the screen by
former death row inmate and crime writer Jose Giovanni (Le Trou, Le
Clan des Siciliens), with Ventura already on board for the project,
Giovanniwanted someone unique to direct the project, Ventura suggested
an assistant director that had caught his attention on a previous
project,one Claude Sautet, best known at the time for assisting Georges
Franju on Les Yeux sans Visage. Sautet immediately agreed and the rest
as they say is history. Sautet crafted a fine gangster film, that plays
heavily on characters and relationships. Davos constantly in hiding has
plenty of time to reflect on his life, past, present and future, his
friendships that no longer seem to be what he believed they were, his
now deceased wife and what will become of his two young sons. Ventura
as a character actor has always amazed me, being both comfortable and
convincing in both the police and criminal fraternity, here his world
weary performance is sublime and powerful as his world crumbles all
around him, as the loneliness and solitude of a man on the run kicks
in. Ventura's former profession as a pro wrestler gets plenty of use as
he throws parisien hoodlums around with a consummate ease. Belmondo as
Stark enlivens the other storyline within the film, that of his budding
relationship with a girl he meets on the road trip. With his forthright
charm, his coming clean to this woman in danger that he is but a
"Voleur" and that "the only good thing about me is my left" as he
knocks out her aggressor, is also a joy to behold, as she falls for him
anyway. Belmondo's performance was overlooked at the time, as Godard's
A bout de Soufflé was released only three weeks previous, Godard
attaining the credit for discovering the new kid on the block, his
versatility within these two films, being there for all to see and
admire. Sautet's film is a classy affair, using plenty of attractive
locations, the film also has very sparse dialogue, Sautet preferring to
let the actors do the work with the merest of looks or glances
sufficing to further the story, needles to say this Noir fan will be
checking out more of Sautet's work in the future.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0283340/comments</url><from>from San Antonio, Texas</from><name>Terrell-4</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Classe Tous Risques (The Big Risk) is a French gangster movie that
doesn't try for style. That's why it has style. Because the movie is so
underplayed and so matter-of-fact, it becomes more and more involving.
And because Abel Davos is played by Lino Ventura, we wind up
emotionally invested in this taciturn, tough killer who loves his wife
and kids, has an encounter with customs agents on the shore near Nice
at night that neither he nor we expect, and who proves just as willing
to shoot a cop or a betrayer with as little emotion as flicking off a
bit of lint. We first meet Davos in Italy with his wife and their two
small boys, one about 9 and one 4. "This man was Abel Davos, sentenced to death in absentia," we're told.
"On the run for years, he had watched his resources dwindle, even as
his anxiety kept him on the move. With the Italian police closing in
each day, France was again his best bet. Maybe he'd been forgotten." Davos was a top gangster in Paris who took care of his friends. That
was several years ago. A heist to give him money to return to France
goes very wrong. Now he's hiding out with his two kids. He calls his
friends in Paris to help him out. He and his kids need to get from Nice
to Paris but the police are hunting him and they've set up roadblocks.
For Davos' two best friends, time has passed and they've moved on. They
don't want to put themselves at risk, and for what? Obligation gives
may to caution. So they hire a young thief, Eric Stark (Jean- Paul
Belmondo), to pick up Davos and the children in an ambulance, then to
drive to Paris with Davos heavily bandaged and the children hidden.
We're on a journey where Davos' options are increasingly limited, where
he must find ways to have his children cared for, where he realizes
there are no more ties of friendship, where betrayal seems likely, and
where quite possibly his only friend left is Eric Stark. This somewhat cynical movie works so well because it does its job
without fussing about. There are no trench coats with pulled-up
collars, no toying with the melodrama of the gangster code so many
French directors have loved. Classe tous Risques gives us Abel Davos, a
man who once was somebody, who now is sliding down to be nobody, and
who reacts with violence and resignation. Lino Ventura dominates the movie, yet when he is paired with Jean-Paul
Belmondo a curious chemistry happens. Ventura as Davos is grim and
worried about caring for his sons. He is humiliated by his situation.
He is a tough man who sees killing someone, if needed, as just part of
the business he's in. Belmondo as the young thief who initially is sent
to be an expendable driver and winds up being a friend to count on,
provides the brightness that keeps the movie from being just one more
ride down the elevator. Belmondo was 27 and looks younger. His unlikely
star power as a lead actor -- broken nose, under-slung jaw -- shines
right off the screen. He makes Erik a match for Ventura when they share
a scene. And Belmondo's scenes with Liliane (Sandra Milo), the young
woman who becomes his girl friend, radiate charm and good-natured sex
appeal. The ending is bittersweet fate, and without a stylistic posture
in sight. We hear Davos say, "Abel's gone. There's nothing left." It
would be well worth watching Classe tous Risques to learn what he
means. There are many fine French gangster films. I'd place this one right
there with Touchez Pas au Grisbi and Bob le Flambeur. To see one of
Lino Ventura's finest performances, watch Army of Shadows.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0495697/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jay Harris (sirbossman6969@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a Black and White film from France,Simple plot, gangster on the run seeking &amp; getting help etc. We have
seen this type film many times over the years. What makes this film
different are mainly its acting &amp; style. All the actors perform
quietly,No one yells &amp; hardly anyone loses his temper. There are quite
a few deaths, some surprising. There are beautiful women as well, but
no sex scenes. No car chases either.JUST talking/ It is so refreshing to listen to people talk, &amp; here we
must read subtitles as well.The acting is near perfect by all. especially the lead played by Lino Ventura &amp; in a smaller BUT vital role Jean Paul Belmondo. These 2
actors were among the best.I said above the film is flawed, There are a few script deficiencies in
few spots, They are minor,The acting is the thing in this movie.
Production is first rate as well.Ratings: *** (out of 4) 88 points (out of 100) IMDb 8 (out of 10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0495697/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jay Harris (sirbossman6969@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a Black and White film from France,Simple plot, gangster on the run seeking &amp; getting help etc. We have
seen this type film many times over the years. What makes this film
different are mainly its acting &amp; style. All the actors perform
quietly,No one yells &amp; hardly anyone loses his temper. There are quite
a few deaths, some surprising. There are beautiful women as well, but
no sex scenes. No car chases either.JUST talking/ It is so refreshing to listen to people talk, &amp; here we
must read subtitles as well.The acting is near perfect by all. especially the lead played by Lino Ventura &amp; in a smaller BUT vital role Jean Paul Belmondo. These 2
actors were among the best.I said above the film is flawed, There are a few script deficiencies in
few spots, They are minor,The acting is the thing in this movie.
Production is first rate as well.Ratings: *** (out of 4) 88 points (out of 100) IMDb 8 (out of 10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/c/ClasseRisques.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1842679</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Sautet's shrugging ambiguity, already piquant, already piercing</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/bigrisk.htm /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1737526</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>It ranks among the best of the French New Wave noir films.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eleanor-ringel-gillespie/</url><url>http://www.accessatlanta.com/movies/content/shared/movies/reviews/C/classetousrisques/index.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1524633</url><name>Eleanor Ringel Gillespie</name><from>Atlanta Journal-Constitution</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>Doesn't quite rate lost-classic status, but it's done with a great deal of dexterity, intelligence and an appealing end-of-'50s cool.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sean-axmaker/</url><url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/269870_limited12.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1505878</url><name>Sean Axmaker</name><from>Seattle Post-Intelligencer</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Romantic codes of honor collide with the unforgiving doom of the gangster thriller with a fascinating ambiguity... in Claude Sautet's lean, tough 1960 crime classic...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-elliott/</url><url>http://www.signonsandiego.com/uniontrib/20060504/news_lz1w04classe.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1502772</url><name>David Elliott</name><from>San Diego Union-Tribune</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>French directors like Melville and Chabrol did more with the basically American forms and inspirations, but Sautet (a fairly major talent) had crack nerves and an alert, humane eye.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-monaghan/</url><url>http://www.freep.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20060324/ENT01/603240315/1036 /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1492413</url><name>John Monaghan</name><from>Detroit Free Press</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>The rerelease of Classe Tous Risques makes you wonder how many other movies this good got scuttled by the French new wave.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/wesley-morris/</url><url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=8622 /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1491402</url><name>Wesley Morris</name><from>Boston Globe</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Even though the film isn't considered a rule-breaking classic, its straight face holds up quite nicely, thank you.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/andy-klein/</url><url>/m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1487133</url><name>Andy Klein</name><from>Los Angeles CityBeat</from></reviewer><comment> ...another eminently watchable example of the French noir trend of the period.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kenneth-turan/</url><url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/turan/cl-et-risques6jan06,0,3542482.story /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1469520</url><name>Kenneth Turan</name><from>Los Angeles Times</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>To come across Classe Tous Risques is like discovering a bottle of marvelous French wine you didn't remember you had, opening it and finding it every bit as delicious as its reputation promised.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/roger-ebert/</url><url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20060105/REVIEWS/60104003 /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1469373</url><name>Roger Ebert</name><from>Chicago Sun-Times</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>A crisp, smart, cynical film about dishonor among thieves.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lisa-schwarzbaum/</url><url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,1136109,00.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1456021</url><name>Lisa Schwarzbaum</name><from>Entertainment Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>A doozy of a French gangster pic that, in its beautifully refurbished and pithily resubtitled re-release, turns out to be one of the highlights of the 2005 movie year.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/andrew-sarris/</url><url>/m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1455460</url><name>Andrew Sarris</name><from>New York Observer</from></reviewer><comment>[T]he young Belmondo alone is worth the price of admission to Classe Tous Risques ...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/maitland-mcdonagh/</url><url>http://www.tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?id=46593&amp;sourcetype=M /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1454719</url><name>Maitland McDonagh</name><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>A killer.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/peter-rainer/</url><url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2005/1118/p14s02-almo.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1454715</url><name>Peter Rainer</name><from>Christian Science Monitor</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>The late Claude Sautet was one of the best, and perhaps the most underappreciated, of the great French directors who came to prominence in the '50s and '60s.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jurgen-fauth/</url><url>http://worldfilm.about.com/od/frenchfilm/fr/classetoursrisq.htm /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1454612</url><name>Jurgen Fauth</name><from>About.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Touching and merciless at the same time.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ao-scott/</url><url>/m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1454452</url><name>A.O. Scott</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Claude Sautet's Classe Tous Risques is the kind of French movie that makes you want to throw on your trench coat, light up a cigarette and shoot somebody.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jan-stuart/</url><url>http://www.newsday.com/entertainment/movies/ny-etclass4515742nov18,0,480858.story?coll=ny-moviereview-headlines /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1454397</url><name>Jan Stuart</name><from>Newsday</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>Belmondo is the clincher: He's got so much jaunty charisma, the screen can barely contain him.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/j-hoberman/</url><url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0546,hoberman,70029,20.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1454187</url><name>J. Hoberman</name><from>Village Voice</from></reviewer><comment>The new titles are flavorsome, and the restoration is up to Rialto's previous high standards -- shades of gray with the pale glow of an overcast autumn sky.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/peter-keough/</url><url>http://www.thephoenix.com/Boston/Movies/6577-CLASSE-TOUS-RISQUES/ /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1815083</url><name>Peter Keough</name><from>Boston Phoenix</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/84523.html /m/classe_tous_risques/comments.php?reviewid=1662068</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>