<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hawai Middowei daikaikûsen: Taiheiyô no arashi</original_title><imdb_rating>6.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Shûe Matsubayashi</director><producer>Toho Company</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
Lt. Koji Kitami is a navigator-bombardier in Japan's Naval Air Force. He participates in the Japanese raid on the U.S...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Yôsuke Natsuki</actor><actor>Makoto Satô</actor><actor>Misa Uehara</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1381803/comments</url><from>from Sacramento, Calif., U.S.A.</from><name>rey alvarez</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

During the 1960's, Toho, the Japanese movie company which made all the
Godzilla movies, produced one or two large-scale special effects movies
every year.  "I Bombed Pearl Harbor" (or Japanese original title "The
Great
Sea Battles of Hawaii and Midway: Storm Over the Pacific") (1962) is an
excellent example of one of these 1960's Toho special effect movies.  This
non-fiction film, which is based on a memoir of a Japanese World War II
torpedo bomber pilot, depicts the attack on Pearl Harbor and the Battle of
Midway  from the Japanese side.  I remember seeing this movie for the
first
time back in the 1970's.  The first thing I realized were the humanity and
courage of Japanese pilots, who are frequently portrayed as beastly bad
guys
in American and British movies.  This movie showed me that they were no
different from the Allied fighting men.  Japanese pilots truly cared about
their own comrades.  They showed tremendous courage under fire.  They
deeply
lamented the deaths of their comrades.All of the film's main characters were portrayed superbly by the Japanese
cast members.  Yosuke Natsuki played the main character, Lt. Kitami, as a
young, gutsy aviator officer with an almost fanatical devotion to his
country and the emperor.  The character took defeat stoically like a real
man.    After the horrendous defeat at Midway, in which he lost many of
his
comrades, he did not whine or gripe; he calmly and unemotionally stated:
"However horrible this may be, this is war.  I have to face it."  Late
international star, Toshiro Mifune, played Adm. Tamon Yamaguchi, who went
down with his flagship the Hiryu.  And late Koji Tsuruta, a real-life
ex-kamikaze pilot turned actor and singer, played Lt. Tomonari (based on a
historical person Lt. Tomonaga who crashed his plane into the bridge of
the
Yorktown during the Battle of Midway).Moreover, the special effect, which was supervised by late Eiji Tsuburaya
(the special effects director of  numerous 1950's and 1960's Japanese
special effect movies), was excellent and awe-inspiring.  The scene in
which
the U.S. Dauntless dive-bombers dropped 1000-lb. bombs on the Japanese
aircraft careers was awesomely filmed.  The site of burning Japanese
aircraft careers was a masterpiece of special effect.  Some of the special
effect scenes are so good that the Universal Studio used portions of this
film to make its 1976 movie "Midway."Unlike Universal's "Midway," which was badly edited, the editing of this
film was coherent and masterfully done.  Even though I did not think that
the script was particularly unique (the story was simply told in a
straightforward way), the overall quality of the film was excellent.  I
recommend this movie to all the film buffs so they can see World War II
from
the other side.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1381803/comments</url><from>from Sacramento, Calif., U.S.A.</from><name>rey alvarez</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

During the 1960's, Toho, the Japanese movie company which made all the
Godzilla movies, produced one or two large-scale special effects movies
every year.  "I Bombed Pearl Harbor" (or Japanese original title "The
Great
Sea Battles of Hawaii and Midway: Storm Over the Pacific") (1962) is an
excellent example of one of these 1960's Toho special effect movies.  This
non-fiction film, which is based on a memoir of a Japanese World War II
torpedo bomber pilot, depicts the attack on Pearl Harbor and the Battle of
Midway  from the Japanese side.  I remember seeing this movie for the
first
time back in the 1970's.  The first thing I realized were the humanity and
courage of Japanese pilots, who are frequently portrayed as beastly bad
guys
in American and British movies.  This movie showed me that they were no
different from the Allied fighting men.  Japanese pilots truly cared about
their own comrades.  They showed tremendous courage under fire.  They
deeply
lamented the deaths of their comrades.All of the film's main characters were portrayed superbly by the Japanese
cast members.  Yosuke Natsuki played the main character, Lt. Kitami, as a
young, gutsy aviator officer with an almost fanatical devotion to his
country and the emperor.  The character took defeat stoically like a real
man.    After the horrendous defeat at Midway, in which he lost many of
his
comrades, he did not whine or gripe; he calmly and unemotionally stated:
"However horrible this may be, this is war.  I have to face it."  Late
international star, Toshiro Mifune, played Adm. Tamon Yamaguchi, who went
down with his flagship the Hiryu.  And late Koji Tsuruta, a real-life
ex-kamikaze pilot turned actor and singer, played Lt. Tomonari (based on a
historical person Lt. Tomonaga who crashed his plane into the bridge of
the
Yorktown during the Battle of Midway).Moreover, the special effect, which was supervised by late Eiji Tsuburaya
(the special effects director of  numerous 1950's and 1960's Japanese
special effect movies), was excellent and awe-inspiring.  The scene in
which
the U.S. Dauntless dive-bombers dropped 1000-lb. bombs on the Japanese
aircraft careers was awesomely filmed.  The site of burning Japanese
aircraft careers was a masterpiece of special effect.  Some of the special
effect scenes are so good that Universal Studio used portions of this film
to make its 1976 movie "Midway."Unlike Universal's "Midway," which was badly edited, the editing of this
film was coherent and masterfully done.  Even though I did not think that
the script was particularly unique (the story was simply told in a
straightforward way), the overall quality of the film was excellent.  I
recommend this movie to all the film buffs so they can see World War II
from
the other side.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0061309/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, CA</from><name>Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Toho's first major color war film is without a doubt one of the most
impressive of their many 60's offerings. The only one I can think of
this easily trumps this is their later BATTLE OF THE SEA OF JAPAN
(1969) which is about the Russo-Japanese War. This is a world war 2
film and probably the quintessential film covering the two largest,
most pivotal events of the Pacific theater - Pearl Harbor and Midway.
These battles would be covered in several later American films but
never with the gusto of this production.This presentation of the Pacific Theater is a little different than us
Westerners are used to. There's something shockingly surreal about
seeing the main characters elatedly cheering the destruction of the
Arizona, or referring to December 7th, 1941 as "a wonderful day".
Unlike German or Italian war films to come over the years after the
war, this film by a former Axis member is not a guilt-ridden depressing
condemnation of the past. Instead, the Japanese (many of the cast and
crew members were veterans of the conflict) seem to be quite proud of
their effort, camaraderie, and achievements. The attack on Pearl Harbor
is shown as a more-or-less unavoidable battle and a great victory.
Little attention is paid to the fact that the Americans are totally
oblivious to the fact they're at war before the bombs drop. The
Americans are actually rarely mentioned by name, only as "the enemy"
and never seen besides their planes, ships, and ground installations.Little can be said about this movie without mentioning the brilliant
effects work by Eiji Tsuburaya and Teruyoshi Nakano. Tsuburaya had made
some of Japan's most impressive propaganda films during the war which
recreated the Pearl Harbor attack, and here he gets to do the same but
in color and with more money and a larger water tank. The 1/16th scale
models look brilliant and the explosions and fires realistic enough for
MIDWAY to steal 16 years later.Dramatically the film comes off as a little stiff, though Natsuki gives
an earnest performance as a young pilot. Mifune plays Yamagouchi with
his usual gravitas, and many recognizable Toho stock performers pop up
in small roles throughout. The film also suffers from its no-frills
straight-forward retelling approach (much like the earlier film THE
MYSTERIANS) which means there's not really any subplots or plot twists.
Just action, effects, and historical reenactments to provide
entertainment. It also suffers a lot of the same failings as other Toho
films of the time with the tendency to reuse effects shots (sometimes
twice in a row), lots of jump cuts (such as an explosion goes off, then
another, but the camera does not move despite a lot of time being cut
out between the two explosions), and a few dodgy miniatures.The real star is the battle scenes; not just the brief Pearl Harbor
recreation, but the drawn out Midway battle that takes up the whole
second half of the film. Excellent music, cinematography, and wholly
believable process shots. Overall a thoroughly impressive war film
which is unfairly hard to find.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0765063/comments</url><from>from St. Davids, Pennsylvania, USA</from><name>SgtSlaughter</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I'll be up front about my experience with Japanese cinema: it ranges
from foggy memories of Godzilla flicks on TNT back in the mid-1990s,
and more recently, a few Japanese war films. I don't know who many of
the actors are, and cannot find much information on the web (or
elsewhere) about this genre. I recognize names, not faces. More
importantly, many of the Japanese films from the 60s and 70s emerged in
the US totally butchered or altered into completely different movies.
"I Bombed Pearl Harbor" holds up quite well in spite of dubbing,
re-scoring and editing.This film has got to be one of the best productions about World War II
in the Pacific theater, solely because it offers an honest, unflinching
look at the Japanese point of view. It's free of annoying clichés,
strong performance and features a number of well-shot action scenes,
filmed entirely in miniature.This is a movie about the men in front lines doing their job. The
Japanese pilots are the main characters, here, shown to be just as
patriotic and honorable as the American GIs audiences are used to
seeing. They're not saints, nor are they demons – they are ordinary
young men, full of ambition and ready to take on the world. But the
horrors of war will change this attitude. We see the course of the
surprise attack on Pearl Harbor and the Midway campaign through the
eyes of Koji (Yosuke Natsuki), a navigator. The film is faithful to
historical facts, and even though it's made from the Japanese point of
view, it remains honest without stretching the truth.There are numerous battle sequences throughout the film. Japanese
special effects master Eiji Tsuburaya directed these sequences, and he
handles every frame beautifully. Although it's obvious that the planes
are models and the ships are floating in tanks, we see no obvious guide
wires and the proportions are very close to perfect. The scenes on the
ground and aboard ship have a very realistic look and feel to them,
unlike many Hollywood films from the same time period. Scenes on the
bridge of an aircraft carrier and in the hangers look much more
authentic than those in 1976's "Midway", which was evidently lensed on
cheap soundstages.The performances are above average. As Koji, the young Natsuki makes a
big impression. We first meet him when he's fresh out of training,
ready to fly off and bomb Pearl Harbor for the glory of the emperor and
his homeland. Things change rapidly: in the middle of his wedding, he
is ordered to report back to his carrier, which is to leave for the
Midway invasion. There, many of his friends get shot down. His best
friend, Matsura (Makoto Sato) almost doesn't make it. By the end of the
movie, very few of the original cast are remaining. Of the ensemble,
Toshiro Mifune ("Hell in the Pacific") makes a very great Admiral
Yamaguchi; his last few scenes are touching and emotion-laden.There are a few strikes against this film as it stands now. The first
is the miserable dubbing. Some of the dialog comes out with conviction,
while other lines sound as though they're being read from cue cards
with no emotion or inflection. The North American home video release is
taken from a rather battered print, full of holes, speckles, scratches
and splices. There are missing snippets of dialog and even some missing
frames. The only good thing to say is that this print is letterboxed
1.85:1, a necessity for the combat sequences. A fully restored copy of
the original version, which runs 118 minutes (as opposed to a
re-scored, edited 98 minute American version) would make this viewing
even better.As it stands now, "I Bombed Pearl Harbor" is a clearly-told, engaging
and well-shot war film offering some outstanding miniature work and
unique look at World War II. This is definitely worth watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1307958/comments</url><from>from Hamilton, NZ</from><name>Nick Johnston</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This film, in Japanese, can be watched even without knowing a word of
Japanese. It is pretty old now, but well put together.Personally, I have seen many films about Pearl Harbor, but the ones that
are
quite interesting are from the other sides perspective. Most war movies I
have seen have been saying that the Allies were the 'goodies' and the Axis
powers were the 'baddies'. That is why this film is an excellent way to
show
how the Japanese felt about the Pearl Harbor bombing!RATING: WORTH LOOKING AT!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1060482/comments</url><from>from Bronx, NY</from><name>Brian Camp</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I BOMBED PEARL HARBOR is one of the very few Japanese films about World
War II to be released in English and offers a fascinating window into
Japanese attitudes toward the war expressed some 15 years after their
defeat. Granted, this was seen on VHS in a cut, English-dubbed print
with some re-editing, so we can't be entirely sure about the points of
view expressed in the original. Numerous questions arise. For instance,
did the original open and close with Franklin D. Roosevelt's radio
addresses on the soundtrack as this version does? Or did Japanese
audiences hear Emperor Hirohito's speeches on the soundtrack? The film, as seen in this version, glosses over the causes of the war
and the reasons Japan was in it. There are no mentions of the United
States or of Americans at all and, of course, no mentions of Japanese
occupation of so many Asian countries during the war. The pilots
heading out to Pearl Harbor at the beginning are told it's their sacred
duty to Japan and the Emperor and that the fate of the Japanese empire
rests on them. They cheer a "successful mission" after the sneak attack
on Pearl Harbor, a sequence that takes up the first 19 minutes of the
film. Most of the rest of the film is taken up with the Battle of
Midway (which took place, as I write this on June 4, on this date 69
years ago). As the battle progresses, to Japan's not-so-inevitable
defeat, radio reports heard in Japan tell complete lies about the
outcome of the battle. It's evident to an informed viewer that the
Japanese military consistently lied to the people and brainwashed its
soldiers and pilots so that they could launch lethal attacks without
any moral qualms and without any realistic sense of what they could
accomplish against American industrial might. Yet the pilots are
treated as noble heroes throughout. There are sentiments of regret
voiced at the end of the film acknowledging what a mistake it all was,
but they come too little and too late to satisfy me.I watched the Hollywood film, MIDWAY (1976), right after this, in order
to get an American account of the battle. The two versions stick quite
closely to the facts and many of the Japanese military figures from I
BOMBED PEARL HARBOR are indeed in MIDWAY as well. MIDWAY even used some
shots from this film, along with quite a lot of actual color film
footage taken by American combat photographers during the battle
itself. Toshiro Mifune plays Admiral Yamaguchi in I BOMBED PEARL HARBOR
and Admiral Yamamoto in MIDWAY, 16 years later. He's dubbed in both
films by familiar voice-over actor, Paul Frees, the absolute wrong
voice for Mifune. (In MIDWAY, Frees' attempt at a Japanese accent is
completely at odds with the unaccented English spoken by all the
Japanese-American actors—James Shigeta, Pat Morita, et al--playing the
other Japanese officers.) Some of the reviews here cite the depiction of the Japanese pilots in
this film as "ordinary" and "honorable" men, who showed "humanity" and
"courage." I'm sorry, but that's like characterizing Nazi concentration
camp guards in a film about the Holocaust as "ordinary" and "honorable"
men who were just following orders. When you allow a fascistic
militaristic mindset to dominate your thinking and behavior, and when
you plunge wholeheartedly into campaigns of murderous aggression
against innocent peoples as the Japanese so frequently did (just ask
China) and call it your "sacred duty," you can no longer be called
"honorable" or "courageous." As a baby boomer who writes extensively
about Japanese film, television and pop music, but who grew up in the
shadow of the war and whose father trained marines to fight in the
Pacific, I have difficulty seeing the Japanese soldiers and pilots who
fought us back then as anything but the "bad guys," no matter how many
tears they shed over fallen comrades or letters they wrote home to
mothers and girlfriends. When I watched this film I found myself
cheering whenever the "enemy" appeared. And when "enemy" planes
launched their attacks on the Japanese carriers, I applauded loudly.
Now I know how American Indians feel when they see a film about
Custer's Last Stand.For a better film about Pearl Harbor, see TORA! TORA! TORA! (1970), a
U.S.-Japan co-production, which also shows the Japanese side of events,
but does it against the larger context of Japanese imperialist
aggression in Asia and a diplomatic comedy of errors. It doesn't soften
or gloss over what the Japanese did, nor does it ennoble the Japanese
pilots who bombed Pearl Harbor. It's a straightforward rendering of
events and it's much more instructive in that regard than this film.
Still, I BOMBED PEARL HARBOR does give us some revealing insights into
the nostalgic haze through which so many Japanese war veterans chose to
remember their efforts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1060482/comments</url><from>from Bronx, NY</from><name>Brian Camp</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I BOMBED PEARL HARBOR is one of the very few Japanese films about World
War II to be released in English and offers a fascinating window into
Japanese attitudes toward the war expressed some 15 years after their
defeat. Granted, this was seen on VHS in a cut, English-dubbed print
with some re-editing, so we can't be entirely sure about the points of
view expressed in the original. Numerous questions arise. For instance,
did the original open and close with Franklin D. Roosevelt's radio
addresses on the soundtrack as this version does? Or did Japanese
audiences hear Emperor Hirohito's speeches on the soundtrack? The film, as seen in this version, glosses over the causes of the war
and the reasons Japan was in it. There are no mentions of the United
States or of Americans at all and, of course, no mentions of Japanese
occupation of so many Asian countries during the war. The pilots
heading out to Pearl Harbor at the beginning are told it's their sacred
duty to Japan and the Emperor and that the fate of the Japanese empire
rests on them. They cheer a "successful mission" after the sneak attack
on Pearl Harbor, a sequence that takes up the first 19 minutes of the
film. Most of the rest of the film is taken up with the Battle of
Midway (which took place, as I write this on June 4, on this date 69
years ago). As the battle progresses, to Japan's not-so-inevitable
defeat, radio reports heard in Japan tell complete lies about the
outcome of the battle. It's evident to an informed viewer that the
Japanese military consistently lied to the people and brainwashed its
soldiers and pilots so that they could launch lethal attacks without
any moral qualms and without any realistic sense of what they could
accomplish against American industrial might. Yet the pilots are
treated as noble heroes throughout. There are sentiments of regret
voiced at the end of the film acknowledging what a mistake it all was,
but they come too little and too late to satisfy me.I watched the Hollywood film, MIDWAY (1976), right after this, in order
to get an American account of the battle. The two versions stick quite
closely to the facts and many of the Japanese military figures from I
BOMBED PEARL HARBOR are indeed in MIDWAY as well. MIDWAY even used some
shots from this film, along with quite a lot of actual color film
footage taken by American combat photographers during the battle
itself. Toshiro Mifune plays Admiral Yamaguchi in I BOMBED PEARL HARBOR
and Admiral Yamamoto in MIDWAY, 16 years later. He's dubbed in both
films by familiar voice-over actor, Paul Frees, the absolute wrong
voice for Mifune. (In MIDWAY, Frees' attempt at a Japanese accent is
completely at odds with the unaccented English spoken by all the
Japanese-American actors—James Shigeta, Pat Morita, et al--playing the
other Japanese officers.) Some of the reviews here cite the depiction of the Japanese pilots in
this film as "ordinary" and "honorable" men, who showed "humanity" and
"courage." I'm sorry, but that's like characterizing Nazi concentration
camp guards in a film about the Holocaust as "ordinary" and "honorable"
men who were just following orders. When you allow a fascistic
militaristic mindset to dominate your thinking and behavior, and when
you plunge wholeheartedly into campaigns of murderous aggression
against innocent peoples as the Japanese so frequently did (just ask
China) and call it your "sacred duty," you can no longer be called
"honorable" or "courageous." As a baby boomer who writes extensively
about Japanese film, television and pop music, but who grew up in the
shadow of the war and whose father trained marines to fight in the
Pacific, I have difficulty seeing the Japanese soldiers and pilots who
fought us back then as anything but the "bad guys," no matter how many
tears they shed over fallen comrades or letters they wrote home to
mothers and girlfriends. When I watched this film I found myself
cheering whenever the "enemy" appeared. And when "enemy" planes
launched their attacks on the Japanese carriers, I applauded loudly.
Now I know how American Indians feel when they see a film about
Custer's Last Stand.For a better film about Pearl Harbor, see TORA! TORA! TORA! (1970), a
U.S.-Japan co-production, which also shows the Japanese side of events,
but does it against the larger context of Japanese imperialist
aggression in Asia and a diplomatic comedy of errors. It doesn't soften
or gloss over what the Japanese did, nor does it ennoble the Japanese
pilots who bombed Pearl Harbor. It's a straightforward rendering of
events and it's much more instructive in that regard than this film.
Still, I BOMBED PEARL HARBOR does give us some revealing insights into
the nostalgic haze through which so many Japanese war veterans chose to
remember their efforts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1060482/comments</url><from>from Bronx, NY</from><name>Brian Camp</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>