<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Leech Woman</original_title><imdb_rating>4.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Edward Dein</director><producer>Universal International Pictures (UI)</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
An endocrinologist in a dysfunctional marriage with an aging, alcoholic wife journeys to Africa seeking a drug that will restore youth.
</synopsis><actor>Coleen Gray</actor><actor>Grant Williams</actor><actor>Phillip Terry</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0043975/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ronnie</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
There's a key scene in the film where Estelle Hemsley, as an old
African woman about to be given the gift a youth, states how a man
growing old gains wisdom and respect while for an aging woman there is
nothing. She is pitied. Unfortunately, this is, for the most part, true
today, especially in films. A much older actor can pair with a
decades-younger actress, and there's no fanfare. The opposite rarely
occurs, and if it does, there's much ado. In this film, Coleen Gray
receives this gift and does have to kill to keep her youth, but
*SPOILERS AHEAD* only to selfish, dangerous people: her cruel husband
(Philip Terry), a guide who ditches her (John Van Dreelen), a crook
(Arthur Batanides) and a jealous would-be killer (Gloria Talbot). She
won't harm her new boyfriend (Grant Williams), because she loves him.
Gray has several classics to her cinema credits, but she'll be
remembered for this role: convincing makeup are given full-bodied
mannerisms, voice inflections that amazingly reflect old, middle, and
young age. Yes, it's a small budget, with much stock footage, and could
have been more developed, plot-wise. But the cast is earnest,
particularly Hemsley, expert as the native old woman, Kim Hamilton as
her younger counterpart, Terry as the nasty, rotten-to-the-core
husband. But the aspects of male vs. female aging will stay with you
after the final fadeout.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1084015/comments</url><from/><name>SdrolionGM</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Unlike a lot of movies given a good workover by the fine folks on Mystery
Science Theater 3000, "The Leech Woman" is fairly watchable.  The idea is
that an aging woman who wants to restore her beauty finds a magic that will
allow her to become young again- but only for a day at a time.  The spell,
unfortunately, also requires her to kill men.Of course, she doesn't particularly care about the lives of men, which is
where the main plot starts.  I won't spoil it for you, because this is a
film I think you might actually enjoy.The movie suffers, unfortunately, from some drab performances by members of
the cast.  The main stars, however, play their roles pretty well, and the
elderly priestess featured in the beginning of the film is particularly
creepy.Also, the plot, though good in theory, seems to get bogged down at times.
The movie crawls along and can get very boring.  But there are some
excellent sequences in there that really bring the movie back from the
gutter.In any case, I recommend at least trying to find the MST3k version of the
film...during the more boring sequences you'll appreciate the boys' humor,
and even the good parts certainly aren't hurt by a little good-natured
jesting.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1908744/comments</url><from/><name>JAPfeif</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I won't go in to the plot much here, as anyone who is reading these
summaries knows it by now. I personally find this to be one of the more
satisfying of the 50's/60's-type Sci-fi films. I'm not sure why other
reviewers are surprised or disappointed with the stock footage in the
African scenes. It's a low-budget horror flick! Every low (or even some
medium-to-high)-budget film (&amp; not just horror/sci-fi) from that era
used stock footage to represent exotic locals. Why should anyone be
critical because "The Leech Woman" did the same? Also, unlike many
others, I found the acting to be quite believable, and subtle (ex:
Sally (to the rejuvenated June (a.k.a. Terri Hart), after seeing that
her fiancée is obviously attracted to Terri): "I'm Sally...I guess your
aunt described ME to you as well". Terri: "Yes she did". Sally: "Well
then I guess she mentioned that Neil and I are engaged". Terri: "No,
she didn't...why should she?" Sally (in a really catty tone) "Oh, I
don't know....I just thought I'd mention it"). Dialogue like this, with
it's underlying tone &amp; subtleties, are a joy in a cheap flick like this
one. I also found the weasle-like antics of June's doctor husband, who
obviously has ulterior motives for suddenly calling off their divorce &amp;
wanting her to come to Africa, quite fun to watch, especially in his
look of surprise when, after June is given her choice of any man for
the sacrifice that will make her young again, picks HIM (especially
after, just moment earlier, his idea of a "great escape plan" is to
leave his wife there occupying the savages while he &amp; the guide make a
run for it, with the promise that "we'll be sure to come back for you
tomorrow"!).The ending WAS a bit abrupt, but again, this was a cheap sci-fi flick,
coming in at the very tail-end of the Golden Age of Sci-Fi, and I think
that one needs to be realistic &amp; forgiving if it isn't up to the
standards of today's films, or even those made earlier when budgets
were a bit more generous. And as for the "no-name cast", as one other
reviewer put it, you've got Grant Williams from "The Incredible
Shrinking Man" and "The Monolith Monsters", Phillip Terry from 1944's
"Monster and the Girl", Gloria Talbott from "I Married a Monster From
Outer Space" and "The Cyclops", and Coleen Gray from 1957's "The
Vampire". Obviously someone doesn't know their classic Sci-Fi movie
stars! All in all, a very satisfying film, too good to have been
lampooned on that bastardization abomination, MST3K. Give it a try if
you haven't.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4145056/comments</url><from>from Brentwood, USA</from><name>AngryChair</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
While traveling through the African wilderness, an aging woman
discovers the secret of youth, but she will have to kill to stay young.A clever story and an outstanding performance from Coleen Gray uplifts
this old B thriller. You've gotta give Leech Woman a little more credit
for being a drive-in movie from the late 50's that doesn't rely upon
some 'monster' to drive it. Leech Woman is instead a more thoughtful
thriller that examines a woman's desperation. It's low budget indeed,
but does have some decent makeup FX, a nice music score, and a
better-than-average cast to hold it together.** 1/2 out of ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0340113/comments</url><from/><name>cinema-11</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I remember watching "The Leech Woman" when I was twelve years
old. There is something absolutely terrifying about this movie,
but yes I agree it isn't Oscar caliber. For a movie made back in
1960 I don't think it's that awful. (Ever mindful that another
movie one year later came out called "Psycho") There is
something sensual in the way men and women are punctured in the
back of the neck and then their blood is consumed by a woman. Or
perhaps at twelve my testosterone was starting to make itself
known. I vividly remember the very end of the movie with Colleen
Gray laying flat on her back looking like some old tattered
witch. It terrified me. Know why? Because the old woman that
lived next door to us looked very similar! For a long time after
seeing this movie I went outside wearing a turtle neck sweater!Not a great movie but certainly not as bad as others .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0214444/comments</url><from>from Hull, Québec</from><name>Philippe Gagnon (film_33@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This film has two chief assets: an excellent performance by Colleen Gray
and
Bud Westmore's expert makeup. The script, though, leaves a lot to be
desired. It's on the dull side and there is very little excitement or
chills. It just drags along. Grant Williams, here in a supporting part, is
bland as usual. And when Phillip Terry, who plays the lousy husband/doctor,
dies, I cheered! Of course the story is unbelievable. That's why they call
it science FICTION. A lot promised but little delivered. But see it for
Colleen Gray and some convincing old/young makeup.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12596887/comments</url><from/><name>JohnHowardReid</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Speedily put into production in order to offer exhibitors a
second-feature lure with bookings of The Brides of Dracula, this little
movie suffers from a tedious First Act. The initial scenes were
obviously designed merely to fill in time, so that latecomers would not
feel at any disadvantage. We're told absolutely nothing that doesn't
develop later on in the plot. A bit of judicious trimming here would do
wonders. And in any event, Coleen Gray doesn't seem nearly old enough
in these early scenes to make her motives credible. Fortunately, she is
marvelously made-up later on—and in these sequences she also gives by
far the best performance of her career.Despite Dein's flat-footed direction and the obvious constraints and
inhibitions imposed by a tight "B" budget, interest is kept at a high
level in the last half of the movie not only by Gray's forceful
portrayal (and the skillful way she is lit and make-up) but by some
neat yet unexpected plot twistsAlas, the film cheats on special effects, the transformations being
accomplished without camera trickery in a most tame and disappointing
manner.Nonetheless, although horror devotees will find the going pretty dull
until the halfway mark, the movie does eventually hit its stride. In
fact, I'd describe it as a key item for any keen fan's personal
collection.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4969213/comments</url><from/><name>mrb1980</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"The Leech Woman" is a film that's a lot better than its title. Coleen
Gray plays the older wife of Phillip Terry, a doctor who's been
experimenting with various mixtures in order to find the fountain of
youth. The acting is quite good by a group of old pros, and the film
throws in about everything: the older woman/younger man plot twist,
alcoholism, tribal rituals, emotional abuse, love triangles, several
murders, smart-mouthed cops, journeys into darkest Africa, revenge and
betrayal, explosions, quicksand...well, you get the idea. Gray does
quite well with a difficult role, with fine support from Terry, Grant
Williams, Kim Hamilton, and Gloria Talbott. I thought the ending was a
little weak, but otherwise it's an entertaining take on an unusual
story regarding rejuvenation. Worth catching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The low rating and numerous negative reviews around here as well as on
external websites warned me to approach "The Leech Woman" with caution
and an absolute minimum of expectations, but I honestly didn't think it
was such a bad movie. Admittedly the script is incoherent and extremely
predictable, but the rudimentary story lines are original and engaging
and - unlike so many other contemporary cheap Sci-Fi movies - this one
at least doesn't feature any overlong boring speeches and dull padding
footage. The screenplay of "The Leech Woman" is already pretty stuffed
as it is, with the tone of the film shifting no less than three times,
so there really isn't any room for boredom. It may perhaps offer just a
few surprises and even less shocks, but at least you won't constantly
be staring at the timer, wondering when it'll be over. The film opens
with a wondrous sequence of a married couple viciously bickering. He's
a heartless and obnoxious scientist continuously preoccupied with his
work (the secret to rejuvenation) and she's a depressed and alcohol
addicted wreck due to his cruelty. When Dr. Talbot meets the 152 year
old Malla, he realizes her native tribe holds the secret of eternal
youth and follows his patient to the heart of the African jungle. There
they witness a ritual that turns the old and wrinkled Malla into a
stunning beauty with just a few drops of juice coming from a dying
man's pineal gland. The slick Dr. Talbot wants the formula and attempts
to win his wife back in order to use her as a guinea pig, but the joke
turns against him when the rejuvenating woman needs to select a man to
sacrifice and, obviously, June picks her beloved husband. She returns
to the States as a young and stunningly beautiful young woman, but she
needs to kill random men and milk their pineal glands in order to stay
desirable."The Leech Woman" definitely has a pretty cool and eventful script; you
just need to overlook a copious number of plot holes, improbabilities
and continuity errors. There's no real suspense to enjoy, but
nonetheless plenty of action and a handful of impressive make-up
effects (especially the make-up that makes old women look even older).
However, the movie's greatest achievement is presumably an
unintentional one: pure and genuine irony! Although a story that
constantly revolves on beauty and popularity, the cast of characters
only includes shallow, substantially ugly and insupportable
individuals. At least Dr. Talbot is a bastard right from the start, but
all the others gradually turn into intolerable people. The pitiable and
humiliated wife becomes a relentless killer, the fragile old lady
becomes a stone-cold tribe leader, the helpful guide transforms into a
shallow runaway lover, the devoted attorney becomes an adulterous jerk
and the cherubic fiancée changes into a jealous fury. Honestly, I've
rarely seen such an unpleasant and even downright misanthropic
collection of people playing together in one film … and that's sort of
fascinating!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1195334/comments</url><from>from new jersey</from><name>phlflip</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Leech Woman was a great flick,regardless of what anybody says about
it.Colleen grays acting was powerful and convincing as the bitter alcoholic
wife of an opportunistic rat who wants to use her as a guinea pig for his
youth serum experiments.If you ask me colleen should have gotten a face lift
instead.And dig that estelle helmsley,she looked like a human prune.Gloria
Talbott also added interest to the film as the jealous rival.As for grant
williams,he was just a cad,typical easily tempted weak male.To constantly
have to kill people with a ring to stay beautiful,what,s wrong with makeup
and hair dye? As for colleens killing it was a toss up,some of the people
deserved it and some did,nt. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1195334/comments</url><from>from new jersey</from><name>phlflip</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Leech Woman was a great flick,regardless of what anybody says about
it.Colleen grays acting was powerful and convincing as the bitter alcoholic
wife of an opportunistic rat who wants to use her as a guinea pig for his
youth serum experiments.If you ask me colleen should have gotten a face lift
instead.And dig that estelle helmsley,she looked like a human prune.Gloria
Talbott also added interest to the film as the jealous rival.As for grant
williams,he was just a cad,typical easily tempted weak male.To constantly
have to kill people with a ring to stay beautiful,what,s wrong with makeup
and hair dye? As for colleens killing it was a toss up,some of the people
deserved it and some did,nt. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1195334/comments</url><from>from new jersey</from><name>phlflip</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>