<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn</original_title><alt_title>Les aventuriers du fleuve</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Michael Curtiz</director><producer>Formosa Productions</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Huckleberry Finn, a rambuctious boy adventurer chafing under the bonds of civilization, escapes his humdrum world and his selfish...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Tony Randall</actor><actor>Eddie Hodges</actor><actor>Archie Moore</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Purists of Mark Twain will find fault with this adaption of Huckleberry
Finn, but I like it and I think it captures the charm of Twain and the
moral lessons he was trying to teach.Small town America, it's strengths and weaknesses is a subject done to
death in novels, plays and film. I myself just did a review of This
Boy's Life which has some of the same themes as Huckleberry Finn.
Hannibal, Missouri of the 19th century sure had more charm than
Concrete, Washington of the 20th century. Yet Eddie Hodges as Huck Finn
had to leave it to fulfill his destiny as surely as Leonard DiCaprio
had to leave Concrete.In fact the most riveting performance in this film is Neville Brand as
Huck Finn's Pap. He's as bigoted and narrow-minded, though more
explicitly racist than Robert DeNiro in This Boy's Life. Today we would
call someone like Neville Brand, trailer park trash.Because the two are on screen for nearly the whole time, the players
essaying the parts of Huck and Jim have to be good and have good
chemistry. Archie Moore who was the reigning Light Heavyweight Champion
when this was made delivers a great performance as the runaway slave
Jim. As does Eddie Hodges as Huck. One theme of Twain's that remains
intact is Huck's growth as a human being after being thrown together
with Jim who he now sees as a person instead of property. In fact MGM put together an excellent supporting cast for tyro players
Eddie Hodges and Archie Moore. Tony Randall and Mickey Shaughnessy as
con men King and Duke are a joy to watch. The whole movie is.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1308795/comments</url><from>from Stockholm, Sweden</from><name>Kim Loughran</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

All the acting was superb. The sets were...well, it was 1960. But
the script! To hear Mark Twain so joyfully transposed, and so
artfully accurate for the film characters and actors! What a straight,
simple joy to see this film, made to entertain and doing it proudly,
with all concerned -- actors and director mainly -- working on the
same premise. And tell me Tony Randall didn't go home whistling
after every day on the set!
But this was Mark Twain done proud. How many other great
writers so easily lend themselves to film scripts? What a writer!
What fun he had with phrases, sayings and words. And how well
all that was put to use in this movie. And PS Archie Moore was a
great heavyweight. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0478557/comments</url><from>from Dillon, Saskatchewan</from><name>ram-30</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
From the man who directed "Casablanca" and "Yankee Doodle Dandy" comes
a colourful, humorous video version of Mark Twain's timeless novel. The
casting is superb. It's hard to think of any other actors from the
early 1960s in these roles, they are so well chosen. Especially
impressive is pro boxer Archie Moore as Jim. His scene where he's
talking about his deaf child is heart-wrenching, quite a feat for a
cross over athlete. The child actor who plays Huck is very good as
well. My honourable mention goes to Tony Randall and Mickey Shaughnessy
who make a great comedy team as the King and the Duke. They are simply
hilarious. Although many of Twain's adventures are deleted, most of the
better known and interesting characters and scenes are included. Many
of these characters are played by Hollywood legends like Sterling
Holloway(the voice of Winnie the Pooh and Jiminy Cricket), Judy Canova,
John Carradine, Neville Brand, and Buster Keaton. All in all, a highly
recommended family film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17470449/comments</url><from>from Urbana, Illinois</from><name>Kelsey C.A.</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn, the movie, has been criticized for
various reasons. Many believe that in making the movie humorous and
enjoyable for audience, it dissolves Mark Twain's message about slavery
and twists the plot line of the book. In my opinion, this is a great
movie that kept me laughing, crying, and on the edge of my seat. It is
true that this movie is very different than the book. For example, in
the book, Huck never becomes a cabin boy, and the Kind and the Duke
never try to kill Huck. These differences, however, kept me wondering
what would happen next. The ending was unpredictable, and that made the
movie interesting. Mark Twain's message about the moral injustices of
slavery is very prominent in the book, but not so prominent in the
movie. This movie, however, was intended for entertainment purposes. If
you have read this book, you will enjoy the movie. If you haven't read
the book, you will also enjoy the movie, but keep in mind that it is
nothing like the book. There has been much controversy about the
portrayal of Jim and how it denigrates blacks. I do not agree. Jim is
actually very smart, and he has another side that he doesn't let Huck
see. For example, Jim knows all along that Huck's father was dead, but
he cared about Huck enough to not tell him. The Adventures of
Huckleberry Finn is a great movie. I recommend it to all audiences!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9021665/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>kirk_bones</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
From the opening scene of the sun setting over the Missisippi,this film
takes you on a magical adventure that will stay with you long after the
final credits roll.Eddie Hodges is perfectly cast as young Huckleberry
Finn who sets off to find adventure along the Mississippi. He is joined
by Jim,Archie Moore, a runaway slave who wants to get to the free lands
and become a free man. This movie is filled with classic supporting
characters from two con men who want to rob the rich to line their own
pockets to a circus owner who paints a donkey black and white to make a
fake zebra. There are many classic scenes,almost too many to mention,
so i will name the most memorable.They include Huck and Jim finding the
reason for feuding,Huck dressing up as a girl to rescue a captured Jim
and Huck passing off Jim as the emperor of Patagonia. This film is also
filled with beauty ,physical and spiritual including the two friends
sitting on their raft talking about sin while looking at the stars .
The thing that overrides the whole movie though is the vibrant colour
that brings out the beauty of the river. At the end of this film you
would have to have a heart of stone not to shed a tear as the adventure
comes to an end. It may have a happy ending but hey don't we all
deserve a happy ending. My score has to be 10/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4196516/comments</url><from>from Prince George, BC, Canada</from><name>Corey Walker</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I just watched this movie on Turner Classic Movies and I really enjoyed
it. I don't know how closely it follows the book, as I haven't read
this book, just "Tom Sawyer", but I find the movie to be a great family
movie. It was fun watching Huck get out of one scrape just in time to
get into another. He was always on the run, along with the Widow
Douglas' slave, Jim. It made think back to my boyhood days and
honestly, it made my boyhood adventures look dull. The plot hearkens
back to a time when life was simple and offered more freedom to boys
then today's world does. I'm not sure the movie is entirely realistic,
but that's quite all right with me. The acting was well done, the
colour quality was great for 1960, and the whole plot flowed quite
smoothly. I didn't quite understand the ending, which I won't spoil for
you. If you like tales of boyhood adventure from an America the world
will never see again, you have to see Huck Finn. And it's got some of
the greatest actors of the day in it as well. What more can you ask
for.10/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17472702/comments</url><from>from Home of the Tigers</from><name>A M</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Although the movie was mildly entertaining, it is a very poor
representation of Mark Twain’s book on which this movie is “based.”
Crucial character elements are either weakly represented or altogether
missing from the movie. In the book, Huck Finn, a young boy, and Jim, a
runaway slave, travel far down the Mississippi River from their
starting point in Missouri. In this movie, they only get a mile or two
past Illinois. The book portrays Jim as a kind-hearted, loving person
who wants freedom for himself and his family. In this movie, he is seen
as a simpleton and gives the impression that the entire story is
racist. Although the movie may not show it, Twain was an abolitionist.
In the book, Huck overcomes the prejudices of his upbringing and helps
Jim to become free, even if Huck must go to hell for doing so.Eddie Hodges and Archie Moore performed decently in this movie from a
pure entertainment point of view, but neither of their characters
showed the elements which Train created in them. Michael Curtiz and
James Lee allowed elements of Twain’s book to be reorganized or left
out altogether. They even created two scenes which never existed even
in part in the book. If you don not mind mediocre acting, by all means
go ahead and watch this movie, but do not think for one second that it
reflects accurately the image or message which Twain created in his
book.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2193169/comments</url><from>from Kingsport, TN</from><name>james higgins (jameshiggins923@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
68/100. Although it takes quite a few liberties with the Mark Twain
novel, the appearances of many well known guest stars and an
exceptional quality in its production make it a very entertaining
movie. It appears they were trying to make it more of a movie geared
more towards family viewing. Fine cinematography and art direction. I was never bored, it wisely is
not too long. Eddie Hodges is a little weak as Huckleberry Finn, and
since it is such a pivotal role, that does hurt the effectiveness of
the film somewhat. Tony Randall is very good, Buster Keaton has a nice
bit as well, as does Andy Devine, Sterling Holloway and Neville Brand.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0631986/comments</url><from>from Evansville, Indiana USA</from><name>dwpollar</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
1st watched 1/27/2010 - 7 out of 10 (Dir-Michael Curtiz): Charming
adaptation of Mark Twain's novel is fun and well played for the most
part. The story revolves around an upstart boy of the title who has an
alcoholic father and overly religious aunt that brings him to a point
of faking his own death in order to escape and debark on an adventure
to New Orleans by way of the Mississippi River. He brings along a slave
named Jim and they meet up with various characters with Huck always
playing himself out of messes by pretending and making up stories.
Eddie Hodges as Huck and Archie Moore as Jim make up a good team as the
pair who really need each other. Jim was blamed for Huck's death so his
goal is to escape North into Illinois so he can be a free man as well
escaping the law. Huck is just avoiding his sad life in hopes for an
adventure. He actually makes the adventures happen as he goes along
including an escapade with a couple of crooks posing as the King of
France and a Duke. Huck is a pretty smart cookie, though, and knows
when to escape from them but they come back later in the story to try
and turn Jim into the authorities for the ransom money. Tony Curtis
plays the King and is supposedly the star of the movie but doesn't
really add much to the movie by his performance -- the real stars are
the actors in the main characters already mentioned. When the movie
ends, you want to carry on with the characters to see what happens to
them next and this shows the true wealth of the story. I don't ever
think Twain make a Huck 2 though, which is a shame.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Mississippi River rafting with Eddie Hodges (as Huck) and Archie Moore
(as Jim) impersonating Mark Twain's pair of runaway drifters. Despite
the obvious attempt to be a classy production, with a well-intentioned
assemblage of cast and crew, this version sinks like a pebble (if not a
stone). It's overcast and miscast, but occasionally satisfying. Lucky
young Hodges, who sang with Frank Sinatra, has a great scene with Andy
Devine and Buster Keaton. Apparently, 20th century filmmakers were too
shy to truly transfer all "The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn" to film.
What they hinted at (or left out completely) can be found by reading
the book - or, if you're lazy, listen to a vocal version of "Moon
River". We're after the same rainbow's end.***** The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn (6/17/60) Michael Curtiz ~
Eddie Hodges, Archie Moore, Tony Randall
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Mississippi River rafting with Eddie Hodges (as Huck) and Archie Moore
(as Jim) impersonating Mark Twain's pair of runaway drifters. Despite
the obvious attempt to be a classy production, with a well-intentioned
assemblage of cast and crew, this version sinks like a pebble (if not a
stone). It's overcast and miscast, but occasionally satisfying. Lucky
young Hodges, who sang with Frank Sinatra, has a great scene with Andy
Devine and Buster Keaton. Apparently, 20th century filmmakers were too
shy to truly transfer all "The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn" to film.
What they hinted at (or left out completely) can be found by reading
the book - or, if you're lazy, listen to a vocal version of "Moon
River". We're after the same rainbow's end.***** The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn (6/17/60) Michael Curtiz ~
Eddie Hodges, Archie Moore, Tony Randall
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1332132</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Colorful family adventure based on Twain's classic</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1408714</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>/m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1316876</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Movie Mom at Yahoo! Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117796680.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1805928</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/77527.html /m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1518124</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9E04E6D7163CEF3ABC4C53DFBE66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1389584</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=100214 /m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=1149400</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/79_ADVENTURES_OF_HUCKLEBERRY_FINN.html /m/1031435-adventures_of_huckleberry_finn/comments.php?reviewid=273771</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>