<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Le trou</original_title><imdb_rating>8.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Jacques Becker</director><producer>Filmsonor</producer><producer>Play Art</producer><producer>Titanus</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
Just as 4 cell-mates are about to launch their elaborate escape from a tiny cell, a detainee from a cell-block under repair is transferred in...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>André Bervil</actor><actor>Jean Keraudy</actor><actor>Michel Constantin</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0965356/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>palmiro</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This film is riveting in its attention to the details of a prison
escape and to the relations between the men involved. And even if
you're not interested in the Marxist vision that inspires Becker in
this last film of his, you will still be captivated by the story. In
any case, to understand Becker's vision, I will necessarily have to
give away the story so beware (and my analysis also makes the film
sound much more schematic and polemical than it will appear to you on
viewing it):***SPOILER***At the beginning of the film one of actors (clearly a car mechanic)
approaches the camera and tells us that we are about to see a true
story, his story. We are led to believe that it is the story of an
escape from prison, and indeed we are taken to Paris' largest prison
where a group of 4 cellmates, already plotting their escape, finds that
they are unexpectedly joined by a new cellmate: a well-dressed (all
prisoners wear their street clothes), somewhat effete, young man who
nominally sells cars at (presumably) his father-in-law's dealership--in
any case, it's clear that he doesn't really have to work or at least
work hard for a living. On the other hand, the other four are clearly
working-class guys who've drawn a bad card in life. After debating
among themselves whether to let the pretty boy in on their plot, they
decide to do so after they learn that he's in for attempted murder and
stands to have a strong reason to want to break out.Becker shows the extraordinary ingenuity of the working-class prisoners
in contriving tools, in developing a postal system between cells, and
in setting up a way of telling time where there are no clocks or church
bells. The implication is: we, the working class, have the minds, the
manual dexterity, and the willingness to work and to build our own
civilization (minus the bourgeoisie). Meanwhile, the bourgeois type is
astonished at how the working-class types are able to organize and
think for themselves ('I've never met men like you before')- -and,
above all, he is moved by their willingness to share their victuals and
their plans for freedom with him. And it is just this solidarity and
mutual support which Becker believes represents an alternative way to
organize human society--an alternative to the self-centered world of
the bourgeois. Note, for example, the character of 'Joe' who opts to
not join in the escape because the police would harass his mother to
death, but who still does not rat on the others even though it's clear
he will have to do additional time and time in solitary after the
breakout. Becker has a nice touch as well in the way he portrays the
prison guards, also from the working-class: generally friendly towards
the 'boys' in prison, with perhaps an authoritarian streak in them but
no suggestion of a sadistic, brutish nature. So when 'Roland' says,
'Poor Gaspard,' after the latter has betrayed them (it was clear that
he'd been tempted earlier to do so when he saw the taxi from the
manhole cover), it is evident that the only real 'brute' is the
bourgeois, who, in the end, will always turn on his pals (and his
fellow man in general)if it serves his interest and who is bereft of
the fellow-feeling which undergirds working-class life. So what about
the claim that this is a true story? The actor who plays 'Roland' is a
non-professional, but it's hard to imagine that he could be as young as
he is if he had actually attempted 3 previous escapes and had to serve
another long stretch for the failed attempt portrayed in the film.
Instead, it's the 'true story' of the working class: a class dominated
by the bourgeoisie but which resists and has the capability to guide
itself without the bourgeoisie; a class which embodies the values of
solidarity and the dignity of work--values which can become the
foundation of an alternative civilization.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0675231/comments</url><from>from Padova, Italy</from><name>pzanardo (pzanardo@math.unipd.it)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Probably, to really get "Le Trou", this splendid, intense movie, you
have to be conscious that the great Jacques Becker was dying during the
making of the film. A quiet stoicism permeates this work of art. The
story is supposed to be very sad, but it isn't. The guys on the screen
are too tough, by no means apt to mourn their dire destiny or,
metaphorically, to ask for the viewer's sympathy.We have the true story of the hole dug by a bunch of in-mates to escape
from a jail in Paris. The screenplay is taken from a novel of the
distinguished writer and film-maker Jose' Giovanni, himself formerly a
convict. Becker chooses to tell the story in the simplest, neatest
possible way. No music at all, an essential, dry, sharp yet powerful
dialog. The in-mates do their job, to try to escape. The director
avoids the annoying cliché, typical of the American jail-movies, of
showing the wardens as sadistic torturers. They are tough and strict,
they don't like but they feel no hate for the prisoners. The wardens
just do their job, that's all. In fact, there are no really despicable
characters in the film. At his last appointment with the art of cinema,
Becker seems to accept and forgive all human beings.A brilliant idea is to show how the guys turn common objects and waste
iron into the tools needed for the escape (a key, a lamp, a pick, a
sand-glass). The little periscope made with a tooth-brush gives raise
to a shocking scene, few seconds of great cinema. We follow the
in-mates' apparently endless, exhausting labor of digging and sewing.
That should be rather boring for the viewer, but it isn't. How comes
there's not a single moment of bore in the film? That's the privilege
of Art. The work of the camera and the black and white photography are
sensational, and convey the intense emotions of the characters. The
psychological study is made in such an understated way that you may
overlook it at a first view. But, after seeing the movie a second time,
and knowing the development of the story, you fully appreciate how the
psychology of the characters is treated, with accuracy and depth. The
actors make an excellent job. This is stunning, thinking that "Le Trou"
was the first movie for Philippe Leroy and Michel Constantin, later
prominent actors of French cinema. And Jean Keraudy wasn't a
professional actor, he was one of the in-mates that actually dug the
hole fourteen years earlier! (at least, this is stated by himself at
the beginning of the movie, and is testified in several books on French
cinema) Are there deep messages in the film? Two wardens bring a fly to feed a
spider. There is the spider, a patent symbol of death, ghastly in its
immobility. Two prisoners are peeping and wondering: what the hell are
the wardens doing? Got no idea. And who cares, after all? Maybe that is
Becker's dry, ironic message. Don't be too deep. Fight against bad
luck, be stoic and brave. Who cares, after all?My opinion is that the artist Becker, displaying the same toughness of
the guys on the screen, just fought to leave us a major work of art.
Our task of viewers is to enjoy and love it. "Le Trou" is an
unforgettable film, which honors the art of cinema.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0129701/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY USA</from><name>Kevin Rayburn (kprayb01@homer.louisville.edu)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Jacques Becker's "Le Trou" is one of the greatest of all prison-break
films.
No film lover should miss it. It is every bit as masterful and tense as
other milestones of this subgenre, including John Sturges' "The Great
Escape," Robert Bresson's masterpiece "A Man Escaped," and Don Siegel's
"Escape from Alcatraz." The meticulous preparation for the escape is a
nail-biter, with many adrenaline-inducing close calls. The ringer: Will
the
newly exonerated prisoner stay with the group and escape or rat on the
others? Those seeking pure entertainment or those seeking existentialist
philosophical fare will be equally pleased. A memorable movie experience.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1506923/comments</url><from>from Hemet, Ca.</from><name>muddlyjames</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This most powerful of escape stories is a wonderful exposition of the most
basic human qualities, ingenuity and cooperation, and the innate drive
toward freedom that brings these qualities into being.While the theme of transcendence is certainly present (although not
be-labored) as in A MAN ESCAPED, it is interesting that, in direct contrast
to Bresson's work, transcendence is here achieved through work WITH others
on a task. The inmates form a unique brotherhood through their joint
reliance. This allows them to be IN the prison while not OF it and is
quietly visible from the early moments of the film. We see this group bond
deepened through each risk taken, each chisel blow against a concrete wall,
and we become emotionally tied to the characters' quest simply through
observing their effort (it is amazing how dramatic hammering away at a
concrete wall can be). No verbal exposition is necessary, no creation of
characters and their pasts intrudes to distract us from their task, which
IS
the drama.Indeed Becker's film is as notable for what is left out as for what is
included. There are no prison "types" created, his style is restrained to
the point of being transparent, not to the point of calling attention to
itself as "bare" or "ascetic" as Bresson's is. We get no exposition of the
horrors of prison life; just enough detailing of the regimentation,
drabness
of environment, and lack of personal space to make us aware of the
institution's suffocating presence. There are no sudden surprises or plot
shifts. Well, maybe one. The shot in the mirror near the end of the film is
so surprising that I literally couldn't take it in for a few seconds, I
thought it had to be a dream: that's how involved with the characters I
was!
Finally, there is no use of music to pump up the suspense. There IS,
however, a powerful and unique use of sound. We hear, in an almost
hallucinatory fashion, every thump, clang, and wail within the prison walls
and, during the digging scenes, Becker apparently uses a dual soundtrack
combining naturalistic sound with heightened effects of the digger's
grunts,
heavy breathing, and THUMPS of metal against rock. Again this serves to
effectively involve us with physical/emotional effort of their task. The
cacophony the end of the film harshly accents our sense of disturbance and
loss.It is also worth noting that the apparent "innocent" in the film is the
only
one who does not achieve transcendence. While he may legitimately gain his
freedom, he remains locked within the bounds of his own ego ("poor Pierre"
says the leader of the break). Another interesting contrast (reply?) to
Bresson.Altogether a powerful statement that humans at work can be intrinsically
dramatic subject matter, that the most simple of subjects can be the most
visually entrancing (and emotionally resonant) and a grand illustration of
the maxim that "God (and/or art) is in the details". 10/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Immediate background:Jacques Becker was dying when he filmed "le
trou,and he made it his legacy;it's the tragedy of man caught on the
web of life -an admirable metaphor shows two wardens feeding a spider
in the undergrounds with a fly-,and anyway unable to escape from the
final death.The first thing to bear is mind is that,calling "le trou" a "prison
movie" would be an insult.Although adapted from a Jose Giovanni's book
-Giovanni had been himself in jail for some time and his depictions are
as close to reality as can be-,Becker masterfully transcends his
subject and gives something definitely new.Some said it was the final
link between "la nouvelle vague" and what the highbrows pejoratively
-and thoroughly unfairly- call "cinema de qualité" but Becker had
predated that overrated new wave by almost ten years :"rendez-vous de
juillet" had already almost everything the young Turks would bring
later.First shock is the use of the wide screen,the cinemascope,which Becker
had never experimented before;and he achieved the impossible: using
this device for a story which takes place ,either in the four walls of
a jail,or in the undergrounds and the sewers .The only picture of the
outside is seen when the two inmates open a manhole.And the second one
is the sound:there's no music at all,except for the final cast and
credits -saving the cast and credits for the end was very rare in the
contemporary French cinema -But the soundtrack resembles some kind of
musique concrete with its relentless thumps, the whispers and the
screams inside the cell,the creaking of the doors ,the waters in the
sewer;and the final cacophony -which is not unlike the one which
Manliewicz used in "suddenly last Summer" the year before- packs a real
wallop.Another Becker's tour de force is his description of the prison life:he
avoids all the clichés that mar so many "prison movies" (the
overpraised "Whatsisname redemption" is no exception):here, the wardens
are,most of the time ,kind and friendly,the relationships with the
inmates remain polite ,maybe sometimes too much:particularly those
between the young man (Marc Michel) and the head warden are almost
paternalistic.Another Becker's permanent feature comes back to the fore in "le trou"
:friendship,solidarity ,which was already present in "rendez-vous de
juillet" and "touchez pas au grisbi".Here it's pure manly friendship
and it seems that a certain misogyny is infiltrating Becker's
world:during the 2 hours + running time of the movie,we only see one
young girl (Catherine Spaak) behind a grille,for a very short while.The
only positive woman whom we' ll never see is (naturally) one of the
five inmates ' s(Michel Constantin) mother("I almost killed her when I
was sent to jail so I do not want to take a chance and try to escape")SPOILER:But even this world where five inmates share everything,where
their friendship is "more than I 've ever had "(Marc Michel's
character) is collapsing;the first cracks were already here in
"rendez-vous de juillet" when some of the young students were giving up
on their plans ,to the main hero's (Daniel Gelin)disappointment.But
"touchez pas au grisbi" took friendship over everything including
money."Le trou" reveals the true nature of man,even if the informer
seems completely desperate at the end of the movie.The mammoth task
they did ,the hole '(le trou) is nothing but a cul-de -sac and it
epitomizes,in a Hustonian way -we're closer to Huston than to Godard
,fortunately,the vanity of everything man can do to escape from his
fate,and in the case of Becker ,to escape from death.END OF SPOILERHad Becker ended his career with his three precedent movies
(Ali-Baba,Arsène Lupin ,Montparnasse 19),his former masterpieces
(Casque d'or,Goupi Main Rouges ,rendez-vous de juillet),could have been
tarnished by association.But "un trou" ,his final masterpiece stands in
little danger of bringing this about.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1246976/comments</url><from/><name>taylor9885 (taylor9885@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Le Trou played on TV the other night, and thus gives me a chance to evaluate
it after 20 years or so. The direction is magnificent: Becker was a genius
at refining the elements of the story down to a bare minimum. Space is used
well; the close-ups of men banging on concrete with improvised tools in a
cramped space are very effective, they look like burrowing animals. Ghislain
Cloquet was a master of black-and-white camerawork; he shot Mouchette and Au
hasard, Balthazar for Bresson, Nuit et brouillard for Resnais, Le Feu follet
for Malle, all great films made greater by Cloquet's work.The endless dull routine enlivened by subterfuge--stealing materials needed
for digging and making puppets to stand in for sleeping prisoners is
brilliantly captured. If the prisoners are bored, so are the staff--the
warden is desperate for some conversation with Gaspard, or with anybody.
Geo's problem is a little hard to understand, I thought he'd want to go
through with the plan. Otherwise I rate it very highly
indeed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1257700/comments</url><from>from Croatia</from><name>arminio</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I watched this masterpiece first time before 10 years and I was stunned.
Now, I watched it before few days again and I am really surprised how this
remarkable movie functions and become better and better.
It is really ingenious portrait of human interaction and cooperation,
great
"prison-escape" drama that bring us unique way of telling story (in long
shots) looking so realistic and powerful.One of the best movies I've ever seen!10/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The thing that surprises me the most about "Le Trou" is how minimalist
it is. Unlike most other prison dramas (such as the overrated
"Shawshank Redemption"), this isn't weighed down by pointless subplots
or needless histrionics. This simply presents a group of characters,
their plan to escape from prison, and the execution (and aftermath) of
the plan. Best of all, it proves you don't need all that needless
filler to make a thrilling story like this. The movie isn't about
anything but the break, and manages to be completely engrossing for an
entire two hours plus running time. This is a raw, gritty, and entirely
realistic depiction of a stock story thats been done to death. Nearly
fifty years later, its still the best prison break film ever made.What elevates this is the sheer virtuosity in the craft of the film.
This was the legendary French director Jacques Becker's last film, and
while he didn't plan for it to be his swan song, there couldn't be a
more fitting one imaginable. All his themes and techniques from his
previous work are fully in bloom here. Becker truly created a
masterpiece. The performances are very good for the material they're
given and have more depth and nuance than initially appearing. The film
is all about simplicity and character interaction, which is exactly
what makes it a masterpiece. (9/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239428/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio USA</from><name>harry-76</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Before his life was cut short prematurely, Director Jacques Becker created
his very personal film, "Le Trou" ("The Hole").  Using mostly then
nonprofessional actors, M. Becker elicited extremely naturalistic and
powerful performances in a reportedly true-life prison-escape drama set in
France. It was especially interesting to see Marc Michel in his film debut.  Made
four years before Michel scored a hit as Roland in "Les Parapluies de
Cherbourg," Michel here subtely creates a fascinating character.  His work
is seemingly effortless, yet always intriguing.  He stands at the center of
a group of convicts planning a daring escape--a group which has difficulty
in fully trusting his loyalty.The routine of prison life as well as the actual escape is done with such
detail that the viewer feels part of the action. The black-and-white
photography enhances the realism of the presentation, done without a musical
background.Generally a "forgotten film," "Le Trou" is a carefully constructed prison
drama, most convincingly executed.  It is a credit to both a hard working
cast and director. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3093460/comments</url><from/><name>Myshkin_Karamazov</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Jacques Becker's swan song is a real gem of a film. Le Trou has such an
amazing kinetic rhythm to it that one both feels and forgets the
claustrophobic environs. Based on a real story turned into a novel by
one of the "escapees", the film has excellent casting, wonderful
(candel-lit!) cinematography and crisp dialog among its other
advantages.The director was terminally ill during the shoot and was to die after
making the final cut. Watching this classic now some four decades since
auteur's death, one can only wonder what an artist it would take to
demand and achieve such breathtaking perfection in art while combating
death at the same time.Do not let yourself be put off by "yet another prison-movie!" talk. It
is too good to be just that. So much so that it could merit comparison
with Bresson's "A Man Escaped". A very deserving 10 out of 10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3093460/comments</url><from/><name>Myshkin_Karamazov</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Jacques Becker's swan song is a real gem of a film. Le Trou has such an
amazing kinetic rhythm to it that one both feels and forgets the
claustrophobic environs. Based on a real story turned into a novel by
one of the "escapees", the film has excellent casting, wonderful
(candel-lit!) cinematography and crisp dialog among its other
advantages.The director was terminally ill during the shoot and was to die after
making the final cut. Watching this classic now some four decades since
auteur's death, one can only wonder what an artist it would take to
demand and achieve such breathtaking perfection in art while combating
death at the same time.Do not let yourself be put off by "yet another prison-movie!" talk. It
is too good to be just that. So much so that it could merit comparison
with Bresson's "A Man Escaped". A very deserving 10 out of 10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3093460/comments</url><from/><name>Myshkin_Karamazov</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>