<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Let's Make Love</original_title><alt_title>Le milliardaire</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>George Cukor</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox</producer><producer>Company of Artists, The</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Musical</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
When billionaire Jean-Marc Clement learns that he is to be satirized in an off-Broadway revue, he passes himself off as an actor playing him in order to get closer to the beautiful star of the show, Amanda Dell.
</synopsis><actor>Marilyn Monroe</actor><actor>Yves Montand</actor><actor>Tony Randall</actor><rt_rating>5.6/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>67</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0991726/comments</url><from>from Syracuse, NY</from><name>Allison Galland</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Unlike many others who have left comments about this film, I really
enjoy it.  This is definitely not high on the intellect scale, but it is a
sweet romantic comedy.
I agree this is not Marilyn's best film, but her performance in the
role is better than anyone else could have done it; very cute and
believable.  Some of the writing really seems to target Marilyn's
own personal life (I don't know if they did that on purpose),
especially when she talks about going to night school.  Also during
the song "Incurably Romantic," Marilyn's dress is flying up (a
parallel to "The Seven-Year Itch?").  Her performance of the song
"My Heart Belongs to Daddy" is just great.  It's really a lot of
fun.
The cameos are awesome, they really make the film into a "time
capsule" of the most popular comedian, dancer, and singer of the
time.  Tony Randall has a nice supporting role throughout the film;
he is great in the scene where he sees Jean-Marc Clement's
"softer side."
Yves Montand and Marilyn Monroe have the strangest relationship
in the movie, and you have to feel bad for Jean-Marc!  He is not
used to NOT getting the girl!  Yves plays this very well, I think.  They
may lack some chemistry, but the two characters are cute and
likable and you really want them to get together.  
So what I'm saying is, this is well worth seeing, especially if you
are a fan of Marilyn or Yves, just don't expect it to be intellectually
challenging... it is a great rainy day flick. :-)

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1849630/comments</url><from>from Berlin</from><name>gnb</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Released in 1960 after Marilyn's super turn in the fantastic 'Some Like
It Hot', LML has often been cited as Monroe's worst movie.There is plenty to work against the film: Cukor's almost non-existent
direction, the rather dreadful musical numbers, Yves Montand's
irritating performance and the wasted opportunities of the star cameos.However, Let's Make Love is a reasonably inoffensive way to waste an
afternoon. The plot is slight and therefore doesn't require too much
brain power to follow and Monroe is, as usual, cinema gold. Despite the
fact that she is slightly overweight here and nothing much has been
done with her in terms of make-up, hair or wardrobe she is eminently
watchable. She gives a convincing, assured performance in her role
turning the simple character of Amanda into a sweet, likable woman. As I have mentioned before in Monroe reviews, I always find it
interesting to see Monroe in films in the 1960s, being very much an
icon of the 1950s.So, is LML really that bad? Well, to be honest no, it isn't. It's
lightweight fluff that doesn't really mean anything but is watchable
non the less. It is unfortunately placed between the sublime 'Some Like
It Hot' and Monroe's bravura performance in the following year's 'The
Misfits' but don't hold that against it. Make up your own minds!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2061510/comments</url><from>from Hoboken, nj</from><name>denis-38</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is one of my favorite Marilyn films.  No, let me amend that--this is
one of my favorite Marilyn performances.  She is sweet, natural,
sympathetic, adorable. She has no character to play and no script and no
director (Cukor was sliding fast at this  point)  But she and Montand are
lovely together; two great charmers surrounded by an overblown 60's
confection of "guest stars" and constant costume changes (although some
of
Marilyn's outfits  are so flimsy one wonders  why they bothered to dress
her
at all?!)  "My Heart Belongs To Daddy" is classic MM, but I have a
perverse
fondness for "Specialization" with Monroe hopping around (she  really
couldn't dance) in this INCREDIBLE gown, belly and backside bulging, a
Reubens come to  life.
It's a very minor film, especially sandwiched between "Some Like  It
Hot"
and "The Misfits"  but there is pleasure to be found if you're into Miss
M.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1758188/comments</url><from>from Port Jefferson, NY</from><name>wglenn</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

This is by no means a great film, but I was pleasantly surprised in the end.
 Montand and Monroe both do good jobs.  Tony Randall is always enjoyable,
and Milton Berle has a great time teaching Montand how to be funny, the best
comic moment of the film.  Having just seen Montand in The Wages of Fear,
one of the most intense movies ever made, it was interesting to see him
goofing off and having a good time.  This role takes him back to some of the
songs he sang early in his career, not long after Edith Piaf discovered him.
 I only wish he had been able to sing more in the movie.  I'm not a big fan
of Monroe - her dumb-blonde routine generally irritates me - but she seems
more vulnerable in this film, more pleasant to watch.  She particularly
impressed me in the musical numbers.  Unfortunately, the costume designer
did a lousy job - everything seems too big on her, or just tacky.  Compare
these costumes to those of Bardot in Une Parisenne, made around the same
time period.  There are ways and then there are ways to show off a body like
that of Bardot or Monroe.  All in all, this is a light piece of fluff, with
some humorous moments, some sappy moments, some good musical numbers, some
bad writing, some good cameos by Berle, Bing, and Gene Kelly, a silly
storyline, Yves Montand, Monroe, and a good dose of fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6643268/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>Lady Targaryen</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Since I am watching all Marilyn's movies, ''Let's Make Love'' was the
second one from the collection to be watched. Marilyn is beautiful as
usual, and we have Cameos from Gene Kelly,Bing Crosby and Milton Berle
as themselves.The movie starts telling the story of Jean Marc's ancestors, and how
his family started to become richer with the time, until his present
days as a billionaire. Jean Marc has power,money and also is a
'Casanova', with a new woman to go out everyday. One day, he discovers
that he is going to be satirized in an off-Broadway theater, and he
goes to see how the play is going to be, until he sees Amanda singing
and dancing in a provocative way and the director,who thinks that Jean
Marc is an actor trying to take the role of himself,cast him as a
member of the show. Decided to go out with Amanda and make her fall for
him, he pretends to be someone else,using the identity of Alexander
Dumas and acting as a poor actor who wants new lessons from Amanda to
improve his acting career. With the time, Jean Marc starts to fall for
Amanda, since she is the only woman who was kind to him without
expecting money or gifts in return. The problem now is his fake
identity.PS: I only have to complain about the ending of this movie, which, in
my opinion, was far from good: I don't think that Amanda should stay
with Jean-Marc, since she always refused and hated rich guys like him,
calling him arrogant and liar,among other things. I think she changed
her idea too quickly about him,after knowing Alexander Dumas' original
identity was Jean Marc, but anyway, no movie is perfect.aka "Adorável Pecadora" - Brazil
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4303635/comments</url><from>from South Korea</from><name>sinatra-11</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie in Aug 4,2005. And I saw it again yesterday. Yes. this
is one of the most hilarious movies I've ever seen. Marilyn's acting
role, as Amanda Dell, was great. Here in this movie, Marilyn Monroe was
not the Marilyn Monroe we know.In Niagara(1953) and The seven year itch(1955), both of these movies,
she portrays as sexy-starlet. But in this movie, she is a very pure and
fragile theater-actress Amanda Dell. Well, we know her platinum blonde
hair attracts a lot of men, but her character,in this movie, is very
friendly to girls. May be many girls lost their feeling of inferiority
after watching this movie.And I saw Marilyn Monroe, Yves Montand, Tony Randall, Frankie Vaughan
and Wilfrid Hyde-White plus Milton Berle(40 million Americans call him
as a Uncle Milky?) Bing Crosby(i love his song 'White Christmas')and
Gene Kelly. These luxurious casting combination is very fantastic.I never expected Crosby and Kelly to appear. I saw a preview version of
Let's Make Love, in there, no cameo appearances of in the preview. But
Kelly and Crosby's cameo appearing made my eyes happy.I think Marilyn's acting career is more valuable in her 30's than
20's.Because in her 20's, she portrayed us her physical attraction.
Sometimes she enticed a man(Niagara), Sometimes vivacious(How to marry
a millionaire), and sometimes valiant(River of No Return).But in her 30's her character showed fragile, pure and vulnerable. I
found out these phenomenon in this movie,Let's Make Love. So I can
figure it out her acting was changed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0415847/comments</url><from>from Boston</from><name>Alice Copeland Brown (alicecbrown@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Without what we know about her now, this movie wouldn't be worth the time it
took to watch it.  However, now we know about what was going on while the
movie was being shot, you can see the attraction between her and Msieu
Montand, whose wife took him back afterwards.  It's funny, since I've seen
him in a French movie, where HIS wife was unfaithful and how he copes with
that.  What goes around comes around, I suppose.Montand has to act silly, which must have been as painful for him as it was
for his character, a multi-billionaire trying to win Miss Musical Star,
Marilyn.  Watching the male singer in this movie was funny, as it reminds
you of the 40s and the Dean Martin style crooners.  Watching Bing Crosby and
Milton Berl teach Yves how to sing and be funny was a hoot!!!  "Don't
'bubba-boo-boo', or you'll get arrested," Bing suggests.
Watching Milton berl walk on his ankles wasn't all that funny, but this was
the 60s after all.I liked the musical numbers, and watching Yves' face do all its rubbery
wrinkling numbers.  He may have been a great actor because he could put on
so many different expressions, but his best movie was the one where he's
trying to run for office in a crooked Banana Republic (sorta like our
present government), a Cost-Grava film.  See this one just to remind you of how beautiful, how vulnerable, Marilyn
was: 2 years from her suicide????!!!!  She really had some nice moves, and a
great figure when a tummy wasn't considered obscene (in our day of anorexic
sexy?? stars).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5219360/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Trey Mercartne</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I was pretty unimpressed with this movie, to be frank. There was
something about every aspect of it that didn't quite add up and you're
left with an essentially dull film, which you're not really too
concerned about by the end. I am a huge fan of Marilyn but I don't feel
she was at all her best in this picture, and I don't think that's
entirely her fault - the film around her is incredibly flimsy. The
dialogue is often wooden and unconvincing, and Montand's character and
his storyline are just totally unbelievable - nothing of what he says
or what he does was convincing to me and this really brought the film
down very hard and very quickly. The musical numbers are pretty
standard fair and were nothing Marilyn hadn't done before. The film
didn't make me laugh and I didn't care what happened to the characters.
If anything I was only sad the talented Marilyn Monroe was a part of
the film - as her portfolio shows she was deserving of far higher
quality films than this. I can't recommend the film as it's not really
worth your time and you probably won't enjoy it - if you just want to
see all of Monroe's film's than see it, but otherwise don't bother.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Let's Make Love, the next to last film of Marilyn Monroe is a harmless
piece of fluff, rather lazily directed by George Cukor. Marilyn was her
usual temperamental self during the filming and I think Cukor decided
to just let it slide.Think mega-rich, a 1960s Donald Trump who speaks French and you have
the character Yves Montand plays. Publicity agent Tony Randall calls it
to Montand's attention that an off Broadway theater review is going to
be satirizing him among other celebrities in the review. Montand
decides to check things out for himself. And the star of the review is
none other than Marilyn Monroe who Montand starts raising his blood
pressure over. Who wouldn't.20th Century Fox used this same plot device in 1937 in On the Avenue.
That time it was rich débutante Madeleine Carroll and her choleric
father George Barbier are being satirized in a show being directed by
Dick Powell who stars in it as well. It was much better done there. Of
course they also had an original Irving Berlin score to help. And
Barbier was always playing those kind of roles. It fit him naturally.Montand is cool and unflappable. I can believe he wants Marilyn, but I
can't believe that this is how he would meet her. Unless one is an egomaniac like Donald Trump, I don't think most people
would care about what some off Broadway show that few will ever see,
says in some satirical sketch.A lot of talented people were involved in the making of this and it
seems a colossal waste of time. Marilyn and Montand and British pop
star Frankie Vaughan had some nice numbers to sing.And we can't forget the three unbilled cameos of Milton Berle, Bing
Crosby, and Gene Kelly who Montand enlists in his quest to win Marilyn.
Their scenes with Montand are the best thing about the film.One other thing though. I can believe Berle and Kelly would come if
summoned by Montand. But Crosby, you're talking about a guy who was as
rich the character Montand played.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"I hope you can kiss better than you can sing." When I heard this line
from the film regarding Yves Montand, I had to laugh, as in real life
Montand sold a bazillion records over his long career.In LET'S MAKE LOVE he plays a mega-millionaire who tries to pretend to
be a stage actor--paying the likes of Milton Berle, Gene Kelly and Bing
Crosby to give him lessons on comedy, dance and singing. So why would a
rich guy like this go to all this trouble? Well, when the industrialist
(Montand) hears that an off Broadway play will be lampooning him (as
well as others), he's curious and sneaks in to watch rehearsals. There
he sees sexy Marilyn Monroe and is so struck by her he doesn't tell
anyone who he really is. And, in a strange twist, the producer decides
to hire him to play himself--not realizing Montand really is the
millionaire! He decides to go with it and says nothing to the company,
as he plans on staying with the production and wooing Marilyn. The
trouble is that he's NOT a professional and so he hires the best people
to train him--and that's where Berle, Kelly and Crosby come into the
film.This story idea is actually reminiscent of a great old film, THE DEVIL
AND MISS JONES--where a rich department store owner decides to pose an
a regular employee in order to spy on "rabble-rousers" in the company.
Though the stories differ quite a bit, both certainly have
similarities. Bkoganbing's review indicates that LET'S MAKE LOVE is
very, very similar to 1937's ON THE AVENUE, though I can't really say
since I haven't yet seen this film.The problems with the film are abundant even though I still think it
earns a 7. That's because the plot is so very likable you can ignore
the ridiculousness of the plot (it really is tough to believe) as well
as that many of the song and dance numbers don't seem all that great.
While Miss Monroe has a HUGE cult-like following, I don't think her
singing and dancing were all that great--but she was nice to look at
and did a better job at acting. Overall, it's a nice little romance and
worth a look.FYI--Casting Montand is an interesting choice to play a nice
industrialist, as he was a member of the Communist party in France up
until 1968!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"I hope you can kiss better than you can sing." When I heard this line
from the film regarding Yves Montand, I had to laugh, as in real life
Montand sold a bazillion records over his long career.In LET'S MAKE LOVE he plays a mega-millionaire who tries to pretend to
be a stage actor--paying the likes of Milton Berle, Gene Kelly and Bing
Crosby to give him lessons on comedy, dance and singing. So why would a
rich guy like this go to all this trouble? Well, when the industrialist
(Montand) hears that an off Broadway play will be lampooning him (as
well as others), he's curious and sneaks in to watch rehearsals. There
he sees sexy Marilyn Monroe and is so struck by her he doesn't tell
anyone who he really is. And, in a strange twist, the producer decides
to hire him to play himself--not realizing Montand really is the
millionaire! He decides to go with it and says nothing to the company,
as he plans on staying with the production and wooing Marilyn. The
trouble is that he's NOT a professional and so he hires the best people
to train him--and that's where Berle, Kelly and Crosby come into the
film.This story idea is actually reminiscent of a great old film, THE DEVIL
AND MISS JONES--where a rich department store owner decides to pose an
a regular employee in order to spy on "rabble-rousers" in the company.
Though the stories differ quite a bit, both certainly have
similarities. Bkoganbing's review indicates that LET'S MAKE LOVE is
very, very similar to 1937's ON THE AVENUE, though I can't really say
since I haven't yet seen this film.The problems with the film are abundant even though I still think it
earns a 7. That's because the plot is so very likable you can ignore
the ridiculousness of the plot (it really is tough to believe) as well
as that many of the song and dance numbers don't seem all that great.
While Miss Monroe has a HUGE cult-like following, I don't think her
singing and dancing were all that great--but she was nice to look at
and did a better job at acting. Overall, it's a nice little romance and
worth a look.FYI--Casting Montand is an interesting choice to play a nice
industrialist, as he was a member of the Communist party in France up
until 1968!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/lets-make-love-6/ /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1989255</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Cukor's movie is less successful as a musical than as a star vehicle (one of her very last) for Marilyn Monroe, who is at her sexiest.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-bourne/</url><url>http://www.dvdjournal.com/quickreviews/l/letsmakelove.q.shtml /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1527591</url><name>Mark Bourne</name><from>DVDJournal.com</from></reviewer><comment>Cukor ... directs with all the panache of an unwanted contractual obligation. Indeed, Marilyn disliked the script but accepted Let's Make Love to fulfill her Fox contract.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dan-lybarger/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=835723</url><name>Dan Lybarger</name><from>Nitrate Online</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Monroe is typically captivating even if this isn't vintage Cukor.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pablo-villaca/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=834866</url><name>Pablo Villaca</name><from>Cinema em Cena</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Apesar do excesso de números musicais, o filme é leve e divertido, trazendo Marilyn Monroe em uma de suas performances mais sedutoras (em seu penúltimo papel no Cinema).</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/letsmakelove.htm /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=801334</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>If you can live with the plot making absolutely no sense, then you should be able to handle this uneven attempt at being a screwball comedy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=792574</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Movie Mom at Yahoo! Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Marilyn's Heart Belongs to Daddy number (and her practice leotard) are worth the price of the video.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=4269 /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=735860</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
69/100
					</rating><comment>Let's Make Love doesn't come close to Marilyn Monroe's best moments, but those who like corny old romances could certainly do worse.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Lets-Make-Love /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=309612</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>Safe to skip.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-szymanski/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1443581</url><name>Michael Szymanski</name><from>International Press Academy</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1401464</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1189813</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=746801</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/80334/lets_make_love.html /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1479815</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9A01E1DA1F3EEF3ABC4153DFBF66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/lets_make_love/comments.php?reviewid=1388652</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>