<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Un taxi pour Tobrouk</original_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Spain</country><country>West Germany</country><director>Denys de La Patellière</director><producer>Continental</producer><producer>Franco London Films</producer><producer>Procusa</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>The most exciting, explosive journey the screen has ever taken through a minefield of human emotions.</synopsis><actor>Hardy Krüger</actor><actor>Lino Ventura</actor><actor>Maurice Biraud</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
At the beginning there are a brief biographic remarks about the
characters. Sergeant(Lino Ventura) commands a group of French
soldiers(Charles Aznavour,Maurice Biraud,German Cobos)escaped after
destruction their unity . Then they penetrate German lines going to El
Alamein.The expedition must contend with warming desert, minefield,
German patrols and a German officer(Hardy Kruger) in their midst. The
misfit group with a prisoner cross the Lybian desert to rejoin his
command after the fall their regiment. Their objective is to avoid the
Germans and somehow encounter Allied lines. As they travel through the
desert, they find an oasis where is a German army and get oil, thanks
they impersonate Nazis.This is an enjoyable movie about friendship, warlike feats, courage and
good feeling. Extraordinary acting for all casting, as Lino Ventura
plays a sergeant and boxer in civil life , he's an experienced soldier
who fought in Norway(Narvik) and another European scenarios; German
Cobos as a tough soldier who wishes strong methods over the German
prisoner; Maurice Biraud as the medic of the group; the singer Charles
Aznavour is a Jew-French and Hardy Kruger as an intelligent Nazi
captain who lived longtime in Paris. The interesting story displays a
quietly observant character studio and a light critical remarks about
the Frenchmen . Packs a great number of haunting black and white images
by cameraman Marcel Grignon and appropriate musical score by George
Garvarentz. The motion picture is well realized by Denys De La
Patelliere(Rififi in Paris,Marco Polo) and assistant director by Pierre
Granier-Deferre(Le Train).The story is proceeded during the African war, the events were the
following : Mussolini occupied Tobruk as part of his campaign to invade
the Suez canal, but the British easily took it from him on January 21,
1941. Hitler sent Rommel and the Africa Korps to retake the city and
after a siege of 242 days they entered the city in December 1941. In
1942, the British surrender the city because they needed troops to
fight the Japanese and Rommel retook Tobruk in June 21, 1942.
Montgomery launched a successful contra-offensive against the Germans
that were defeated by Eight Army in the battle of El Alamein which
occurred in July, 1942. It was not until November 13, 1942 that
Montgomery and his Eight army were able to secure Tobruk once and for
Allies. Another films dealing the African campaign include : Desert
rats(Robert Wise),Tobruk(Arthur Hiller);Raid on Rommel(Henry Hathaway),
Rats of Tobruk(Terence Young), and Battle El Alamein(Giorgo Ferroni).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1808226/comments</url><from>from Belgium</from><name>pete36</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Story takes place during 1942 in the Libyan desert at the crucial
battle in El Alamein, when the British finally defeated the German
"Afrikakorps". But this is a French movie so it deals with the Free
French troops who were fighting alongside the allied forces.The basic storyline is quite simple : during a raid on a German supply
dump, the French CO gets killed and the remaining members of the squad
have to make their way back to friendly lines. Along the way they lose
their patrol car but then capture an enemy truck, together with a
German captain (Hardy Krüger).Lino Ventura, one of France's most famous actors, is the grumpy
ex-prizefighter turned NCO (very close to his real-life personae). He
was already a respected actor but this really launched him to French
super-stardom. Also well-known singer Charles Aznavour co-stars, but
movie's main reputation lies with its script and dialogues (a mix
between comedy and tragedy) by Michel Audiard, who was the scriptwriter
of countless other successful Frrench movie classics (usually starring
JP Belmondo or Jean Gabin).This war movie may not so be well known outside of France, but up to
this day it remains a true French classic. French public TV choose to
air 'Taxi to Tobruk" on May the 1st this year, an important holiday in
France.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14920874/comments</url><from>from Germany</from><name>RogerFranzose</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A really funny war movie and even today still worthwhile seeing. Tells
a lot about the mentality of Germans and french...! Not only in the
army but also about the people - even today. The 'movie-buffs' will
know what I mean...a pity this film is far underrated and not very well
known. Intense acting, riveting plot, keeps one glued to the story!
Hardy Krueger and Lino Ventura are simply great actors! Hopefully these
comments may change that the movie is better known in the future
because it has all the chances to become a "war classic". Does anybody
know if the film is available at least on (an European language
version) VHS-video?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3827310/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>paws-7</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This film is simply one of the best I've ever seen about WW2. It shows,
with few characters, few accurate words and in the overwhelming
emptiness of the desert, the true face of war: total nonsense!The plot, which puts 4 French soldiers in the situation of taking a
German prisoner, together with his car, on a trip through the desert
back to El-Alamein, is brilliantly written by Michel Audiard. The
author shows us how enemies, being held away from fighting, can learn
to progressively appreciate themselves... or not. Irony and emotion
just stick together along the whole film to the end. True, human and
disabused.I don't have anything more to say. Or just one thing: it's the fourth
time I watch that film, it's the fourth time I'm caught by it until the
last second!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3397133/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>hstaurati</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Un taxi pour Tobrouk was one of the very first war movies I watched as
a child, and I was impressed with the depth of the characters that were
portrayed in it. No stereotypes here; just a movie about an unlikely
band of people, trying to survive in the dessert. One thing that I will
never forget, (please do not count it as a spoiler!!!) is when the
French soldiers discuss about what they should do with their prisoner,
and they say that "you should kill them before you get the chance to
know them". If that does not portrait the madness of war, then I
wonder, what is? Others have already written a lot about the plot, so I
will not go into details. All I can say is that it is bad that this
movie is not available on a subtitled version, for all of us, the poor
people who do not know French, to buy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3397133/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>hstaurati</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Un taxi pour Tobrouk was one of the very first war movies I watched as
a child, and I was impressed with the depth of the characters that were
portrayed in it. No stereotypes here; just a movie about an unlikely
band of people, trying to survive in the dessert. One thing that I will
never forget, (please do not count it as a spoiler!!!) is when the
French soldiers discuss about what they should do with their prisoner,
and they say that "you should kill them before you get the chance to
know them". If that does not portrait the madness of war, then I
wonder, what is? Others have already written a lot about the plot, so I
will not go into details. All I can say is that it is bad that this
movie is not available on a subtitled version, for all of us, the poor
people who do not know French, to buy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>