<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Wernher von Braun</original_title><alt_title>L'homme des fusées secrètes</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><country>West Germany</country><director>J. Lee Thompson</director><producer>Morningside Productions</producer><producer>Fama-Film</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
The life story of the famed rocket scientist Dr. Werner von Braun, one of the most brilliant and controversial figures of the space age...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Curd Jürgens</actor><actor>Victoria Shaw</actor><actor>Herbert Lom</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0851910/comments</url><from>from tampa, florida</from><name>tsmiljan</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A passe hagiography of the life of Werner von Braun, a great rocket
engineer
with a questionable past. It's original title was "I Aim For the Stars."
The
best line I ever heard about this film was: "I aim for the stars, but
sometimes I hit London."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2366327/comments</url><from>from Regina, Canada</from><name>sprpick</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
As Michael J. Neufeld's important new biography "Wernher Von Braun:
Dreamer of Space, Engineer of War" demonstrates, Columbia Pictures "I
Aim For The Stars" has only a passing relationship to reality.Neufeld says that at first Von Braun was fascinated with the idea of a
bio-pic when it was pitched to him by Columbia in the late '50s. He
thought it would do a power of good for his ceaseless efforts to
promote space travel to the American public. As production advanced,
though, he realized the movie was going to draw unhealthy attention to
his Nazi past and he was disenchanted by the hostile sub-text inserted
by the screen-writers and director: that he was a well-meaning wimp who
gave into Nazi evil.He was no wimp, as the book shows, but he was far more involved with
the Nazis than is shown in the movie.Far from being the reluctant civilian member of the Nazis pressed into
the Party late in the war, Von Braun, Neufeld says, was a sometimes
uniformed member of the SS who was promoted and decorated several
times.The movie does correctly depict Von Braun being tossed into jail
briefly for getting on the wrong side of Heinrich Himmler, but it
probably wasn't as traumatic as this film suggests. Von Braun kept
going on to bigger and better things in Germany right until the end of
the war.The movie doesn't touch at all on what was the most shameful part of
Von Braun's life and career: his complicity in the atrocious treatment
of slave labourers in the underground Dora rocket plant in Germany in
1944 and '45.To this day, documentary film is frequently shown on TV of emaciated
prisoners near dead but weeping in relief as they are liberated by
Allied soldiers. A surprising amount of this footage was taken at Dora.Von Braun generally disavowed any knowledge of prisoners being
mistreated and executed in his rocket factories, but Neufeld suggests
he actually knew quite a bit about it and felt guilty about it until
the end if his life.As Neufeld says, Von Braun loathed the movie (possibly out a guilty
conscience) and tried to distance himself from it and forget the whole
thing. Fortunately for Von Braun, any controversy that followed the
release for "I Aim For The Stars" quickly blew over. It also helped
relatively few people saw it because it was box office turkey, except
in Germany where he remained a national hero.The movie survives, although barely as a long undistributed (1992) VHS
tape. I managed to see a bad dub on to DVD. And while on the whole, the
movie is silly -- especially the bogus love story between the mythical
British spy in Von Braun's rocket plant and an equally mythical rocket
scientist "colleague" -- it is an interesting historical document
that's given new currency by the Neufeld biography.Hopefully, Columbia will see fit to re-issue it on an official DVD or
at least make it available for download as that technology improves and
becomes more widely available.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17461442/comments</url><from/><name>rlymzv</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This movie starts with the younger years of von Braun's life when he
was experimenting with rockets and propulsion.The film shows the March 1944 arrest of von Braun by the Gestapo. The
alleged crime was that Von Braun had declared his main interest in
developing the V-2 was for space travel, not as a weapon. Also, since
von Braun was a pilot, it was suggested that he was planning to escape
with V-2 secrets to the Allies.After a recording of von Braun referring to Adolf Hitler in an
insulting manner is heard, the scientist is told he will be executed,
but through Dornberger's influence, Hitler becomes convinced that von
Braun's intellect puts him in a class of people too important to be
executed.After surrendering to the Americans, Von Braun refuses to consider
himself a war criminal, but Maj. William Taggert, a former newspaperman
whose wife and baby were killed in a London bombing raid, argues that
because von Braun "invented an infernal device used to support an
iniquitous regime," he was a war criminal.Wernher von Braun was responsible for the space age becoming a reality
in the 20th century. Von Braun was named by Life magazine as one of the
"100 Most Important Americans of the 20th Century," touting him as the
man who "launched the greatest adventure of all, a journey to the
Moon".This interesting film includes some of von Braun's strongest critics
but is balanced with von Braun's contributions to the American space
program. The film ends in 1958, however von Braun when on to design the
Saturn V moon rocket that put a man on the moon (the Saturn V still
remains the most powerful rocket ever built, and it never had a
critical failure).Anyone interested in space travel will enjoy this movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
As one of Herr von Braun's erstwhile targets I am conscious of the fact
that any film glorifying his achievements in the totally ludicrous so-
called "Space Race" (America's captured ex-Nazis vs Russia's captured
ex-Nazis)may not get a completely objective review from any Brit old
enough to remember his "kinder" the V.1 and V.2s raining down on
southern England in the service of his beloved vaterland. The fact that
thousands of untermenschen died in slave labour conditions working
directly under his command seems to have escaped the makers of "I aim
at the stars".Shame on them.Curd Jurgens....well,maybe just a smidgen
of pride in his fellow countryman's attainments helped assuage any
artistic or moral doubts he may have had about portraying a mass
murderer as a man with a social conscience who rather too swiftly
embraced the doctrine of Pax Americana. If there are any redeeming
features to this movie they passed me by. The overriding impression I
got was that on the last day of World War 2 there were 3 million Nazis
in Germany and on the first day of peace there weren't enough to start
a poker school.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0435484/comments</url><from>from Kingston, Ontario, Canada</from><name>Dennis Clark (dclark@sprint.ca)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie describes the life of Wernher Von Braun very well. It also
gives relevant historical background on man's early forays into
space.
It is a good movie for anyone who is interested in the development
of
the science of rocketry because this man was highly instrumental in
developing the Saturn V booster which took man to the moon in the late
1960s.
I have been trying to find a VHS version of this movie without
success so if anyone knows of where I might obtain it your suggestions
would be appreciated.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
It's a pity that this story of Dr. Werhner Von Braun was not made some
20 years later when we could have a full record of the man's
achievements. The film would also be the story of the US beating the
Soviet Union to the moon. Where it stops in 1960 we were just starting
to play catch up.Let me say that looking at Werhner Von Braun, Curt Jurgens looks
absolutely nothing like him. But at the time Curt Jurgens was the best
known German name internationally in the cinema. My guess is that one
of the reasons he took the role was to give Germans a rehabilitated
hero of sorts.Von Braun was not a hero to Germans as say Max Schmeling or Erwin
Rommel, two Germans tainted with Nazism and used for a time, but never
really part of the Nazi movement. But Von Braun's achievements in
rocket science did gain an admirer in Adolph Hitler who like most other
leaders of government look to science to help war making capabilities.
Though most aren't quite as brutal.It was a good thing that Von Braun did get arrested by Himmler's SS
towards the end of the war. It made most Americans willing to trust him
with our own science during the Cold War.With a brief prologue showing a teenage Wernher's interest in rocket
science, the film is a biographical study of Von Braun from his days in
Peenemunde developing the V-2 rocket weapons for the Nazis right up to
the US Army's successful launch of the Explorer satellite which gave us
an orbiting satellite to match the Russian Sputnik.When the story sticks to Von Braun's achievements it's fairly accurate,
but the producers felt a little espionage sideline involving shapely
woman spy Gia Scala was also necessary. She gets fellow Peenemunde
scientist Herbert Lom's hormones going and later on she's in a position
to put a good word in for Jurgens and the rest of his colleagues. Also
Von Braun did not marry Mrs. Von Braun played here by Victoria Shaw
until after World War II. As I write this, the widow Von Braun is still
alive.James Daly as an American officer in Army intelligence is loath to use
Nazi scientists, he regards anyone connected with Hitler in a minor way
as evil. His role is similar to the one Richard Widmark played in
Judgment at Nuremberg. Daly comes off as incredibly self righteous, but
he does ask disturbing questions.Werhner Von Braun did not have the biggest of budgets and was shot in
black and white to take advantage of newsreel footage. Still the cast
does this one in earnest and for those interested in the early days of
the space race, this is a film for you.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13319872/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Larryr33323</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
As a member of the National Association of Rocketry (hobby group). I
enjoyed this movie's historical footage for its value to the scale
modeler (model rockets that fly). It also tries to capture some of the
internal struggle within the man. With working with the military while
fostering his dreams of manned flight after the War.For a more un-laundered perspective seek out _Man/Moment/Machine_ and
the von Braun episode concerning the V-2 on the History Channel.The only time I've seen this movie on television was about ten years
ago on the _Super Station_ (WTBS). I don't recall if his rank as a
Colonel in the S/S was indicated in this film. Enjoy it for what it is.
A glorification of one of the most important persons responsible in our
beating the _Russkies_ in getting to the Moon first.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"I Aim at the Stars" purports to be the story of Werner von Braun, one
of the men responsible for getting the U.S. into space. In many ways,
it is, but like many geniuses, von Braun lived a life full of
controversy. To the film's credit, that controversy is somewhat handled
here, though not enough.The film covers von Braun's obsession with space travel, his work for
Germany during the war, which resulted in rockets being used as war
weapons, and he and his teammates handing themselves over to the
Americans after the war. One word comes to mind: collaborator, but in
von Braun's case, it goes a little deeper. Some people, such as opera
star Elisabeth Schwarzkopf, collaborated with the Nazis. von Braun
collaborated with anybody who could help him further his work. When
that was no longer Germany, he was out of there.It's foolish to go into all the aspects of von Braun not covered in the
film. There are many more objective accounts of his life and work with
the Nazis and whether or not he had to join or was a devoted member of
the party. Curt Jurgens does an excellent job as von Braun, depicting
him as a strong and determined man dedicated to his work first, last,
and always.The beautiful Victoria Shaw has a small role as his wife, Maria; James
Daly plays an American soldier violently opposed to von Braun working
for the U.S. Herbert Lom plays a member of von Braun's team who refuses
to go to America, and he's very good.There is some great rocket footage; many of the scenes in the film are
short, almost like television scenes. It's not a big-budget movie.
There is a love story subplot between a spy and one of von Braun's
team; in fact, there was a spy, a female dentist, who reported some of
his negative comments to the Nazis.Werner von Braun was an individual of great accomplishments who helped
the U.S. win the war in space. In the film, he is depicted as a
reluctant Nazi, and it's true that he was, in fact, arrested by the
Nazis for saying things against the party privately. In the end he was
an opportunist and a survivor who did what had to be done to achieve
his goals. Like many biographies, this film is merely one view.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"I Aim at the Stars" purports to be the story of Werner von Braun, one
of the men responsible for getting the U.S. into space. In many ways,
it is, but like many geniuses, von Braun lived a life full of
controversy. To the film's credit, that controversy is somewhat handled
here, though not enough.The film covers von Braun's obsession with space travel, his work for
Germany during the war, which resulted in rockets being used as war
weapons, and he and his teammates handing themselves over to the
Americans after the war. One word comes to mind: collaborator, but in
von Braun's case, it goes a little deeper. Some people, such as opera
star Elisabeth Schwarzkopf, collaborated with the Nazis. von Braun
collaborated with anybody who could help him further his work. When
that was no longer Germany, he was out of there.It's foolish to go into all the aspects of von Braun not covered in the
film. There are many more objective accounts of his life and work with
the Nazis and whether or not he had to join or was a devoted member of
the party. Curt Jurgens does an excellent job as von Braun, depicting
him as a strong and determined man dedicated to his work first, last,
and always.The beautiful Victoria Shaw has a small role as his wife, Maria; James
Daly plays an American soldier violently opposed to von Braun working
for the U.S. Herbert Lom plays a member of von Braun's team who refuses
to go to America, and he's very good.There is some great rocket footage; many of the scenes in the film are
short, almost like television scenes. It's not a big-budget movie.
There is a love story subplot between a spy and one of von Braun's
team; in fact, there was a spy, a female dentist, who reported some of
his negative comments to the Nazis.Werner von Braun was an individual of great accomplishments who helped
the U.S. win the war in space. In the film, he is depicted as a
reluctant Nazi, and it's true that he was, in fact, arrested by the
Nazis for saying things against the party privately. In the end he was
an opportunist and a survivor who did what had to be done to achieve
his goals. Like many biographies, this film is merely one view.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>