<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Kala Bazar</original_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>Vijay Anand</director><producer>Navketan</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A man sells movie tickets on the black market, but starts to have a change of heart after he falls in love.
</synopsis><actor>Dev Anand</actor><actor>Waheeda Rehman</actor><actor>Nanda</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0204122/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Suresh C. Verma</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Dev Anand again plays the role of an anti-hero with a lot of restraint and
deftness. A rare film, by Indian standards, where the heroine is shown
falling in love twice. Wahida Rehman is initially in love with Vijay
Anand,
who, having gone abroad for higher studies, falls in love with another
woman, and so does Wahida, who, after initial reluctance, falls for Dev
Anand. The film is also notable for the fact, that in this film, all the
three Anand brothers, Chetan, Dev and Vijay acted together. Chetan Anand
gave an excellent performance in a cameo role of an Advocate, who fights
for
the reformed Dev Anand. With excellent screenplay and dialogues, the film
showed the calibre of the young director, Vijay Anand, who was directing
his
second movie only. Another highlight of the film was its music by Sachin
Deb
Burman. Mohammad Rafi's "Apni to har saans ik toofan hai" and "Khoya khoya
chand, khula aasmaan" are excellent numbers. Another good song by him is
"Sooraj ke jaisi golai, chanda si thandak hai paai". His duet with Geeta
Dutt "Rimjhim ke tarane leke aai barsaat" to date remains one of the best
rain songs. Asha Bhosle's solo "Sach hue sapne mere, jhoom le O' man mere"
is one of her best songs. Her duet with Manna Dey "Sanjh dhali, dil ki
lagi"
is a typical experimental number by Burman da. The film also has a
beautiful
bhajan in "Na main dhan chahun, na ratan chahun", sung by Geeta Dutt and
Sudha Malhotra.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10901395/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>xpics</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Kala Bazar meaning 'black market' essentially dealt with black
marketing of movie tickets which Dev Anand does in the film. The story
follows the template of a protagonist who takes the wrong path to make
money and then realizes his mistake for which he has to pay back.Raghuvir (Dev Anand) loses his job and is in dire straits when he sees
a man (Rashid Khan) selling tickets in black outside a cinema-hall.
Seeing that as a good source of quick money, he too decides to black
movie tickets. But for that he needs capital to start with. So he robs
Advocate Desai (Chetan Anand) of Rs 5000 and soon sets his own network
of black marketers outside all prominent cinema-halls of Bombay.One day, outside a theatre, he stumbles upon Alka (Waheeda Rehman) who
hates black marketing. Raghuvir is attracted towards Alka but Alka is
in love with Nand Kumar (Vijay Anand) who goes abroad to study.
Meanwhile Raghuvir attempts to woo Alka on their trip to Ooty but in
vain. Though he is unable to win Alka, his feelings towards her makes
him a changed man and he gives up the path of black marketing.Kala Bazar was Vijay Anand's second directorial venture post the
success of his debut venture Nau Do Gyarah. His writing was
multi-layered where he enmeshed a charming love story inside the
central plot of going the wrong (illegal) way in life. There were some
very unconvincing conflicts like how the 8th pass Raghuvir showed a
sudden keen interest towards gaining knowledge because of Alka.
Coincidentally he also accidentally stumbles upon a BA scholar (Krishan
Dhawan) who takes his tuitions. But the pacing was very fast and kept
the viewer engaged.Like in Nau Do Gyarah, where he stationed a major portion of the film
in the hill station of Mahabaleshwar, here Vijay Anand explores the
beauty of the South Indian hill station Ooty. Dev Anand kept strolling
through gardens of Ooty in the song 'Khoya Khoya Chand' in his
trademark swaying motion where he kept swinging his arms all through.
It might appear kind off funny today but back then it was Dev Anand's
patented dancing style which he continued for years to come. The scene
immediately after the song was considerably bold by the 60s standards
where Waheeda Rehman removes her sari to use it as a cord to pull Dev
Anand up, when he slips down from the cliff.The love story in the film was refreshingly restrained and despite a
love triangle, Vijay Anand never loaded the proceedings with melodrama.
The screenplay never makes a huge hue and cry of the scene when Waheeda
Rehman rejects Dev Anand and yet remains his friend or subsequently
when she gets back to Dev Anand and disowns Vijay Anand. The director
had a very matured and progressive outlook towards relationships.The film also deals with its title conflict of black marketing very
smartly. Dev Anand's repentance for his misdeeds and the way he
convinces his gang to give up the wrong path is very interestingly
portrayed. The courtroom drama in the climax (where Chetan Anand fights
for Dev Anand) is thoughtfully conceptualized and very well-worded with
a balanced and impartial point of view. It neither glorifies or
glamourizes Raghuvir's black-marketing nor does it ignores his remorse.Through black marketing outside cinema-halls of Mumbai, the film
captures the glory of good old movie theatres of the city, some of
which (like Liberty and Metro) exist even today. Vijay Anand also very
intelligently incorporated the real-life premiere footage of the film
'Mother India' in the initial reels of Kala Bazar thereby adding
immense (cameo) star value to the film showing the likes of Dilip
Kumar, Nargis, Guru Dutt, Rajendra Kumar, Sohrab Modi, Kishore Kumar,
Mohammad Rafi, Lata Mangeshkar and many more names. Years later
Manmohan Desai and Farah Khan replicated the same formula in their
films Naseeb (1981) and Om Shanti Om (2007) respectively and to good
effect.Like any Navketan production, even this film was blessed with melodious
tunes by S D Burman. The soundtrack had everything from love songs to a
bhajan to a Helen cabaret number. 'Khoya Khoya Chand' and 'Rimjhim Ke
Tarane Leke Aayi Barsaat' are timeless tunes. The picturization of the
song 'Teri Dhoom Har Kahi' starring Dev Anand and his sidekick Rashid
Khan was borrowed by Rakesh Roshan in a similar theme song 'Yeh Paisa
Bolta Hain' starring Kader Khan and his sidekick Johnny Lever in his
1989 film by the same title Kala Bazar.Dev Anand was charming as always and gave a splendid performance in a
character that had an interesting graph. Waheeda Rehman looked
beautiful and was natural as ever in her performance. Vijay Anand and
Chetan Anand were good in their special appearances. Nanda played a
supporting part as Dev Anand's sister and was decent.- Gaurav Malani
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12629447/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>nat_carni</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A very heart warming movie with great acting and absolutely lovely
songs. A must see for cinema that portrays the grittiness of life. Dev
Anand's acting is restrained and effortless. He displays all the charm
that he is rightly famous for and looks quite the dandy in his ascot,
coat draped over this shoulder's and bouffant hair style. None of the
phony and overdone glitz of today's movies - simple, charming and a
strong commentary on the insidiousness and vagaries of corruption in
India. It must have been quite daring in 1960. The music and songs are really wonderful and worth the effort to see
this film. The song shot in Ooty is very well formatted as is the foot
path scene in Mumbai illuminated by the street light. This is a classic
of Indian cinema as is Dev Anand's other movie of 5 years later -
GUIDE. Both are must see movies for those who enjoy Hindi films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12629447/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>nat_carni</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A very heart warming movie with great acting and absolutely lovely
songs. A must see for cinema that portrays the grittiness of life. Dev
Anand's acting is restrained and effortless. He displays all the charm
that he is rightly famous for and looks quite the dandy in his ascot,
coat draped over this shoulder's and bouffant hair style. None of the
phony and overdone glitz of today's movies - simple, charming and a
strong commentary on the insidiousness and vagaries of corruption in
India. It must have been quite daring in 1960. The music and songs are really wonderful and worth the effort to see
this film. The song shot in Ooty is very well formatted as is the foot
path scene in Mumbai illuminated by the street light. This is a classic
of Indian cinema as is Dev Anand's other movie of 5 years later -
GUIDE. Both are must see movies for those who enjoy Hindi films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12629447/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>nat_carni</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>