<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Zazie dans le métro</original_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Louis Malle</director><producer>Nouvelles Éditions de Films (NEF)</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis>
This merry farce depicts a satirical view of the French society: Twelve years old Zazie has to stay two days with her relatives in Paris...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Catherine Demongeot</actor><actor>Philippe Noiret</actor><actor>Hubert Deschamps</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0323948/comments</url><from>from Dobbs Ferry, NY</from><name>Robert Hirschfeld (boberich@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw "Zazie" in Paris in 1962, and my French at that time was
rudimentary. Nevertheless, for sheer manic energy, wonderful visual
comedy, and performances that transcended the language barrier, I loved
it. I've seen it since and still love it. Among its other virtues for
me, this film introduced me to the marvelous actor Philippe Noiret.
Malle proved to be a director with virtually unlimited range with
respect to style and mood. Consider some of his other fine films:
"Lacombe, Lucien," "Atlantic City," "Murmur of the Heart," and "My
Dinner with Andre," to name only a few. I guess what Richard Lester did
with the Beatles might be close to this when it comes to sheer antic
charm, but I think "Zazie"still stands alone. Unless you have zero
tolerance for whimsy and insist on Deep Meaning in your movies, I think
that you're likely to enjoy this one...if you can find it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0599456/comments</url><from>from Montréal, Québec</from><name>sm.starman</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Raymond Queneau is my favorite writer.  He was one of the rare giants of
french litterature who could make you really laugh out loud while you were
reading one of his classics.ZAZIE DANS LE MÉTRO was his funniest novel, but if you are not fluent in
french, you will miss a lot of the jokes; Queneau loved to play with the
language.Fortunately, Louis Malle has done a good job in adapting the humor of
Queneau, translating the novel into a more visual, slapstick, cartoon-like
movie.  An intelligent comedy that is it's own unique category.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0330035/comments</url><from>from Cap-de-la-Madeleine, Canada</from><name>Mario Bergeron (MarioB)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

In the early sixties, New Wave French Cinema were very
serious
about themselves, with Godard and Truffaut.  But Louis
Malle,
who was from the same generation, don't take anything seriously
in this unforgettable movie.  I really love the viewer
analogy with the Roadrunner!  Everythings goes nuts in
this movie: Sounds, situations, logic, actors.  It reminds
us of the Mack Sennett movies.  It's also got a lot of
charm
for the very funny and smiling face of little Demongeot
playing
Zazie.  And how about young Philippe Noiret? He will become
one of the greatest French actor of all time.  Like the
Jacques Tati's movies of the same era, this comedy can't
grow
older.  Seeing today is seeing it with the same joy as
in
1960.  A must!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399279/comments</url><from>from Milano, Italy</from><name>Mario</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

A product of the French New Wave, this movie is more than 40 years old, but
it still has the powers to make you leave your mouth open, either to laugh
or just to be in awe.
Extremely different from anything you can find on the screens today, "Zazie"
is able to entertain you even without a coherent plot or a bunch of lines
that make sense.
A dark-short-haired witty little girl goes around an extremely colorful
Paris meeting unusual and funny people. Does this remind you of anything?
Actually "Zazie" had already gone beyond the borders of the land that would
be explored by "Amelie" 40 years later. Maybe this means that the future is
behind our backs? It is time to turn around.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7201317/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>evanh-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I've just seen this movie on DVD and enjoyed the humor and wit.
According to some Dutch and French web-pages like
http://perso.orange.fr/cinefrance/1960/zazie.html Zazie is not played
by 12yo Catherine but by a 9½yo Milène, what seems right to me by the
looks of her, she's definitely too petite for a 12yo, age 9 or 10 seems
much more likely. In the trailer she is described as a 9½yo too. Her
lines seem a little too adult now and then, but bear in mind who wrote
the scenario! Louis Malle was famous for breaking taboos. This movie
was intended for enjoyment, like a comedy, but with a sharp view on the
changing French society. Also some comments on hypocritical ways of
dealing with taboos like homosexuality and "dirty old men". Funny to
see the traffic congestion in Paris, already then, and the looney
effects, inspired by Tex Avery.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0297262/comments</url><from>from Mad City, WI</from><name>grendel-28</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Frankly, in the world of corny jokes and lightweight punchlines of the
Hollywood comedies I hunger for the good old French physical comedy. Malle
is one of the best ju-ju men in the business and in Zazie laughs never
stop.
Actually, in this movie anything ever stops as people are running rather
then walking and driving rather than sitting still. The story is quite
simple, a little girl is sent by her mother to Paris to her uncle and the
only thing she wants really is to see subway (metro). Of course she runs
away, of course everybody starting after her, of course there are some
dumb
cops and sinister-looking strangers... Or maybe I got it all wrong for
having laughed so hard I could not read the subtitles (and my French would
barely guide me through a menu in some bistro). Think of it as a live
action
Roadrunner movie on caffeine...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur21278766/comments</url><from>from Germany</from><name>Rindiana</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This has to be seen to be believed! Malle seems just as well to be the
victim of Zazie's dark whirlwind surrealism as the audience themselves.
Never again achieved an adolescent movie character such an anarchic
quality. Despite all the displays of technical outrageousness and pure
buffoonery, the pic never feels as superficially sketch-like as many of
Dick Lester's works. And the complete lack of warmheartedness is a
relief in a picture featuring a young girl! Now that's a truly original way to declass French bourgeoisie and throw
an anti-Fascist pie in their faces! And it's one of the few hommages to
silent comedy (amongst sundry allusions to cinema and social topics)
that really work. And it's one of Malle's best.9 out of 10 polar bears
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2300673/comments</url><from>from Paris, France</from><name>Lalit Rao (cpowerccc@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Films featuring metro are a sub genre in itself.In French cinema,2 of
the most eccentric metro films are :subway and Zazie dans le métro.On
the one hand "Subway" is more of an "in the metro" film,on the other
hand "Zazie dans le métro" can be defined as something of "outside the
metro" film.Nothing much happens in the metro itself.This is because in
the film Parisian metro is just a metaphor in order to allow a young
girl to explore the intricacies of the adults' behavior.The young girl
whose role is nicely played by Catherine Demongeot is a veritable
trouble maker.Although she is in Paris to enjoy her stay, she is more
interested in pestering her uncle.Great French actor (now
dead),Philippe Noiret plays the role of the hapless uncle who is
absolutely at a loss as to how to reply to his niece's absurd
questions.This film by Louis Malle is quite unusual as there is no
other film which can match its spirit of freewheeling fun.For fact
finders, the film is based on a novel by Raymond Queneau who was close
to surrealist writers of his times.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0598738/comments</url><from>from Tuross Head, Australia</from><name>monabe</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Great cinema, with a wonderful exuberance and style.  Louis Malle showed
his
great talent and versatility in this romp of cheeky comedy.  Blessed with
a
Zazie that (for me ) captures the essence of the character originally
created by Raymond Queneau, this is a 60's French film that continues to
bring naive pleasure to those to whom it is a memory of the renaissance of
French cinema in the early 60's, and (hopefully) will still retain a few
inspirational moments for those see this movie thirty years on and who
have
had the benefit of later comedic directors who learned from this
well-crafted and thoroughly entertaining movie.   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Zazie, a young girl from the provinces, is brought to Paris by her
mother, who wants to spend some time with her lover. When asked by her
uncle what part of Paris she wants to see, she answers: the metro!
Zazie's wish was not to come true because of a transit strike in the
city that has closed the underground system. The result is chaos in the
streets where thousand vehicles try to go nowhere.The young girl surprises because of her dirty mouth. She can out curse
even the most experts in the subject. A trip to see the Eiffel Tower
with her uncle Gabriel, brings the young girl face to face with
tourists and an assortment of people she has never seen in her life.
Deciding to take off to explore on her own, puts Zazie in touch with a
series of Parisian characters that she would not see otherwise in her
more provincial setting.Louis Malle's "Zazie dans le Metro" was his third film. He was clearly
paying homage to the silent films of the beginning of the century. The
flavor of the picture reminded us of the Keystone Kops with its frantic
pacing and running gags. The style of the film is quite in contrast
with the previous movies of Mr. Malle. Perhaps the chaos in the film
stands as a metaphor for the way he perceived things in a metropolis
like Paris.A young Philippe Noiret, who up to then had been seen a lot of
television, makes a wonderful Gabriel, the entertainer at a small
cabaret. Young Catherine Demongeot plays Zazie with an intensity that
her nine years made possible. Vittorio Caprioli shows up in several
disguises. Carla Marlier makes a wonderful Albertine, the almost silent
wife of Gabriel. Yvonne Clech, Hubert Deschamps and the rest of the
crew contribute to the zaniness of the atmosphere created by Mr. Malle.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Zazie, a young girl from the provinces, is brought to Paris by her
mother, who wants to spend some time with her lover. When asked by her
uncle what part of Paris she wants to see, she answers: the metro!
Zazie's wish was not to come true because of a transit strike in the
city that has closed the underground system. The result is chaos in the
streets where thousand vehicles try to go nowhere.The young girl surprises because of her dirty mouth. She can out curse
even the most experts in the subject. A trip to see the Eiffel Tower
with her uncle Gabriel, brings the young girl face to face with
tourists and an assortment of people she has never seen in her life.
Deciding to take off to explore on her own, puts Zazie in touch with a
series of Parisian characters that she would not see otherwise in her
more provincial setting.Louis Malle's "Zazie dans le Metro" was his third film. He was clearly
paying homage to the silent films of the beginning of the century. The
flavor of the picture reminded us of the Keystone Kops with its frantic
pacing and running gags. The style of the film is quite in contrast
with the previous movies of Mr. Malle. Perhaps the chaos in the film
stands as a metaphor for the way he perceived things in a metropolis
like Paris.A young Philippe Noiret, who up to then had been seen a lot of
television, makes a wonderful Gabriel, the entertainer at a small
cabaret. Young Catherine Demongeot plays Zazie with an intensity that
her nine years made possible. Vittorio Caprioli shows up in several
disguises. Carla Marlier makes a wonderful Albertine, the almost silent
wife of Gabriel. Yvonne Clech, Hubert Deschamps and the rest of the
crew contribute to the zaniness of the atmosphere created by Mr. Malle.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>