<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>David e Golia</original_title><imdb_rating>4.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Ferdinando Baldi</director><producer>Ansa Film</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
The story of the film is adapted from the Old Testament: The Philistines declare war on the Israelites and wrench the Arch of the Allience from them...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Orson Welles</actor><actor>Ivica Pajer</actor><actor>Hilton Edwards</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This Italian made sand and sandal epic would probably be long forgotten
were it not for the presence of Orson Welles as King Saul. Certainly
the man who played David in David and Goliath, Ivo Payer, certainly did
not enter the ranks of screen immortals.David and Goliath took as many liberties with scripture as any good
Cecil B. DeMille film, but without DeMille's sense of grandeur and
spectacle. For instance in this film as a result of the battle where
David defeats Goliath and the Philistines are routed, the Ark of the
Covenant which the Philistines had captured is returned. Actually those
are separate incidents that are not connected at all.Another thing is that at least I've always interpreted David to be a
rather callow youth when he was doing his shepherd thing before God
sent Samuel looking for him. And he's still a callow youth when he's in
battle with Goliath. The old Negro spiritual is called Little David
Play On Your Harp, not without reason.Ivo Payer is a rather muscular young man looking like he stepped from
of those Italian muscle man epics so popular at the time. Of course the
sight of all that bare chested beefcake sent many hearts fluttering in
the audience. In that sense David and Goliath is right in the DeMille
tradition.The only reason this film is remembered if at all today is because of
Orson Welles. Welles at the time was picking up work here and there to
finance his own projects. Sometimes it would be something as good as
Compulsion the year before, more often it was something like David and
Goliath.Still Welles is a consummate professional and he invests Saul with an
air of tragedy about him. At the point we meet Saul, God has already
decided he's not the man for the job as King of Israel. But Saul is not
about to accept that verdict. If he can't beat David head on, he'll try
and co-op David by bringing him into his household and matching him up
with his daughter.And of course there's Saul's son Jonathan. He's there, but none of the
business about a gay relationship between David and Jonathan is in this
film. Jonathan knows full well that his father has lost favor with the
Lord and he's aware of his father's character weaknesses. He too,
befriends David more out of a sense of survival than anything else.English actor Hilton Edwards plays Samuel the Prophet and he comes
across as a poor man's version of Finlay Currie. He's the only other
English speaking player in the cast besides Orson Welles.David and Goliath will not pass muster with either biblical scholars or
with lovers of big screen spectacle. Still fans of Orson Welles will
want to see this film to see how much a great talent can lift even a
piece of mediocrity to a level of some respectability.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13022713/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tsf-1962</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This cheesy but entertaining sword-and-sandal movie has more in common
with the muscleman spectacles being made in Italy at the time than it
has with the superior Biblical epics made by Hollywood in the same era,
such as "Ben Hur" and "The Ten Commandments." The dialogue is stilted,
the acting stiff, and the departures from the Biblical narrative make
it unsuitable as a Sunday school lesson (i.e., Jerusalem did not become
part of Israel until David conquered it after Saul's death; in one
scene the prophet Samuel quotes verses from the Book of Ecclesiastes,
which hadn't been written yet). On the credit side, the movie has lots
of pretty girls (what's a Biblical epic without scantily clad dancing
girls?) and an exciting battle scene. Hilton Edwards (billed as Edward
Hilton) hams it up amusingly as Samuel, and an alarmingly obese Orson
Welles gives a commanding performance as Saul, showing that life can be
tough for a working actor even if you're a genius. Aside from Welles,
only the sexy Eleonora Rossi-Drago, as Saul's scheming daughter Merab,
manages to create a three-dimensional character. Overall, the acting is
so poor that circus strong man Kronos, as Goliath, actually gives one
of the better performances even though all he does is grunt.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0356685/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon</from><name>Jacknife-4</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Released as David And Goliath, this is a very enjoyable classic Bible
story.
On the cover it is billed as an Orson Wells picture, however, Wells does
not take the prominent focus.  This movie explores the opposite side of
the
Philistenes gearing up for war against Israel, an aspect not usually
covered
in Bible stories.  If you like classic film, this is definitely one that
should be seen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3329978/comments</url><from>from Phx. Arizona ("Arizona Smells Funny"!- Homer Simpson)</from><name>happipuppi13</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
It was one of those nights when there was absolutely nothing good on
TV. I went through many channels on my TV and landed on Trinity
Broadcasting Network. I do on occasion watch TBN but usually for Robert
Schuller or maybe when I feel I need extra inspiration.This movie began and "David and Goliath" was all I needed to see to
stay tuned,along with reading the story as a boy and the fact Orson
Welles plays Saul. (I wonder if that was "his" voice in the English
dubbing?) Cetainly if any film needs a good restoration this one really
needs it. I think it would be a lot more enjoyable if it were.Welles does a great service to this film and I don't think there ever
was a film that didn't benefit from his presence (even The Muppett
Movie featured Welles!) Aside from the grandeur that is Orson,is some
good storytelling but some of the unfortunate liberties movie makers
seem to take with biblical stories.First there's David himself,with the curly locks and and looking like a
muscle bound cross between Michael Landon or Kurt Russell. (Acoording
to IMDb the actor who plays him passed away August 17th,2006 oddly
enough). David also has a first love who apparently,according to a wise
old man,was taken from him by a flash of lightning in a rainstorm for
God's higher purpose. Of course she had dreamed the other night that
she was taken far from their land,quite a coincidence.As we know,David has been chosen by God to one day replace Saul as the
King Of Isreal and tired and worn out looking Saul's not about to take
it. David arrives in Isreal sees sin after sin taking place in the
streets (one female dancer looks like she stepped off a burlesque
stage) and (amazingly) gets the entire mass in the streets to quiet
down.Just long enough for him to give a speech about their sins and
basically that it's an abomination before God and how it's Saul's lack
of leadership that's led to it. You'd think a young man who'd just arrived in a city and starts
shooting his mouth off would get stones thrown at him but,no they all
cheer for him. One of Saul's guards approaches David and David gives
him one heck a blow to the head with his fist! leading to David being
given Sanctuary by the church.Meanwhile,another king is threatening to overtake Saul and have both
his country and Isreal. (The English voice for this king sounds like a
guy from the tough side of Chicago!)His lackey offers to draft the
giant monster of a man Goliath (I'm guessing 10ft. tall or more)to help
defeat Saul and his armies. (The lackey sounds like Ernest T. Bass from
The Andy Griffith Show.) In one funny scene Goliath picks him up off
the ground (in an obvious clay figure moment).Anyhow David is finally brought before Saul and as would happen,he
takes a liking to Saul daughter and becomes Saul's ally (although Saul
doesn't know it yet.) Then we get to the battles between the two
kingdoms and what we tuned in for to begin with. To see David take out
Goliath with his "sling-shot". (A stretchy piece of material with a
cradle for the rock). A good deal of this movie mirrors The Ten Commandmants but certainly
isn't on that grand level. Mostly just in plot point and look:Leader
trying to stop God's chosen one - sins of the people of Isreal - big
sets and of course the perfect looking heroes. ..and it's only 90
minutes.Overall though,despite it's weaker points (english dubbing is always
unintentionally funny)it's a pretty good movie. I'd recommend it for
younger viewers and maybe people who like biblical epics or Orson
Welles devotees. 6 stars for convincing enough sets,a great battle sequence and the
casting of Welles and whoever chose Goliath (where'd they find that
guy?). Along with a well told story,then again the Bible has plenty of
them to tell. (END)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8048890/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>Chris.</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Spaghetti biblical study elevated somewhat in status by the appearance
of Orson Welles playing King Saul. Ivo Payer is David, the man who
would be king of the Israelites, but who must first defeat Asrod, King
of the Philistines (Meniconi) who's managed to lure the hermit behemoth
Goliath (Kronos) as his secret weapon. Beginning with David's journey
to Jerusalem, where he quickly establishes himself as a shepherd (or
radical, depending on your lean), freeing the slaves and showing
compassion for the wicked, he is taken in by the Prophets and groomed
as the next King. His inevitable battle to the death with Goliath is a
disappointingly brief action sequence, with Goliath shown in the
distance to distort the height difference which is obviously far less
than desirable. The bloody battle that follows is everything a sword
and sandal movie promises to be, again, albeit too brief.Welles is essentially a peripheral character although unsurprisingly,
his performance towers above those around him; Massimo Serato as ally
turned conspirator Abner does a reasonable job and although not as buff
as a Steve Reeves or Brad Harris, Ivo Payer isn't as wooden as one
might expect of films of this ilk. Meniconi too isn't bad as the evil
Asrod, although why he would bet the house on a 6 foot maybe 5 inch
Neanderthal who can military press an ancient stone tablet beggars
belief. But then it did happen according to the Old Testament. Goliath
was probably much bigger than depicted here – cinematography tricks
fail to enlarge Kronos to the necessary proportions.Colourful sets, appropriate score and functional dialogue (dubbed)
permits some standard of entertainment and unlike most biblical epics,
"David &amp; Goliath" is compact at about an hour and a half. If you're
home alone over Easter or Christmas, don't have high expectations and
could cop a low-key sermon (scantily clad dancing girls an unexpected
bonus), "David &amp; Goliath" might keep you mildly entertained.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3836774/comments</url><from>from Olliergues, France</from><name>Dr Jacques COULARDEAU</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
When Orson Welles did not have anything to eat he had to become an
actor in films that are hardly worth, at times, mentioning, and yet he
tries to do what he can as an actor to save the film. That's typical in
this one. The Bible is badly revisited in an episode that is not that
particularly thrilling because too much known. The film more or less
understands some political questions and sees in the attack of the
Philistines against Israel an allusion to the menace against Israel
from its Arab neighbors. But all that is naive. The stone civilization
against the metal civilization from the north as Solomon will put it
later is hardly seen. A sling and a stone against spears and a sword.
This symbolism is present but unexploited. That also means The Semites
(and that is a lot more than just the Jews) against those from the
North, those who speak the Indo-Iranian languages of Mesopotamia, of
Babylon, of Persia. All that is missed, and a lot more. The harp is
also present but not used to its tremendous meaning. The oldest harp we
know in this region is Sumerian and not Israeli or whatever. Israeli
music is derived from that Sumerian music of some fifteen centuries
before, and it is David who is going to establish the music school of
the Temple, of the Levites, and also ,the singing school that will
produce the prosody and the psalmody of the Ancient Testament, two
musical forms that are both the results of older traditions and the
root of twenty centuries to come. Apart from that the film is naive and
primitive. I prefer the version given by Handel in his Saul.Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris Dauphine, University Paris 1
Pantheon Sorbonne &amp; University Versailles Saint Quentin en Yvelines
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3836774/comments</url><from>from Olliergues, France</from><name>Dr Jacques COULARDEAU</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
When Orson Welles did not have anything to eat he had to become an
actor in films that are hardly worth, at times, mentioning, and yet he
tries to do what he can as an actor to save the film. That's typical in
this one. The Bible is badly revisited in an episode that is not that
particularly thrilling because too much known. The film more or less
understands some political questions and sees in the attack of the
Philistines against Israel an allusion to the menace against Israel
from its Arab neighbors. But all that is naive. The stone civilization
against the metal civilization from the north as Solomon will put it
later is hardly seen. A sling and a stone against spears and a sword.
This symbolism is present but unexploited. That also means The Semites
(and that is a lot more than just the Jews) against those from the
North, those who speak the Indo-Iranian languages of Mesopotamia, of
Babylon, of Persia. All that is missed, and a lot more. The harp is
also present but not used to its tremendous meaning. The oldest harp we
know in this region is Sumerian and not Israeli or whatever. Israeli
music is derived from that Sumerian music of some fifteen centuries
before, and it is David who is going to establish the music school of
the Temple, of the Levites, and also ,the singing school that will
produce the prosody and the psalmody of the Ancient Testament, two
musical forms that are both the results of older traditions and the
root of twenty centuries to come. Apart from that the film is naive and
primitive. I prefer the version given by Handel in his Saul.Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris Dauphine, University Paris 1
Pantheon Sorbonne &amp; University Versailles Saint Quentin en Yvelines
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-hall/</url><url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=features&amp;Id=1786 /m/1055728-david_and_goliath/comments.php?reviewid=1529767</url><name>Phil Hall</name><from>Film Threat</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Where are the Philistines when you really need them?</comment></review></movie>