<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Where the Boys Are</original_title><alt_title>Ces folles de filles d'Ève</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Henry Levin</director><producer>Euterpe</producer><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Four very different college girls drive to Fort Lauderdale, Florida for spring break and seek out various adventures and romance for themselves.
</synopsis><actor>Dolores Hart</actor><actor>George Hamilton</actor><actor>Yvette Mimieux</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2286500/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ClydesStuff</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

In 2003 Turner Classic Films had a poll where fans could vote (out of a
list)for films they would like to see on DVD.  The top five vote getters
would be the films getting the DVD treatment.  Surprisingly, this is one of
the five films that voters preferred along with Days of Wine and Roses, Dr.
Jekyll and Mr. Hyde, The Postman Always Rings Twice, and The Wind and the
Lion.  It's a testament to how well this film has held up for the past
forty-three years, not an easy task considering it's subject
matter.The basic premise is this: Four college girls escape the freezing north
during spring break and head to Ft. Lauderdale because as the title says,
that's where the boys are.  Not much to make a film about I suppose, but
stories have hit the big screen with a lot less plot than that going for
them.  What Where The Boys Are does have going for it is a witty ahead of
it's time script by screenwriter George Wells (based on a novel by Glendon
Swarthout), a cast of attractive relatively new stars assembled by producer
Joe Pasternak and some nice Florida Scenery.The cast is headed by Dolores Hart as Merritt Andrews.  Although having a
high I.Q., Merritt is having trouble in college because she has a tendency
to say what's on her mind, and sometimes what's on her mind must have sent a
shiver down the spine of many parents in the early sixties.  In one class,
she dares to suggest that premarital sex (playing house is how she puts it I
think) might not only be OK but quite necessary.  Daring stuff in those
days.  It also immediately gives us a more complex character in Merritt
which helps lift this film a cut above others in this genre.  Dolores Hart
is exceptional as Merritt, and because of this she is the center of our
attention from the beginning of the film to the end.  Ms. Hart is one of
those actresses whom was never given a chance to show us her real potential
in the short time she was an actress before answering her calling to enter
the convent.  Pay close attention to her performance as Merritt as I did and
you'll understand what we may have missed.Paula Prentiss makes her big screen debut as Tuggle and immediately shows a
fine screen persona with a flair for comedy.  She's the one who has vowed to
be a "good girl".  In other words, no wedding ring, no hanky panky.  The
parents of the sixties probably loved her.Yvette Mimeaux plays naive freshman Melanie.  She ends up taking Merritt's
ideas in class about sex and putting them into action.  In 1960's morals, we
know she's headed for trouble and was probably the poster girl for parents
to point out the evils that would befall you for indulging in a little bit
of bedroom parlor games.  Mimeaux is OK in the role, it's just a role that
isn't written very well and probably the weakest part of the film. Connie Francis is a revelation as girl hockey player, Angie.  We are never
given her views on sex so you can paint her in a neutral corner.  For some
reason (I guess because she's a hockey player)she has trouble getting a guy.
 I seriously doubt someone who looks like her would have that kind of a
problem, but Francis plays the role in a ditsy kind of way.  She's adorable,
and we love her.  Add to this the fact that the girl can sing up a storm and
you'll replay the opening titles several times just to hear that heart
throbbing voice.Then there's the fellows.  Jim Hutton plays TV Thompson, a hitchhiker who
has a thing about hats, that the girls pick up on their way to Fort
Lauderdale.  He hooks up with Tuggle, and their wit blends together so
perfectly, that Hutton and Prentiss went on to make several more films
together.  Their moments together on screen are priceless.  George Hamilton
plays Merritt's love interest Ryder.  Ryder is a millionaire who goes to
Princeton, rides around in his grandfather's yacht and has eyes for Merritt.
 Hamilton is playing the usual George Hamilton type of role, but for this
film it's perfect as Ryder Smith would probably be just like George or vice
versa.  His scenes with Merritt are very cleverly written. He attempts to
find a way to seduce her, but knows she is way too intelligent to fall for
the standard come ons.  They have good chemistry together.  Frank Gorshin
plays a nearly blind jazz musician named Basil, whom Angie seems to end up
with by default.  It works because they both seem to have a whacked out
comedy sense.  Unfortunately, all poor Melanie can end up with is a couple
of wicked evil guys who want her for only one thing and I'm sure you know
what that is.  John Brennan as Dill and Rory Harrity as Franklin manage to
be sleazy enough to do what they have to do, than you can forget them both
which apparently most people did as evidenced by their lack of screen
credits after this film.  Also on hand are a delightful Barbra Nichols as
the sea nymph and Chill Wills in a couple of brief but funny scenes as a
police captain.Where this film excels is in the performances and chemistry of it's young
cast.  Together they make for many enjoyable screen moments.  Where it
greatly falters is in some of it's very out dated premises about
relationships between men and women.  Despite the fact that they are all
college women, Where The Boys Are would still have us believe that the only
thing these women are interested in is finding the right guy who will wrap a
ring around their finger.  Even Merritt, who is outspoken early in the film,
ends up wanting nothing more than to get Ryder and his millions down the
aisle.  The fact that this film also falls back on the premise that if you
hop in the hay with a guy, you'll suffer severe penalties for it.  This is
hammered home by the presence of Melanie.  Because she makes the "mistake"
of doing what nice girls shouldn't, she automatically is punished for it. 
Enough of the film is taken up with this aspect, that it continually brings
a cloud cover over the proceedings and bogs down an otherwise enjoyable
film.My advice is to overlook the drama.  Enjoy the witty dialog, the on screen
chemistry of the stars, the Florida scenery, and listen to Connie Francis
belt out Where The Boys Are a few times.  Heck, that alone is enough for me
to give this film a B.            
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0415574/comments</url><from>from Illinois</from><name>icblue02</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This film succeeds in the sense that it isn't a stereotypical beach
flick. As a current college student, I can attest that it is rather
believable, and, oddly enough, some of it applies to college gals
today...nearly 40 years later. Actually, WHERE THE BOYS ARE offers the
public a fairly realistic, in-depth portrayal of everyday kids in the
60s, as opposed to other beach movies of the period. Simply put:
Frankie and Annette had nothing on these gals! Contrary to what the title may lead one to believe, the focal point is
not terribly superficial. Yeah, sure, the girls head to Lauderdale to
nab a Yaley or two, but that becomes somewhat secondary to what
actually transpires. Whether it was meant to be or not, this film is
one of decisions, learning, and friendships that are strengthened due
to the experiences four college girls share during Spring Break in Ft.
Lauderdale. The actors themselves are very believable; none of the main players
outdo the others. Hart, Mimeux, Francis, and Prentiss do a wonderful
job of conveying many different sides to the characters they portray.
The supporting cast is equally skilled and effective in varying roles.Though this isn't Academy Award winning material, it is definitely
worth watching!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3608743/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, CA, USA</from><name>Ed Uyeshima</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Forty-five years have elapsed since its original release, but it is
amazing how this 1960 film introduced a particular genre that continues
to be produced today granted in a far more explicit manner - the
spring-break, beach-party movie where attractive teens go through a
sun-drenched mating ritual and somehow love triumphs over carnal
knowledge. Back then, the concept didn't seem quite as jaded as it does
now, and consequently there is an entertaining naiveté about the
timeworn story of four co-eds from a snowy Midwestern college who
journey to Ft. Lauderdale for spring break to meet boys.The plot is based on the then-accepted notion that girls in college are
only marking time waiting for husbands to come along, but the journey
to that goal depends on the girl. The four in question are Merritt, a
smart blonde who is not living up to her academic potential as she
questions the moral code around premarital sex; Melanie, so deeply
insecure she mistakes sex for love with a less-than-honorable Ivy
Leaguer; Tuggle, a tall brunette who zeroes in on an even taller,
eccentric hitchhiker; and Angie, the supposedly plain one who gets used
to being ignored by men.Directed in a perfunctory fashion by Henry Levin, this is not the type
of movie where you are terribly impressed with the performances, but I
have to say the acting is certainly miles above subsequent beach-party
movies. Elvis' former leading lady Dolores Hart plays Merritt credibly
even as she is being seduced by a youthful George Hamilton wanly
playing Ryder, a well-to-do Ivy Leaguer with a conveniently located
yacht. As the most troubled of the girls, Yvette Mimieux (always loved
her name) accurately captures the constantly forlorn, little-girl-lost
state of Melanie, a teen-aged Blanche du Bois in the making.So pert and charming as Angie, Connie Francis actually seems miscast as
a plain-Jane, especially when she sings "Turn on the Sunshine" with a
stage polish completely out of character. The standout is Paula
Prentiss who portrays Tuggle with her unique personality in full bloom
and partnered the first of several times with Jim Hutton as the
comically obnoxious TV. She is an under-appreciated comedienne with a
loopy charm and vibrantly twangy voice all her own - it's a shame her
career never really took off the way it deserved to.I think the film does make a valid, sometimes even perceptive attempt
to address the confusion that Eisenhower-era girls had over sex and
love. Girls were expected to function under a double-standard where the
only way to attract boys was to have something to offer but at the
price of their reputations. This point is hammered home when the tone
shifts in the last portion to melodrama. At the same time, the film is
filled with predictable comic scenes, including a contrived mêlée in an
underwater tank with the zaftig and nasal Barbara Nichols as Esther
Williams-wannabe Lola Fandango.Prentiss offers her services and remembrances to the alternate audio
commentary track on the DVD, which also comes with a looking-back
featurette which includes interviews with Prentiss and Francis. Who
knew this film would launch a hundred imitations? The minute you hear
Francis sing the title tune, it is hard for a baby boomer not to get
nostalgic. If you have an interest in understanding the mid-century
moral code enforced upon the youth of America, especially girls, I can
think of worse films to see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0493442/comments</url><from>from Hollywood, ca</from><name>rlcsljo</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

My mother sent me to see this film when I was about 9 or 10 expecting a good
wholesome beach movie, and I was shocked! (If she only
knew!).
1)  A girl actually advocated pre-marital sex! (but was hypocritical about
practicing her ideas)
2)  Another girl actually did it! (although nothing was shown, not even
kissing)
3)  Another girl said she only wanted to have babies! (nothing new here,
except for her honesty)
4)  Another girl was horny, and tried to do something about
it.
5)  And of course the boys actually came out and asked for
sex,
although couched in the "decent" terms of the fifties/sixties.People (mostly "liberated" women) complain that this movie was about
oppression of women (they didnt feel "complete" without a man), but this was
women's liberation (women were horny and honest about it)The marvelous casting and dialogue made this film one of the great american
classics of its genre that still holds up today.definitely a 10!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0970559/comments</url><from>from Abbotsford, Canada</from><name>Grahammer (nickels@canada.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Like many others who have commented previously on Where the Boys Are
(WTBA),
I was initially rather shocked at the film's frank discussion of sex. Once
I
thought about it more deeply, however, it was the open talk of marriage
that
was really fresh to my ears. I was born 11 years after this film was
released and watching movies like this gives me a unique insight into
history that goes well beyond the broad brushes of most sixties reviews
and
textbooks. Clearly both boys and girls of the time were struggling with
the
implications of sexuality in relationships - not a whole lot different
than
today.What is different about WTBA than the films for young people of today or
of
my youth (e.g., The Breakfast Club) is the explicit discussion of
marriage.
In WTBA both the girls and the boys use different levers to try to achieve
their ends. The girls use the potential for sex to get the one thing they
want - marriage - and the boys use the potential for marriage to get what
they are after - sex. I was amazed to hear that all the girls (even the
one
with an IQ of 138!) were so focussed on catching a husband at 19. None of
the movies for youth that I have seen recently even touch the subject of
marriage except maybe to joke about it.While many would argue that no one gets married at 19 anymore, that
ultimate
end of any relationship still looms out there for young people like a
giant
prize (or punishment) at the end of dating. The only help I got in seeing
young people get together and eventually get married was in The Princess
Bride, which could easily be dismissed as fairy tale. I recall in my late
teens having to turn to more adult movies like When Harry Met Sally or
even
Enchanted April to find some guidance for seeing a relationship through to
its logical end. Maybe today's youth are skipping over She's All That and
going to movies like High Fidelity for similar answers. One would hope
so.So instead of a breezy beach movie I got a social history lesson on the
mating rituals of my parents' generation. I hope there's a movie that
prompts this kind of discussion for my own kids someday.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2821700/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>Christopher (mrcaw1@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Where The Boys Are (1960 Dir. Henry Levin)
Fort Lauderdale College Spring Break! Oh Boy! Oh Girl! See where the
perennially tan George Hamilton first acquired his swarthy complexion.
Also
features one of the best '60s light comediennes Paula Prentiss as "Tuggle
Carpenter". Lots of talk amongst the girls about how far they should go.
Lots of talk amongst the boys about how far they've gotten. A classic
American take on life when the air was clean and sex was dirty. Before
there
was MTV's Spring Break, there was this movie. Great for viewing with mixed
company (that's old-fashioned slang for boys and girls
together).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2158049/comments</url><from>from Long Island, NY</from><name>curtaincall9000</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

i don't understand how anyone cannot like this film! the story about the 4
co-eds is mind-grabbing but i couldn't help wondering if all that sex talk
would be looked upon well, it being the good old sixties. i would descibe
this film as smooth, quirky, dramatic, and fun. i am a HUGE fan of frank
gorshin and i loved his portrayl of basil. the whole cast was was very
good
and that made it a great film. i usually rent this film at least once a
month. but am i the only one who adores basil's glasses?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1912784/comments</url><from>from Westcliff-On-Sea, Essex, England</from><name>dancingfool</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

While listening to a Connie Francis CD yesterday, I read the liner notes
and
found that she had made a few appearances in films. This morning, in one
of
those all too rare spooky coincidences, I found that Where The Boys Are
was
on TCM.I watched with anticipation and smiled from start to finish - except of
course when the comedy turned to drama, a transition that was expertly
handled by the director.A fun film in the tradition of Muscle Beach and Muscle Beach Party, with
good performances all round and an excellent turn from Frank Gorshin. I
shall never be able to listen to jazz in the same way again! It's a shame
that Connie Francis did not appear on screen more often, as judging by
this,
her debut, she could easily have enjoyed as much success as an actress as
she did a singer.Not as camp as the two aforementioned Frankie Avalon classics, though I'm
sure "Have You Met Miss Fandango?" had drag queens squealing with
delight.If you are ever in need of cheering up, you could do worse than to watch
this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1994594/comments</url><from>from Nebraska</from><name>allanschur</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

OK, it might get a silly at times but generally a very entertaining
movie!
Get the popcorn (and a couple of tissues!!), sit back and .... enjoy!
You'll recognize the young actors.  For most, this was far from their
last
movie!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1379892/comments</url><from>from Allentown, PA</from><name>jjkaul (jjkaul@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I was hysterical when Frank Gorshin fell into the fish tank followed by
the rest of the gang. "Where The Boys Are" is one of the best movies of
the sixties. Anyone who came of age at that time can definitely relate
to the magical love Merritt found, the tragedy that Melanie
experienced, the wanting to be loved and accepted as did Tuggle and
Angie. The suave George Hamilton made many a young girls heart race
faster. Girl crazy Jim Hutton with his style setting baseball hats and
comedic personality was simply hilarious. The title song, one of my
favorites still gives me chills. I have seen this movie countless times
and I love the nostalgia it brings back each time. When it airs, enjoy
it at least once. You will love it, I promise.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1379892/comments</url><from>from Allentown, PA</from><name>jjkaul (jjkaul@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I was hysterical when Frank Gorshin fell into the fish tank followed by
the rest of the gang. "Where The Boys Are" is one of the best movies of
the sixties. Anyone who came of age at that time can definitely relate
to the magical love Merritt found, the tragedy that Melanie
experienced, the wanting to be loved and accepted as did Tuggle and
Angie. The suave George Hamilton made many a young girls heart race
faster. Girl crazy Jim Hutton with his style setting baseball hats and
comedic personality was simply hilarious. The title song, one of my
favorites still gives me chills. I have seen this movie countless times
and I love the nostalgia it brings back each time. When it airs, enjoy
it at least once. You will love it, I promise.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1379892/comments</url><from>from Allentown, PA</from><name>jjkaul (jjkaul@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1320466</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>A guilty pleasure if ever there was one.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>http://www.dvdtown.com/review/Where_The_Boys_Are/11577/1898/ /m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1234396</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/10
					</rating><comment>It must have been some kind of alternate universe these movie people lived in, because it wasn't any sort of world I knew.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1399149</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1383385</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117796314.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1806735</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9503E4D7123DE733A25753C2A9679C946091D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1389895</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=130044 /m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=1274075</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/9258_WHERE_THE_BOYS_ARE.html /m/1023508-where_the_boys_are/comments.php?reviewid=20914</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>