<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Last Woman on Earth</original_title><alt_title>La dernière femme sur terre</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Roger Corman</director><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
Ev; her husband, Harold; and their lawyer friend, Martin, are skindiving while on vacation in Puerto Rico...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Betsy Jones-Moreland</actor><actor>Antony Carbone</actor><actor>Robert Towne</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0960268/comments</url><from>from Montreal, Canada</from><name>Christian (christian94@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

This sci-fi tale examines the fate and the human struggles involved
in
the incredible realization that a woman and two men may be the
last
surviving humans on Earth, following a peculiar catastrophy.The analysis of selfishness, love, jealousy, money, work,
accomplishment
and the purpose of life are very well examined.  All in the context
of
these extreme circumstances, the issues become very vibrant.
The
dialogue and acting help you feel the despair and distress of
the
characters.Unfortunately, what could have possibly been one of the best black
&amp;
white sci-fi movies, fell short- very short- in the end.  The ending
is
uselessly incoherent, improbable and needlessly violent (a
horrible
fight on top of everything).Still worth a watch for the first hour of the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2447552/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL</from><name>ksmith19</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a fine film that does much with almost nothing; shot on
location in Puerto Rico without a finished script, 'The Last Woman on
Earth' is a lean, mean post apocalyptic drama machine. Despite the poor
print(s) the DVD was assembled from, Roger Corman's minor directorial
genius shines through, especially in shots like the one where Harold,
Martin and Ev all confront each other after coming back from the beach.
Narratively efficient, suspenseful and even kind of thought-provoking,
this film is a well-crafted low budget classic. Contrary to other
comments here, the ending is great, especially considering how lame it
could have been; at no point is the outcome certain in the way that
predictable yawner 'Six String Samurai' was. And the fact that the
poster is nothing like the actual film is a good thing, unless you're
looking for Italian sexploitation trash. For a more reasoned
assessment, check out Kim Newman's book 'Apocalypse Movies,' but if
you're looking up this film you probably already know that one
backwards and forwards. If you want an interesting and engaging vision
of what the world might be like after it ends, you won't be
disappointed here.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1908551/comments</url><from>from Newfoundland, Canada</from><name>Space_Mafune</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This very underrated low budget end of the world movie focuses on what
drives men against one another. When the world's oxygen supply is
inexplicably cut off for a short time, a trio of divers using oxygen tanks,
a married couple named Harold (Anthony Carbone) &amp; Evelyn Gern (Betsy
Jones-Moreland) and their friend Martin Joyce(Robert Towne), suddenly find
they are from all appearances the only 3 people left alive. But 2 men and 1
woman don't make for a very good mix we soon discover.This is absolute fascinating to watch unfold. Jones-Moreland gives one of
her finest performances and the final showdown between Harold and Martin in
the Church is an unforgettable moment. One problem the film has is it never really explains things enough...they
just happen but maybe that's not such a bad thing after all come to think of
it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Harold and Evelyn Gern are "vacationing" in Puerto Rico, with friend/lawyer
Martin when while scuba diving they realize that all the world's oxygen has
left the atmosphere for some inexplicable reason.  For all purposes and
intent, they are the last human beings on Earth.  What shall they do?  Can
two men and one woman coexist alone?  Watch this film and those questions
shall be answered.  This film is very creative on many counts and it is a
satisfying tale of what life might be like for a handful of survivors in a
post-apocalyptic state. The film is a Roger Corman quickie/cheapie, yet
don't make that keep you away.  Corman is a good director and does know how
to get the most with what he is given.  The script is written by Robert
Towne, and although it has holes, it is inventive and interesting.  The
acting by Anthony Carbone, Betsy Jones-Moreland, and Robert Towne as the
trio is very good. Jones-Moreland is lovely and she gives a very good
performance.  Above all, the film reiterates the flaws that exist in each of
us no matter what circumstances we are thrust into.  On a side note, the
same director, same crew, same actors, and same locations were used for a
film simultaneously made with this one...Creature From the Haunted Sea.  A
word of advice:  AVOID IT!, but see The Last Woman on Earth.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5353728/comments</url><from>from cinti., ohio</from><name>eeegah</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I picked this slab-o cheese on a double billed disc w/ "The Attack of
the Bee Girls" @ Meijer for 2 bucks. Now if you are a fan of B-Films, I
highly recommend the trip to Meijer. They have a ton of cheap-o DVDs in
a big crate. You can get 5 DVDs for 10 dollars. I also picked up a gem
called "The Crippled Masters" (a 70s Kung-Fu Revenge flick, and yes,
they are crippled). But, I'm getting way off on a tangent...The Last Woman on Earth is an interesting film with some unintentional
laugh-out-loud parts. What's interesting about it is how well mannered
they are during the end of the world. There are two males and one
female left alive after some kind of doomsday devise is detonated,
which is never really explained. In this type of scenario you'd expect
people to behave wildly; looting the electronics store, stealing
Italian sports cars, driving a tank through the middle of downtown (as
I believe this happened in a film called "The Quiet Earth"). Instead
they wear pressed slacks, shave, mix cocktails (no one explains how
they still have power, let alone ice cubes) and fight over one boat in
a harbor full of 'em. This is not Corman's most entertaining film and
you will find your attention slipping in and out, but for my money it
beats the latest sitcom or reality show.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1451754/comments</url><from>from Pocono Summit, PA</from><name>KDWms</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

A setting resulting from sci-fi; but heavy philosophizing in the vast
majority of the film:  Ev becomes the last woman on earth - well, at
least,
in Puerto Rico, where she is vacationing with her gambling-addicted,
workaholic, material-oriented, not-quite-above-board husband, Harold; and
their free-spirited lawyer friend, Martin.  They emerge from a
scuba-diving
session and gradually realize that everyone else on the island - perhaps
globally - has suffocated from a mysterious (but impermanent) breach of
the
oxygen supply.  From this point, it is a psychological study of the
differing priorities of the three characters.  Viewers who are interested
in
interpreting some varieties of human behavior will find THAT in this
movie.
Others, however, may prefer more of the type of action which will NOT be
found here.              
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3050539/comments</url><from>from NJ</from><name>CelluloidTime</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

"Last Woman On Earth" moves along at a steady clip and has an exciting
ending (with a disappointing conclusion).  It is a film that benefits from
smart writing, an on location shoot, and an interesting meshing of script
with Jazzy soundtrack. There is an underwater scene that was quite
excellently filmed. For that matter, the whole film was quite excellently
filmed.  Even though this film predates the first James Bond film, it has a
bit of a "Dr. No" feel to it.  No, it is no "Dr. No", but neither was its
budget a Bond budget. You're not missing much if you never see "Last Woman
On Earth", but if you do see it you won't feel like you wasted 71 minutes of
your life.  It's a pretty good film -- a sad little tale about good and
evil.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
On the 5th of April 2005, the legendary horror producer/director Roger
Corman turned 79 years old and that was my reason (the obsessive geek I
am) to re-watch one of his most overlooked films. Last Woman on Earth
is a modest but ingenious SF-thriller that got pushed back and
eventually forgotten due to other, bigger cinema projects handling
about the same topic. That's quite regretful, as this is a well written
and entertaining little film with quite some tension and above average
acting performances. The plot is fascinating and follows a rich couple
and their lawyer friend on vacation in Puerto Rico. When they make a
day-trip out on the open sea to dive a sudden and unexplainable lack of
oxygen kills off the isle's entire population…likely the whole world!
They initially collaborate to survive and work out an escape plan, but
pretty soon the first fights appear. The situation gets really
complicated when the lawyer also develops feelings for … the last and
only woman on earth. Like nearly every Roger Corman product, the film
lacks budget and eye for detail. Yet, the Puerto Rican filming
locations are beautiful the man's directing is very straightforward.
The constantly increasing hopelessness of the characters is
terrifically portrayed and the inevitable climax of paranoia is very
impressive. The ending is somewhat disappointing (as other reviewers
already pointed out) and hard to accept after the overall convincing
first hour. But then again, it's not easy to shoot an appropriate
climax to an apocalyptic-minded movie, is it? The three-headed cast
delivers good performances. Especially compared to that other film
Corman quickly shot in Puerto Rico – Creature from the Haunted Sea –
this is a good and recommended picture. Pay close attention to Robert
Towne, by the way. Around the time of Last Woman on Earth, he was still
an unnoticed Corman pupil but he soon after became one of Hollywood's
most praised scriptwriters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19536660/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>Juliette Dorotte</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
At first I was quite surprised three films all dealing with the same
subject, the end of the world and survival of a few humans, should have
been made within 5 years: The World, the Flesh and the Devil by R.
MacDougall (1959), Last Woman on Earth by Corman (1960) and finally The
Last Man on Earth by U. Ragona (1964). Yet these three works happen to be very different, and for that reason,
all interesting in a different way. The first one is set in a huge
city, reinforcing the feeling of desolation and claustrophobia, and
approaches the question of racism, since one of the only humans left is
an African-American man. The third one presents the unique man on
earth, restlessly fighting a group of zombies, called vampires. The
second one, Last Woman on Earth, also deals with three people alone in
the whole world, and, like the World, the Flesh and the Devil, offers a
love triangle, or a 2 men/1 woman situation. The characters are
isolated in Puerto Rico, threatened by diseases, they want to leave the
island but just won't. I don't think action or adventure is focused on
here, rather the psychological evolution of three people who gradually
show a despicable relationship to other humans.In conclusion, this movie stands out for its subtle treatment of human
desires, and the hints it makes to raw capitalism, transforming people
into mere goods.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
What drew me into Last Woman on Earth, after the fact that it was
included as one of the ten features on a three-disc set of science
fiction films for ten cents and was directed by Roger Corman, was that
the script seemed to be a good deal smarter, or at least intriguing,
than would be expected. As Robert Towne's first produced screenplay, he
makes it almost like a living-dead movie without the flesh-eaters.
Everyone is dead, aside from the three main characters, following a
short, unexplained lapse of oxygen to the planet (or rather the little
tropic section the characters are at), and it leaves the three of them
to fend for themselves. But there's a power-struggle, and a sort of existential dilemma- to
throw out the term once again- in the love-triangle of the husband
Harold (Anthony Carbone), Evelyn (Betsy Jones-Moreland), and Martin
(Robert Towne, credited with an alias) there's a code that is attempted
to be stuck to, but is lost in the face of all lack of humanity left.
Sad to the point of denial, then acceptance, and still denial, the
three are still caught in the grip of paranoia, jealousy, and
'every-man-for-himself' mentality that would be in a zombie flick,
though with a lot more at stake with the ambiguity.It might not be Chinatown in terms of overall excellence, but it's a
script more imbued with ideas and hard-boiled dialog- for the first
twenty minutes it's like a film-noir with Harold as a banker/gambler
who doesn't quit at his vices while on vacation, and the sexual tension
present already between Evelyn and Martin- but it's at least a good
start at achieving psychological tension, for Towne, who also as an
actor doesn't do too shabbily in delivering some sarcastic and acidic
dialog. I also liked how any real explanation as to why there was a
depletion of oxygen, or why it suddenly comes back on, was left out. It
adds a level of creepiness in seeing the occasional dead body, like the
woman on the beach that Martin sits next to and refers to as his 'blind
date' to Harold. If anything, Towne could've increased the chilling
fact of the bodies all strewn about in post-asphyxiated form, though it
goes without saying that the budget was likely too tight to allow many
dead extras lying about.Indeed, with the lack of any human presence, compared to other Corman
pictures sandwiched in around the period like Little Shop of Horrors or
Creature of the Haunted Sea (or rather any of the other films Corman
directed *that year*), this is almost Antonioni, least in the B-movie
sense. One of the wise things, or just practical things, that Corman
does do, aside from his location shooting, is to not get in the way of
Towne's material much- he shoots often very simply, with the occasional
nifty angle in a beach scene or in the climax when the two men are
running after one another in fighting poses. The biggest flaws though,
as with many of Corman's films, come with the acting, which is almost
as if second rate cuts of Bogie and Bacall were called in by
Jones-Moreland and Carbone, with Towne (in also his first acting
performance) doing possibly just as good, if not better, than the other
two at conveying the dread and melodrama at their situation. This, plus
Corman's lack of attention to certain things with editing and goofs
(albeit the print that's available on the box-set is also sub-par, like
Grindhouse quality), make it not much greater than the better B-movies
of the period.But as a B-movie there's ground covered that will intrigue those who
are prepared for more than just a simple alien or viral plot or a
sexploitation flick. It's also the kind of pic that would probably do
very well as a remake; it's not too bad on its own, but unlike recent
films of late which rely on making billions on refashioning past
product, this could be great without having to be a big money-maker
with a tune-up of sorts. Experimental, darkly funny and strangely
tragic, Last Woman on Earth is one of the better Corman movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
What drew me into Last Woman on Earth, after the fact that it was
included as one of the ten features on a three-disc set of science
fiction films for ten cents and was directed by Roger Corman, was that
the script seemed to be a good deal smarter, or at least intriguing,
than would be expected. As Robert Towne's first produced screenplay, he
makes it almost like a living-dead movie without the flesh-eaters.
Everyone is dead, aside from the three main characters, following a
short, unexplained lapse of oxygen to the planet (or rather the little
tropic section the characters are at), and it leaves the three of them
to fend for themselves. But there's a power-struggle, and a sort of existential dilemma- to
throw out the term once again- in the love-triangle of the husband
Harold (Anthony Carbone), Evelyn (Betsy Jones-Moreland), and Martin
(Robert Towne, credited with an alias) there's a code that is attempted
to be stuck to, but is lost in the face of all lack of humanity left.
Sad to the point of denial, then acceptance, and still denial, the
three are still caught in the grip of paranoia, jealousy, and
'every-man-for-himself' mentality that would be in a zombie flick,
though with a lot more at stake with the ambiguity.It might not be Chinatown in terms of overall excellence, but it's a
script more imbued with ideas and hard-boiled dialog- for the first
twenty minutes it's like a film-noir with Harold as a banker/gambler
who doesn't quit at his vices while on vacation, and the sexual tension
present already between Evelyn and Martin- but it's at least a good
start at achieving psychological tension, for Towne, who also as an
actor doesn't do too shabbily in delivering some sarcastic and acidic
dialog. I also liked how any real explanation as to why there was a
depletion of oxygen, or why it suddenly comes back on, was left out. It
adds a level of creepiness in seeing the occasional dead body, like the
woman on the beach that Martin sits next to and refers to as his 'blind
date' to Harold. If anything, Towne could've increased the chilling
fact of the bodies all strewn about in post-asphyxiated form, though it
goes without saying that the budget was likely too tight to allow many
dead extras lying about.Indeed, with the lack of any human presence, compared to other Corman
pictures sandwiched in around the period like Little Shop of Horrors or
Creature of the Haunted Sea (or rather any of the other films Corman
directed *that year*), this is almost Antonioni, least in the B-movie
sense. One of the wise things, or just practical things, that Corman
does do, aside from his location shooting, is to not get in the way of
Towne's material much- he shoots often very simply, with the occasional
nifty angle in a beach scene or in the climax when the two men are
running after one another in fighting poses. The biggest flaws though,
as with many of Corman's films, come with the acting, which is almost
as if second rate cuts of Bogie and Bacall were called in by
Jones-Moreland and Carbone, with Towne (in also his first acting
performance) doing possibly just as good, if not better, than the other
two at conveying the dread and melodrama at their situation. This, plus
Corman's lack of attention to certain things with editing and goofs
(albeit the print that's available on the box-set is also sub-par, like
Grindhouse quality), make it not much greater than the better B-movies
of the period.But as a B-movie there's ground covered that will intrigue those who
are prepared for more than just a simple alien or viral plot or a
sexploitation flick. It's also the kind of pic that would probably do
very well as a remake; it's not too bad on its own, but unlike recent
films of late which rely on making billions on refashioning past
product, this could be great without having to be a big money-maker
with a tune-up of sorts. Experimental, darkly funny and strangely
tragic, Last Woman on Earth is one of the better Corman movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/l/LastWomanEarth.html /m/last_woman_on_earth/comments.php?reviewid=1870916</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Micro-masterpiece</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pablo-villaca/</url><url>/m/last_woman_on_earth/comments.php?reviewid=1702737</url><name>Pablo Villaca</name><from>Cinema em Cena</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>A estréia de Towne como roteirista (e ator!) traz sua parcela de bons diálogos e momentos interessantes, mas, de modo geral, o roteiro denuncia a pressa com que foi escrito e Corman, claro, não se preocupa muito em polir o filme com mais cuidado.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-oehley/</url><url>http://www.scifimoviepage.com/lastwoman.html /m/last_woman_on_earth/comments.php?reviewid=1686823</url><name>James O'Ehley</name><from>Sci-Fi Movie Page</from></reviewer><comment>Tennessee Williams for the post-apocalypse . . .</comment></review></movie>