<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Fugitive Kind</original_title><alt_title>L'homme à la peau de serpent</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Sidney Lumet</director><producer>Pennebaker Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Val Xavier, a drifter of obscure origins arrives at a small town and gets a job in a store run by Lady Torrence...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Marlon Brando</actor><actor>Joanne Woodward</actor><actor>Anna Magnani</actor><rt_rating>6.3/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>60</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Tennessee Williams was a stunning writer for the theater... The impact
of his plays can overwhelm an audience with its superior force...Written in 1957, "Orpheus Descending" is a reconstruction of Williams'
1940 "Battle of Angels," filmed under Sidney Lumet's direction as "The
Fugitive Kind."Williams subtracted elements of the ancient myth of Orpheus and
Euridice to examine the sadistically patriarchal Southern Gothic town
and to create a violent plot, involving ruined love, weakness, sex,
betrayal, vengeance and lingering hatreds... "Orpheus Descending" shows
how social prejudice threatens the lives of identified outsiders...This classic play is not quite his masterpiece... "A Streetcar Named
Desire" is... It lacks some of the regretful charm of "The Glass
Menagerie" and the entire impact of "Cat On a Hot Tin Roof."
Nevertheless it is a deeply moving work of art...Williams was known for his compelling dialog and themes that - for
their time - often seemed strange or shocking... He vividly suggested
the sexual tensions and prevented violence of his tormented character,
usually with compassion as well as irony...The film focuses on a handsome drifter from New Orleans, named Val
Xavier, wearing a snake skin jacket - Williams' trademark of a rebel,
non-conformist - Val is a "fugitive kind" who comes in off the
highway... He is a rural Orpheus who descends to rescue his love, not
in Hades precisely, but among the intrigue, chatter, and violence of
the hot-tempered town of Two Rivers, Mississippi... He is a wandering
guitar player who embarks on an affair with a lonely frustrated unhappy
storekeeper's wife Lady Torrance...Anna Magnani is intelligently sensual and charming as Lady... Joanne
Woodward is the hungry grotesque drunken Carol who tries to seduce Val
in a cemetery... Both women are so intense, that they force you to
become involved with them...The genuine community provides also interesting watching: Victor Jory,
positively magnetic as the brutal oppressive husband Jabe Torrence; the
vindictive sheriff R. G. Armstrong; and the soft-hearted Vee (Maureen
Stapleton).Lady Torrence is a study of the immigrant woman who has acquired a
patina of resilient toughness but who slowly admits her sensuality...
She catches perfectly contradictory emotions of one who is wary of the
stranger but who longs for his healing touch...With handsome magnetism, Brando is no less compelling... He is quite
convincing avoiding all the clichés of the drifting Don Juan... With
some kind of lucid intensity, he mixes his character's predatory and
uncivil arrogance with flashes of sweet tenderness...The film (definitely worth seeing) is extremely poignant and
captivating... The direction is excellent and the action moves very
smoothly, never allowing you to relax...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4590945/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tsbooks1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
While The Fugitive Kind suffers from inconsistent pacing and some
over-blown dialog, it is worth watching for the peerless performances
delivered by Anna Magnani and Victor Jory. Magnani's desperate
vulnerability and passionate need for love and vindication are so
powerfully and truthfully portrayed that even the great Brando seems
pale and insubstantial beside her. Without Jory's vilely hateful
depiction of the dying husband, however, even Magnani's powerhouse
performance couldn't save the film. Seldom has such wanton cruelty been
so effectively captured on screen. Brando is a bit mannered at times
but the sheer animal magnetism he possessed at this point in his career
transcend the script's pretensions. Woodward wrings more than could
rightfully be expected from her over-written part. R.G. Armstrong as
the corrupt sheriff and Maureen Stapleton as his kind-hearted wife
shine in supporting roles, but it is Magnani and Jory who transform the
film into a riveting cinematic experience.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I suspect that Tennessee Williams probably agreed to change the title
of his classically sounding play Orpheus Descending to The Fugitive
Kind in order to insure box office. Possibly some of Marlon Brando's
fans garnered from The Wild One might pay their admissions thinking
they were seeing something like that. I can think of worst ways to be
exposed to one of America's most respected playwrights.This was Brando's second time doing Williams for the screen, the first
time being A Streetcar Named Desire. Curiously enough this was Anna
Magnani's second time doing Tennessee Williams for the screen as well,
she won an Oscar in 1955 for The Rose Tattoo. So the combination of
Brando and Magnani seemed a natural for the screen. I don't think The
Fugitive Kind is as good as Streetcar or The Rose Tattoo, but the parts
are meaty enough roles for both these honored players.Characters seem to drift in to The Fugitive Kind from other Williams
work. Brando's Val Xavier is quite like Chance Wayne in Sweet Bird of
Youth, in fact in the review's title is the illusion Brando himself
makes of his character. He's an early 30 something drifter with a
talent for sex and music, the former probably more than the latter.Unlike Chance, Xavier doesn't have a female keeper, but he'd like to
find one. He passes up liaison with the town trollop played by a third
Oscar winner in the cast, Joanne Woodward for the older and married
Anna Magnani.Magnani is trapped in a loveless marriage to a dying Victor Jory, a
petty tyrant who runs the town general store. Like Big Daddy in Cat on
a Hot Tin Roof, Jory is dying of cancer at a much more advanced stage
of the disease than Burl Ives had. Picture Big Mama from that play hot
to trot for Chance Wayne and you've got the essence of The Fugitive
Kind.Joanne Woodward has an interesting part. Part of her loose behavior is
in rebellion against the time honored tradition of institutional racism
that is the south that Tennessee Williams grew up in. I'm not an expert
on Tennessee Williams, but of the works I've seen that are revived
frequently, this is the only one where Williams directly brings up
racism. Orpheus Descending on Broadway only ran 68 performances in 1957. Two
members from the Broadway cast made it to the screen, R.G. Armstrong as
the sheriff repeating his role and Maureen Stapleton who had Joanne
Woodward's part on stage, essays the part of the sheriff's wife who
also is married to another middle aged tyrant. Considered a lesser work
of Williams at first, Orpheus Descending is now revived frequently by
stock theater companies everywhere. A critically acclaimed revival on
Broadway in 1989 with Vanessa Redgrave and Tammy Grimes and Kevin
Anderson helped bring Orpheus Descending into its proper place in the
sun.Maybe if a remake is ever done, it will even be done under its proper
original title. Till then we can be well satisfied with this version.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Tennessee Williams and Meade Roberts co-adapted Williams' play "Orpheus
Descending" about a reluctant stud drifting through backwater town,
stirring up the passions of an Italian shopkeeper who's married to a
cranky invalid. Eerie and fabulously atmospheric piece gives the women
in particular (Anna Magnani, Joanne Woodward, Maureen Stapleton) great
roles to play. Marlon Brando, well-cast as the guitar-strumming
gadabout with the bedroom eyes, doesn't seem as fully involved, and his
focus tends to wander. Overall, an intriguing soap opera for mature
audiences, beautifully photographed by Boris Kaufman and nimbly
directed by Sidney Lumet. *** from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0136588/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Ontario, Canada</from><name>Benoît A. Racine (benoit-3)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This story flopped as a play and as a film. That's too bad because that
happens to be Tennessee Williams' most revealing play about the dark
underbelly of racism, violence, vigilantes, lynchings and social
injustice in the Deep South. Be warned: This ain't "Gone With the
Wind". Its subject matter couldn't have been very popular with American
audiences at any time or any place. Even today, Jabe (Hades), the king
of the Underworld, where he keeps his Persephone/Eurydice (Lady)
prisoner, sounds an awful lot like what George W. Bush will probably
sound like in his declining years, uttering curses and maledictions
against life, knowledge, science, progress, social change and uppity
Negroes. I think the film works because it makes no concession to
realism and frankly asserts the story's mythological elements. Lumet,
Magnani, Brando, Jory, Stapleton, Armstrong and Woodward make it work
and deliver a film and performances that are bigger than life and
worthy of the best European art films of the period. Kudos for the set
design, the art direction, the music (by Kenyon Hopkins) and the
photography. This is a film you can't help but watch in absolute awe at
the guts it took.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The Fugitive Kind is a hot story of desire and loss and craving and
heartbreak between a man and two women set in the deep south. Sounds
like quintessential Tenessee Williams, and it is in spurts. Sometimes
Williams leans towards being a little preachy, however true (little
moments like when Brando and Stapleton have a quiet back and forth
about racism via her painting kind of nails it on the head much), but
it's his skills at doing melodrama that strike up the coolest beats. In
fact, this is one of those super-cool movies of the late 50s that could
have only starred someone like Brando, who looks at times disinterested
in the scene but at the same time completely engaged, curious, smooth,
harsh, and knowing of what life can bring with his trusty
Ledbelly-signed guitar. It's not necessarily a towering work for the
ages ala Williams collaboration 1 Streetcar Named Desire. But that
doesn't mean it should be much under-looked either.As an early effort for Lumet it's also a scorcher dramatically; he's so
good with the actors that whatever little missteps the script might
take in pouring on the poetic prose in how some of the characters talk
(there's a scene between Brando and Anna Magnani's characters by some
ruin of a spot where she says people used to make love that is actually
quite boring) can be usually forgiven. Magnani especially is
interesting because she should be a case of miscasting, which,
apparently in later years, Lumet admitted to. She seems low-key at
first, but her strengths bloom out tenfold when it comes time to act
like the hard-knock-life kind of woman she is, who's in a crap marriage
and had a horrible affair with a man who didn't do anything after the
summer they spent together. Now she's put into a situation where she
does and doesn't want this drifter, and vice versa, and she's sometimes
just as cool (though also quite tough and demanding in that big Italian
mama way) as her counterpart.Meanwhile there's also Joanne Woodard, who has the kind of part many
actresses love to chew on; feisty, outspoken, loud but also emotionally
moody to the point that she admirably tries (and doesn't quite get to)
the heights of Vivien Leigh with her classic Blanche Dubois. Overall,
Lumet gets a good feel for the period- and shot in New York state no
less- while working with good material and an even better cast. It
won't ever be as revered as his other work, and at the same time it's
much better than some would give it credit for, where the tragedy acts
like another sweaty Southern caricature bemoaning existence and fitting
on a bad pair of shoes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3476285/comments</url><from>from brooklyn, ny</from><name>red34birds</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

i cannot believe that i had never heard of this movie. the only
possible explanation is that it was spun out of a play that bombed.
that said, Sidney lumet does an amazing Job of lithely sprinkling the
classical over northern Mississippi (without screaming 'look were being
classical now') from a historical perspective the themes dealt with
here are amazing both for their envelope pushing and their subtle
overlay. the acting is the best I've seen. Brando is third best, Anna
M. is next. both are outdone by Woodward. The character actors Jorie
and Stapleton are better than all of them.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3863684/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>MoreLord</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is not a well-written film, but the acting is phenomenal. Brando
and Magnani have really great chemistry and that's what carries the
film. It is the acting of these two that make me want to watch this
film time and time again. I didn't necessarily like Joanne Woodward in
her role, it just didn't seem to fit her. It seemed like she was trying
too hard or something, so I just tuned her out. But I was always tuned
into Brando--its just something about him that just pulls you
in--wondering what he'll do next in the scene. Anyway, The
cinematography is great and adds to the moodiness of the film. Overall,
the movie isn't necessarily Brando's greatest film, but it's by no
means one of his worst. Unfortunately, there wasn't much to work with
as far as the script, so the acting had to carry the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3971256/comments</url><from>from Bowling Green Kentucky</from><name>Ambrotype</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Indeed this movie is a bit wordy at times,particularly the scenes with
Anna Maganani but the Quality of the Acting and the
Photography/Lighting is at times second to none.In fact the lighting of
the the graveyard scene inspired me years ago to become a Photographer.The Marlon Brando/Joanne Woodword scenes are superb throughout,the
scenes of the two of them ripping down the "Dixie" Highway in her
beater Jaguar Convertible are priceless.Maureen Stapleton portrays an
Artist with real emotion.You can feel/smell the presence of the the
sweaty,racist invalid Jabe.'The Juke Joint' scenes are classic.Even the
Soundtrack is good.You must see this Outstanding movie.It will stay with you.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20961309/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>secondtake</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The Fugitive Kind (1960)This is one of those great movies that slips its way into that big gap
between the great Hollywood Golden Age to the great New Hollywood of
the late 1960s. An awful lot of films from the period between (1955-65)
are weak or even downright bad, big budgets and all. The Hollywood gems
in that time are usually a little gut wrenching, and many are based on
plays, or push political issues (I'm thinking of "The Apartment" and
"The Manchurian Candidate"). The famous directors coming to their own
during time include Elia Kazan and Robert Wise, and of course Sidney
Lumet, who directed this one.This is all working class, plainspeaking, emotive material. Right from
the get-go with leading man Marlon Brando doing a long take as he
stands before a judge, we are filled with heart-wrenching stuff, people
who want to be something and don't know how, or people with big hearts
that are broken or dirty. The cast, beyond Brando, is terrific: Joanne
Woodward as a young floozy with a sharp sense of independence, Maureen
Stapleton as a simple and faith filled wife of the sheriff, and Anna
Magnani, intense and troubled but superior in her own out of place way.There are powerful displays of white narrow-mindedness (call it
bigotry, but it is largely aimed at just anyone they don't like) that
don't quite fall into clichés, there is love that shouldn't be and that
never is, there is old world morality and inbred local gossipy
immorality. Things are bound for collision even by twenty minutes in,
and there are innuendoes and hidden histories waiting to blossom. Lumet has a knack for the serious, with his 1957 breakthrough film "12
Angry Men" a template for his career. As lively and even crazy as this
movie is, it's also probing deeply into human woe and maladjustment
(often deliberate). The core of the writing belongs to Tennessee
Williams, who of course is all about inner troubles and outward
misunderstood or mistaken actions. There is nothing superficial here,
not in the acting, the filming, or the scenes (set in the South but
filmed near Saratoga Springs, New York). And if the wet, dark nights
scenes and interiors with people quarreling and fighting aren't enough
to suck you in, the story, about wanting to live, nothing more, is
beautiful and important. All four of the main characters are deeply
good people, and all flawed in small but debilitating ways. Which should sound familiar. As over the top as it sometimes seems,
you'll identify with the position some of the people end up in. Brando
is temperamental but patient and with a profound sense of justice.
Woodward is a free spirit misunderstood (and punished) but the uptight
and hypocritical society around her. The themes are frank for 1960,
including an implication of a male so manly and irresistible the women
want him (and get him) even when it's completely wrong. And when it's
right. The sexuality, partly pumped up by the writing of the openly gay
playwright (Williams), is all over Brando's face and in his scenes. And
this is his movie.High high drama, but from within. And explosive. Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20961309/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>secondtake</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The Fugitive Kind (1960)This is one of those great movies that slips its way into that big gap
between the great Hollywood Golden Age to the great New Hollywood of
the late 1960s. An awful lot of films from the period between (1955-65)
are weak or even downright bad, big budgets and all. The Hollywood gems
in that time are usually a little gut wrenching, and many are based on
plays, or push political issues (I'm thinking of "The Apartment" and
"The Manchurian Candidate"). The famous directors coming to their own
during time include Elia Kazan and Robert Wise, and of course Sidney
Lumet, who directed this one.This is all working class, plainspeaking, emotive material. Right from
the get-go with leading man Marlon Brando doing a long take as he
stands before a judge, we are filled with heart-wrenching stuff, people
who want to be something and don't know how, or people with big hearts
that are broken or dirty. The cast, beyond Brando, is terrific: Joanne
Woodward as a young floozy with a sharp sense of independence, Maureen
Stapleton as a simple and faith filled wife of the sheriff, and Anna
Magnani, intense and troubled but superior in her own out of place way.There are powerful displays of white narrow-mindedness (call it
bigotry, but it is largely aimed at just anyone they don't like) that
don't quite fall into clichés, there is love that shouldn't be and that
never is, there is old world morality and inbred local gossipy
immorality. Things are bound for collision even by twenty minutes in,
and there are innuendoes and hidden histories waiting to blossom. Lumet has a knack for the serious, with his 1957 breakthrough film "12
Angry Men" a template for his career. As lively and even crazy as this
movie is, it's also probing deeply into human woe and maladjustment
(often deliberate). The core of the writing belongs to Tennessee
Williams, who of course is all about inner troubles and outward
misunderstood or mistaken actions. There is nothing superficial here,
not in the acting, the filming, or the scenes (set in the South but
filmed near Saratoga Springs, New York). And if the wet, dark nights
scenes and interiors with people quarreling and fighting aren't enough
to suck you in, the story, about wanting to live, nothing more, is
beautiful and important. All four of the main characters are deeply
good people, and all flawed in small but debilitating ways. Which should sound familiar. As over the top as it sometimes seems,
you'll identify with the position some of the people end up in. Brando
is temperamental but patient and with a profound sense of justice.
Woodward is a free spirit misunderstood (and punished) but the uptight
and hypocritical society around her. The themes are frank for 1960,
including an implication of a male so manly and irresistible the women
want him (and get him) even when it's completely wrong. And when it's
right. The sexuality, partly pumped up by the writing of the openly gay
playwright (Williams), is all over Brando's face and in his scenes. And
this is his movie.High high drama, but from within. And explosive. Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20961309/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>secondtake</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-long/</url><url>http://www.dvdtown.com/review/fugitive-kind-the-the-criterion-collection/dvd/8016 /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1882431</url><name>Christopher Long</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/10
					</rating><comment>Unfortunately the movie doesnt offer much else to supplement Brandos masterstrokes. </comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-kendrick/</url><url>http://www.qnetwork.com/index.php?page=review&amp;id=2369 /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1882398</url><name>James Kendrick</name><from>Q Network Film Desk</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Seeing Marlon Brando still at the young, Method-fueled heights of his career makes the film imminently watchable</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sean-axmaker/</url><url>http://www.seanax.com/2010/04/26/the-fugitive-and-the-devil-two-portraits-of-the-south-revived-by-criterion/ /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1881534</url><name>Sean Axmaker</name><from>Seanax.com</from></reviewer><comment>Highly theatrical and dripping with gothic atmosphere, it's hardly realistic and the love story never convinces, but it is mesmerizing...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pablo-villaca/</url><url>/m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1881529</url><name>Pablo Villaca</name><from>Cinema em Cena</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Carregado de subtexto e profundamente crítico no que diz respeito ao conservadorismo norte-americano, traz Brando e Magnani impecáveis e intensos em uma narrativa sensível e impecavelmente comandada por Lumet.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/fugitive-kind-the-1961-5/ /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1750333</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>The superb acting by Marlon Brando, Anna Magnani, and Joanne Woodward and some lyrical passages of Tennessee William's play compensate for the stagnant production--a must for Brando fans.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/fugitivekind.htm /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1619783</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>A stagy and ponderous film that lacks soul.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-nusair/</url><url>http://www.reelfilm.com/mgmbrand.htm#fugitive /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1453921</url><name>David Nusair</name><from>Reel Film Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
2/4
					</rating><comment>...though Brando delivers a performance that's just as engaging and mesmerizing as one might expect, the movie is a dull, relentlessly talky exercise in pointlessness.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nick-davis/</url><url>http://www.nicksflickpicks.com/fugkind.html /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1119803</url><name>Nick Davis</name><from>Nick's Flick Picks</from></reviewer><rating>
D
					</rating><comment>An almost unbelievably sluggish and uninflected adaptation of Tennessee Williams' searing Orpheus Descending.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1212895</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/walter-chaw/</url><url>/m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1161701</url><name>Walter Chaw</name><from>Film Freak Central</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117791153.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1742967</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/67155/the_fugitive_kind.html /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1475364</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9F00EEDF153EEF3ABC4D52DFB266838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1389546</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=103655 /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=1149317</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/12158_FUGITIVE_KIND.html /m/fugitive_kind/comments.php?reviewid=26316</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>