<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>College Confidential</original_title><imdb_rating>4.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Albert Zugsmith</director><producer>Famous Players</producer><producer>Allen-Meadows</producer><producer>Albert Zugsmith Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Sociology professor Steve McInter is conducting a survey at Collins College about the mores and lifestyles of the young people...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Steve Allen</actor><actor>Jayne Meadows</actor><actor>Walter Winchell</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0257686/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Louis Rugani (x779@webtv.net)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

I saw this theatrically, and despite the mindless comings and goings of
the
unexplainable cast that was assembled for this opus, it seemed everyone
involved in its production was enjoying themselves tremendously ... and I
did too. It's one of those thrown-together packages that still manages to
entertain, though when it's all over you'll be hard-pressed to explain
exactly why you enjoyed yourself. Wacky fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Wow, did the casting in this film pique my interest. Here are some of
the stars of this odd little film: Steve Allen and his wife (Jayne
Meadows), Jayne Mansfield AND Mamie Van Doren (I can't believe they
could squeeze these two in the same screen), Herbert Marshall, Rocky
Marciano (the boxer), Conway Twitty(!), Cathy Crosby (Bing's niece) and
lots of kids of famous stars--Robert Montgomery Jr., William Wellman
Jr. and Elisha Cook Jr.! And, in an odd move, gossip columnists Sheila
Graham AND Walter Winchell! Talk about a strange cast! The film begins
with Mamie Van Doren coming home late from a date. It's rather funny
seeing this 30 year-old bombshell playing a college student and it was
also funny seeing her father (Elisha Cook Sr.) and his overreaction
when she got home late. Of course, if I had a daughter who looked like
Miss Van Doren, I am sure I'd be just as crazed when she came home
late!!! After her dad interrogates her further, Mamie responds by
saying she was out late...with one of her professors (Steve Allen)!
When pressed, she blamed his "sex survey" and him trying to force
himself on her--THAT'S why she's home so late.Instead of trying to verify all this, Cook bounds into Allen's office
the next day--making accusations and fuming. Allen seems to have a
solid alibi, but after Cook storms off, it isn't so certain this IS the
case. Is Allen a pervert asking 'dirty questions' and on the make for
co-eds or is this just the case of some amazingly sexually repressed
people overreacting to a harmless sociology survey? In other words, is
Mamie a slut or is Allen a creeper? Tune in to see the answers.In the meantime, when the audience isn't sure who exactly is at fault,
the question is muddied because some Allen's behaviors then look a bit
creepy. For example, you see him with a motion picture camera recording
the teens at the lake. Is this more 'research"?! Plus you learn that
this isn't the first college girl to claim Allen's made improper
advances. Plus, he loves to invite the students over to his house for
parties. And, for her part, Mamie seems about as shy and innocent as
Divine--as she relentlessly pursues her boyfriend. Her 'innocent child'
routine is very transparent and how anyone could worry about HER
becoming corrupted is a puzzler! Eventually, Allen runs afoul of the
law and eventually he and his 'sex survey' are on trial. This occurs
after it appears as if the professor might have been set up for a
morals charge. No one really seems to care whether or not Allen really
did anything--they just want to punish him! Can the teacher get a fair
shake in this apparent witch hunt? See this--as the ending is just
crazy--with Allen speechifying and a way over the top performance by
someone else to cap it all off.Overall, hardly believable and often poorly written and silly. BUT,
considering how silly it all gets, it IS very entertaining.By the way, there is a funny inside joke in the film. When Sally Blake
(Van Doren) is about to testify, one of the folks in court describes
her as "...a Mamie Van Doren type"!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

This movie has no real redeeming qualities. It is a silly mess. And how they
got some of these stars to even do this thing is a mind bender. But then
again the cast is not what you call a stellar cast. Steve Allen is a
sociology professor with a special project he would like to complete before
getting ran out of town. He is conducting a survey that is 20% sexual
questions, but the towns people fear he is corrupting their community
college students. Jane Meadows is a reporter trying to do a story on the
professor accused of hanky panky with some of his students.Since I am not and never have been a Steve Allen fan, the only reason I
watched this was for singer Conway Twitty. I have always liked Twitty when
he was a rock 'n' roller. He was not too much of a disappointment, but he
only had a few lines and a couple of scenes. And even he had to ashamed of
the song he sang. Also in the cast is Mamie Van Doren. She was in top form
playing Twitty's girl. A sexpot is a sexpot, how can I
complain?Also in this silly romp are: Mickey Shaughnessy, Elisha Cook Jr.,Walter
Winchell, Rocky Marciano and Cathy Crosby.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0550290/comments</url><from>from Cold Spring, KY</from><name>Andy Sandfoss</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I saw this peculiar film a couple of times very late at night in the
60's; I thought it humorous and slightly provocative at the time. But I
was about 12 then too. When I got to see it again as an adult on AMC, I
found my tastes and perceptions had changed somewhat. My chief
impressions of it now are: a) Steve Allen wasn't a very good actor, b)
his wife Jayne Meadows wasn't very good either, c) the film was awfully
contrived and preachy, and brimming with stereotypes. I found it
interesting that at the time Allen chose to play a heroic professor
persecuted for seeking frankness and truth about sex, and years later
he lead a self- righteous "anti-smut" crusade against movies and TV. I
suppose that sometimes hypocrisy needs years to ripen and bloom. In any
case, this film isn't likely to arouse much interest or respect
nowadays.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1163639/comments</url><from>from mission, ks</from><name>eminges</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>

In my ongoing quest to find the World's Worst Movie, I thought I'd found a
new hero: Albert Zugsmith.  Sex Kittens Go To College and Private Lives of
Adam and Eve were awful in new, interesting, and creative ways.  You can't
actually debase actors like Woo Woo Grabowski, Mickey Rooney, and Martin
Milner; you put them on the same set, give them a little freedom to create,
and let them surprise you with their creativity in making you want to crawl
under porch with the brown recluse spiders and whimper.So I was sure that College Confidential would complete the set: "C" -list
actors, a fresh shipment of tight sweaters for the goils, hot rods and
sexual frustration for the guys, and a solemn promise in the promos to
deliver hot thrills you KNOW Zugsmith couldn't make good
on.Big mistake.  There's a difference between making a fool of yourself and
publicly humiliating yourself.  In College Confidential, at the height of
his career, Steve Allen publicly humiliates himself.  Many people don't know that in later life, he became enough of an expert on
the Bible to have several serious books of commentary published in
hardcover.  Perhaps, years later, it was waking up at three AM in a cold
sweat from remorseful nightmares about College Confidential that turned
Steve Allen's face to the Lord.  We'll never know.  I DO know is that this is the first bad film I couldn't finish (although I
got through Plutonium Baby only by walking out for twenty minutes in the
middle).  When the grim inevitability of the Spiked Punch Scene became
clear, I turned off the VCR, got a bowl of Apple Cinnamon Cheerios, wandered
out to the darkened balcony, and thought about Death for an hour.  Then I
felt better.       
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0476215/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, CA</from><name>frere</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie has a professional cast and good production values but it so
unclear as to what it wants to be about that its all for nothing. It does
portray college students pretty much as they really are: ready to label
other people as creeps, not seeing what creeps they are themselves.
However,
Steve Allen really does seem creepy as the professor. That scene, where he
accidentally shows the porno film cut into the home movies of wholesome
student fun! It really and truly is embarassing to watch, just as if you
were really there. I've never seen a  scene like that it in any other
movie.
The only thing that comes anywhere near close is the gay bar scene in
"Advise and Consent" Any showcase for Mamie Van Doren is a good thing. I
would say more but I couldn't finish watching it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13656993/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>planetguy</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I agree with the "defies expectations" label. This film gets high marks
from me because it is so bizarre. It seems to have a point, although
its insanely portrayed. Sex was then and is still now a taboo that is
beyond the capability of a large fraction of Americans to deal with.
Want proof of that? Just look what happens when sexual peccadilloes of
celebrities including politicians are made public. All other interests
come to a standstill until that story is taken to its chilling
cornclusion. As Oscar Wilde said, he would rather crawl to the North
Pole on his knees than have the public know about his sex life. This
movie doesn't really confront this issue but does show a nice depiction
of the a low-key mob mentality. Why the real people consented to do
this movie is a puzzle, but its good they did.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12596887/comments</url><from/><name>JohnHowardReid</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Herbert Marshall fans are going to be a bit distressed to find their
idol sharing the seamy surroundings of Uncle Albert's "College" with
the likes of Steve Allen, Conway Twitty and Uncle Al's usual grab-bag
of exploitable "names". Usually, the direction at least can be rated as
pretty slick in an Albert Zugsmith production, but on this occasion he
has directed the movie himself. Instead of rating as reasonably lively,
the proceedings here are dull, slow-moving and indeed
super-lethargically paced. Production values also seem unusually tight.
In addition to flat camera-work, boringly routine film editing, and
cheap, clapboard sets, even the songs are dull and desultory. And worst
of all, Miss Van Doren reveals little of her customary talent. Alas,
even measured by lowly Zugsmith standards, this entry is pretty much of
a bore.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4969213/comments</url><from>from Arizona</from><name>mrb1980</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
It's rather hard to believe that Steve Allen, Jayne Meadows, Mamie Van
Doren, Mickey Shaughnessy, Conway Twitty, Elisha Cook, Jr., Rocky
Marciano, Herbert Marshall, and Walter Winchell could appear in the
same movie. These folks (plus many others) all appear in "College
Confidential", and the film is predictably bad.Allen plays sociology Prof. Macinter, who is surveying the sexual
attitudes of his students, much to the chagrin of some students'
parents. Macinter believes in openness about sex, and therefore creates
something of an uproar in his conservative college town. He is showing
some home movies of his students when suddenly a (gasp) nude scene is
spliced into the film, causing all kinds of trouble for Macinter,
including the cold shoulder from his girlfriend (Meadows). A "trial" of
sorts is held in the general store of pious and self-righteous Sam
Grover (Shaughnessy). The trial is accompanied by some of the most
painfully preachy sermons you'll ever hear on film. A surprise twist
ending exonerates Macinter...but sorry, you'll have to watch the movie.I really like Steve Allen and have loved about everything he's ever
done, but this movie is just ridiculous. It was considered somewhat
daring in 1960, but now it just seems silly. The appearance of
30-year-old bombshell Van Doren as a college student just makes the
proceedings all the more preposterous. I will admit that the ending is
worth watching, but it sure takes a long time to get there. You may
want to watch this movie just for the cast, but you'll never watch it
for the story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169553/comments</url><from>from North Hollyweird</from><name>reluctantpopstar</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I suppose there is some point to be made here about classic Liberal
values, but the point is put across so ham-fistedly and lead-footedly
that you almost want to side with the outraged squares (represented by
Elisha Cook) who supposedly want to tar and feather Steve Allen's
protagonist professor character and run him out of town.For me, the true moment of hogwash is the "porno movie" scene at the
prof's beachside playhouse. When the supposed stag film that has been
edited into Steve's innocent home movies comes on the screen, all the
students get disgusted and walk out! YEAH, RIGHT! Even in 1959, I'm
sure college students would not be averse to watching ancient
"pornography," since most of the stuff from that era is so tame it
looks like a current Victoria's Secret TV commercial that plays at any
hour of the day. And then he's charged with "corrupting the morals of a
minor." Shut up! All of these people were over 18, which means that
they were all ADULTS (okay, perhaps a few were under 18, but only
just...we're not talking about children here).Then comes the final "courtroom" (aka general store) scene, which as
usual in bad movies, contains endless pompous and self-righteous
speechifying disguised as Weighty Pronouncements. UGH! He did make one
important point at the end though...if this could happen now, what
chance do men of science and enlightenment have in the future against
the will of the ignorant mob? With today's current political situation
in mind, not much chance, Steve, not much. With that in mind, I elevate
the movie's rating, but only just, from a 1 to a 2.That's the highest I can rate this turkey in good conscience.However, it does feature Woo Woo Grabowski, who has the best stage name
this side of Whoopi Goldberg.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169553/comments</url><from>from North Hollyweird</from><name>reluctantpopstar</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I suppose there is some point to be made here about classic Liberal
values, but the point is put across so ham-fistedly and lead-footedly
that you almost want to side with the outraged squares (represented by
Elisha Cook) who supposedly want to tar and feather Steve Allen's
protagonist professor character and run him out of town.For me, the true moment of hogwash is the "porno movie" scene at the
prof's beachside playhouse. When the supposed stag film that has been
edited into Steve's innocent home movies comes on the screen, all the
students get disgusted and walk out! YEAH, RIGHT! Even in 1959, I'm
sure college students would not be averse to watching ancient
"pornography," since most of the stuff from that era is so tame it
looks like a current Victoria's Secret TV commercial that plays at any
hour of the day. And then he's charged with "corrupting the morals of a
minor." Shut up! All of these people were over 18, which means that
they were all ADULTS (okay, perhaps a few were under 18, but only
just...we're not talking about children here).Then comes the final "courtroom" (aka general store) scene, which as
usual in bad movies, contains endless pompous and self-righteous
speechifying disguised as Weighty Pronouncements. UGH! He did make one
important point at the end though...if this could happen now, what
chance do men of science and enlightenment have in the future against
the will of the ignorant mob? With today's current political situation
in mind, not much chance, Steve, not much. With that in mind, I elevate
the movie's rating, but only just, from a 1 to a 2.That's the highest I can rate this turkey in good conscience.However, it does feature Woo Woo Grabowski, who has the best stage name
this side of Whoopi Goldberg.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>