<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Cone of Silence</original_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Charles Frend</director><producer>Aubrey Baring Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A seasoned pilot is condemned for an error which causes a crash. The pilot later dies in a crash with similar circumstances and an examiner looks for scientific reasons for the crashes.
</synopsis><actor>Michael Craig</actor><actor>Peter Cushing</actor><actor>Bernard Lee</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0564686/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Al Baker</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is quite a good movie with a cast of familiar faces (Peter Cushing,
George Sanders, Gordon Jackson). The screenplay is based on David Beaty's
novel which was inspired by actual events. In October 1952 one of BOAC's
new
Comet jetliners crashed at Rome Airport. The accident was due to a design
error that allowed the pilot to raise the nose too high on take off and
stall the airplane on the ground. The pilot was blamed for the crash and
relegated to flying piston engined freighters. The following year another
Comet, on a delivery flight to Canadian Pacific Airlines crashed on taking
off from Karachi, Pakistan in identical circumstances. Following this
accident, design modifications were made to the Comet to prevent further
similar incidents.The movie follows this scenario quite closely, except that Captain Gort,
the
pilot blamed for the crash (played by Bernard Lee), continues to fly the
fictional "Phoenix" jets and  subsequently dies in an identical accident.
It
is left to the Airline's initially sceptical training Captain (Michael
Craig) and Captain Gort's daughter (Elizabeth Seal) to clear her father's
name and get the airplane modified in the nick of time to prevent a third
crash.Although made on a smallish budget and with some model shots that look a
little shaky today, this is a cut above the typical Hollywood airborne
disaster epic. Little seen today, especially in it's original 'scope ratio,
this deserves more recognition.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1609098/comments</url><from>from Swansea, Wales, UK</from><name>swanjac</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

I haven't seen this film for years, which is a pity because all i
remember
are a few powerful scenes thanks to the very impressive
cast.
Based on true events, but subtly changed to avoid law-suits, its actually
a
compelling little drama, a shame it hasn't been shown more
often.
The story on which it is based, the KNOWN Design Flaws in the Comet which
were Covered up by the De Havilland company, and the subsequent
"sacrifice"
of an entire airline and its passengers in Italy, is actually screaming
out
to be remade!
In this case, the truth is far worse than fiction...in the film, decent
noble people save the day, in the reality alas...less noble and darker
motives won...and people died needlessly.
The performances in this little melodrama were so good, i actually
remembered this film for at least 25 years...thats when i last saw it i
think..well worth catching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11556497/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>bairdmhi</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This film had good actors and good direction, and it was worth the few
dollars that I spent on the DVD. However I was disappointed by the weak
McGuffin.That is the term invented by Alfred Hitchcock for the key ingredient in
the plot that everyone is chasing -- the jewels, the microfilm, the
beautiful princess or whatever. In this case the McGuffin was the
rather obvious fact that under hot and humid conditions the air is less
dense and therefore a higher speed is needed to take off a plane. It
seems incredible that all those talented designers and skilled pilots
seem to have missed the McGuffin until the final scene.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11556497/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>bairdmhi</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This film had good actors and good direction, and it was worth the few
dollars that I spent on the DVD. However I was disappointed by the weak
McGuffin.That is the term invented by Alfred Hitchcock for the key ingredient in
the plot that everyone is chasing -- the jewels, the microfilm, the
beautiful princess or whatever. In this case the McGuffin was the
rather obvious fact that under hot and humid conditions the air is less
dense and therefore a higher speed is needed to take off a plane. It
seems incredible that all those talented designers and skilled pilots
seem to have missed the McGuffin until the final scene.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11556497/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>bairdmhi</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>