<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sotto dieci bandiere</original_title><alt_title>Sous dix drapeaux</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>USA</country><director>Duilio Coletti</director><producer>Dino de Laurentiis Cinematografica</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>Sensational 665-Day Pursuit of the Killer-Ship Atlantis!</synopsis><actor>Van Heflin</actor><actor>Charles Laughton</actor><actor>Mylène Demongeot</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8504382/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>  (opet@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Sadly, this movie has not been commercially available for many years.
It is story about a rarely mentioned weapon of WWII, the German Surface
Raider. They were ordinary merchant ships lined with amour plating and
medium-sized navel guns. Unlike the famous U-boats which could hide
beneath the sea, Surface Raiders relied on disguise to blend in with
normal shipping traffic until they could find a lone ship they could
surprise and sink.This is the story of the hunt to find and destroy the best of them, the
ship Atlantis. It is a story of bravery and ingenuity on both sides as
the British Admiralty is caught up in a vast game of hide-n-seek with a
clever adversary.I choose to write this review largely because I have, over the years
read a few rather poor opinions expressed about it. I can't wait for it
to reappear somewhere, someday. My only explanation as to why someone
who is a fan of naval war films would not thoroughly enjoy this one is
the fact that the last three times I saw it over fifteen years ago the
reels of the movie were in the wrong order! (I swear). That dampens the
suspense considerably and gives it a very muddled, confused look. But
even mixed up it beats a lot of movies I've seen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1574876/comments</url><from>from St Augustine, Florida</from><name>carolted</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I have not seen this film in more than 30 years. I can't
imagine
why it is not available on vhs or dvd. I saw it originally
in
the theaters and it made quite an impact on me. I love sea
tales
and this is one of the finest. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1574876/comments</url><from>from St Augustine, Floria</from><name>carole dutton (carolted@aug.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

It has been many years since I saw this film but I remember it
to
be interesting with a differant view of the war through the
eyes
of the captain of the german raider, Atlantis. He is shown to
be
compassionate in saving as many lives as he can from the ships
that
he sinks and is not at all in agreement with Hitler's policies
but
his country is as war and so he obeys his orders.
It is a shame that this film is not available on tape or otherwise
as
it depicts the other side of German officers not in "lock step"
with
Hitler.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3918284/comments</url><from>from Cambridgeshire, UK</from><name>Keith G</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
A thoroughly enjoyable movie with real ships and lots of original
wartime footage, which make it a refreshing change from some of the
slick but unconvincing modern offerings. More than a few of the usual,
expected stereotypes are depicted, but the plot chunters along at a
cracking pace, interspersing furious naval action with some
well-observed 'stiff upper lip' screenplay, some nerve-wracking
espionage work and any number of amusing little character studies.Honour, death, determination, courage, childbirth, duplicity, fear and
humour are dealt with in turn and all acted out in a thoroughly
workmanlike manner. Van Heflin is superb as the captain of the German
ship and the unutterably delectable Mylene Demongeot is stunning as a
perky nymphette who, obviously fearing her looks would fade before the
end of the film, seemed desperate to hook a guy (any guy) before the
end credits! As might be expected, the entirely dependable Charles
Laughton did a sterling job of playing Charles Laughton - in a Sailor
Suit! Without exception the rest of the supporting cast were top notch
- all the way down to the brave little kids being winched aboard ship
in a cargo net!!As it is based on true events, this movie is all the more worth
watching by anyone who enjoys naval warfare stories and is heartily
recommended!An 8 out of 10 without hesitation for me....
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0558468/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>lobo1955</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is truly a classic!  It portrays war at sea, as a deadly game of hide
and seek.  Cause as much havoc and destruction, without being identified or
located.  In this movie, the enemy(the British) has no idea what kind of
ship(s) or submarine(s)are sinking vital merchant ships.  It is a raider
ship,with a clever Captain that can change the appearance  of his ship as
quickly as changing clothes!  Nationalities were no obstacle.  It also
showed that all German officers were not followers of Hitler.  This one, in
real life, went on to serve as a NATO naval officer.  This ship's crew
should have lots of war stories for the grandchildren.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2694100/comments</url><from>from Edinburgh. Scotland</from><name>sogs (smischa@blueyonder.co.uk)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I don't see this film in as nearly a bad light as some of the other
commentator's here. There is good performances from Van Heflin and
Laughton is always a joy to watch. There are certainly some obvious
Italian extras thrown into this movie but whats bad about that? I for
one can give the thumbs up for the female actors. Great bodies on them
even though its in black and white! Stock footage is used in abundance
for the sinking of the ships but the actual guns firing and being
uncovered on the German vessel looks like the real deal to me. So sure,
its not a masterpiece but give it a chance and I am sure you will find
it a time passer.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1034207/comments</url><from/><name>Bob R (bikerbob75@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Under Ten Flags..Is in my opinion one of the best acted and directed
movies
dealing with world war II. It depicts a man's duty to country..  his
personal honor to himself in up-holding honest and humanitarian beliefs
even
when required to do his duty and kill the enemy. The lead is by veteran
actor Van Heflin.,who plays the captain of the German Raider
"Atlantis".,this is based on a true story and facts of the german surface
raider "Pacas" during world war two. This type of war movie needs to be
returned to the screen to show our younger generation that although war is
brutal and even unavoidable man can still win or lose with dignity and
honour. I would like to see this movie made available on Video and
returned
to TV.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5267142/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>triumph-tsx</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Rarely seen like it's subject matter, a film whose story is well told
and a world away from the child-like American war epics released later
in that decade. The surface raider Atlantis was perhaps the most
successful of it's type preying upon merchant shipping destined for
Great Britain and her allies. The performances top-to-bottom are
splendid although the silent scenes at the German Atlantic Naval
Headquarters in Paris ratchet up the tension like little else on
celluloid-more so because of it's being based on truth. Superior to
naval films both those that came before and after it because it's story
is so compelling, true and hardly known. There are no sides to be taken
and yet one wishes both sides well in this game of naval chess. Indeed,
the captain of the merchant ship Abdullah who -in war circumstances
would be considered a hero- comes out as the only villain of the piece.
That the Germans mostly all speak with American accents is forgotten
easily in the action and minor characters are well-sketched by their
players. There is none of the John Wayne -machismo and black and white
simplicity that makes most war films loud but laughable but rather
admiring the quiet professionalism of sailors at war- highly
recommended, indeed !
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
However incredible they may seem the events narrated in this picture
actually occurred and starred by Bernhard Rogge (Van Heflin), captain
of the German raider at that time called Atlantis . It deals with the
sensational 665-Day chase of the Killer-Ship Atlantis captained by
Bernhard Rogge pursued by the British staff commanded by Admiral
Russell (Charles Laughton ) ; including an intrigue upon secret agent
(Alex Nicol) robbing documents by means of a dangerous mission .This interesting war movie contains suspense , thrills, sea battles and
historical events . It's an European co-production lavishly and mostly
produced by the great Italian producer Dino De Laurentiis . Exceptional
cast formed by European actors as Italian as Gian Maria Volonte ,
Eleonora Rossi Drago ,Folco Lulli , Corrado Pani , American as Van
Heflin ,Alex Nicol ,Walter Barnes , French as Mylene Demongeot ,
British as Charles Laughton , Cecil Parker , Ralph Truman , and German
as John Ericson ,Peter Carsten , Gerard Herter , Helmut Schmid , Diete
Eppler . Very good musical score by the classic Nino Rota , with tunes
similarly composed to the subsequent The Godfather . Atmospheric
cinematography by Aldo Tonti , though is necessary a fine remastering
and contains several stock-shots . The motion picture is well directed
by Duilio Coletti .The picture is based upon events which actually occurred during a
series of naval actions in 1940-41 and carried out by Bernhard Rogge
(1899-1982) exceptionally played by Van Hefiln . Rogge was one of many
German officers who were forced to apply for a German Blood
Certificate, that would allow their racial background to be overlooked
(he had a Jewish grandparent).He was awarded a Japanese ornate Samurai
sword and the Oak Leaves to the Knight's Cross of the Iron Cross for
his actions as the commander of the Hilfskreuzer (auxiliary cruiser)
Atlantis . Rogge became a Vizeadmiral (vice-admiral) by the end of
World War II, and eventually became a Konteradmiral (rear-admiral) of
the West German Bundesmarine. Rogge also was one of the few German
officers of flag rank who was not arrested by the Allies after the war.
This was due to the way he had exercised his command of Atlantis.The
skipper of the British vessel, City of Baghdad, which the Atlantis sunk
in July 1941, stated, "His treatment of prisoners left respect, instead
of hatred". Admiral Karl Dönitz, who was prosecuted for war crimes at
the Nuremberg Trials, cited his own support of Rogge in an effort to
clear himself of the charge of being antisemitic. Rogge was later a
German officer for Nato in the territorial Allied Naval Forces .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6917519/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ce8ctdow</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
The previous review is correct, this is a poor film. However the lack
of blood 'n' guts is based on fact. Atlantis was captained by Bernhard
Rogge. The skipper of the British vessel, "City of Baghdad", which the
Atlantis sunk in July of 1941, stated, "His treatment of prisoners left
respect, instead of hatred." The Captain of the "City of Baghdad" was
Captain J. Armstrong-White. He wrote the foreword in "Atlantis, The
story of a German Surface Raider" written by U. Mohr &amp; A.V. Sellwood.Rogge became a Vizeadmiral (vice-admiral) by the end of World War II,
and eventually became a Konteradmiral (rear-admiral) of the West German
Bundesmarine.Rogge also was one of the few German officers of flag rank who was not
arrested by the Allies after the war. This was due to the way he had
exercised his command of Atlantis.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6917519/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ce8ctdow</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
The previous review is correct, this is a poor film. However the lack
of blood 'n' guts is based on fact. Atlantis was captained by Bernhard
Rogge. The skipper of the British vessel, "City of Baghdad", which the
Atlantis sunk in July of 1941, stated, "His treatment of prisoners left
respect, instead of hatred." The Captain of the "City of Baghdad" was
Captain J. Armstrong-White. He wrote the foreword in "Atlantis, The
story of a German Surface Raider" written by U. Mohr &amp; A.V. Sellwood.Rogge became a Vizeadmiral (vice-admiral) by the end of World War II,
and eventually became a Konteradmiral (rear-admiral) of the West German
Bundesmarine.Rogge also was one of the few German officers of flag rank who was not
arrested by the Allies after the war. This was due to the way he had
exercised his command of Atlantis.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6917519/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ce8ctdow</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>