<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>G.I. Blues</original_title><alt_title>Café Europa en uniforme</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Norman Taurog</director><producer>Hal Wallis Productions</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Musical</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Tulsa is a specialist in the US Army stationed in Germany. He loves to sing and has dreams to run his own nightclub when he leaves the army...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Elvis Presley</actor><actor>Juliet Prowse</actor><actor>Robert Ivers</actor><rt_rating>4.7/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>0</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Elvis was photographed in uniform while still in service (in Germany) for
this amusing, light service comedy.  He must make good on a bet made for
another serviceman who's been sent to Alaska -- to bed dancer Prowse within
a week.  She's legendarily cold, but warms up to E's garrulous charms and
his chivalry.  She takes him out to the country, where he sings to her on a
ski-lift and (unfortunately) at a children's puppet show.  This is really
the beginning of the new Elvis, the family Elvis, which is now despised by
many fans of his grittier 50s act, but also really helped him sustain his
career through the weird 60s pop music atmosphere.  A lot of people that are
into Elvis are down on his movie recordings, but the fact is that this is
what kept his stuff going when others who came up in rock and roll (Chuck
Berry, Gene Vincent, Bill Haley, etc.) were faltering or beginning
exclusively European and Mexican tours and films.  The film, as it is, should serve as nostalgia for some, and as a bright spot
of silliness on the now much bleaker cinema screens.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1725119/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas, NV</from><name>Shane Paterson</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Those of us who're into Elvis' music and other parts of his considerable
musical and cultural legacy should probably hate this movie.  After all,
it
was the first symptom that something fundamental had changed in Elvis'
career after his two years in the US Army.  This film, obviously inspired
by
recent events in Elvis' life, gives us a sanitized King who's
family-friendly and anything but the threat to society's moral fabric that
he was perceived as being a few short years before.  At 25, Elvis was now
vetted as suitable for family consumption.  Not that that's a bad thing.
The March, 1960 recordings that produced some of Elvis' biggest hits ("Are
You Lonesome Tonight" and the phenomenally-successful "It's Now Or Never"
among them) featured some of the best material that he'd ever recorded,
but
generally confirmed a shift -- or perhaps really a broadening -- in focus.
Maybe the two years in the Army and his first real exposure to the world
beyond his own country had matured him, especially given that he'd
suffered
through the loss of his mother during that time.Still, the version of Elvis that "GI Blues" presented went a step further
than just maturity.  If it'd been a one-off deal there'd have been no
problem -- the problem was that they kept trying to remake the film, as
Elvis himself complained.  And the problem with THAT, when you come down
to
it, is that the man was capable of much, much more.  Certainly, he was
able
to act more effectively than we'd see in later properties like "Clambake"
and "Double Trouble."  The two films that followed this one, the great
"Flaming Star" and "Wild In The Country," ably proved that.  Then along
came
the box-office smash "Blue Hawaii," giving Elvis his biggest film receipts
since "GI Blues" and cementing to a great extent his Hollywood future.  As
if the loss of a potentially great and certainly charismatic acting talent
weren't enough, the focus on the bottom line led inexorably to weaker and
weaker soundtracks.  It didn't take long before Elvis was, with a few
exceptions, turning out substandard recordings that would eclipse in
volume
and sales the still-great studio work that he too seldom did during the
'60s.  As catchy as I find some of these movie songs, and despite the
redeeming qualities to be found in many, the sad fact is that most of what
he recorded for the movies was far, far below what he was capable of even
on
a bad day.  Take the movies, but leave the man his music.  That is the
real
tragedy of Elvis' movie career, I think, and the reason why we should
cringe
at the thought of "GI Blues," the movie that started it
all.But I can't do that.  I really can't hate such a good-natured film.  Even
this early in his '60s formula-movie days the music is watered-down to a
great extent but most of the songs are still of high quality and some are
exceedingly catchy or well done (e.g., the title song, the beautiful
"Doin'
The Best I Can," "Shoppin' Around," and even the sometimes-maligned
"Wooden
Heart").  The soundtrack sold like hotcakes -- over two years on the US
charts! -- and the movie did huge business.  Yes, indeed, Elvis was back!
It's not the movie's fault that it became a turning point and one with,
ultimately, dire consequences.  Elvis' performances is, as befits the
material, not as gritty or edgy as that of his previous role (in 1958's
classic "King Creole") and this is more a straight musical-comedy of the
kind that'd sustained Hollywood for decades.  There are a few twists,
though, such as the acceptance of one of Elvis' bandmates having fathered
a
child out of wedlock, and Elvis gets to show off his comic skills to great
advantage in several scenes, including those that center upon that baby,
'Tiger.'  Actually, it's the scenes with 'Tiger' that I always remembered
above all else from when I first saw this movie back in the '70s.  I like
some of the things that indicate a self-awareness in the movie:  Elvis'
line
at the movie's end, delivered to the camera, is most obvious, but the
whole
"Blue Suede Shoes" jukebox scenario's pretty funny and Elvis makes two
references to "All Shook Up" during the narrative.  Elvis does get to
flash
a couple of looks of anger and even arrogant confidence across his face a
couple of times -- he was utterly convincing, just with a look, at
portraying such emotions -- but for the most part he's a fairly
happy-go-lucky sort in this film.  He radiates charm throughout, echoing
the
sentiments of his "Love Me Tender" costar, Richard Egan:  "That boy can
charm the birds right out of the trees."  Elvis' male and female co-stars
all do a competent job throughout, and someone evidently thought enough of
Juliet Prowse's long-legged dancing routines to include two of them in the
film.The producers shot scenes while Elvis was still in Germany but used a
double
for his long-shots.  All of the German scenes that we see are either
projected behind the principals or are scenes shot on location with other
people, while Elvis was still over there finishing his tour of duty.  They
obviously put a lot of thought into storyboarding the film and getting
costumes and everything else sorted out so that location shots would match
soundstage scenes. This was not a quick and nasty 'quickie' film -- that
would come later, beginning with the filming of "Kissin' Cousins" in
1963."GI Blues":  it's a nice, entertaining movie, so it does its job.  No
heavy
themes or messages, just the kind of thing that lets you spend a little
time
in the land of escapist, lightweight, boy-meets-girl stories.  It has its
place.  It's just a pity that its place turned out to be right at the
pivot
point in the career of the most exceptional vocal and stage performer of
the
century.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
GI Blues was Elvis Presley's fifth picture and first one since his
return from the Army as America's most celebrated draftee of the
Fifties. It also marked his first film with director Norman Taurog who
did nine films with the King.Taurog like so many in Hollywood in front of and behind the camera was
getting less and less employment and taking what he could get. These
were the kind of people that Elvis's manager Colonel Tom Parker made
sure helped his meal ticket in any way possible. Norman Taurog won an
Oscar in 1931 for Skippy and was nominated for his direction of Boys
Town in 1938 which won Spencer Tracy an Oscar. Over the years Taurog
directed such musical performers as Bing Crosby, Dean Martin, Mario
Lanza, Eddie Fisher, and Debbie Reynolds. This man was most assuredly a
help to the King's career and I've no doubt Parker was behind getting
him. Parker is a controversial figure, especially among Elvis's legion of
fans as to whether he helped or hindered Elvis's career. He might have
done a little of both, but one thing the man was always sure of is that
in Presley's movies, he made sure that he got the best support in front
and behind the camera. Norman Taurog extended his own career via the
King. Everybody made out here.The Colonel also was a master at keeping the publicity going while
Elvis was a $78.00 a month GI serving in Germany. So much so there was
a tremendous about of advance publicity about this film which was about
a young rock and rolling soldier who finds love in Frankfurt.Elvis gets hooked into a Guys and Dolls type bet that he can't spend
the night in Juliet Prowse's apartment. Prowse is a local entertainer
at one of the clubs in Frankfurt and she's got a reputation as one cold
lady. But you know she ain't got a chance with the king.Part of the publicity surrounding this film was Juliet Prowse's
relationship with another guy she did a film with that year, Frank
Sinatra. She and Sinatra were quite the item and they announced their
engagement and then broke it off just as quickly. Juliet was quite the
dancer both in GI Blues and in Can-Can. I remember all of this quite
well as a lad. And it was always a special treat in Elvis films when he
got a female co-star who was also musical like Ann-Margret, Nancy
Sinatra, or Juliet Prowse.Elvis had a bunch of songs in the film including his own Blue Suede
Shoes playing on a jukebox during a bar brawl. One song I really liked
was Pocketful of Rainbows which he sings to Juliet while riding in a
cable car. It should have been a bigger hit for him.GI Blues was a fine jump start for Elvis's return to the big screen and
to his loyal legion of fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1378887/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>movibuf1962</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I loved this film. It's not typical Elvis in the sense that for once he
doesn't play the irreverent gigolo with a woman waiting for him in
every bar; his one big dream is to do music in his own nightclub. He's
quite likable and ends up even being noble when he turns the plot (of a
soldier engulfed in an bet with his army buddies to 'defrost' a
gorgeous nightclub dancer) on its side when he falls in love with the
stunning Juliet Prowse. This one is similar in tone to VIVA LAS VEGAS
because female lead Prowse is an independent woman, and not a typical
Elvis groupie. That's why I like it all the more. She is never, in my
opinion, actually 'refrigerated;' even when she turns down a pass from
Elvis she's not so much rude as she is firm in her convictions. But
what a dancer- with a pair of gams that stretch into next week!! Her
introduction in the film (which shows a spinning cardboard cutout in a
marquee window turn into the actual Prowse- in a strapless white,
shredded dress) is breathtaking!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0274721/comments</url><from/><name>Joe-290</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Elvis rocks the peace time army and breaks through the defences of a hard
hearted cabaret dancer in a fictionalised musical version of his own
military service. Tulsa (played by Presley), Rick and Cooky ,three army
buddies spend most of their off - duty time together. When they are not
playing music as a combo, they are frequently at  their favourite nightclub.
The main attraction is a red head dancer named Lili. Many have tried to melt
this beautiful icicle but have failed. Rick and Cooky bet that Tulsa will
succeed where all others have failed.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Back in Hollywood, after a two-year stint in the US army, Elvis Presley
(as Tulsa McLean) is a stationed-in-Germany singing soldier out to bed
sexy dancer Juliet Prowse (as Lili). This tailor-made film set the
standard for the successful "ELVIS" movie. Presley spent the 1960s
swinging and singing through "Top Ten" box office and record charts.
"G.I Blues" propelled Elvis back into Quigley Publications "Box Office"
ten most profitable movie stars, where he stayed through 1966. The RCA
soundtrack went platinum, and was #1 for ten of its amazing 111 weeks
on the LP chart. RCA planned no 45 RPM singles (which helped album
sales), but "Wooden Heart" and "G.I. Blues" became hits anyway.Unfortunately, the musical's trend-setting success overshadowed
Presley's superior studio recordings from the time (listen to "Elvis Is
Back!"). Also note, the re-recording of "Blue Suede Shoes" is a pale
imitation of the 1956 original. So, a creative cancer was being forged.
But, it's not fair to fault "G.I. Blues" for the sight and sound of
Elvis Presley singing "Old MacDonald Had a Farm" in "Double Trouble"
(1967). And, although everyone (including Presley) longed for him to be
a great dramatic actor, he shows up in "G.I. Blues" as a charming and
natural light performer. Herein, Presley introduces many of the playful
mannerisms used throughout the remainder of his career, in musicals and
on stage.****** G.I. Blues (8/18/60) Norman Taurog ~ Elvis Presley, Juliet
Prowse, Robert Ivers, James Douglas
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Elvis' first post army movie is about what?  A G.I. in West Germany wants
to
buy a nightclub in Oklahoma. Tulsa McLain (Elvis) takes on a wager that he
hopes will solve his money problems. He is to stay the night with ice cold,
leggy dancer, Lili(Juliet Prowes). Girl dances for boy; boy sings for girl.
But baby sitting becomes the problematic solution to the plot. A more grown
up look for Elvis and a great soundtrack that is more pop than rock.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
In Frankfurt, the G.I. Tulsa McLean (Elvis Presley) bets all the money
his friends Cookie (Robert Ivers) and Rick (James Douglas) and he are
saving to buy a night-club of their own in USA that his mate Dynamite
will seduce and spend a night with the untouchable cabaret dancer Lili
(Juliet Prowse). When Dynamite is transferred to Alaska, Tulsa has to
replace him in the bet, but he falls for Lili and tries to call off the
game."G.I. Blues" is a silly and naive story, being a pretext to see and
hear Elvis Presley only. But I believe every fan of this great singer
will appreciate his songs and his chemistry with the charming and sexy
Juliet Prowse. This movie certainly is not a masterpiece, but is very
enjoyable and a worthwhile entertainment. My vote is six.Title (Brazil): "Saudades de um Pracinha" ("Missing a G.I.")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2573153/comments</url><from>from Iceland</from><name>Bjorn (jbjorns)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Though this movie sealed Elvis's fate as to what kind of films he'd be
churning out by the dozen; it's hard not to like it.Elvis is thoroughly charming as Tulsa, an American GI stationed in
Germany. He takes part in a rather despicable bet as he claims he can
"defrost" a sultry dancer (Juliet Prowse). He succeeds in charming her
but, to his own surprise, also falls for her.Well, the story's simple - but it sets the stage for some truly
entertaining Presley songs and some knockout dancing by the charming
Juliet Prowse who also gives a good performance. The film is
energetically made and the usual Presley "possé" is fairly likable
here.There's no denying the fact that the "defrost" bet is very tasteless
but Elvis's character sidesteps it quite nicely. Here Elvis plays
basically the same character as in his subsequent films; a mischievous
lad, wholly independent, with a surprisingly strong moral sense and
prone to landing in at least one bar fight. But this is the first
light-hearted Presley flick and he looks like he's enjoying himself and
the songs really are top notch. "Tonight is so right for love" and
"Shopping Around" are among many highlights here and it's very funny to
see a guy in a bar pick "Blue Suede Shoes" on the jukebox by some
rocker named Elvis Presley (and that lands him in a fight with...well,
Elvis).Although "G.I. Blues" laid the groundwork for some inferior films to
come it's a very pleasant film and comes recommended to more than just
hardcore Presley fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
G.I. Blues (1960) ** 1/2 (out of 4) Better than average Elvis vehicle has him playing a G.I. who dreams of
one day owning his own nightclub. He makes a bet with some older
soldiers that he can take out a dancer (Juliet Prowse) but soon he
starts to have feelings for the woman and wants out of the bet. Elvis'
comeback film is a pretty good one even though there are still a few
weak moments. For the most part the film is charming enough to keep
itself going from start to finish even though the thing runs a tad bit
too long. Elvis must have been very comfortable in the role of a G.I.
because I've never seen him as relaxed in a role. He actually does a
pretty good job here and comes off very natural and gets to show off
some of his sense of humor. It goes without saying that this film
wanted to cash in on The King's military career and for the most part
they nail him in the role. The supporting players are equally
impressive and add a lot as well. Prowse is very sexy in her role and
manages a good performance. The film stealers for me were Robert Ivers
and Leticia Roman as the sidekicks. Ivers has a great comic timing and
makes for several funny sequences. The music numbers here are all
rather hit and miss with none of them what I'd call classic Elvis. I
thought the use of Presley's "Blue Suede Shoes" was a nice touch as was
the sequence with Elvis trying to babysit. The film is certainly
lightweight and predictable but it does have enough charm to make it
worth watching and I'm sure the girls in 1960 were passing out at the
site of Elvis in the shower.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
G.I. Blues (1960) ** 1/2 (out of 4) Better than average Elvis vehicle has him playing a G.I. who dreams of
one day owning his own nightclub. He makes a bet with some older
soldiers that he can take out a dancer (Juliet Prowse) but soon he
starts to have feelings for the woman and wants out of the bet. Elvis'
comeback film is a pretty good one even though there are still a few
weak moments. For the most part the film is charming enough to keep
itself going from start to finish even though the thing runs a tad bit
too long. Elvis must have been very comfortable in the role of a G.I.
because I've never seen him as relaxed in a role. He actually does a
pretty good job here and comes off very natural and gets to show off
some of his sense of humor. It goes without saying that this film
wanted to cash in on The King's military career and for the most part
they nail him in the role. The supporting players are equally
impressive and add a lot as well. Prowse is very sexy in her role and
manages a good performance. The film stealers for me were Robert Ivers
and Leticia Roman as the sidekicks. Ivers has a great comic timing and
makes for several funny sequences. The music numbers here are all
rather hit and miss with none of them what I'd call classic Elvis. I
thought the use of Presley's "Blue Suede Shoes" was a nice touch as was
the sequence with Elvis trying to babysit. The film is certainly
lightweight and predictable but it does have enough charm to make it
worth watching and I'm sure the girls in 1960 were passing out at the
site of Elvis in the shower.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/giblues.htm /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1843781</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>First film released after Elvis was discharged from his military duty.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-a-nesbit/</url><url>http://oldschoolreviews.com/rev_60/gi_blues.htm /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=761079</url><name>John A. Nesbit</name><from>Old School Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>'Elvis does an adequate job carrying the movie, playing his natural self in a project that was produced solely to capitalize on his return to civilian life.'</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1407741</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1394191</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dan-jardine/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=2211 /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=7770</url><name>Dan Jardine</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
68/100
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117791256.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1732549</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/70181/gi_blues.html /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1518050</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9D06EFDF1431EF3ABC4D53DFB767838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1389570</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/3881_G_I_BLUES.html /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1369556</url><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=103685 /m/gi_blues/comments.php?reviewid=1149367</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>