<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Cash McCall</original_title><alt_title>Cet homme est un requin</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Joseph Pevney</director><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Cash McCall is a young and slick business man who buys failing businesses and resells them. Grant Austen's Plastics is even more of a prize to Cash...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>James Garner</actor><actor>Natalie Wood</actor><actor>Nina Foch</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0220554/comments</url><from>from Lucas Buck, NC</from><name>Doctor_Bombay</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When Natalie Wood was in her prime, she was at the top of the biz,
stunningly beautiful, sharp, but accessible. And no one played the
all-american stud better than Jim Garner.Call it a bedroom farce if you like but Cash McCall combines a lot of
wheeling and dealing with a good old fashioned boy-meets-girl to make a very
pleasing movie.At first glance, McCall (Garner) is part playboy,  part ruthless
businessman, but we know better; that his heart of gold belongs only to Lory
Austen (Wood), a woman he met last Summer, and he's thought of nothing but
her since.Standard fare, well done with attractive stars, that alone puts it in the
upper 20% as far as I'm concerned. Enjoy it. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10348034/comments</url><from>from Claremont, USA</from><name>dougdoepke</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The best part of this Technicolor exercise is the light it shines on
high-power business dealings and how these were treated in the
Production Code 1950's-- and is worth a quick few words.In that Cold War decade, Hollywood discovered the drama of corporation
boardrooms and big business in such films as the ruthless Patterns
(1956), the intrigues of Executive Suite (1954), and the comedic Solid
Gold Cadillac (1956). All in all, these movies hold up well despite the
passage of years. The trick for films of this type was to be realistic
enough with the big money scheming to hold audience interest without at
the same time indicting the upper tiers of capitalism. For to do the
latter would, among other reasons, serve the interests of the Soviet
side of the Cold War then at its peak. As a result, in such movies
conscience or a force for good usually prevails at the last minute over
ruthless business connivings no matter how unconvincing the abrupt
triumph. And that's very much the case in the otherwise routine Cash
McCall.At first, McCall is characterized as a corporate vulture—a
wheeler-dealer who buys up struggling companies, disassembles them for
profit, and then walks away from whatever communities he may have
destroyed in the process. But, of course, it's hard to make a
sympathetic lead out of such a ruthless character, even for such a
likable personality as James Garner. So the screenplay begins to fudge.
He's next characterized as a dis-assembler whose aim is to build up
anew from the pieces, though the human consequences are not made clear.
And finally, after a thorough conversion, he becomes a full-fledged
business humanitarian putting communities first for reasons that also
remain rather unclear, but does, of course, produce a happy ending.
Thus, the ends of the Production Code, the Cold War, and audience
expectations are duly served.The movie itself is pretty unmemorable. To me the pairing of the mature
Garner and the rather callow Wood seems a brittle one, no matter how
much the winsome Wood is glamorized. Then too, Garner suppresses his
charming Maverick side in the interests of getting into McCall's
character, but in the process gives up his special appeal as an actor.
On the other hand, it's a fine array of supporting players, especially
Henry Jones whose Bassett- hound face registers an unusual array of
subtle emotions. His is a very different appearance for that
glamour-obsessed time period. Anyway, the movie's a decent enough
entertainment, but outside of its wheeler-dealer instruction manual,
remains pretty forgettable.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
James Garner makes a dashing young entrepreneur of the business world
in Cash McCall, the second of two films made from Cameron Hawley's
business world novels, the other being the acclaimed Executive Suite.
Hawley certainly knew how to capture the business world well and put a
proper face on it.Usually it's not a real good idea to mix business with pleasure, but in
Cash McCall, Garner succeeds quite well. I now know where some of the
plot of Grease came from. If you'll remember John Travolta and Olivia
Newton-John have a summer fling which ends, but then find themselves in
the same school in different social circles.Cash McCall begins with Garner already having had that fling with
Natalie Wood on vacation in Maine and he discovers she's the daughter
of Dean Jagger, president of a plastics firm he's looking to acquire.
When he discovers who she is it does complicate matters, but Garner is
a most resourceful man. In the end it all works out to everyone's
satisfaction, but there are a few bumps in the road. Those bumps are
what the film is all about.James Garner has played so many con men on the big and small screen it
would have been an easy matter for him to slip into that familiar
characterization for him. But he plays this one absolutely straight and
does quite well with the part. Of course if he had been anything less
than up front he wouldn't have gotten Wood. Natalie was just radiant in
her role as the Philadelphia Main Line princess, a bit more human than
Tracy Samantha Lord of The Philadelphia Story.Besides Dean Jagger, the leads are backed by an established group of
players portraying various business types as Edward Platt, E.G.
Marshall, Otto Kruger, Parley Baer, and Roland Winters. Two
performances that are really outstanding are Nina Foch as the hotel
chief housekeeper at the place where Garner resides occupying an entire
floor and part of another and Henry Jones as an efficiency expert who
Garner recruits. I'm surprised that Cash McCall was not taken up as material for a prime
time soap opera in the Eighties, the decade of such. It certainly has
all the ingredients.Still it remains as one of James Garner's best early film performances
and usually on the top 10 list for his fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0456082/comments</url><from>from Maryland, USA</from><name>Cammy-3</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

One of my favorite movies as a child. Look at her face in the close-ups,
when the movie flashes back to their meeting in the rain at his mountain
cabin! Such a romantic movie, and Ms. Woods' clothes are fabulous examples
of
50s high fashion.
And Cash Mc Call's penthouse is a perfect high-tech palace for the
times.Natalie has the doting parents we all wished we had back then and a mother
who is worried this beautiful creature will be an old maid at 23. Ah, life
was simple then.The business oriented plot is engaging, the dialogue springy and
believable
for the times. Though marraige and family are still the only acceptable
goals for good girls in this story,  you don't care as you root for true
love to conquor all and the cold business man to see the light and let the
good guys win.Rent it, if you have never seen it. An underappreciated
gem.
I wish I had told Ms. Wood how much I liked the film, the one time I met
her
in the late sixties, but she was rather pregnant
at the time and not terribly concerned with her career.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0103793/comments</url><from>from Canterbury, England</from><name>Stefan Kahrs</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

In many respects this looks like a 1980s film that has been moved through a
hole in the time/space continuum into 1959.  From a cynical 1990s
perspective, much of it is probably a touch too sweet, especially the
romance, but the way high-flying business is portrayed was way ahead of its
time. It is very much as we would find it in mid-1980s films such as Wall
Street or Other People's Money.  In case some of the dialogue/monologue
sounds familiar: Pretty Woman seems to have "borrowed" significant
chunks.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0968789/comments</url><from>from New York City</from><name>mark.waltz</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Cash McCall is a business tycoon who has been taking over various
corporations through buy-outs without regards for the people he works
for him goes after a plastics company owned by Dean Jagger so he can
resume a relationship with Jagger's daughter, Natalie Wood. It appears
that the year before, they had a brief romance which somehow soured,
and now he wants to marry her. James Garner plays the title character,
and Natalie Wood is the girl. Wood looks a bit older here than she does
in several films she did shortly after (particularly "Splendor in the
Grass", "West Side Story", and especially "Gypsy"). Her hair style is
probably the main reason, and the character appears to be a bit older
too, even though she still lives with her folks. While Garner and Wood
are undoubtedly gorgeous together, they don't share the same spark that
Rock Hudson and Doris Day did in the previous year's big romantic
comedy hit "Pillow Talk", or even the two films that Garner later did
with Ms. Day. Wood, who as "Queen of Warner Brothers" after Ms. Day
departed, probably thought it looked good on paper, and while it has
some amusements, it actually looks better than it actually plays. The
lead characters, even Garner's rather ruthless businessman, are
likable, and Garner indulges McCall with a sense of standards of decent
business practices that other hot young actors of the time might have.This is an unfortunate film choice for poor Nina Foch, who must suffer
all sorts of indignities as an embittered divorcée who develops a crush
on McCall and is humiliated by him after she ruthlessly tries to break
him and Wood up. It's sad to see this pathetic creature pine after a
man who obviously doesn't love her. The scene where she begins to think
he is just isn't convincing enough to make us believe that she would
think he was talking about her in the first place, when it was very
clear he was talking about someone else. She also has the misfortune to
wear probably the ugliest hat in film history, one that's actually
feathered but looks like a fruit bowl turned upside down.There have been much better films on big business, including one by the
same author ("Executive Suite"). It features a wonderful supporting
cast, most notably Henry Jones (who will never be confused here with
his role of LeRoy in "The Bad Seed") and Eli Wallach. It's colorful and
beautifully designed, but ultimately superficial and weak.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
James Garner has always had a knack for making every character he's
played his own. From his early T.V. days as western star Brent Maverick
to the last series, The Rockford files. His ease to become the center
attraction is a natural pose for such a talented individual. In this
story directed by Joseph Pevney, he plays Millionaire tycoon, Cash
McCall who's amiable gift for buying and quickly selling industrial
real estate is surprisingly lucrative. That is until he meets with
eye-candy Natalie Wood who plays Lory Austen, the beautiful daughter of
Grant Austin (Dean Jagger) a retiring designer. With a top successful
group of businessmen led by Winston Conway (E.G. Marshall), Gilmore
Clark (Henry Jones) and Harrison Glenn (Edward Platt), he plans to reap
a rich bonus with the biggest deal of his life. However, small
incidents like his personal housekeeper Maude Kennard (Nina Foch)
wrongly believing McCall is seeking her as a wife and his number one
business competitor, General Danvers (Roland Winters) believes McCall
is trying to cheat him, are becoming more than annoying. All in all,
this Garner vehicle is fun in a number of ways, but all end up creating
the correct imagines originally written by author Cameron Hawley. ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2366174/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>XweAponX</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
When you first hear of this flick, you think it is like most of
Garner's "Light Comedy" from the 60's - Not so. This film shows the a
steamy underside of the Big Business "Scene" and the kind of trickery
that goes on... And how even an honest down to earth deal could be made
to look like a swindle, with a little jealousy and backstabbing added
when least expected- And for that you have to give proper credit to
Nina Koch for playing a kind of reverse "Erica Martin" from Executive
Suite.Garner is surrounded with some of the great character actors of the
time: Dean Jagger, E. G. Marshall (From "12 Angry Men"), Otto Kruger
(From Hitchcock's "Saboteur" and "Magnificent Obsession"), Edward Platt
("Chief" from "Get Smart").And of course Natalie Wood, and in this film she gives one of her
best... She is an absolute firecracker. I like the fact that the
interaction between Garner and Wood is a little subdued.One thing that is amazing, is that this was directed by Joe Pevney, who
directed some of the best episodes of Star Trek Original Series.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Stock market tycoon James Garner (as Cash McCall) pursues pretty
children's book illustrator Natalie Wood (as Lory). Previously, they
had something of a summer romance, when Ms. Wood's character fell
hopelessly and head over heels for Mr. Garner (as you will surely
notice in the character's demeanor). Older divorcée Nina Foch (as Maude
Kennard) is also hot for the "Maverick" TV star. Complicating matters,
Wood is the daughter of businessman Dean Jagger (as Grant Austen), who
owns the "Austen Plastics" company Garner hopes to acquire. The cast,
color, and sets are attractive - but, the story is amazingly obvious,
and dully performed by the co-starring couple. Listen up for Garner to tell the General he's "up the well-known
creek…without a paddle." **** Cash McCall (1/20/60) Joseph Pevney ~ James Garner, Natalie Wood,
Nina Foch, Dean Jagger
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0231348/comments</url><from>from Louisville, Colorado</from><name>William Kucharski</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a great, fun film with the feel of similar films of the era
such as 1962's "That Touch of Mink," whose plot bears more than a
passing resemblance to this film's.James Garner is great as usual, as is the radiant Natalie Wood. Dean
Jagger's performance as the plastic company patriarch strikes just the
right note and Henry Jones does his usual excellent job as the somewhat
smarmy assistant.But one of the real stars of the film is its 1960 decor. It really sets
the period but also has a very distinctive look that is now considered
retro-"atomic chic" with more than a little "Googie" thrown in.I've no idea why this film hasn't been released on DVD (it's perfect
for anamorphic DVD at a 1.85:1 aspect ratio). If you don't want to rent
or purchase the VHS tape, your only recourse is to await its very
infrequent showings on cable (most recently on Encore's "Love" channel
some six or so years ago.)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0231348/comments</url><from>from Louisville, Colorado</from><name>William Kucharski</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a great, fun film with the feel of similar films of the era
such as 1962's "That Touch of Mink," whose plot bears more than a
passing resemblance to this film's.James Garner is great as usual, as is the radiant Natalie Wood. Dean
Jagger's performance as the plastic company patriarch strikes just the
right note and Henry Jones does his usual excellent job as the somewhat
smarmy assistant.But one of the real stars of the film is its 1960 decor. It really sets
the period but also has a very distinctive look that is now considered
retro-"atomic chic" with more than a little "Googie" thrown in.I've no idea why this film hasn't been released on DVD (it's perfect
for anamorphic DVD at a 1.85:1 aspect ratio). If you don't want to rent
or purchase the VHS tape, your only recourse is to await its very
infrequent showings on cable (most recently on Encore's "Love" channel
some six or so years ago.)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0231348/comments</url><from>from Louisville, Colorado</from><name>William Kucharski</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/cashmccall.htm /m/cash_mccall/comments.php?reviewid=1956690</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>Glossy soap opera about rocky dealings in romance and business.</comment></review></movie>