<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Criminal</original_title><alt_title>Les criminels</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Joseph Losey</director><producer>Merton Park Studios</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
An ex-con who's taken part in the robbery of a racetrack is caught and sent back to prison, but he won't tell his fellow gang members where he's stashed the loot...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Stanley Baker</actor><actor>Sam Wanamaker</actor><actor>Grégoire Aslan</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The Criminal (aka The Concrete Jungle) is, for my money at least, one
of Joseph Losey's two best films (the other being King and Country),
but it never really garnered the kind of success or reputation it
deserved, possibly because it had the misfortune to open on the same
day as Saturday Night and Sunday Morning, which completely overshadowed
it. Billed as 'the most violent film ever made in Britain,' even 45
years on it's still vicious stuff. Indeed, in the entire cast of
characters that populate Alun Owen's excellent and unsentimental
screenplay - irredeemable crooks, vicious prison warders, prison
governors who don't really want to know, amoral molls and assorted
perverts and thugs - the only two people in the entire film who aren't
totally corrupt are Laurence Naismith's arresting officer (who is still
not above letting on about his informants) and the piano tuner who
appears in one brief scene. The plot is a simple enough variation on
Touchez Pas au Grisbi, with Stanley Baker's con pulling off a big job
and immediately being ratted out by one of his partners who wants a
bigger share, but the stark execution and background is what carries
it. Certainly its vision of the British prison system as a Hellish
melting pot of refuse of all persuasions - Irish, Australian, Italians,
West Indians, the mentally disturbed - where the guards don't only turn
a blind eye to vicious beatings but even facilitate them is a kick in
the groin to the more sedate cop movies of the day.It's also full of memorable little moments, from the prison weasel
spreading the news of an informant's return in-between lines of Knick
Knack Paddywhack to Kenneth J. Warren's inability to say anything
without incorporating the word 'loike.' Robert Krasker's black and
white cinematography has more bite to it than most of its
contemporaries, from the hard stark edges of the prison scenes to the
bleak half-snowscape of the haunting final shots, while Johnny
Dankworth's score makes great use of Cleo Laine's mournful prison
balled ("All my loving, all my joy/Came from loving a thieving boy"]).
The supporting cast is impressive, offering a virtual who's who of
perfectly cast 60s British character actors, including many faces that
would later memorably turn up among the ranks in Baker's Zulu). Unlike
the wave of British gangster flicks to litter the straight-to-video
shelves post-Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels, this feels like the
real thing rather than a bunch of nicely brought up middle class kids
playing dress-up. For some curious reason Anchor Bay's otherwise
excellent transfer omits the end credits, played over a melancholy shot
of prisoners walking in circles in a stark and wintery exercise yard.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0208117/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>aromatic-2 (aromatic@ivillage.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Joseph Losey does a superb job of directing cinema-verite'-style from start
to finish.  From the moment Cleo Laine sings Thieving Boy over the opening
credits, I knew I was in for a special experience.  Stanley Baker spent a
career delivering some of the most haunting criminal characterizations of
all time, and this is one of his all-time best.  Patrick Magee is memorable
in a minor supporting role. An incredible gritty film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Joseph Losey's C.V. was nothing if not eclectic.Once considered by some
critics as a major force in British Cinema,he can,with hindsight ,be
seen to have been following trends rather than creating them for most
of his career.Nonetheless,his films were,as a rule,recognisably the
work of a considerable artist,albeit one working within the limits
imposed by the studios,and within clearly defined genres. He was
involved in film-making for 45 years,right up to his death in 1984.
Blacklisted by the H.U.A.C.,Mr Losey brought a welcome dash of verve
and inmagination to a fairly moribund British Film Industry. He could
take a straightforward prison movie like "The Criminal" - destined to
be a pot-boiler in the hands of many an English hack director - and
turn it into a rather remarkable work. The British cannot do crime
films.I know we think we can,and we certainly make enough of them,but
the results give lie to the proverb that practise makes perfect.It's
not enough to fill the screen with snarling professional Cockneys with
tattooed fingers like bunches of sausages spouting rhyming - slang
never heard outside of a script writer's study in Islington.Watch
Britpop gangster films like"Lock,stock etc" or "Essex Boys" and you can
scarcely hear the dialogue for laughter and the more ludicrously
violent the film gets the more the audience laughs."The Criminal" is
not noticeably risible. There is violence,but it is not comic book
violence,it is the sort of violence that leaves it's victims scarred
physically and mentally. There is real menace.Mr Stanley Baker and Mr
Sam Wanamaker are hard men. Compared to them Mr Sean Bean is a
pussycat,Mr Vinnie Jones a dilettante. It is not so much a film noir as
a film gris,the exteriors shot in bright light,softening the contrast
whilst retaining pin-sharp focusing.These shadings of grey reflect the
moral ambivalence of the main characters.Only the truly unpleasant P.O.
Barrow,played with hissing relish by Mr Patrick Magee,is shot in high
contrast. Mr Stanley Baker is very convincing as a major
criminal,hardly surprising when you consider he had been known to move
in the same social circles as some of London's biggest villains.He
makes no unnecessary gestures,remains aloof from his fellow
prisoners,truly a man apart.You just know he won't be taking up those
courses in basket weaving. The plot - such as it is - revolves around a
"Thieves fall out" scenario familiar to moviegoers since the first
train robber galloped across the flickering screen.It's familiarity
doesn't matter,its what Mr Losey does with it that counts,after
all,"Romeo and Juliet" wasn't exactly state of the art cutting edge
audience challenging stuff when Shakespeare first got hold of it.
Released at a time when British films were just about to enjoy a short
- lived renaissance,"The Criminal" ended up being trampled under the
feet of critics lavishing excessive praise on a succession of flat cap
and whippet sagas that eventually disappeared up their own outdoor
privy. Viewed at a distance of 45 years,Mr Wanamaker crossing the
street in his camelhair coat is an image that will remain long after
the last crumpled Woodbine is ground out in an overflowing ashtray in a
smoke - filled changing room before the poor exploited hero runs out -
coughing to play football/rugby league/pigeon racing in front of an
audience of seven men and a dog - probably a whippet.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur21143436/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>susannah-straughan-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Stanley Baker's dodgy Irish accent strikes the only false note in
Joseph Losey's hard-nosed crime drama. A lethal combination of charm,
guile and brute force makes jailbird Johnny Bannion the top dog in B
block. Once he's released, Bannion is plunged straight back into a
world of free-flowing booze, casual sex and cool jazz in his
well-appointed bachelor pad. But there's no thought of going straight
as he plots a lucrative racetrack heist with the reptilian Carter (Sam
Wanamaker). The intrigue here lies not in the heist itself but in the
web of betrayals that follow, as Losey and screenwriter Alun Owen build
an authentic portrait of the criminal underworld on both sides of the
prison wall. There's no hint here of the cartoonish Swinging London and
stereotypical cockney villains that continue to plague British cinema.
Robert Krasker's photography lends a stark beauty to the pollarded
trees in the prison courtyard and Johnny Dankworth's score, punctuated
by a mournful Cleo Laine ballad, is superb. With its harsh, sweaty
depiction of prison violence, this is a million miles from the
upper-class shenanigans depicted in the director's later films like The
Servant and The Go-Between.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0396182/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>BOUF</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Stanley Baker is convincing as a brutal villain, but it looked to me
that he could easily have been nobbled by several of his prison
inmates. There's a lot of talk that attempts to sew the plot together,
but not a lot of action - and I don't mean fights and car chases, I
mean the difference between taking the audience on a cinematic journey
as opposed to being told what's happening by the dialogue. There's too
much telling and not enough showing. Several of the set-pieces in this
essentially crime/gangster genre story are clumsily handled. The
robbery is poorly covered: we don't know what the plan is, or what the
perpetrators are up against, plus several opportunities for high
tension are muffed. In the prison, the conflicts are fairly well
developed and realised, but often they're stagey or overwrought.
Gregoire Aslan is an excellent 'capo' and there is some good character
work by the supporting cast, but there is also some woeful acting. The
general statement of this film is that this is a grim, bleak, violent
society in which ordinary man is always imprisoned - that part works,
but as a drama or a thriller it's clunky and uneven. An under-developed
script, some patchy, but energetic direction, and a generally excellent
job of anamorphic lensing by Aussie Robert Krasker.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
When I was in Hollywood late last year, I managed to watch Losey's
classic sci-fi THESE ARE THE DAMNED (1963) - surely Hammer Films'
strangest release; at the time, while I had been sufficiently impressed
with the film (despite the poor quality of the print I came across but,
at least, it was the full-length version!), I had also found the
experience somewhat overwhelming.I couldn't quite explain why I felt this way but, having now watched
this contemporaneous title (which, in comparison to the fanciful
apocalyptic narrative of THESE ARE THE DAMNED, is a relatively
straightforward crime drama of the prison/caper variety), I realized
that it was due to the essential stylization of Losey's mise-en-scene
which, apart from giving a heightened sense of reality to the already
intense proceedings, also rendered the film guilty of a certain
pretentiousness (marking virtually every scene) not found in similar
genre efforts, certainly British-made - demonstrating a definite change
of attitude in cinema towards a greater sense of artistry but also more
lenient censorship (the sex and violence in this particular film, while
not especially graphic by the standards of even a few years later, are
clearly more pronounced than in the previous decade)! Still, to be
honest, all of this actually serves to make the film doubly arresting -
particularly during this gritty phase of Losey's career (his statelier
later work grew increasingly more opaque).What a cast! Stanley Baker was never better than as the almost
legendary con whose individuality makes him an outcast even among his
own kind, and he's surrounded by some very fine actors - most notably
Sam Wanamaker (as his contact on the outside but who harbors ambitions
of taking over the gang), Patrick Magee (his first impressive role as a
corrupt and menacing prison warden), Gregoire Aslan (as the ageing
mobster who rules the underworld even from inside the penitentiary and
to whom everyone - Baker included - must acquiesce) and Nigel Green (as
Baker's double-crossing associate). Surprisingly, the supporting cast
is peppered with faces familiar from several horror films like Rupert
Davies (WITCHFINDER GENERAL [1968]), Edward Judd (THE DAY THE EARTH
CAUGHT FIRE [1961]), Murray Melvin (THE DEVILS [1971]), John Van Eyssen
(HORROR OF Dracula [1958]), Noel Willman (THE KISS OF THE VAMPIRE
[1963]), Kenneth J. Warren (THE CREEPING FLESH [1973]) and Patrick
Wymark (THE BLOOD ON SATAN'S CLAW [1971]).Speaking of which, Hammer Films stalwart Jimmy Sangster reportedly
contributed to the excellent screenplay (actually credited to A HARD
DAY'S NIGHT [1964] scribe Alun Owen!). The film's remarkable and
claustrophobic black-and-white cinematography is by the great Robert
Krasker (Oscar winner for THE THIRD MAN [1949]). Another big plus is
Johnny Dankworth's jazzy score, featuring a recurring ballad sung by
Cleo Laine.While essentially character-driven, the film's seedy milieu and
sadistic streak allows for a number of vivid sequences (though the
race-track robbery itself is rather thrown away!) including the wild
party held at Baker's flat on being released from prison (highlighting
sexy Margit Saad who subsequently replaces Jill Bennett as Baker's
moll), the equally chaotic prison riot, Baker's escape from the
penitentiary (having been betrayed after the robbery and recaptured)
and the inevitable showdown with the ruthless Wanamaker.Unfortunately, apart from the theatrical trailer and admittedly
extensive talent bios for both Losey and Baker, the Anchor Bay DVD is a
bare-bones affair; pity neither of them is around anymore (Baker died
far too young in 1976 at age 49 and Losey, already in his 50s when the
film was made, followed him in 1984) to have been involved in this
otherwise sparkling edition! Having watched THE CRIMINAL and, more recently, Losey's SECRET CEREMONY
(1968), I've rekindled my interest in this important director's work: I
have four of his films as yet unwatched on VHS - THE BIG NIGHT (1951),
THE ROMANTIC ENGLISHWOMAN (1975), DON GIOVANNI (1979) and LA TRUITE
(1982) - and still need to pick up several of them on DVD - EVE (1962;
unwatched...if I can find a copy of the Kino disc which includes two
different cuts of the film, neither of them the complete 155-minute
version!), THE SERVANT (1963), KING AND COUNTRY (1964; unwatched),
MODESTY BLAISE (1966), ACCIDENT (1967), the upcoming THE ASSASSINATION
OF TROTSKY (1972; unwatched) and GALILEO (1975; unwatched).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7888387/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>allenrogerj</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
A strange film.On the one hand it is a realistically drawn Melvillean study of
criminals who fall out and destroy one another; on the other it is a
non-naturalistic Behanesque portrayal of prison life, its hierarchies
and the relationships among and between warders and prisoners. At a
guess, the crime story dominated in the original script and Alun Owen
emphasised the prison scenes and introduced the element of ensemble
work in the later version. The problem with this mixture of films,
either of which could be good on its own, is that they don't fit
together- that's leaving aside the film's Dickensian relish for
characters, regardless of their relevance to the story. Thus the comic
Northerner who wants to hire the gang's getaway taxi after the robbery,
the piano-tuner in Bannion's flat (what does Bannion want a piano for
anyway?- it's isn't consistent with his character.) when they are
talking plans for the robbery, many of the prisoners- effectively
portrayed as helplessly institutionalised, Magee's talismanic and
enigmatic head warder, the prison doctor, the cynical prison governor-
all distract from the film's plot, but aren't given enough time for
their own story, which might be more interesting- the mixture of
antagonism and co-operation between prison staff and prisoners- "Come
on" says a screw, "I always treat you straight; you do the same for
me." an effective tactic- is well-portrayed and rouses our interest
without satisfying it. Equally, important parts of the crime story are
thrown away- we never see the robbery and Bannion goes back to prison
remarkably quickly- six weeks, we are told- we never even learn how
long he will spend back in prison. The women- the abandoned moll played
by Jill Bennett and her replacement- aren't convincing at all, mere
plot-devices; on the other hand, the suggestion that some of the
characters are homosexual is well-placed and carefully shown in
passing. There are strengths too- effective and sometimes beautiful
camera-work, especially in the prison scenes, all of the actors are
good in their parts, a very fine score by John Dankworth. It's
certainly a film worth seeing, but we can't help regretting what it
could be but isn't- but then, that's true of so many British films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The blacklisted Joseph Losey whose loss to the American cinema was the
United Kingdom's gain took his knowledge of American prison films to
fashion this gem. Starring in Concrete Jungle is the premier British
tough guy Stanley Baker in a role that in America, Humphrey Bogart
might have been given first crack at.Whoever said there was no honor among thieves must have run with
Baker's mob. When we meet him, he's a day away from his release from
one jail sentence, but not until some prison justice is meted out to a
newly arriving Patrick Magee with whom Baker has a grudge over a
previous job. No sooner is Baker out than he's back in a nice caper concerning the
robbery of a racetrack. But thieves being what they are somebody rats
and Baker's back in stir. But not before he's buried the loot and
doesn't tell anyone, the same thing he was mad at Magee for.It's a scurvy lot Baker has for friends, I haven't seen this many bad
people hold a viewer's interest without there being any redeeming good
people in a film since I first saw Goodfellas. But like Goodfellas
there is something fascinating about Baker and the whole crew, people
like Sam Wanamaker, Gregoire Aslan, etc. Even the cops like Laurence
Naismith aren't especially heroic. Naismith admits as much, he's just
got a well developed system of stool pigeons which any cop worth his
badge has.Baker really dominates the film, the United Kingdom hasn't produced an
actor like him since. Concrete Jungle is a classic example of his tough
guy appeal and a great introduction to him.And you'll love Cleo Laine's singing of A Thieving Boy at the beginning
and end of the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0807997/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>gwilym49</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

A haunting and unique depiction of prison and criminal life in Britain in
the early 1960s. 40 years after its release I still wish to see this film.
Before the Great Train Robbery and the prison riots of more recent times
the
violence and tension portrayed in the work seem to strike a very deep chord
which anticipates these later events. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8239592/comments</url><from>from The Last New Jersey Drive-In on the Left</from><name>Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Shrewd, fearsome underworld kingpin Johnny Bannion (a superbly steely
and convincing performance by Stanley Baker) gets sprung from the joint
so he can mastermind a bold racetrack heist for his slick, shifty
hoodlum buddy Mike Carter (a splendidly smarmy Sam Wanamaker). Johnny
winds up being incarcerated again after hiding the stolen loot. Can he
survive long enough in jail to get back out and retrieve the money?
Director Joseph Losey, working from a sharp, precise script written by
Alun Owen and Jimmy Sangster, offers a fascinatingly vivid and
flavorsome depiction of the seedy criminal milieu, relates the
arresting story at a steady pace, and maintains a fierce, unrelenting
intensity that never lets up to the literal bitter end. This film
further benefits from top-notch acting by a stellar cast, with
especially stand-out turns from Baker, Wanamaker, Gregoire Aslan as
cunning Italian mop capo Frank Saffron, Margit Saad as Johnny's brash,
enticing new girlfriend Suzanne, Jill Bennett as neurotic spurned moll
Maggie, Patrick Magee as rugged, no-nonsense prison guard captain
Barrows, Laurence Naismith as meddlesome detective Mr. Town, and
Kenneth J. Warren as the brutish Clobber. Robert Krasker's crisp, fluid
black and white cinematography, the colorful characters, John
Dankworth's rousing jazzy score, the uncompromisingly grim'n'gritty
tone, the haunting bluesy theme song that's gorgeously sung by Cleo
Laine, a potent central message about how greed and money lust destroy
the human soul, and the powerful downbeat ending add immensely to the
considerable jolting impact of this bang-up little winner.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8239592/comments</url><from>from The Last New Jersey Drive-In on the Left</from><name>Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Shrewd, fearsome underworld kingpin Johnny Bannion (a superbly steely
and convincing performance by Stanley Baker) gets sprung from the joint
so he can mastermind a bold racetrack heist for his slick, shifty
hoodlum buddy Mike Carter (a splendidly smarmy Sam Wanamaker). Johnny
winds up being incarcerated again after hiding the stolen loot. Can he
survive long enough in jail to get back out and retrieve the money?
Director Joseph Losey, working from a sharp, precise script written by
Alun Owen and Jimmy Sangster, offers a fascinatingly vivid and
flavorsome depiction of the seedy criminal milieu, relates the
arresting story at a steady pace, and maintains a fierce, unrelenting
intensity that never lets up to the literal bitter end. This film
further benefits from top-notch acting by a stellar cast, with
especially stand-out turns from Baker, Wanamaker, Gregoire Aslan as
cunning Italian mop capo Frank Saffron, Margit Saad as Johnny's brash,
enticing new girlfriend Suzanne, Jill Bennett as neurotic spurned moll
Maggie, Patrick Magee as rugged, no-nonsense prison guard captain
Barrows, Laurence Naismith as meddlesome detective Mr. Town, and
Kenneth J. Warren as the brutish Clobber. Robert Krasker's crisp, fluid
black and white cinematography, the colorful characters, John
Dankworth's rousing jazzy score, the uncompromisingly grim'n'gritty
tone, the haunting bluesy theme song that's gorgeously sung by Cleo
Laine, a potent central message about how greed and money lust destroy
the human soul, and the powerful downbeat ending add immensely to the
considerable jolting impact of this bang-up little winner.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/c/Criminal.html /m/1117776-criminal/comments.php?reviewid=1848462</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Losey is an incomparable engineer of frenzy</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/criminal1960.htm /m/1117776-criminal/comments.php?reviewid=851015</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Losey does an excellent job of depicting the brutality of both prison life and the British underworld.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1117776-criminal/comments.php?reviewid=1417932</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/69843/the_criminal.html /m/1117776-criminal/comments.php?reviewid=1517917</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102411 /m/1117776-criminal/comments.php?reviewid=1149278</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>