<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Exodus</original_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Otto Preminger</director><producer>Otto Preminger Films</producer><producer>Carlyle Productions</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
The theme is the founding of the state of Israel. The action begins on a ship filled with Jewish immigrants bound for Israel who are being off loaded on Cyprus...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Paul Newman</actor><actor>Eva Marie Saint</actor><actor>Ralph Richardson</actor><rt_rating>6/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>67</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1098460/comments</url><from>from Virginia, USA</from><name>Galina</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Adapted from one of the best books of the last century, Otto
Premenger's "Exodus" (1960) had all the components of an exiting,
deeply moving masterpiece. It was made by a very talented and
celebrated director ("Laura" , "Anatomy of a Murder"); most scenes of
the film were made in locations where the original events had occurred;
one of the best ever American actors(Paul Newman) played the main
character, Jewish hero, a fearless Freedom fighter, Ari Ben Canaan; Sal
Meneo gave an absolutely compelling performance as Dov Landau, a young
man, a boy really who had survived the horrors of Auschwitz, the only
survivor of a big family from Warsaw. Ernst Gold won an Academy award
for his truly magnificent musical score. Sadly, "Exodus" is not a
masterpiece – it is an overlong, heavy handed, and rather unimpressive
movie that caused satirist Mort Sahl to say, "Otto, let my people go"
as he watched the film's 220-minute preview. Ironically, with all this
running time, the best, the most inspirational parts of the book did
not make it to the film. Among them are historical events dealing with
the origins of ghetto system, pogroms in Russia, the long and
fascinating journey of two brothers from a small Russian town to
Palestine by foot, the ideas of Theodor Herzl, the birth of kibbutzes
in Palestine, and enormous labor of kibbutznicks to make the land
fertile, to grow plants and trees where the desert, rocks, and swamps
had been, as well as the tragedy of European Holocaust and dramatic
story of United Nations voting for partition of Palestine in 1947 and
the war of the infant state against its multiple and hostile neighbors
for the right to exist and be an independent country. I watched the
movie just before I left for my trip to Israel a few weeks ago and I
took the book with me there. Reading the book while be able to see the
places it describes with such passion and love, to see the land that is
called "promised land" or "Holy land" WAS one of the most emotional and
unforgettable experiences in my life, watching the movie was not. It is
just an illustration to the fantastic book – no more, no less. IMO, the
book deserves the same treatment that Puso's "Godfather" had received –
it should've been adapted into several movies, not just one. Like in
Godfather, Part II, the scenes of the past and present should've
alternated, given the viewers deeper insight in the events and the
passions and politics behind them. Or even better, perhaps "Exodus"
should've been adapted into TV mini-series format where every important
character would've had enough time for his/her story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1592694/comments</url><from>from Biloxi, Mississippi</from><name>gftbiloxi (gftbiloxi@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Early in the film, while discussing the squabbling between Jews and
Arabs over Palestine, an exasperated Eva Marie Saint sighs and asks
"How is it all going to end?" How indeed! It is a question the world
has asked for more than half a century, and to date there is no answer
in sight.Concerning the creation of the Jewish state of Israel, the 1958 Leon
Uris novel EXODUS was among the great bestsellers of its era and
remains widely read to this day. The 1960 film version was also widely
admired at the time of its release--but it is seldom seen today. There
is a reason for that. In spite of its reputation, the film is
remarkably slapdash. The cinematography is poor, lacking arresting
visuals and often so sloppy that the shadows of the boom mikes are
visible here, there, and everywhere throughout the film. The sound mix
is also quite poor, with post-production effects as much off the mark
as they are on. But the great flaws here are the script and the cast.Written for the screen by Dalton Trumbo, the script has a very
artificial and very talky quality. This might be overlooked if Trumbo
actually had anything to say in the process--but he does not, and a
remarkably gifted cast struggles vainly against one artificial line
after another. Paul Newman is horrifically miscast; Eva Marie Saint,
Ralph Richardson, and Lee J. Cobb fare a bit better, but Jill Haworth
is chiefly memorable for giving the single worst performance in the
film. As for Sal Mineo's much lauded performance, today it seems
extremely theatrical.Even so, EXODUS would remain passable were it not for the incredibly
naive brand of Zionism the film adopts. More than fifty years later
after endless wars, waves of terrorism, and failed peace talks we all
know that it was NEVER as simple as this movie would have us believe.
When all is said and done, the most memorable thing about EXODUS is the
Academy Award-winning score by Ernest Gold, which really is as good as
every one says it is.The film is presently available to the homemarket as a no-frills DVD.
Final thought: it has moments of interest and on rare occasions even
brilliance, but those moments are few and far between. Best left to
those who remember it fondly from its 1960 debut.Gary F. Taylor, aka GFT, Amazon Reviewer
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Growing up in Brooklyn in the Fifties and Sixties, I can tell you that
every Jewish household seem to have a copy of Herman Wouk's Marjorie
Morningstar and Leon Uris's Exodus. The characters in Exodus among the
people I grew up with became as known as family members. So when Otto
Preminger made the film, he had a built in audience, almost in the same
way that every Star Trek movie has.But we're not talking about a mythical future. The novel is about
Israel's founding, but the issues still remain and Exodus should be
required viewing for all who wonder about the need for a Jewish state.
Wouldn't hurt to read the book either. Exodus got only one Oscar, but there was really no competition there.
Ernest Gold's musical score is one of the great ones done for the
cinema. I remember how much it was played back when I was a lad. It's a
vigorous and uplifting melody and like so many other good film scores
it carries the viewer along in what is a lengthy movie.Paul Newman and Eva Marie Saint are capable enough leads, but it is the
supporting characters that really make this film. Two of my favorites
are David Opatoshu as Akiva Ben Canaan, an Irgun leader and Gregory
Ratoff as Lazavitch who was the rabble rouser on the ship Exodus. You
will remember both of these people after viewing Exodus. Why the
Academy overlooked either of them for nominations is beyond me. But
that was a year rich in supporting performances.Making this film must have been the highlight of the career of David
Opatoshu. He was a leading actor in the Yiddish Theater and to be in
this film must have been a dream come true. Seeing him in various
roles, Opatoshu never gave a bad performance in his career. Sal Mineo as Dov Landau was nominated for Best Supporting Actor,the
young concentration camp survivor who joins the Irgun. Sal had some
stiff competition that year. Other nominees were Chill Wills for The
Alamo, Jack Kruschen for The Apartment, and Peter Falk for Murder, Inc.
Groucho Marx made a public declaration that his vote was for Sal Mineo
after an appalling campaign appeal was started for Chill Wills. But the
winner was Peter Ustinov for Spartacus.According to a new biography of Sal Mineo, he was very jealous of
Ustinov's victory and would curse him out if his name was even casually
brought up in conversation. I'm convinced that Leon Uris in writing Exodus was influenced by the
Diary of Anne Frank in creating the character of Karen played in the
film by Jill Haworth. Funny also that the film version of the play came
out the year before Exodus. It was as if Anne Frank had survived the
camps and had come to the birthing of Israel. She's an innocent child
who still retains her faith in people like Anne Frank did, making what
happens to her all the more tragic. If you've read the book before
seeing the film, Haworth's performance was all the more poignant.Unfortunately Exodus is not history because the war is still being
fought by the Jewish people against those who would wish and do evil
upon them. Would that it were just history.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"Exodus" centers on the successful escape, masterminded by the
Palestinian underground leader, Ari Ben Canaan, of over 600 Jewish
refugees from Cyprus to Palestine; the underground activities in
Palestine; and the first Israeli-Arab conflicts following partition… Surrounding these and other events are many personal dramas, including
Ari's romance with American nurse Kitty Fremont (Eva Marie Saint) and
his friendship with a sympathetic Arab chieftain Taha (John Derek).
It's a stirring and visually beautiful film, but it contains one of
Newman's least exciting performances…Some contend that Newman's motivational Method conflicted with
Preminger's authoritarian approach; others that he was miscast… But Ari
is the kind of dedicated, single-minded loner Newman is expert
at—except, of course, that the dedication is to a cause, not to
himself… When Newman insults the well-meaning Cypriot, Mandria (Hugh Griffith),
his friends tell severely that his action is wrong, affirming that
Mandria is a real friend… He replies: "When the showdown comes, we will
always stand alone. Mandria will sell us out like all the others. We
have no friends, except ourselves." Those lines are also in the novel,
but they could almost have been written expressly for Newman, whose
self-sufficient characters often speak in this manner…The real problem is that Newman never gives Ari warmth or humanity… His
initial impatience, hostility, arrogance and indifference to individual
problems are understandable, since he is planning crucial events… But
even when he is supposed to be getting warmer, more understanding,
aware that outsiders can be trusted (Kitty, a Christian, becomes deeply
committed to the cause), his behavior remains almost exactly the same… He never comes to life until the last scene, a passionate funeral
oration, and by then it's too late… There's none of the charm or
vitality that makes us interested in even the most vicious of Newman's
antiheroes… In the one instance where Newman is supposed to be
funny—his impersonation of a British officer—he is forced and uneasy…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0312941/comments</url><from>from Ukiah, California</from><name>Aldanoli</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Seeing "Exodus" early in the 21st century, one is robbed of the
experience that moviegoers of the early 1960s would have had; it's
impossible to see a movie about the birth of Israel now without the
perspective of the Six-Day War of 1967, which changed the perception
many non-Jews had of Israel. That, and the events that the Six-Day War
led to, have eroded the moral assurance that many of the main
characters of "Exodus" espouse about Israel and its founding, and would
eventually lead to the moral quagmire found 45 years later in Steven
Spielberg's "Munich." Today, "Munich" is much closer to the grayness of
who is right or wrong in the modern-day Middle East than the
black-and-white assumptions that drive the characters of "Exodus" in
1947 -- or its creators in 1960.And it's likewise much harder to accept Paul Newman in the role of a
Jewish freedom fighter; though he was already a big star in 1960 (which
was no doubt the reason that he was chosen for the part), one cannot
evaluate his performance here without recalling all the other high
points of his career that were still ahead of him -- "The Hustler,"
"Cool Hand Luke," "Hombre," and of course his two big triumphs with
Robert Redford, as Butch and Sundance and in "The Sting" -- not to
mention a career that kept humming even into the 1990s. He's hardly
remembered for this role at all today, and though even he isn't in
every scene in a sweeping epic like this, it's hard to look at the
movie without remembering all that would come later.What stands out today more than Newman's performance, therefore, are
the many secondary characters -- Sal Mineo as the tortured survivor of
Auschwitz with secrets that lead him to the Irgun (and a performance
that would earn him his second and last Oscar nomination); David
Opatoshu as a Menachem Begin-like figure who believes violence is
better than negotiation; and Jill Haworth, all of 15 at the time, and
who would have a bevy of ingénue roles into the 1960s, but whose career
would dribble out by the end of the next decade.In particular, this was a great role for Opatoshu, who is probably best
remembered today for his many guest shots on television (like Newman,
most that came after this, in everything from "Twilight Zone" and
"Mission:Impossible" to "Star Trek" and "Hawaii Five-O"). Though he is
recognizable for those roles, it's worth remembering that he came out
of Yiddish Theater and was a controlled, subtle performer who rarely
got the kind of meaty role that he had here -- and one that no doubt
was important to him.So, while it's mainly remembered today for Ernest Gold's stirring theme
music, "Exodus" is interesting as a window into a different time and a
different way of thinking -- both about its subject matter and its main
character . . . and the once and future star who played him.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0256632/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>Carol-23</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I've heard that author Leon Uris was disappointed in the conversion to the screen of his marvelous novel.  However, given the time frame allowed for a movie, I believe it is totally
faithful to the SPIRIT of the novel and actually follows key
events as written (the stand-off in Famagusta aboard the Exodus between the Palestinian Jews and the British; the escape from Acre prision).  This movie educated me as a pre-teen about
the plight of the post-war Jews and turned a non-Jew into a real Zionist.  I saw this movie several times when it was in the
theatres in the '60s and now own it on video.  Its relevance has stood the test.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The years have dimmed my memory of EXODUS but I realized that I should
have written a review for it long ago. What stayed with me, after
seeing the film, was the gorgeous and uplifting "Theme from Exodus" by
Ernest Gold.I never read the Leon Uris novel, but understand that a lot of
incidents had to be underplayed in the film because the huge novel
required a long film of over three hours to do it justice. As it is,
it's a bit overlong and full of rich, episodic incidents in the story
of the creation of the Palestian war of liberation. It's a sprawling
epic and does get a bit tedious at times but the performances all hold
the interest.Especially good are PAUL NEWMAN and EVA MARIE SAINT in the leads, with
SAL MINEO giving what is arguably his best performance as a rebel with
a cause, and numerous other international players lending their
talents.But the overall effect is somewhat blunted by too much exposition and a
lethargy that seems to build during the middle of the story. However,
no denying it's quite an achievement on an historical basis and that
Ernest Gold score is still worth admiring.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Otto Preminger's presentation of Leon Uris' novel "Exodus" tried to
evoke comparisons, in its trailer, to "Gone with the Wind" and "The
Birth of a Nation". Those films overcome ideological flaws, and remain
genuine, undeniable classics. Despite the starry cast and sweeping
grandeur, "Exodus" fails to achieve its epic intentions. Mr. Preminger,
coming off the superb "Anatomy of a Murder", gives it a long and dull
direction. Paul Newman (as Ari Ben Canaan) and Eva Marie Saint (as
Kitty Fremont) are quite unconvincing, in the leading roles. Still,
there are some good characterizations, and nicely staged scenes.The film offers two obvious, award-garnering career moves: Sal Mineo's
masterful supporting performance, and Ernest Gold's beautiful musical
score. Mr. Mineo (as Dov Landau) won a "Golden Globe" as "Best
Supporting Actor"; and, arguably, he also deserved the year's "Academy
Award". His subplot, played with pretty blonde newcomer Jill Haworth
(as Karen Johansson), is far and away the most interesting story,
thanks to Mineo's acting work. Mr. Gold's "Exodus" theme is also
outstanding, selling well over a million copies of the Ferrante and
Teicher version alone; it won not only an Oscar, but also a Grammy as
1960's "Song of the Year".****** Exodus (12/15/60) Otto Preminger ~ Paul Newman, Eva Marie Saint,
Sal Mineo
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0492558/comments</url><from>from SE US</from><name>grahamsj2</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Wow. I LOVE this film! Director Otto Preminger outdid himself on this
one. The music is a hauntingly beautiful, legendary score. Set in
postwar Palestine, the Jewish settlers await the crucial UN vote on the
creation of the State of Israel. The story is told from a decidedly
Jewish point of view, so there is some "slant" to the storytelling. I
think that the Arab side of the story could have been told in more
depth. There are wonderful peaceful scenes of the countryside and it's
pastoral people. The peace is sometimes shattered by the Irgun or
Haganah who are violently fighting the British protectorate troops.
Once Israel is voted into existence, the fighting begins for survival.
The Palestinians believe that they've lost their country and will fight
to get it back. This is a fight that is going on yet today and that
makes the history depicted in this film all the more relevant. The cast
is so star-laden that the acting is first-rate. Many of the big names
of the day are here: Paul Newman, Eva Marie Saint, Sal Mineo, Lee J.
Cobb, Jill Haworth, Peter Lawford and John Derek. This is truly an epic
film!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15626982/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>harvhil</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The film version of Leon Uris' Exodus was intentionally scripted for an
American audience unfamiliar with Holocaust and Jewish themes. In fact,
the film harps on major character Kitty's discomfort just being around
Jews. Exodus is a 1960's Hollywood version of the creation of the
modern State of Israel "for dummies", and in this it succeeds. While
not having any religious Jewish content whatsoever, the film discuss
themes of Jewish identity after the Holocaust, the plight of Jewish
refugees under the British, the internal struggle of the Haganah versus
the militant Irgun, and major historical incidents in the War for
Independence 1948. While inaccurate about the actual Exodus ship
incident, the film was a milestone in American Jewish cinema and
identity. To this day, the film's music remains a mainstay in Jewish
American homes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15626982/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>harvhil</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The film version of Leon Uris' Exodus was intentionally scripted for an
American audience unfamiliar with Holocaust and Jewish themes. In fact,
the film harps on major character Kitty's discomfort just being around
Jews. Exodus is a 1960's Hollywood version of the creation of the
modern State of Israel "for dummies", and in this it succeeds. While
not having any religious Jewish content whatsoever, the film discuss
themes of Jewish identity after the Holocaust, the plight of Jewish
refugees under the British, the internal struggle of the Haganah versus
the militant Irgun, and major historical incidents in the War for
Independence 1948. While inaccurate about the actual Exodus ship
incident, the film was a milestone in American Jewish cinema and
identity. To this day, the film's music remains a mainstay in Jewish
American homes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15626982/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>harvhil</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jordan-hiller/</url><url>http://www.bangitout.com/articles/viewarticle.php?a=2556 /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1828944</url><name>Jordan Hiller</name><from>Bangitout.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/4
					</rating><comment>The style of filmmaking is simply too polite and serene to carry the edgy, dangerous material of Uris's novel</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/exodus-1960-4/ /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1780939</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Preminger's ambitious chronicle of the formation of the State of Israel contains some stirring moments, but as an epic it's too sprawling, overlong, and lacks dramatic center.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/exodus.htm /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1700212</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>Otto - let my people go!</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/exodus/review/114156 /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1682898</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>A stirring chronicle of Israel's struggle for independence in 1947.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tom-milne/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/64108/exodus.html /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1475788</url><name>Tom Milne</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Watchable mainly for the sheer skill and drive of Preminger's direction, although at 220 minutes even that long outstays its welcome.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9803E2D61130EF3ABC4E52DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1389841</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>In the end, one should take from this picture a shaken feeling of having been through a lot of harsh and ennobling experiences.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=127337 /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1247102</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>Propaganda masquerading as drama, it makes for a decidedly turgid viewing experience.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chireader.com/MovieCaps/E/EX/03242_EXODUS.html /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=6586</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>Intelligence applied exactly where it is most rare: in the lavish, star-studded epic.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/susan-granger/</url><url>/m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1668008</url><name>Susan Granger</name><from>www.susangranger.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>/m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1422500</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>F5 (Wichita, KS)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/brandon-judell/</url><url>/m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=848056</url><name>Brandon Judell</name><from>PopcornQ</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=837896</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117790768.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1006872-exodus/comments.php?reviewid=1806583</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>