<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Kapò</original_title><imdb_rating>7.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><country>Yugoslavia</country><director>Gillo Pontecorvo</director><producer>Cineriz</producer><producer>Vides Cinematografica</producer><producer>Zebra Films</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
A young Jewish girl leads an escape attempt from a concentration camp.
</synopsis><actor>Susan Strasberg</actor><actor>Laurent Terzieff</actor><actor>Emmanuelle Riva</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0169112/comments</url><from>from North Carolina</from><name>Ripshin</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This Italian film, following the travails of a young Jewish girl in a
Nazi work camp, is successful due mainly to its realistic sets, and the
performances of Strasberg and Terzieff. Supporting cast members also
shine throughout the film. The whole concept of the "kapo" is new to
me, and it added a further dimension to the horrific Nazi experience
not covered in films such as "Sophie's Choice" and "The Pianist."
Deservedly, it was nominated for an Academy Award (Best Foreign
Language Film) in 1960. Strangely enough, most filmographies of
Strasberg fail to highlight her incredible performance in this film.
Certainly, it must have reflected her performance as Anne Frank on
Broadway. The same year as "Kapo," George Stevens released his film
version of "Anne Frank," starring Millie Perkins, who took the role
once Audrey Hepburn turned it down. Certainly, Strasberg must have been
considered.A "kapo" was a prisoner of a concentration camp that watched over the
other prisoners in a specified group. A kapo received better clothing,
food, and was not required to work. 2001's "The Grey Zone" would be an
appropriate double-feature with this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0491610/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, B.C.</from><name>Howard Schumann</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Nominated for an Academy Award for Best Foreign Film in 1960, Gillo
Pontecorvo's second film Kapo features Susan Strasberg as a Holocaust
victim who decides that she will do anything to survive, even join the
enemy. Kapo, which stands for Kameradenpolizei, refers to death camp
collaborators who are recruited from the "criminal element" to
supervise other prisoners in return for better treatment and more
privileges. Pontecorvo, who fought in the Italian Resistance as a
member of the Communist Party, presents a realistic picture of what
life in a concentration camp must have been like but no movie can fully
capture the madness and inevitably any attempt to dramatize it must
take on aspects of melodrama.Strasberg, who had played the title role in The Diary of Anne Frank on
Broadway several years earlier, portrays Edith, a 14-year old Jewish
girl who is sent to a concentration camp with her parents when Jews are
rounded up in Paris. After watching her parents die in the gas chambers
along with other women and children, Sofia, a friend, introduces Edith
to the camp doctor who provides her with a new identity as the
non-Jewish Nicole. Cutting her hair and dressing her in the work
clothes of a prisoner that died that morning, she is sent to a labor
camp where she witnesses repeated horrors including the hanging of a
young girl for alleged sabotage.Desperate to stay alive, she offers herself to a German soldier Karl
(Gianni Garko). Although little about this relationship is developed,
it leads to Nicole accepting the job of a Kapo, and the victim becoming
a victimizer, brutally enforcing the camp's harsh rules on her fellow
prisoners. It is only when she witnesses the suicide of a close friend
Terese (Emanuelle Riva) and falls in love with Sascha (Laurent
Terzieff), a Russian prisoner of war, that she is able to redeem the
human values that had once been an integral part of her life. Much of
this happens over a period of time but the passage of time is not shown
and Nicole's transformation from a loving young girl to a bullying camp
guard seems too quick and facile to be truly convincing, and there is
little self-reflection in the process. The experience gained in this
film, however, paved the way for Pontecorvo's masterpiece The Battle of
Algiers, only a few years after.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0102677/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>John Seal</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Only the survivors of the Holocaust can tell us what the concentration
camp experience was really like, but Kapo is probably as close as
cinema can get to recreating the numbing horrors of the camps--and that
includes Schindler's List. Susan Strasberg is superb as Edith, the
Jewish teenager who is saved by chance and then becomes a collaborator
in order to survive. The film's greatest strength is its ability to
make us comprehend the forces that compelled inmates to become
kapos--the Nazi equivalent of prison trustees--and almost (but not
quite) makes us sympathize with them. Snatched from the jaws of the gas
chamber only to have the power of life and death thrust upon them, the
kapos did what they had to do in order to survive--and who amongst us
would not take that same chance if thrust into the heart of Nazi
darkness. This incredibly powerful film is filled with astonishing
imagery, none more powerful than the scene of Edith/Nicole watching
helplessly as her parents are forced to jog to their demise amidst a
crowd of children and elderly inmates--people who are inessential to
the Reich's war machine. This important film, long forgotten in the
United States, has now been unearthed by Turner Classic Movies, and
hopefully a DVD is not far behind.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0355380/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas, Nevada</from><name>DumaNV</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Quite an excellent character study of what people will do to survive.
Although not as powerful as other prisoner of war films such as "Seven
Beauties" it stands out because of the performances of all the women
and especially Susan Strasberg who does a magnificent job starting out
as the young innocent girl, hiding the fact that she is Jewish, a
bewildering task, and her agonizing evolution into a hardened guard.Don't look for huge sets and gruesome scenes of gas chambers and ovens
here. It's not that type of film. It's a simple story of the slow
chipping away of humanity that dire conditions force. Dignity and
nobility give way to cruelty and inhumanity and simple survival becomes
a thing to justify as time goes on. By telling this type of story
through the eyes of a young impressionable person is excellent.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3150849/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>taibunsuu-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I've never really liked holocaust flicks because they get well, usually
made so that the dumbest of the dumb to 'get it.' Kapo is just a movie
that shows, not tells, which of course makes the best story. Thanks to
TCM for playing this gem that I'll buy on DVD as soon as it comes out.
I'd never even heard of it, and I have seen a LOT of flicks.Susan Strasburg does an incredible job as Nicollete / Edith. Her
transformation from shell-shocked victim to cynical survivor is
absolutely gripping. The tension in the movie builds to nearly
unbearable level and the end simply leaves you scooping your jaw off
the floor.This is the type of movie I sorely needed after going on a loooong dry
spell of celluloid garbage. Why this movie isn't famous, I have no
idea, but it should be.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0888584/comments</url><from>from Baltimore, MD</from><name>Kelt Smith</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I was not previously aware of this gem. I found it on TCM after it had
already been on for about 10 minutes. I kept thinking that the lead
actress looked just like SUSAN STRASBERG &amp; for good reason. It was. The
fact that it was foreign with sub-titles threw me initially. Very
realistic, almost raw, which was surprising considering that this movie
was made in 1959.STRASBERG as 'Nicole' works her way up through a concentration camp to
become the woman in charge of her fellow prisoners. Strong language,
violent situations, but this is a story about WWII, not the 'Enchanted
Forest'. Good storyline, good direction, &amp; a terrific performance by
SUSAN STRASBERG that was all the more admirable when you realize that
she was all of 20,21 when she made this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Although it features two French leads (Laurent Terzieff and Emmanuelle
Riva) ,"Kapo" has disappeared from the French dictionaries of films
whereas lots of duds are included.With the exceptions of "Nuit et Brouillard" (which was an exceptional
documentary ) and Wanda Jakubowska 's "ostatni etap' (1947) there were
few movies which at the time broached the concentration camps
subject(the last scenes of Dmytryk's "young lions" ,1958)Susan Strasberg was impressive ,mainly in the first hour though the
evolution of her character is not always believable.Besides,her
relationship with Sascha weakens the plot .Emmanuelle Riva almost outshines Strasberg,maybe because she was a more
experimented actress (she was featured in Resnais's "Hiroshima Mon
Amour" ) and her scene when she is translating the German words in a
voice chocked with emotion may be the strongest in the whole movie.The "potato" scene is also revealing.I remember what Simone Veil ,a
former French minister (secretary) (and herself a former prisoner in a
concentration camp),said after watching the last episode of "Holocaust
" (the seventies miniseries) : "in the camps ,people were not as
helpful ,as kind ,as compassionate as they are in the film" ."Kapo"
shows a very harsh world where the women are almost always fighting
against their mates:that's the story of Edith /Nicole .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19804208/comments</url><from>from Spain</from><name>psagray</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Edith", (Susan Strasberg) is a French Jewish girl that during the Nazi
occupation is detained in a concentration camp, fortunately achieves
escape the gas chamber, and pretending to be a dam common is deported
to a labor camp in Poland, where reaches the status of "Kapo"
Extraordinary and unknown film by one of the pioneers of political
film, He was always interesting director Gillo Pontecorvo. Film ahead
of its time. It was one of the first films address without scruple, the
theme of Jewish holocaust and one of the more realistic in its
recreation.The first part of the film is more descriptive contains some scenes of
prisoners being driven to the concentration camps and to the gas
chambers, making it clear that seeks the script.The main actors and bit actors, all of them with some magnificent
performances, and the historic value, up its main inducements, The
music does not follow nor the rhythm, nor the level of the film. The
history of love in the second half, in spite of entertain abandons the
principles with which was conceived the production, and the same
director recognize him later. The film is benefiting from a wonderful
indent, and a remarkable ambiance, which transmits effectively the
hardness of the concentration camps.Resume, the interest of the film lies in being one of the first that
addressed openly the horror of the concentration camps, showing
particularly the situation of women, and in which analyzes with great
crudely psychological adaptation of "Edith" to a terrible reality It's
a film essential for interested and scholars of the "Holocaust" during
the "WWII".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4061961/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>Eumenides_0</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
My journey with Gillo Pontecorvo started with The Battle of Algiers and
continued with Queimada. Now I finally have the pleasure of going back
to the movie that first cemented his position as one of the best
directors ever, Kapo. Once again he's assisted by the great European
screenwriter Franco Solinas, a man who has given so much to world
cinema and yet remains forgotten.Kapo is not a movie about revolutions; it's perhaps Pontecorvo's most
traditional and intimate movie since it doesn't concern the sweeping
history of a country or conflicts between cultures. It simply follows
Edith, a Jewish girl returning home after a piano lesson. She arrives
just in time to be taken, with her family, by the SS. Through luck, a
doctor creates a new, non-Jewish, identity, for her. Her family is sent
to Auschwitz, but she goes to a labour camp, where she may survive.What follows is a slow transformation from a shy, innocent girl into a
ruthless woman who'll do anything to survive. Her chance comes when she
becomes a Kapo, or one of the inmates in charge of the other inmates.
She's well fed, well clothed, she has some respect from the German
soldiers and inspires terror in the other women. Susan Strasberg
becomes the character, always captivating even when she's ruthless. She
reminds me of Giancarlo Giannini in that other masterpiece about
concentration camp prisoners, Pasqualino Settebellezze.This is a very bleak Holocaust movie because it paints a picture of the
inmates that may leave some people uncomfortable. This is not
Schindler's List, Life is Beautiful or The Pianist, all hard movies,
but in which we see the people helping each other in a good spirit of
comradeship. The reality of Kapo resembles more that of Primo Levi's
Survival in Auschwitz, or Tadeusz Borowski's We Were in Auschwitz,
objective, emotionless memoirs about what people would do to survive
every day in a concentration camp, of how low they'd go in their
degradation, of how their will to survive made them forget morality and
decency.Although a bit dated, Kapo remains a great study of the worst side of
human nature. The camp may seem a bit unrealistic nowadays as well as a
love story that develops within its electric fences, but back then the
concentration world wasn't as well studied as it is today. What remains
is really a powerful story directed with craft and compassion.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12079061/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>siddingo</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
i'm trying to order a video of this incredible movie, &amp; in so doing
have seen the comments about it. i haven't seen this movie in about a
year, but i must reply in response to the previous viewer's comments.
"kapo" is the zenith of film noir, or should i say, the best of the
"film nadir." it may be the darkest movie i've seen. the black &amp; white
filming certainly intensifies its starkness. when i first innocently
viewed "kapo," i remember being initially surprised, then moved, then
deeply disturbed. couldn't susan's choices have been any of ours born
at the same wrong time, wrong place? only i may not have chosen the
heroic finale that susan chose. her choices introduce that question in
ourselves--would we have chosen to save others as she did? or would we
have preferred to save ourselves? an eternal dilemma that cannot be
answered unless we are actually put into her position--God forbid.
released in 1959, 14 years after WWII was over, makes me wonder what
movies will be made 14 years from now, or should i say, 14 years from
when the war in iraq is over... SEE this movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12079061/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>siddingo</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
i'm trying to order a video of this incredible movie, &amp; in so doing
have seen the comments about it. i haven't seen this movie in about a
year, but i must reply in response to the previous viewer's comments.
"kapo" is the zenith of film noir, or should i say, the best of the
"film nadir." it may be the darkest movie i've seen. the black &amp; white
filming certainly intensifies its starkness. when i first innocently
viewed "kapo," i remember being initially surprised, then moved, then
deeply disturbed. couldn't susan's choices have been any of ours born
at the same wrong time, wrong place? only i may not have chosen the
heroic finale that susan chose. her choices introduce that question in
ourselves--would we have chosen to save others as she did? or would we
have preferred to save ourselves? an eternal dilemma that cannot be
answered unless we are actually put into her position--God forbid.
released in 1959, 14 years after WWII was over, makes me wonder what
movies will be made 14 years from now, or should i say, 14 years from
when the war in iraq is over... SEE this movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12079061/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>siddingo</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>