<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Millionairess</original_title><alt_title>Les dessous de la millionnaire</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Anthony Asquith</director><producer>Dimitri De Grunwald Production</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
A Millionairess and a doctor cannot marry until they meet conditions set-up by their respective parents.
</synopsis><actor>Sophia Loren</actor><actor>Peter Sellers</actor><actor>Alastair Sim</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0249396/comments</url><from>from Marietta, GA, USA</from><name>Hermit C-2</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Chemistry can be a funny thing. This movie stars two charismatic legends of
the cinema, Sophia Loren and Peter Sellers. Its script, on the surface, is
intelligent and well-written, full of snappy dialog. (It's based on a play
by G.B. Shaw.) They combine to make a relentlessly dull movie. Loren is a
rich heiress who for some reason has to marry again to satisfy conditions of
her father's will and Sellers plays an altruistic Indian doctor in London,
where the movie is set, with whom she has an uninteresting love/hate
relationship. I found it all but impossible to keep my attention focused on
the screen as the film worked its way toward its conclusion. It made for one
of the longest 90-minute movies I've ever seen.Part of the problem I think is that characters here are not developed, they
just burst out in full force the moment you see them, making a viewer feel
like he or she has started watching in the middle of the film. Also, as a
romance, the movie is completely flat, with zero chemistry between the
leads. It's no wonder you don't hear much about this film from fans of Loren
or Sellers, or Shaw for that matter.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
You cannot hit the target perfectly every time, and this is true of
dramatist as the rest of us.George Bernard Shaw gave us MAJOR BARBARA, PYGMALION, ST.
JOAN,HEARTBREAK HOUSE, MAN AND SUPERMAN, ... but he could do mediocre
work. I think he had become a bit of an old fogy. His mind had gotten
set into certain thought patterns that he would not give up. Whether
this was due to disenchantment in the failure of the political Labor
Party movement to improve England I can only leave to his biographers
to fight out. He retreated into a fantasy world. It sometimes succeeds with flashes
of his wit but for the most part he falls on his face. In this period
Shaw demonstrated a remarkable belief in "strongmen". He looked at
those dynamic dictators abroad in Russia, Italy, and Germany, and the
result was GENEVA (1935) a play that is rarely considered for revival
today - the audience might riot at it's apologia for Stalin, Mussolini,
and Hitler. Shaw felt that one could not look at these men and their
actions without seeing the total aim that they were pushing. The
problem with Shaw's vision was he was buying their aims for efficiency
and for better economic standards for the bulk of their peoples.
Certainly they were dynamic but Shaw ignored huge political crimes. He had always favored the work of a great person who cut to the chase
ignoring the damage left and right. Undershaft in MAJOR BARBARA was
typical of this - he fights poverty by giving good wages and housing
and health care to the people who work in his armaments plants. That he
might encourage war is nonsense - "Make war on war" is how he sees it. Only in the Great War had Shaw questioned this. He created Boss Mangan
in HEARTBREAK HOUSE, who is really Undershaft up to date (1916).
Undershaft had a ready, self-congratulatory statement and answer for
everything. Mangan seems that way but his feet of clay are shown. He
whines about his business policies that have helped lead to the present
disaster to Britain. He can't undue them, for fear of losing his "Boss"
position due to his shareholder's anger. And in the end, Mangan is
killed (by an enemy bomb, ironically enough). It would take World War
II to finally make Shaw realize how misplaced his faith in "Great Men"
was. Notably he did not write that much after 1939.He showed he hope that private philanthropy by the wealthy might help.
His plays keep suggesting solutions by the rich like BOUYANT BILLIONS.
THE MILLIONAIRESS is a similar play. It actually can succeed as a
comedy - Katherine Hepburn played Epifania successfully on stage. But
it's point of view is hard to take.SPOILERS COMING UPEpifania has just become the richest woman in the world. She is seeking
fulfillment in love. Her father (whose painting looks like Peter
Sellers in a beard) has set the standard for whomever she will marry in
the long run. It's hard to match. She asks for the assistance of the
family lawyer (Sagamore - Alistair Sim), who introduces her around.
Naturally the first person she dates seriously is that notorious
fortune hunting scoundrel Dennis Price - but that relationship soon
ends. Epifania decides to commit suicide. She approaches Sagamore, and
Sim without blinking an eye hands her the recipe for a fool proof
instantaneous, painless poison. Disgusted she goes to the Thames and
throws herself in. And she meets Sellers, playing Dr. Kabir from India.Sellers is as mother fixated as Loren is father fixated (Seller's
mother's picture looks like Loren). Loren falls for him, but he seems
more concerned about his indigent patients and his clinic. What follows
is Loren's attempts to win Sellers, first as a desperate patient, then
as a would-be financial angel. Nothing she does stimulates him (he is
rather surprised). Finally she does get him to agree to taking a test
her father set up: can Sellers make a fortune out of 500 pounds (in
three months), and Sellers gives her a test his mother set up for the
woman he was to marry: can she live on 500 pounds for three months.We watch Loren go to work for small restaurant owner, Victorio De Sica,
for three months - she ends up making it into a nightspot for the rich,
and De Sica admits that he thinks he will sell it and then find a side
street to start a nice small family restaurant again. Sellers tries to get rid of the money as quickly as he can - he puts
out a tray with the money on it, and a sign saying "Free Money". His
patients thinks it's a joke and don't take it. Finally he manages to
unload it on fellow physician Noel Purcell, after a dinner they attend
(where they both get drunk). This is disappointing to Loren, who
decides that as Sellers has failed she will enter a convent (one that
she has funded). Sim, not liking such a waste, contacts Sellers that
Loren is going to commit suicide. This finally rouses Sellers, who
shows up to prevent such a catastrophe.Sim actually gave the best performance of the three actors, but I feel
it is because his Mr. Sagamore was just reacting to the activities of
the other two. He was like a breeze of fresh air in the film's actions.
Also the work by Purcell and De Sica was quite good, as small as both
performances were. Loren and Sellers did well. There is some chemistry.
Sellers read too much into this. Reputedly he thought Loren and he
would become an item, but Loren never saw it that way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1968521/comments</url><from>from Brick, NJ</from><name> (rcraig62@comcast.net)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

      The Millionairess reminds me of why people will sit through generally
stale movies sometimes instead of just packing it in, the odd glitter or
chemistry between two major movie stars who one does not often get to see
together.  This is a flat uncompelling piece of work about a newly minted
heiress (Sophia Loren) who can't find the right man to marry and a devoted
Indian physician (Peter Sellers) who has no interest in money- or
women.      Sellers performance is about the only thing that takes this picture
above banality; he has so much integrity as an actor that he raises the
level of the mostly shoddy material. He has some truly wonderful, charming
moments as the doctor who resists the stunning Loren at every turn (the same
could not be said off-camera; Sellers wrecked his first marriage over the
obsession).  Loren, is a good, but not great actress; her appeal lies
heavily in her charm and good humor.  Here, those qualities are muted by the
character she plays: a self-obsessed bombshell who has no real love to give-
only money- and doesn't understand why a man of true integrity won't respond
to that.  But what's wrong with the screenplay is fairly obvious.  In the
typical Hate At First Sight movie romance, the characters learn and grow to
see the virtue of the each other's worth, then fall in love.  Here, they
don't.  Sellers character gives no indication of wearing down, Loren's never
stops being exasperating (in one scene, she fakes an illness at 4:30 AM so
Sellers will come over to examine her). When they hook up at the end, it's
totally implausible and not very satisfying (she fakes committing suicide to
draw him to her).      That said, the movie is not quite boring, the audience may be drawn to
the radiance of the stars in spite of itself, but it has no real spark and
no drive.  The look of it is quite nice, it's expensive without being gaudy.
But it doesn't serve the actors very well; even the great Alastair Sim isn't
well-used.  I suspect watching The Millionairess is something like being
super-rich, one gets the feeling of having too much time to kill.  2** out
of 4
      
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1336711/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>massimo1943</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Amazing that nobody commented on Sophia guepiere and garter belt!O.K. Guys. The movie is somewhat dull and you may be sure that neither
Sophia Loren or Peter Sellers could have been nominated for Oscar on
this performance. But, does anybody remember the scene when Sophia
undresses in Peter,s doctor cabinet and shows herself in a black
guepiere , black stockings and garter belt? If you have forgotten this,
you are only forgiven if you are younger than two years or older than
ninety-nine And , moreover, we were back in 1960, when such scenes in
movies, particularly in my native Italy, were not frequent! For the
remaining part, I must agree that the story is weak, the other actors (
including an improbable Vittorio De Sica) are unnoticeable, and Sophia
as a millionaire is less credible than as a Naples Pizza seller!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3534361/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>oliver-123</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I never saw this when it first came out, though I remember the song
that went with it (but does not feature in it), and only caught up with
it when the Times gave away free DVDs with its Saturday edition
recently. I agree entirely with other criticisms; too little happens,
the dialogue doesn't flow naturally, some of the acting is wooden and
there are pointless cameos (e.g. by Alfie Bass) and weak attempts at
slapstick (various persons ending up in the Thames). The setting seems
to be modern, i.e. 1950s, but the East Enders the Indian doctor treats
belong to an older time, the time of Shaw's own play, except that some
are Indian or similar. Part of the problem seems to be the placing of
some of Shaw's epigrammatic dialogue in a weaker and rather
inappropriate framework; the millionairess is much more ruthless and
unpleasant in the play, as I remember it. Sophia Loren is a pleasure to
watch, and there seems to be genuine chemistry between her and Peter
Sellers (as I believe was reported off-set), but they cannot save this,
and good actors like Alastair Sim and Dennis Price are wasted.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3600916/comments</url><from>from Thessaloniki, Greece</from><name>dmtls</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I am a big fan of Peter Sellers and this is one of the two reasons I
saw this movie.The other one was to get some of this 60s wonderful
feeling. Unfortunately both my expectations drowned during movie's
running time. Seller's seemed simply not to fit in the role (at least
not as much as he has spoiled us to expect from him), and nothing was
there from this 60s feeling (apart from some truly kitsch, and for this
adorable, nostalgic retro-future building interiors). All in all this
was neither a good nor a bad movie, just a boring one.I am sure
everyone expected something more than a dull and a bit childish comment
on common social problems.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Sophia Loren is "The Millionairess" in this 1960 film also starring
Peter Sellars, with director Vittorio de Sica playing a small role. The
film is adapted from a play by George Bernard Shaw. I seem to remember
that Garson Kanin and Katharine Hepburn had planned to do this play as
a movie, but it never happened. I can't imagine why they wanted to do
it, and I frankly don't know if their version would have been much
better. At least in this production we got to look at Sophia and her
exquisite wardrobe.Loren plays an Italian heiress who falls for an Indian doctor (Sellars)
devoted to helping the poor. She is determined to get him, even
building a huge hospital for him, but nothing seems to work. Her father
stipulated that if she married, she must give her husband-to-be 500
pounds, and within three months, he must have made it into 15,000
pounds. It turns out that Sellars' mother had a similar rule for a
proposed wife - she must go out into the world with 35 shillings and
the clothes on her back and make a living. Loren takes the bet and
hands Sellars 500 pounds. She walks into a pasta-making sweatshop, cuts
out the middleman, brings in modern equipment, lets the workers
unionize, and makes a fortune for the owners and herself. The Sellars
character leaves the money he was given on his reception desk, but no
one takes any.There is absolutely no action and no pacing in this film, and it fails
to hold interest except when Sophia shows up in a new outfit. It's
obvious that it's a play, and it would have to move a lot faster in
order for it to have even a chance at working. Sophia is definitely one
of the wonders of the world, and in 1960, she was on top of it, an
absolute goddess with a voluptuous body, the kind never seen today.
She's beautifully dressed by Pierre Balman. Sellars is excellent as
always, but this would be at the bottom of the list as far as his early
films.Dull.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1518804/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>BadWebDiver</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Let me just start off by saying that George Bernard Shaw is one of my
all-time favorite playwrights, and Peter Sellers is one of my all-time
favorite comic actors. So naturally I think this is a pretty good
movie. I admit the concept is more interesting than the actual
execution. But certainly the personality of the leads does compensate.
And it is a very intriguing idea.I think the best moments are when Sophia Loren's character gets the
good doctor to make a house call, the Doctor trying to give his fortune
away on the street and no-one bothering to take it (Would that still be
the case today?), as well as Alistair Sims excellent lawyer. And having
worked in the medical profession (as a lab clerk), the dry comments on
the high-tech lab equipment, and ruthless beurocracy of a large medical
institution rang especially true. There are certainly some exceptional
social commentary behind the human story, which is the trademark of
Shaw's work.But I like this movie especially for being the inspiration of the
classic novelty song "Goodness Gracious Me!", which the two leads
recorded in order to promote the movie. I actually think the song works
better.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1408348/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Zachary (zach19@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I loved this film as a boy growing up in the 60s, and I love it
today.
In today's society in which sex is flaunted and perverted in the
movies,
it's nice to be able to take a trip back in time and see movies in
which
sex was depicted more as an "innuendo". 
Sophia Loren is one of the most beautiful women of all-time; and Peter
Sellers was one of the funniest comics of all-time. Together they made a
romantic comedy that could compete and surpass many of
today's
romantic comedies. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
This film starts off with Sophia Loren inheriting her father's fortune
after his death. Early on, I disliked the movie as Loren's character
was ridiculous--more of a caricature than a real millionairess. I'm a
bit surprised I didn't turn off the movie and actually stuck with it.
In so many ways, her selfish and petulant routine was almost like a
burlesque of that sort of person, as it was too broad and not the least
bit subtle or believable. Rarely have I ever felt this annoyed by
Loren--a genuinely bad role for the otherwise talented actress. The
only saving grace for this incredibly annoying creature was her
solicitor, played by Alistair Sim--whose indifference to her ridiculous
behavior was at least enjoyable.After Loren proves unlucky in love, she happens to run into an Indian
doctor (played by Peter Sellers). Unlike other men, he is completely
indifferent to her boorish misbehaviors or ample 'charms'. And, since
Loren is playing a spoiled screwball, she falls for Sellers and does
almost anything to get him. Frankly, this is an interesting but utterly
ridiculous idea--and certainly not enough of a basis for a movie, as
there is absolutely no chemistry between them and it didn't make sense.
Sellers is pretty good and realistic in this role, but it isn't comedic
in the least--despite the film being a comedy! In fact, his Indian
character from THE PARTY would have probably worked better with this
sort of broad comedy.Overall, a rather pointless waste of the talents of the actors. You'd
think they could have done better. But, actors cannot overcome bad
writing and indifferent direction. Clearly a misfire.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
This film starts off with Sophia Loren inheriting her father's fortune
after his death. Early on, I disliked the movie as Loren's character
was ridiculous--more of a caricature than a real millionairess. I'm a
bit surprised I didn't turn off the movie and actually stuck with it.
In so many ways, her selfish and petulant routine was almost like a
burlesque of that sort of person, as it was too broad and not the least
bit subtle or believable. Rarely have I ever felt this annoyed by
Loren--a genuinely bad role for the otherwise talented actress. The
only saving grace for this incredibly annoying creature was her
solicitor, played by Alistair Sim--whose indifference to her ridiculous
behavior was at least enjoyable.After Loren proves unlucky in love, she happens to run into an Indian
doctor (played by Peter Sellers). Unlike other men, he is completely
indifferent to her boorish misbehaviors or ample 'charms'. And, since
Loren is playing a spoiled screwball, she falls for Sellers and does
almost anything to get him. Frankly, this is an interesting but utterly
ridiculous idea--and certainly not enough of a basis for a movie, as
there is absolutely no chemistry between them and it didn't make sense.
Sellers is pretty good and realistic in this role, but it isn't comedic
in the least--despite the film being a comedy! In fact, his Indian
character from THE PARTY would have probably worked better with this
sort of broad comedy.Overall, a rather pointless waste of the talents of the actors. You'd
think they could have done better. But, actors cannot overcome bad
writing and indifferent direction. Clearly a misfire.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>