<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Romeo, Julia a tma</original_title><alt_title>Roméo, Juliette et les ténèbres</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Czechoslovakia</country><director>Jirí Weiss</director><producer>CBK</producer><producer>Ceskoslovenský Státní Film</producer><producer>Filmové Studio Barrandov</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
Pavel, a young student living in Prague in 1942, hides a Jewish girl in his apartment building's attic...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ivan Mistrík</actor><actor>Daniela Smutná</actor><actor>Jirina Sejbalová</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0988112/comments</url><from>from Seattle</from><name>ebbets-field</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

A love story, wartime thriller, and social commentary set during the Nazi
occupation of Czechoslovakia.  Artfully shot in black and white, and
undergirded by a strong musical track, it explores the risks of sheltering
a
Jewish fugitive whose a life might be saved (or might not), but where the
lives of many bystanders are thereby put in peril.Fritz Lang's earlier US-made "Hangmen Also Die" dealt with the same
historical event (the assassination of occupation head Gen. Heydrich), but
his was a more kinetic and extroverted treatment compared to Weiss' more
personal, introspective, and poetic view.  In a sense, this is the Anne
Frank story moved from Amsterdam to Prague.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur18697014/comments</url><from>from Scotland, United Kingdom</from><name>Auteurist-en-Ecosse</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Jiri Weiss's 1960 film Romeo, Juliet and Darkness is a wholly
convincing, tightly controlled account of the human costs of despotism.
The story takes place against the background of the Nazi occupation of
Prague, and more specifically the horrible repercussions visited upon
the population after the assassination of Heydrich, the leading Nazi in
Czechoslovakia. A young man, in his final year at school, takes in and
shelters in the attic of his mother's house a Jewish girl of the same
age, going to great pains both to conceal her presence and to find food
for her. Weiss's direction is superb, with particularly good
establishment of the atmosphere of the flats where most of the action
occurs. Watching the move now, one almost feels one is present in the
Prague of 1942, the movie being particularly effective at showing how
routine life goes on under even the most harsh of political
circumstances. The two young actors in the lead roles both give
excellent and very moving performances. There are also a range of
vividly-drawn characters in the background. At least two things make
the film noteworthy, looking at it from today's perspective. First, the
film is almost wholly free of any propagandistic elements, presumably
quite an achievement given the time and place of its production. The
film, with its emphasis on a humanistic depiction on the trials of
ordinary people, points towards the Czech New Wave films which would
appear five or six years later. Second, Weiss's direction is such that
the film is simultaneously vivid and yet understated, the relative
absence of histrionics making it all the more absorbing. The denouement
is very powerful indeed, making the film (available on DVD in the UK)
one that is very worthwhile seeking out. I bought the DVD not knowing
what to expect; I ended up watching a masterpiece.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1902636/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>oOgiandujaOo</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Here we have a love story set in a quadrangled apartment block in
Prague during the Second World War, as background the real life
assassination of cruel Nazi despot Reinhardt Heydrich, and the
resultant inhuman reprisals. By coincidence, a young Jewish refugee,
Hanka, arrives at the apartment block a day after her contacts have
departed, totally alone, she is befriended by Aryan teenager Pavel who
stows her away in a storeroom up in the rafters where he usually
develops photos.There's something very curiously appealing about the motif of the
isolated ethereal and quiet Jewess, Hanka in this movie is reminiscent
of Rowena in Sir Walter Scott's famous novel Ivanhoe; though speaking
in ethnic terms is somewhat of a betrayal of the love between Hanka and
Pavel: he points out that terms like Aryan are "their language".I think that innocence is the prevailing theme, the setting a rather
barren and lonely one for such a pretty flower. In my corner of the
world teenagers video-message each other home-brew pornography, watch
videos of beheadings on the internet and play vandal-simulation
computer games. In the world that Jirí Weiss has created/resurrected,
the lovers discuss moving to the North Pole, as a day there lasts six
months of the year. For them it is a magic place heard of only in
books, instead of a place which a group of idiots race to in a
four-by-four on television (if you don't teeth with that popular
culture reference, consider yourself fortunate).What's quite realistic in the movie is the way in which love thrives on
reliance. Hanka is dead without Pavel, who sells off prize possessions
in order to keep her fed. This in counterpoint to modern times, and my
corner of the world, where a woman needs a man, as they say, like a
fish needs a bicycle, and often romantic love exists, if at all, as a
knowing post-ironic pretence rather than as an enveloping universe or
the velvet swaddle that it can be. An analogy of Hanka and Pavel's love
in the movie is of a binary system, two stars orbiting around one
centre of gravity, alone together in vastness. By the by Pavel
identifies Proxima Centauri as binary, whereas in fact it is nearby
Alpha Centauri which is binary.Hanka is so curious, she has mysterious aquiline features, and a
feeling of comfortable fatalism, if that isn't too odd a thing to say,
which is shown in material terms by the ease with which she wears her
Star-of-David-tagged overcoat. If you've ever held a small bird you
will know this feeling of fragility, hollow bones and feather
contribute to a feeling that you're holding a fragile
almost-nothingness in your hands. There's something of that in spritely
Hanka. I think Pavel is a great and interesting Romeo, he's so gentle
and kind, but really powerless, which you can see when a false alarm
happens and he almost disintegrates.The ethnic tensions in the movie are worth exploring, Prague was
historically a multicultural city and contained a sizable population of
ethnic Germans (Aryans) and also German-speaking Jews. It's therefore
not unusual to find a lady in the movie who is Czech by nationality but
also speaks fluent German and has taken up with a German Wehrmacht
officer. This population of German speakers lived under considerable
threat, naturally viewed as collaborators (with varying degrees of
accuracy), an end to occupation a threat as much as a relief. Indeed
after the war the controversial Beneš decrees realised that threat and
initiated the forced exile of the majority of the German-speaking
population.There's potentially profit to be gained from comparing this to another
Eastern European WWII city under siege, Lwow from Zulawski's The Third
Part of the Night (1971). Zulawski's film is all blanched nausea,
surreal, fractured, like a fever dream. Romeo, Juliet and Darkness by
contrast is more benign, chary of showing violence, sedate and making
good use of suggestion and implication, for example the lingering
thought of the night-time of six months (which is basically the
Heydrich incident). Despite the very innocent and unassuming nature of
both the filming, characters and the subject, I think the movie speaks
loudly of love and tolerance, and should be commended.For my friend Claire.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1902636/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>oOgiandujaOo</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Here we have a love story set in a quadrangled apartment block in
Prague during the Second World War, as background the real life
assassination of cruel Nazi despot Reinhardt Heydrich, and the
resultant inhuman reprisals. By coincidence, a young Jewish refugee,
Hanka, arrives at the apartment block a day after her contacts have
departed, totally alone, she is befriended by Aryan teenager Pavel who
stows her away in a storeroom up in the rafters where he usually
develops photos.There's something very curiously appealing about the motif of the
isolated ethereal and quiet Jewess, Hanka in this movie is reminiscent
of Rowena in Sir Walter Scott's famous novel Ivanhoe; though speaking
in ethnic terms is somewhat of a betrayal of the love between Hanka and
Pavel: he points out that terms like Aryan are "their language".I think that innocence is the prevailing theme, the setting a rather
barren and lonely one for such a pretty flower. In my corner of the
world teenagers video-message each other home-brew pornography, watch
videos of beheadings on the internet and play vandal-simulation
computer games. In the world that Jirí Weiss has created/resurrected,
the lovers discuss moving to the North Pole, as a day there lasts six
months of the year. For them it is a magic place heard of only in
books, instead of a place which a group of idiots race to in a
four-by-four on television (if you don't teeth with that popular
culture reference, consider yourself fortunate).What's quite realistic in the movie is the way in which love thrives on
reliance. Hanka is dead without Pavel, who sells off prize possessions
in order to keep her fed. This in counterpoint to modern times, and my
corner of the world, where a woman needs a man, as they say, like a
fish needs a bicycle, and often romantic love exists, if at all, as a
knowing post-ironic pretence rather than as an enveloping universe or
the velvet swaddle that it can be. An analogy of Hanka and Pavel's love
in the movie is of a binary system, two stars orbiting around one
centre of gravity, alone together in vastness. By the by Pavel
identifies Proxima Centauri as binary, whereas in fact it is nearby
Alpha Centauri which is binary.Hanka is so curious, she has mysterious aquiline features, and a
feeling of comfortable fatalism, if that isn't too odd a thing to say,
which is shown in material terms by the ease with which she wears her
Star-of-David-tagged overcoat. If you've ever held a small bird you
will know this feeling of fragility, hollow bones and feather
contribute to a feeling that you're holding a fragile
almost-nothingness in your hands. There's something of that in spritely
Hanka. I think Pavel is a great and interesting Romeo, he's so gentle
and kind, but really powerless, which you can see when a false alarm
happens and he almost disintegrates.The ethnic tensions in the movie are worth exploring, Prague was
historically a multicultural city and contained a sizable population of
ethnic Germans (Aryans) and also German-speaking Jews. It's therefore
not unusual to find a lady in the movie who is Czech by nationality but
also speaks fluent German and has taken up with a German Wehrmacht
officer. This population of German speakers lived under considerable
threat, naturally viewed as collaborators (with varying degrees of
accuracy), an end to occupation a threat as much as a relief. Indeed
after the war the controversial Beneš decrees realised that threat and
initiated the forced exile of the majority of the German-speaking
population.There's potentially profit to be gained from comparing this to another
Eastern European WWII city under siege, Lwow from Zulawski's The Third
Part of the Night (1971). Zulawski's film is all blanched nausea,
surreal, fractured, like a fever dream. Romeo, Juliet and Darkness by
contrast is more benign, chary of showing violence, sedate and making
good use of suggestion and implication, for example the lingering
thought of the night-time of six months (which is basically the
Heydrich incident). Despite the very innocent and unassuming nature of
both the filming, characters and the subject, I think the movie speaks
loudly of love and tolerance, and should be commended.For my friend Claire.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1902636/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>oOgiandujaOo</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>