<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The League of Gentlemen</original_title><imdb_rating>7.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Basil Dearden</director><producer>Allied Film Makers (AFM)</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
A disgruntled veteran recruits a group of disgraced collegues to perform a bank robbery with military precision.
</synopsis><actor>Jack Hawkins</actor><actor>Nigel Patrick</actor><actor>Roger Livesey</actor><rt_rating>6.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0171012/comments</url><from>from Moscow, Russia</from><name>Stewart Naunton (snaunton@online.ru)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A British army colonel, pensioned off and embittered, assembles a motley
group of specialist, criminal and deviant ex-officers who share his
bitterness.  He has in mind a bank robbery.  They arm themselves, courtesy
of their former employer, then execute the robbery impeccably, right in the
centre of the City of London.  The bags of loot are filled, but, at the
pictures, crime seldom pays....That this film has been reviewed as a comedy demonstrates, once again, that
British and American are two cultures disguised by a common language.  The
humour here, of that characteristically British sardonic kind, is incidental
to a drama of frustration, disappointment and inadequacy.  The humour is
just the way the British speak.  The clever and low key "raid" on the army training centre is finely done. 
So much so that it overshadows the robbery itself and therefore slightly
unbalances the action.This is one of those films, craftsmanlike and enjoyable, yet not desperately
exciting, that finds its greatest value precisely in being a period piece. 
The League of Gentleman is a fascinating social document.  Made in 1959, it
catches the moment in British history when, as its Empire dissolved, the
social infrastructure that supported it and that had made Colonel Hyde what
he had been, also disintegrated.  This aspect could almost have been
deliberate, explaining the very long opening sequence (another unbalancing
factor) that introduces us to the seven main characters.  There are
shockingly frank moments: the honourable man with the overtly promiscuous
wife; the gigolo; the religious fraudster (or pervert - the message is
obscured); another of the heroes an "other man", a homosexual; the pressure
of life in a small house with a loud television set.  So, too, the
casualness with which machine guns are used in a robbery by men trained in
the code of gentlemen.  The dull and seedy presentation of Hyde's home and
base, large but far from grand, is further evidence of the decline of his
class.  So, too, a robbery that was intended as a hymn to the effectiveness
of military planning, brought to naught by one stupid mistake and a small
boy.Yet this is not a sententious film, their is no preaching, none of that
British nostalgia for the old ways, but almost a respect for the robbers and
a recognition that life had to become more ruthless as a stiff society began
to flex.  How it was elsewhere, I do not know, but this watchable film will
show anyone what was happening in Britain just before the Sixties began to
swing.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1297715/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>starvin4megravy</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Well ... if your name is Major Hyde, you thank Her Majesty very much,
and plan a simply spiffing wheeze!Hyde, played to gruff perfection by Jack Hawkins, is supremely proud of
his meticulous planning skills, learned and sharpened in a 25 year
military career. When ignominiously pensioned off, he puts these
strengths to good use in plotting a daring million-pound robbery.Now, as an ex-military man, Hyde is aware that his "operation" cannot
succeed without putting together a squad of the very best experts;
displaying the kind of guile and ruthlessness that earned him his lofty
rank, he also knows that it's rather handy if one's selected team has
nothing much to lose.The film opens by introducing us to Hyde's hand-picked candidates in
turn - each receiving a mysterious invitation to lunch, stapled to one
half of a crisp new fiver none of them can afford to ignore. A jolly
rum bunch they are, too - we see a wonderfully gloomy panorama of
post-war London, scattered with promiscuous wives (Nanette Newman, no
less), doomed businesses, loveless marriages and good times going
rapidly bad. Enough to make a fellow wish he were back in the army -
especially should he happen to be a bogus priest, an "odd man out" or
simply a chap who always makes the same mistake twice ...Was late-1950s Britain, in fact, a land fit for heroes? Does pride come
before a fall? Or does crime, perhaps just this once, pay?Place yourself in the hands of these esteemed Gentlemen for a
wonderfully enjoyable caper movie, and find out for yourself. The story
fairly crackles along, and particularly to be relished is the interplay
between Hawkins and the always-watchable Nigel "Old Darling" Patrick. Notwithstanding Oliver Reed's jarringly unfunny cameo, this is easily
one of my top ten movies. May we be spared for ever the Hollywood or (worse?) the BritFilm
re-make!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1642840/comments</url><from>from (e.g. London, England)</from><name>nickname1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This 1959 (or 1960) film shares the same title as the 1990's comedy about
weird northern folk, but is a far more savage satire of decay in the
establishment.A redundant Colonel recruits a unit of marginally more corrupted
subordinate
Army officers, to stage an American Style heist, based on a US pulp
fiction
novel. Very few of the characters would initially be associated with the
establishment. Their past failings include treason, war-crimes and
negligence resulting in deaths.Jack Hawkins (Colonel Hyde) knits the characters together over the course
of
the film.  By reinventing a form of army discipline the characters appear
to
rediscover their aplomb.The actual robbery is almost incidental, occupying ~ 10% of the
film.My real fascination was with the development and interaction of the
characters. Even 40 years on their callousness is at times shocking and
the
'Blame Ireland' example of scapegoating still resonates, especially in the
context of the characters' personal failures in other theatres of the
ex-empire.The film is nearly 2 hours long, but seemed much shorter. Post war film of
the City of London (and elsewhere) before 60s redevelopment is a
bonus.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1809307/comments</url><from>from Royal Berkshire, UK</from><name> (georgethetee@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie is an involving, intriguing and ultimately poignant heist
thriller.  Since the advent of a comedy TV show which took it's name, the TV
Guides have taken to describing this film as a 'comedy'. Obviously they've
never watched it - the moral is, get your movie info from IMDB, not a
rubbish newspaper or magazine TV Guide.The movie's premise is good - a disenchanted ex-army officer dispairs of
success on 'civvy street' so decides to organize his own squad of former
soldiers and pull off a military operation with a difference - they will rob
a bank.  This film was the inspiration to the real-life Great Train Robbery,
which involved a 20-man gang stealing £3,500,000 in 1963.Characterization is good and believable; as with all British movies of the
era, there is an excrutiating tendency to overly-ingenious rhetoric, one
wonders sometimes how they think of such witty remarks.  That aside, it's
thoroughly convincing. The film code of the day of course required that no
film could ever show a criminal benefiting from his crime, but instead of
the usual tiresome accidental spilling of the booty out of a train/car/plane
window, we have a more realistic, and indeed somewhat sad
resolution.Yes, it is a bit old now, but if you can hang-up your hang-ups about that,
you may find yourself pleasantly surprised.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1988746/comments</url><from>from Godalming, England</from><name>Phil (aypee)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This film apparently inspired the British comic troupe "The League Of
Gentlemen".I'm not surprised.The film was directed by the popularly underrated Basil Dearden and
starred
the equally underrated Jack Hawkins.What a shame they're so underrated!The cast were brilliantly chosen and the plot is inspired. It would
probably
be impossible to remake this film acceptably well - it is very much of
it's
time.Nigel Patrick will tell you, old darling, that you should watch this film
with warmth and humour - the way it was made.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0102677/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>John Seal</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Jack Hawkins, excellent as always, heads a superb cast in this marvelously
entertaining look at the moral decay of Britain's upper classes in the
post-war period. Some of Britain's greatest film talent was at work on this
project, including screenwriter Bryan Forbes, director Basil Dearden, and
cinematographer Arthur Ibbetson. If you want to see the granddaddy of caper
films, this is it. It's also your chance to see Oliver Reed playing a
flaming queen: believe it or not!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1355003/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>sol-</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a heist film that really rises above the ante of its genre, due
to the motivations behind the main characters. The characters are all
former army officers, who were dismissed due to misconduct on their
behalf, with the exception of the mastermind behind the robbery, who
brings them all together. His name is Hyde, and he was halfway to
becoming a full colonel before the army forced him into retirement. He
is separated from his wife, and without army life, he has nothing left
to do. So for the fun of it, rather than the money, he organises a
heist.The acting in the film is superb. The expressions that Jack Hawkins
uses when playing Hyde signify that he is in it for the thrills rather
than the loot. He looks on with joy, rather than stern, careful
consideration, as he and his men organise everything that they need to
do. He is in power again, since he is the head of the operation, and
since he knows that everyone who he picks will want to go along. All of
his men are not only crooks but ones with financial problems. And as
the only one with plenty of money and no criminal record, he enjoys the
idea that he can duck out at any time.The supporting actors also show in the end that they are enjoying their
work. While initially in it for the money, the return to army
regulations - by which Hyde runs the operation - excites them. Nigel
Patrick and Bryan Forbes are particularly good as the more suave
members of the heist team. One problem though is that we never get to
know the characters really well. They are defined by what we are told
about them, rather than their actions, particularly with the Padre,
played by Roger Livesey. A former quartermaster, he shows excitement at
being able to take up the job again, but he is given very limited
screen time, and his involvement with acts unbefiting a priest is oft
mentioned, but his personality rarely shows anything more than that he
is just another one of the men.I find it rather odd that the film is marketed as a comedy. There is
one section, when they raid the army, that is bouncing with humorous
touches, and Gerald Harper, as a nervous army captain, gives off an
excellent performance. The rest of the film though only has the
slightest edge of humour, from Hyde badmouthing his wife to a rather
awkwardly inserted cameo by Oliver Reed as a homosexual performer. The
comedy is not important though, and the plot is intriguing enough as it
is, but it does make the raiding the army section stand out, as it jars
the film's mood and style.If not flawless, it is still a very well made film. The rousing, grand
music score is excellent, not just because it fits well over the
action, but because it is sort of a parody of the scores of old war
movies. The film looks great in black and white, and some of the
sequences are very well shot. One example that stands out in memory is
a shot where the camera goes through the walls of two different rooms,
crabbing to the right, and swooping a little bit, almost like a person
trying to not bump into a vase as he passes through a wall. The visual
look of the film and the audio are just excellent, and well suited to
the interesting screenplay.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5231034/comments</url><from/><name>loza-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
A pretty believable bunch of characters come together at the invitation
of their old regimental colonel to preform a daring blank raid he once
read in a novel.Some pretty good performances by Hawkins, Bird, Kieron Moore, etc. Some
pretty memorable scenes too: the inside of the police van at the end.
The meeting in the hall with the ballet rehearsals going on upstairs,
the grease-coated frying pan in Jack Hawkins's house.The sudden introduction of the affable silly ass character at the end
is a stroke of genius.Watch out for Oliver Reed as the camp ballet dancer. He might have been
unknown at the time; he might have only had one line: but he was still
a STAR!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0643062/comments</url><from>from Virginia Beach</from><name>tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Spoilers herein.I don't know when this genre first appeared -- the `team heist' -- but this
surely is the film that defined it as a genre.A team of distinct characters. A genius planner. An incredibly elaborate
plan. Lots of group dynamics, including humorous episodes. Some twists. As
with a few other British genre-definers, this is as nearly perfect as one
can get until the ending.And as with many genres, the ending is malleable. The most recent I have
seen is the `Oceans' Eleven' remake, where the crooks get
away.Attenborough's acting style is never so plain as here. One can see his
theatrical approach to film -- it stretches through all his directing
through to `Passage to India.'Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 4: Worth watching. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0108786/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Tom May (joycean_chap@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

An enjoyable effort in the Ealing vein, more specifically in the black comic
vein of "Kind Hearts and Coronets" or "The Naked Truth", with fairly
upper-class individuals gleefully straying from the straight and narrow. It
is a mark of the film's whimsical success that one is made to sympathise
with what is basically a gang of upper-class soldiers resorting to
criminality. The wit, camaraderie and very subtle pathos of the ex-soldiers
is very well worked - adrift as they are in peacetime, the planned heist
provides some scope for their talents.Most of the actors make their mark in some way - Roger Livesey, Nigel
Patrick and particularly Jack Hawkins, are wonderful. Robert Coote is
wonderfully spot-on in his late appearance as Brigadier Bunny Warren.The script is finely crafted and while not up to the standard of "Kind
Hearts...", this is quite a fine little film, always mildly winning in some
way throughout its duration.
Rating:- ****/*****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0108786/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Tom May (joycean_chap@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

An enjoyable effort in the Ealing vein, more specifically in the black comic
vein of "Kind Hearts and Coronets" or "The Naked Truth", with fairly
upper-class individuals gleefully straying from the straight and narrow. It
is a mark of the film's whimsical success that one is made to sympathise
with what is basically a gang of upper-class soldiers resorting to
criminality. The wit, camaraderie and very subtle pathos of the ex-soldiers
is very well worked - adrift as they are in peacetime, the planned heist
provides some scope for their talents.Most of the actors make their mark in some way - Roger Livesey, Nigel
Patrick and particularly Jack Hawkins, are wonderful. Robert Coote is
wonderfully spot-on in his late appearance as Brigadier Bunny Warren.The script is finely crafted and while not up to the standard of "Kind
Hearts...", this is quite a fine little film, always mildly winning in some
way throughout its duration.
Rating:- ****/*****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0108786/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Tom May (joycean_chap@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sean-axmaker/</url><url>http://parallax-view.org/2011/02/03/basil-deardens-london-underground/ /m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1958206</url><name>Sean Axmaker</name><from>Parallax View</from></reviewer><comment>... a sturdy and meticulous heist film built on an appreciation of teamwork, camaraderie and hard work: a professional work about professionals working.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/douglas-pratt/</url><url>/m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1335652</url><name>Douglas Pratt</name><from>DVDLaser</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment> Fans who love nothing better than to get lost in the intricate plans of a complex robbery will be in heaven.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1255572</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Entertaining heist film. Watch for a quick bit from Oliver Reed.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/leagueofgentlemen.htm /m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=24654</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>The League of Gentlemen is a fine example of old-fashioned English humor: droll and civil.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1427438</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/80235.html /m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1480757</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/mem/movies/review.html?title1=&amp;title2=League%20of%20Gentlemen%2C%20The%20%28Movie%29&amp;reviewer=BOSLEY%20CROWTHER&amp;v_id=28667&amp;pdate=19610125&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1389120</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=105231 /m/1034384-league_of_gentlemen/comments.php?reviewid=1148315</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>