<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Les bonnes femmes</original_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Claude Chabrol</director><producer>Paris Film</producer><producer>Panitalia</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Ginette, Rita, Jacqueline and Jane try to find fulfillment and love in their lives. Rita has a fiancé whose family is obsessed with social distinction; Jane has a boy-friend in the army...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Bernadette Lafont</actor><actor>Clotilde Joano</actor><actor>Stéphane Audran</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
We first encounter the women in the story late one night as they step
out from a night club. Jane and Jacqueline are going home on foot. Two
men jump into a white Cadillac and keep following them as one of them,
Marcel, wants the two women to go to another night spot. We also see a
somewhat mysterious man who gets on his motorcycle and tails the car
and the women. This shadowy figure will remain a mystery until the last
minutes of the film, yet, he will be connected with the women in ways
that are not immediately known to the viewer.Jane, is a bold woman who seems not to be a stranger to sexual
pleasures. Jacqueline, on the other hand has a romantic nature. After
spending some time with Albert and Marcel in the cabaret, Jacqueline is
bored and goes home. Jane, who goes with the men to their apartment,
returns home in time to change to go to work. Ginette and Rita are the
other friends, and co-workers, in a small appliance store. Louise, the
cashier, is more or less in charge of the girls and she identifies
herself with Jacqueline, who in spite of having come in late for her
first day at the shop, seems to be a kindred soul.Ginette, who shares a flat with Jane, is a woman living a double life.
She works in the shop, but is a singer who works in a theater that has
variety acts. She doesn't want to let the other girls know what she
does. Rita, the fourth friend, is engaged to a fatuous man who appears
to be embarrassed to be introducing her to his parents.These four women appear to be living boring lives. Their only escape is
the night life all around them. Jacqueline, who is approached by a
delivery man at the shop for a date, refuses him. At the same time,
that night, at a swimming pool she is saved from Marcel and Albert's
horseplay with her in the water by the motorcyclist. This meeting leads
to an unexpected turn of events for Jacqueline, who doesn't have a clue
as to what is going to happen to her. A hint to Jacqueline's fate is
comes later in the film, as she asks Louise about a "fetish" she
carries with her.This film was not seen widely in this country after it was released. In
fact, it remains an enigma why it was not discovered by film fans, the
way it deserved. Claude Chabrol, the director, who also contributed to
the screen play, gives the story a great staging. It's one of his works
that most closely resembled a product of the New Wave movement as it
took the cameras into the streets to show a slice of the lives of these
four women that are so closely connected.There is a lot to admire in the way Mr. Chabrol designed this film. He
got great support by the amazing cinematography of Henri Decae, one of
the best in the French cinema. Even after more than forty years after
this film made its debut, it has much to be admired in what Chabrol was
able to accomplish with it. The character studies of these women living
ordinary lives reveals the director knew them well.Clothilde Joano makes an impression as Jacqueline. Bernadette Lafont
does wonders with her Jane. Stephane Audran, who went to star in a lot
of films of her then husband, is quite effective as Ginette. Lucile
Saint-Simon, is Rita, who had a short role. Ave Nimchi, has some good
moments as Louise, the cashier. Jean-Louis Maury and Albert Dinan are
seen as Marcel and Albert. Mario David plays Albert Lapierre, the
motorcyclist.This film is a "must see" for all Claude Chabrol's fans
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3923531/comments</url><from>from Ottawa, On</from><name>Nikolaus Maack</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"This is where we're going," the film says, over and over again. It
whispers it. "We're going over here."I laugh. The film is joking. It must be. Yes, yes, I understand. Very
funny.The film is not joking. It's taking us exactly where it promises to
take us. And when we get there, it's not so much surprising that we've
arrived there, as that I refused to believe the film. And yet, here we
are, as promised.*** And here's where I spoil the movie for people who haven't seen it.
***Did anyone else get the impression that the women in this film aren't
naive at all? They're not oblivious to the dangers of men. Quite the
opposite -- they're drawn to it. The reason the murder at the end is so
shocking is that it's not shocking in the slightest. From the very
beginning, you know Jacqueline is going to die. You know Albert is
going to kill her. The movie tells you this, over and over again. An
assortment of scenes point at this fact.The music tells you. Various scenes discussing danger then we cut to Mr
Motorcycle and his maniacal face. The scene with the lion. Throughout
the entire picture, we know.And what's stranger still -- Jacqueline knows she's going to die. At
least, that's the impression I am left with. Louise, the older woman
with the bloody handkerchief, soaked with the blood of a man who killed
many women. When she was a girl, she found that killer attractive. She
rushed forward to the guillotine, soaked her hanky in the killer's
gore, and keeps it as a "fetish", in her purse, forever.Only Louise and Jacqueline are portrayed as romantics. They're serious.
They're smarter than the other women. They know more about desire. But
the film implies all women are like this -- just some of them recognize
it.The scene that is most disturbing is the woman dancing at the end,
staring straight into the camera. Her expression says, "I know exactly
what I'm doing. I know exactly what men are. I am no victim. I would
gladly die for love."At least that's what I saw in this film -- an uncomfortable, creepy,
disturbing concept that true love only happens when one person totally
consumes (or kills) another.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1547997/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>youwinjack</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A friend of mine - a film scholar - once said that this film shouldn't
work but it does. He was absolutely right. I cannot think of one good
reason why this film should be as good as it is. The tone is
observational, like many films of the "New Wave," but it lacks the
frenetic energy of Godard, or the jaded lyricism of Truffaut. The tone
of the film changes drastically at several points, and in any other
film this would become a big turn off. But a strand of sincere honesty
about the characters and their emotions holds the film together,
stronger than any formality.Let the film take you where it wants you to go, and the experience is
wonderful.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1826769/comments</url><from/><name>snucker</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

i liked this film.  it has an ambigious quality about it, almost
paradoxical.  it has a feel of a documentary and is observational in
nature,
yet there is a obvious message or view taken by chabrol and the women in
this film.  they're doomed objects of desire for men.  the women have this
elusive quality about them, they're beautiful and somewhat misguided about
the men in thier lives.  they seem unattainable, yet vulnerable to a
ominous
unspoken danger that awaits them that is denoted by the music.  there's
this creepy yet mysterious sounding music that runs through the film when
the female characters roam through the streets.  and for some reason, all
the men in this movie are misogynist jerks!  they disrespect these women
and
believe they're entitled to them. yet, these women flirt with them and
passively resist them for most of the film.  chabrol lovingly shoots these
women and has affection for them, but also sadness at their romantic
naivety
about the men in their lives that will bring them doom.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0805697/comments</url><from>from dublin, ireland</from><name>Alice Liddel (-darragh@excite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Chabrol's career is often seen as moving from the naturalism of his early
films to the extreme stylisation of his great mid-period.  It's not as
simple as that, but in 'Les Bonnes Femmes', Chabrol achieves a balance
between the two that he has rarely equalled.  The story of four shopgirls,
their work and social lives, has all the plotless and poignant banality of
realism, while the closing third, with its move from Paris to the country,
its seducer-cum-motorbike-riding-devil (reg. no.: 666) talking about the
Creator, as little schoolboys called Balthasar pass by; and its closing
vision of Hell/Purgatory bespeak a more Cocteau-like world of mythology and
religion.  But there is Cocteau too in the framing of Jacqueline in the shop
window, while Chabrol's filming of treacherous nature later on is uncommonly
vivid.  Although 'Bonnes' is his least typical film, it is also his most
lovable, and seems to get richer with the years.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Claude Chabrol made a film before Les bonnes femmes, Les Cousins, which
is what made him known as part of the French New Wave (he preceded
Truffaut and Godard by a year). But viewing Les bonnes femmes before
seeing Les Cousins, I almost feel like this is a director's first film,
for a director like Chabrol, as it shows a lot of his concerns as a
filmmaker: an observational stance with women, their sexuality and
their distance from the opposite sex, the mundane in a bourgeois life,
and the Hitchcock angle of danger and the unknown. It's also in line
with the other Nouvelle Vague films in the sense that the filmmaker has
broken out of any ties to a studio or sets, and everything is out in
the streets or on location in places like nightclubs and music halls
and swimming pools, and usually with hand-held cameras and (seeming)
improvisation with the actors. This is a gritty, on-the-streets Chabrol
one isn't used to from seeing films like This Man Must Die and The
Butcher.And yet I don't know if I can say it's as great as the big early films
of the period like The 400 Blows and Breathless. Chabrol's film does
carry, I'm sure, some personal weight. And he's interested in these
girls, their casual life and goings-on, and how so easily one of them
can be lured by a mysterious man in a mustache who follows them around
in a motorcycle. But it's such a loosely structured film- barely a
plot, even less, if you can imagine, than Breathless- that it takes a
moment for us to realize something is going on. Which perhaps is part
of Chabrol's angle here: like Fellini's film I Vitelloni, we're just
watching these four girls in their everyday occurrences, going to a
zoo, going to a nightclub and hooking up with two (obnoxious)
strangers, going to a music gall where one of the girls is secretly
singing and doesn't want to go on for fear of embarrassment of the
others seeing her, and just walking around. Or, as well, the
complacency of working at a TV store where no one comes in.We are drawn in to these girls and who they are, however limited
they're really shown as full characters (more-so Chabrol is interested,
I think, in these girls as 'types' possibly, or in looking at them in a
semi-documentary perspective). And metaphor is used from time to time;
I'm sure the visit to the zoo, and Chabrol's carefully timed and
composed reaction shots of the animals in the cages, is deliberate as
to the girls' own self-prison of 20-something frivolity. And there's
also the matter, again, of the motorcycle guy, who somehow charms this
girl. Actually not somehow, as in this sort of Nouvelle Vague
film-world it's precisely the kind of guy a girl would fall for, even
one seemingly so uptight as the one he goes after. Seeing how this
plays out between them can go one of two ways, and how Chabrol shows it
in the last fifteen minutes is totally masterful. There's a sense of
the inevitable, but he keeps us uncertain as an audience, which is
good. I'm glad I couldn't quite see where the ending would go, though
when it came it made sense and was satisfying (it even raised up the
worth of the film overall a full notch).But a masterpiece? Probably not. It's like a breezy fling through a
Parisian quarter, on the dark streets and cool nights with beautiful
girls and not-so-beautiful but flirty men, and it has some wonderful
moments. It just doesn't add up completely into something that makes
you want to shake your friend up and say "You MUST watch this!" like
400 Blows, or even The Butcher.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9988355/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>zoeyneo</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I own this DVD and have seen it many times. Fitting for its genre, it
is intense, dark, sensual, and poetic. It's like riding in a car that
you know is going dangerously fast but you're enjoying it too much to
ask the driver to slow down. Although the storyline is quite simple,
indeed not much happens to the girls before the ending climax, their
fervor and hunger for life is palpable. It is the mood more than the
events in the film that make its strong impact. Jane is mesmerizing,
charming and complex, at different times a little girl, a rebellious
teenager, or a flirtatious temptress. On the opposite side, Jaqueline
is an utter mystery, implying a nature both extremely intelligent and
extremely troubled. The men in the film are basically facades, people
there to react to the girls, or to lead them into situations where they
must react, or ***spoiler coming*** claim them as their victim. But
even in the case of the murder, it is less about the killer and more
about Jaqueline allowing herself to be taken by him emotionally, and
what came to her as a result. Les Bonnes Femmes is a story open to much
interpretation, rich with clues and artistic integrity.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3161232/comments</url><from>from Eel Pie Island</from><name>rowmorg</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Just to prove that portraying males as all-negative is nothing new, see
Les Bonnes Femmes: the employer with wandering hands, the drippy
suitor, his bossy Dad, the snobbish fiancé, the lurking psycho, the
bad-jokes bully-boy and his fatty hanger-on, the absent lad on national
service. Every one of them is no good. And yet the four shop-assistants
are no better, they exist only for the men. Whatever the fellows throw
at them, they're up for it. It's a chilling worldview, with a cynical
twist at the end, (plus a tacked-on coda that seems to be from another
movie). Along the way, there's some really hammy acting from the girls'
employer that clashes badly with the realistic mood, and some longueurs
as the girls get bored at work and we get bored right along with them.
The young Bernadette Lafont is a joy, but she fades out in Reel Three
when the lovely Clotilde Joano comes to the fore. Whatever happened to
Clotilde? Her subsequent career was undistinguished, and she died at
age 42. This is mostly a watchable slice of Paris life from the late
50s, although the Algerians who caused so much mayhem only a few years
later are nowhere to be seen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0442119/comments</url><from>from Upstate New York</from><name>Red-125</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Les bonnes femmes (1960), directed by Claude Chabrol, was shown in the
U.S. with the title The Good Time Girls. The film depicts the lives of
four Parisian shopgirls. (I guess now we would call them retail clerks,
but in 1960 they were shopgirls.) The women are all looking for romance, and they do no one any harm, but
their lives are not filled with the glamor and excitement that the term
"good time girls" evokes. They go to music halls, public swimming
pools, and the zoo. They let men cruising by in cars pick them up. They
stay out all night and stumble half asleep into work the next day. One
of them is pursued and courted by a mysterious motorcyclist.All four young women are attractive. Three of them went on to have
important careers in the French cinema--Bernadette Lafont , Clotilde
Joano, and Stéphane Audran. (Audran later married director Chabrol,)Although Chabrol is a superb director, and the actors are talented, the
film just didn't work for me. The young women had vacant lives, they
had no aspirations or dreams of something different, and they had a
naiveté that was sad rather than charming. This is a movie worth seeing if you have a particular interest in the
French New Wave, in Claude Chabrol, or in the young actors who were not
yet major stars. I wouldn't seek it out as casual viewing. We saw it on
VHS, and it worked well on the small screen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from Encino</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The 'overacting of the boss' mentioned in the previous comment is totally
intentional! Chabrol is playing around with genres here, exaggerating for
effect. He straddles the fence between comedy and tragedy for the entire
film, veering this way and that whenever it serves his purpose: to paint an
allegory of absurd modern existence through the soul of modern young
females. The surreal modern music at the beginning clues you in, and the
awesome final scene with the empty, tragic eyes of the girl finding her
only
happiness when a man asks her to dance brings it all together beautifully.
Man! what a great film! I didn't want to leave the theater after watching
it
twice in a row, but I was too tired. As disappointing as Chabrol's films
have been to me over the years, this one was a jackhammer of a surprise.
The
Hitchcock elements are there but they don't dominate and straitjacket
everything else. On a level with "Breathless," "Shoot the Piano Player,"
yet
completely unlike either of them, this film defines the "New Wave"
aesthetic, which to this day, some forty years later provides a standard
for
Tarantino types to strive for. Films like these can only be directed by
masters who have the nerve and audacity to bend genres to their whim and
speak their ultimate truth through the nature of the medium itself.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from Encino</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The 'overacting of the boss' mentioned in the previous comment is totally
intentional! Chabrol is playing around with genres here, exaggerating for
effect. He straddles the fence between comedy and tragedy for the entire
film, veering this way and that whenever it serves his purpose: to paint an
allegory of absurd modern existence through the soul of modern young
females. The surreal modern music at the beginning clues you in, and the
awesome final scene with the empty, tragic eyes of the girl finding her
only
happiness when a man asks her to dance brings it all together beautifully.
Man! what a great film! I didn't want to leave the theater after watching
it
twice in a row, but I was too tired. As disappointing as Chabrol's films
have been to me over the years, this one was a jackhammer of a surprise.
The
Hitchcock elements are there but they don't dominate and straitjacket
everything else. On a level with "Breathless," "Shoot the Piano Player,"
yet
completely unlike either of them, this film defines the "New Wave"
aesthetic, which to this day, some forty years later provides a standard
for
Tarantino types to strive for. Films like these can only be directed by
masters who have the nerve and audacity to bend genres to their whim and
speak their ultimate truth through the nature of the medium itself.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from Encino</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>