<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Gasu ningen dai ichigo</original_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Ishirô Honda</director><producer>Toho Company</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
A librarian is subject to a scientific experiment which goes wrong and transforms him into 'The Human Vapour'...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Tatsuya Mihashi</actor><actor>Kaoru Yachigusa</actor><actor>Yoshio Tsuchiya</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1325465/comments</url><from>from Pittsburgh, PA</from><name>Hessian499</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

The title may suggest a bad sci-fi movie, but this film is actually quite
dramatic and well produced. Part mystery and part science fiction, it is
well acted and the special effects of the man turning into the vapor is
expertly done. The segments of the Vapor traveling about the city and
telling of his experiences are a high point of the movie, and explain what
it would feel like to actually be a cloud of gas. The central story, of
the
attraction between the Vapor and the dancer, is well written and
effectively
developed on screen. This is an example of a Japanese science fiction film
that often gets overshadowed by the likes of Godzilla and Rodan, but is
quite good on its own merits. Watch it if you get the chance!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0390624/comments</url><from>from Antwerp, Belgium</from><name>KuRt-33 (kurtaerden@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

"At first I could not understand the terror in Dr Sano's eyes. Then I
knew:
I had been transformed into something terrifying. Something repellant...."Maybe not necessarily repellant, but the sight of someone's body
vaporizing
till he becomes invisible... well, I've seen prettier things.The second feature of this double bill is The Human Vapor and was directed
by Ishirô Honda, the man who also gave you Gojira (a.k.a. Godzilla) and
countless sequels with the rubber-suited monster.
Honda worked for Toho Studios who, apart from Godzilla and Samurai films,
made four movies about humans who could change the state of their bodies.
The Human Vapor, released in 1960, was the last of these four
films.No monster in Gasu Ningen Daiichigo (1960) or The Human Vapor, but a
librarian who agrees to be a test subject for a scientific study. Little
did
librarian Mizuno know the other test subjects had died during the test. He
discovers he can vaporize his body and kills the professor (by
asphyxiation).
Mizuno might want to turn his back to humanity, but he's also madly in
love
with a beautiful dancer who's been saving for her comeback performance. He
decides to help her by robbing the bank. Maybe not such a bad idea, but
it's
a crime my friendly neighbourhood officer tells me.
The police pursue his trail (he might be invisible, but his car isn't) to
the place where Vapor-Man abandons his car. Smart move, if it weren't for
the fact that there's only one house nearby. That's where She lives and
when
She suddenly appears to have enough money for her comeback and can't/won't
reveal any information on her maecenas, she's arrested.This makes Mizuno so angry he becomes even madder than he was before (it
seems like the test affected both his visibility and his sanity) and he
wants revenge for the imprisonment of his beloved dancer. More banks are
robbed and more people get killed.
That's as far as I'll go because, who knows, you might want to check this
movie out and as the saying goes, there's no crying over spilt endings.
The
movie is very decent and a remarkable ending.The bad news is The Human Vapor isn't just the American title of the film,
it's also the American version and sadly a lot went lost in the
translation.First and foremost, Gasu Ningen Daiichigo was a mystery and in The Human
Vapor the anti-hero tells his story in a long flashback. This would've
been
only half so horrible if the narration had been more interesting and if it
hadn't replaced the dialogue in quite a lot of scenes (which leaves us
with
the "I told him and then he said" effect). The jerking effect of the
re-edited version is also not really a plus side.
Even the soundtrack was changed. If you can't remember why the soundtrack
seems so familiar, you must have seen The Fly (1958).Crappy editing, dialogue and Americanized dubbing (Japanese characters are
less credible with sentences like "Ah, go peddle your papers!") aside,
nothing can keep us from knowing this is a terrific movie. Even if it
falls
from 10/10 to 8/10, an eight is still better than most things you're
subjected to. The Human Vapor still has enormous amounts of tragedy and
pathos, an anti-hero who can't control his limitless powers and an
enchanting but painful love story. What it lacks as a crime story, it wins
as a character study. It's fascinating to see how Mizuno evolves from a
friendly lab rat into a psychotic megalomaniac.
We also wonder about the role of the dancer Fujichiyo.Does she know where the money came from? Does she also love Mizuno? Her
personality is quite different from the other female character in the
film,
the reporter Kyoko. Traditional versus modern.Mizuno's acts are beyond redemption, but still you feel some sort of
sympathy for the Human Vapor and most of that comes from his unconditional
love for Fujichiyo. (Not unlike the Phantom of the Opera's love for
Christine Daaé.)
True, the special effects are minimal, but who needs special effects in a
sci-fi movie when you've got a story?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>INFOFREAKO</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The Human Vapour shows that there was a lot more to 60s Japanese science
fiction movies than Godzilla and Mothra. While the version I watched was
badly dubbed and transferred to video, it still stood out as superior
b-grade sci-fi. The FX may be quite primitive but the concept was handled
well, the acting more than adequate, and the central relationship between
the Vapour and the Kabuki dancer was suprisingly touching. Try and track
this one down if you're looking for something different.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0437174/comments</url><from>from Sacramento, California USA</from><name>OllieSuave-007</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Somber screenplay writer Takeshi Kimura at his best. Probably the most
sad and dramatic of all Toho sci-fi epics. Here, we have the title
character, who is a librarian in his "real" life willing to go through
all depths to please his lover, the Kabuki dancer, even if it means
causing casualties and wreaking havoc. Caught in the mix is a policeman
and a reporter, out to catch the rampaging "Vapor Man" before he causes
any more harm. I usually prefer more light-heated pieces, like the
works of writer Shinichi Sekizawa. Though this is a really dark film,
which could use more lighter themes, it is good story-telling, and the
end would astound you. A good thriller even by today's standards, and a
suitable addition to any Toho movie fans.Grade B
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"The Human Vapor" is a more somber effort from the legendary Toho
studio, best known for producing the Godzilla series. It proves there's
a lot more to Japanese b-film-making than just giant lizards. Despite
the laughable dubbing and occasionally bizarre reediting of the film,
it works in the end with a climax more depressing than expected. The
lead performances by Yoshio Tsuchiya and Kaoru Yachigusa are both
sympathetic and accomplished (once again, looking past the dubbing).
And just like "Matango" and "The Manster", this has a surreal and
dreamlike atmosphere that makes the proceedings all the more
compelling. There's no scientific explanation for any of the events,
which certainly works in this movie's favor. Its not really science
fiction, but more of a fantasy. "The Human Vapor" is rather difficult
to come across, but if you do manage to track it down, by all means
watch it. Its not perfect, but surprisingly emotional and with more
depth than most of these films. (6/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2721657/comments</url><from>from brooklyn NY</from><name>sol1218</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
**SPOILERS** Washing out, due to contracting tuberculosis, as a top
test pilot for the Japanese Air Force Mizuno suffered a nervous
breakdown that landed him into a Tokyo sanitarium. It was at the
sanitarium that Mizuno met and fell in love with fellow inmate the
famous and equally destroyed,mentally, Fujichiyo who at one time was
Japans greatest dancer.Declared by the sanitarium doctors as being fully recovered and Let out
in the outside world Mizuno ends up working as a librarian. In his work
in the library Mizuno is approached by a Dr. Sano who's been a great
fan of his when he was flying planes for the air force. Dr.Sano telling
Mizuno that he can get him back into shape to fly planes has Mizuno
agree to him being experimented on by the doc. Dr. Sano ends up putting
Mizuno into this state of suspended animation for 10 days. when he
comes out of it he's told by a scared and nervous Dr.Sano, who seemed
surprised that he survived that it, the experiment was a total failure.
Finding out from Dr. Sano that there has been other experiments by him,
where all those involved died, and with him now being the only survivor
an outrage Mizuno suddenly turns into a cloud of gas and attacks Dr.
Sano engulfing and suffocating him to death.Mizuno realizing that he has achieved, due to the late Dr. Sano's
experiments, super powers goes on a crime spree vaporizing into a fine
mist and then robbing Toyko banks and killing a number of bank
employees and police by asphyxiating them. Mizuno then makes his escape
by fading away into thin air. Mizuno's, who's later dubbed by the
police and newspapers as the Vapor Man, crimes are not for his own
greed and misguided revenge against the world but to get enough money
to have his love dancer Fujichiyo be able to get back to dancing by
having a public recital of her talents. Mizuno wants Fujichiyo to
become Japans premier dancer and the crazed Mizumo doesn't care how
many banks he'll rob and people kill, with his new found powers, in
order to do it.A really strange and at the same time touching love story, if you can
excuse or overlook the bank robberies and killings involved, of a man
,Mizuno, gone insane with love for the woman ,Fujichiyo, he loves.
Who's a sweet caring and conscientious person not having the heart to
betray and turn him in to the police. For the crimes that he committed
for her which she had no knowledge of.Arrested and thrown in jail Fujichiyo refuses to tell the police who
her lover, who's committing all these vapor crimes, is. It's Mizuro
himself who comes forward to tell the shocked public that he's the
notorious Vapor Man and vaporizes himself going on to both rob a bank
and kill a bank guard to prove it.The police are helpless to stop the Vapor Man and finally have to
release Fujichiyo. That leads to her, and the Vapor Man, renting out a
Tokyo theater to give her dance recital like the Vapor Man always
demanded. At the recital a bunch of drunken yahoos crash the place
thinking that it's some kind of strip show. This has the attending
Mizuno, whom these jerks don't realize, the Vapor Man tell them to get
the hell out of the theater and get their money back at ticket counter.
This makes the theater crashers even more rowdy and in return Mizuno
vaporizes attacking them and driving the entire bunch out in panic.The Tokyo police in a last desperate move, when the theater is emptied
out with only Mizuno and Fujichiyo being in it, pump gas into the place
in oder to knock out the Vapor Man and take him captive. Fujichiyo
realizing what's happening and wanting to stop once and for all the
death and destruction of her lover Mizuno pulls out a lighter. As she
and Mizuno embrace, after her very successful dance number, Fujichiyo
flicks her bic and blows the entire theater up killing herself in the
process. Mizuno unfortunately survives and now has to live the rest of
his life, which is forever, with the guilt of not only the many people
he killed and victimized as the Vapor Man. He also has to live with the
fact that he drove his one and only love Fujichiyo to kill herself
because of the crimes that he committed for her.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2065295/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bok602</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The Human Vapor is a surprisingly worthwhile change from the usual
round of men in rubber suit Japanese horror films. It is an effective
cross between The Invisible Man and Phantom of the Opera with just a
dash of Hangover Square.The kabuki sequences were very well staged. The musical score is lush,
heartfelt and at times quite moving. It has tremendous production
values and some good, sincere acting. It is marred only by over-abundant comic relief and choppy editing
(although the latter is almost certainly the fault of it's American
distributors).It is also hampered by its current un-availability in any medium. My
sad, long out of print, much-abused VHS rental copy is close to 20
years old and appears to have been made from a very worn out, badly
scratched and faded TV print.Does anyone know of a restored print? A letter-boxed version? A DVD????
All in all though, it is worth watching....really.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7991675/comments</url><from>from Portland, OR, United States</from><name>flapdoodle64</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Ishiro Honda is best known for his Kaiju films, which is rather a shame
because he made many other fine and creative movies. This scifi/horror
mix a good example of one of his more intimate, darker and multilayered
creations and is to be recommended to old-school fans of these genres.The scifi/monster elements in this film are a variation on H G Wells'
Invisible Man, although our protagonist/villain is more complicated and
more tragic than Wells'. The protagonist in this film uses his
superhuman powers to rob banks and finance the come-back of a Noh
dancer who is recovering after a recent stay in a sanitarium, and there
are a number of scenes with her dancing and wearing traditional
garb...these scenes are in contrast to the eponymous protagonist, who
wears a business suit and participates the sordid business of crime.
Yet our protagonist loves the dancer and the dancer appears to at least
partially reciprocate.In the hands of a lessor director, this material could become boring
and maudlin, yet this film is moody, suspenseful, and there is a
haunting sense of impending tragedy that is maintained throughout. '
Certainly our protagonist has become unhinged, and there are hints that
the Noh dancer may also have been at the sanitarium for mental health
problems. So then, this film presents us with mix of madness, art and
science fiction that is interesting on several levels...not the least
of which is the love story between a fragile artist and a homicidal
lunatic.In a strange way, this film has many of the same themes as the 2010
pseudo art house flick, 'Black Swann,' yet is more deft and has more
depth.The FX, while clearly belonging to the world of 1960, are creative and
tell the story, and contribute to the coherent mood of this film. The
American version has been edited badly, but still conveys the major
meanings. I recommend this to fans of old-school horror and scifi, and
to those studying the work of Ishiro Honda.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2754429/comments</url><from>from Austin, TX</from><name>Carmen Gonzalez</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Wow! Caught this on Trio as part of the Quentin Tarrantino Week. Although
I
love giant monsters, It was cool to see Honda do a movie without them.
What
I most admire about his movies are the quirky/funky artificial looking art
direction. It's top notch here. If you like 60's go-go stuff with a twist,
you will dig this crazy movie!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1451567/comments</url><from>from Madrid, Spain</from><name>Lindsay Mark Moxham (elmoxham)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw this film only once, in Sydney around 1977, and was called "Vapour
Man". I have looked for it sporadically since due to the soundtrack. The
theme is as haunting as Bernard Herrman or Elmer Bernstein and was
implanted
into my mind until a couple of years ago when I was unable to recall it.
Japanese cinema and TV series like "The Samurai" and "Phantom Agents" were
almost as influential on Australian kids of the time as American and
British
products and luck we were indeed. Really heartbreaking
theme.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1451567/comments</url><from>from Madrid, Spain</from><name>Lindsay Mark Moxham (elmoxham)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw this film only once, in Sydney around 1977, and was called "Vapour
Man". I have looked for it sporadically since due to the soundtrack. The
theme is as haunting as Bernard Herrman or Elmer Bernstein and was
implanted
into my mind until a couple of years ago when I was unable to recall it.
Japanese cinema and TV series like "The Samurai" and "Phantom Agents" were
almost as influential on Australian kids of the time as American and
British
products and luck we were indeed. Really heartbreaking
theme.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1451567/comments</url><from>from Madrid, Spain</from><name>Lindsay Mark Moxham (elmoxham)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/human_vapor/comments.php?reviewid=1417366</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-r-leeper/</url><url>/m/human_vapor/articles/236676// /m/human_vapor/comments.php?reviewid=236676</url><name>Mark R. Leeper</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
6/10
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>