<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Doctor in Love</original_title><imdb_rating>5.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Ralph Thomas</director><producer>Rank Organisation, The</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
Doctors Burke and Hare leave the confines of St Swithins for the world of general practice, stopping off on the way as patients at the Foulness Anti-cold Unit...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Michael Craig</actor><actor>James Robertson Justice</actor><actor>Virginia Maskell</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1304731/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>RitaRisque</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

No Dirk Bogarde?! Well this Doctor installment is doomed before it even
begins. No Sparrow, no Joy - Burke and Hare are adequate, but it's not the
same calibre as the last films. Though James Robertson Justice is
wonderful,
his Lancelot Spratt seems to get better as they go along. His performance
in
this, as he is about to go under the knife himself, is indescribable, and
not to be missed. Priceless comedy! Almost makes up for the silliness of
the
rest. Another great moment is when he and two young strippers (who have
luckily not yet stripped!) burst through a screen showing a great ape and
into an auditorium, full of stately old gentleman; who all seem pretty
pleased at the disturbance. 6/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0978359/comments</url><from>from Stockton, England</from><name>david-697</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This, the third sequel to Doctor In The House, Doctor In Love, sees the
temporary absence of  Dirk Bogarde's Simon Sparrow (he returned for Doctor
In Distress); instead chief medical duties fall to Michael Craig's Doctor
Hare, an equally young and inexperienced young Doctor.In truth, though Craig is a likeable leading man, his role is largely
dispensable as the main centre of interest is, (for me anyway) the
wonderful
comic cast gathered for this movie.  You can't help feeling sorry for
Craig,
as he shares scenes with such great scene-stealers as Leslie Philips (in
his
`Doctor' debut as the aptly named Doctor Burke), Irene Handle, Joan Sims
and
Liz Fraser. The last two (together with Philips) were at the time
mainstays
of the `Carry On' films and help bring a touch of sauce to the
proceedings.Of course, no mention of the cast could ignore the great James Robinson
Justice, once again playing Sir Lancelot Spratt.  Though off-screen for
quite awhile, his scenes are the most memorable of the movie and, as
always,
he never fails to make me laugh out loud.Doctor In Love isn't perfect, for example I found it hard to sit through
the
song that plays through the opening credits without feeling slightly
embarrassed (it's awful!).  Also you can't fail to notice that there
doesn't
seem to be any plot to speak of, more a collection of sketches (there is a
romantic interest, played by the very lovely Virginia Maskell of Only Two
Can Play fame, but she's introduced pretty late in the movie).  But these
are minor flaws.It's true that compared to contemporary comedies, Doctor In Love is
obviously from a more innocent age, but if your willing to give it a try,
it
remains perfect Sunday afternoon viewing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0415113/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Oct (wjphillips@clara.co.uk)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

By 1960 Dirk Bogarde deemed himself too old and serious to continue as
Simon Sparrow in the series of medical romps from Richard Gordon's
novels. Instead Michael Craig, a former extra who looked similar though
more thickset, was top-billed in "Doctor in Love". That he and his
partner Leslie Phillips should be named Drs Burke and Hare says
everything about a string of mildly farcical incidents, laced with
lavender-blue dialogue poised on the brink of permissiveness, which
kept the pot boiling for Betty Box and Ralph Thomas.In truth Craig also is too serious for the part. He had just co-written
the anti-trade union screenplay for "The Angry Silence" and seems
preoccupied, letting the ebullient Phillips treat him as a stooge in
almost every joint scene. There are other dampeners. Lancelot Spratt
(James Robertson Justice) is no longer hovering continuously in the
background as the ogre of the medical school-- the doctors are taking
first steps in general practice-- and the love interests are Carole
Lesley (aka Maureen Rippingdale) and Virginia Maskell, both of whom
could have featured in a "Pinewood Babylon" sleaze book as future
suicides. Poor Miss Maskell, Craig's love interest, had the saddest
starlet's eyes since Gail Russell.Never mind: there's Joan Sims and Liz Fraser as randy strippers to
enliven the earlier sequence in a cold-cure laboratory, plus Irene
Handl playing against her usual charlady type as a very butch, tweedy
female professor. More camp comes from the inimitable Reggie Beckwith
as factotum in Craig's surgery-- "I'm a sort of Universal Aunt, you
might say"-- and he puts on a fine drunk scene in a police station. For
star spotters there is a glimpse of "Last of the Summer Wine"'s Peter
Sallis, unbilled, as a patient. Other Britflick support favourites such
as chinless wonder Nicholas Phipps, Esma Cannon and John Le Mesurier
pop up. One episode embroiling Spratt in a police raid on a strip club next to
a lecture hall is notably well staged. The film rolls briskly along:
Thomas, never more than a journeyman, was rarely less than competent at
storytelling, a skill sadly missed these days. Three years later he
persuaded Bogarde to come back for a final crack at Sparrow in "Doctor
in Distress".

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2863432/comments</url><from>from Lincoln England</from><name>Stephen Bailey (diana@bailey6770.fsnet.co.uk)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

More medical antics in the classic "doctor" series. What plot there is
concerns 2 young doctors (Burke &amp; Hare) attempting to drag a quaint old
medical practice into the 20th century. Doctor In Love does lose
something without Dirk Bogarde, but the wonderful James Robertson
Justice "I shall do nothing of the kind!" makes up for it. There were
excellent small roles for Joan Sims as a stripper and John le meseruir
(I bet I've spelled that wrong?) as an officious doctor who dares to
tangle with "Sir Lancelot". The scene where Robertson Justice
accidentally finds himself in a strip club and then breaks through into
the medical conference next door accompanied by strippers and a gorilla
is hilarious. It's a sad coincidence that Virginia Maskell (the new
young doctor) and Carole Lesley (Dr Burke's girlfriend) both ended
their own lives a few years later. They were both beautiful. Doctor In
Love isn't the best in the series (Michael Craig is NO Bogarde) but
it's certainly worth watching and made me laugh quite a lot.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0885866/comments</url><from>from Ile-de-France / Paris Region, France</from><name>Nicholas Rhodes</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I have all these Doctors' films on DVD ! They make for good watching
although they are not as funny as the Carry-ons ! As for today's
comedies, they are non-existent compared to these. My favorite
character HAS to be James Robertson Justice as Sir Lancelot Spratt !
He's even funnier in "Doctor in Clover". Its a shame that his
appearances in these films always seem to be fleeting and over in a
jiffy ! I did not know the actor Michael Craig and found his
performance the least interesting ! On the other hand I have always
loved Leslie Philips and he never fails to give a hilarious performance
with his ill-planned sexual adventures ! He's much funnier than Dirk
Bogarde who played in some of the initial "Doctor" films. Fenella
Fielding is a character on her own as is Nicholas Parsons ! There are
some lovely ladies in the film, including Virginia Maskell and I was
most distressed to discover that two of the most beautiful actually
committed suicide in real life during the years following the film.
Very "early sixties", this film also serves as a documentary record of
what is henceforth turning into our distant past .............
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7058339/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>petersj-2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The plot such as it is is so light in substance but I must say the
movie is pleasant. I very much doubt people who never sat in a cinema
watching these movies will enjoy it, for me its a lovely memory.Not
much happens in the movie and you might smile but don't expect any big
laughs.James Robertson Justice as always walks away with the film. I
sometimes find Leslie Philips a little annoying and although very sauve
he comes across as rather sleezy. Joan Sims has a delightful, all too
brief cameo. Its funny how the world has changed, these days the guys
in this movie would be up on sexual harrassement charges. Its perfectly
normal in this movie for doctors to flirt with nurses. This was a much
kinder time. THese days men cant flirt and its safer to be gay. Dirk is
not there but Michael Craig is a pleasant leading man. He is very good
looking and he gives a gentle performance. Its all very sweet,
restrained and under played. Craig came to Australia for the JCW
management to star in a few west end comedies and later residing here
and became much loved as a TV performer in shows such as Medical
Centre"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Things are all change at the hospital when Sir Lancelot Spratt
announces his retirement. However Dr Hare is distracted already
suffering with illness before being placed on the ward with jaundice.
It is here where he meets nurse Sally Nightingale and woes her away
from Dr Hinxman – only to have her do a runner with some other man,
ditching the both of them. With Hare broken hearted, Dr Burke suggests
they head away for a few weeks and decide upon an experimental medical
commune testing cold remedies. Of course the fact that two of the other
'guinea pigs' are exotic dancers don't help the two horny doctors abide
by the rules, bringing them into conflict with the strict and
professional staff.With this being the fourth film in the Doctor series, nobody can really
complain that they don't know what they are getting themselves into.
And so it is with the usual mix of flirtatious humour and shambolic
plot that this film opens and continues in that fashion. Early on the
film establishes that this is about the usual antics of the
women-loving doctors, and that's about the lot of the plot. It very
much depends on your sense of humour – if you like fairly basic, Carry
On type of stuff then you should at least be amused by this. This is
not to say that it is inventive or witty, because it isn't and most of
it just treads along a fairly ordinary road without really making more
than the most basic of efforts. Like another reviewer noted, it makes
for a good 'wet Sunday afternoon' film because it is nicely dated and
has a comic air to it even if it has few actual laughs. If anything the
actual plot (involving Hare) bogs down the film, while the other more
bawdry scenes at least have a sense of fun.In this film in the series Dirk Bogarde stepped out and was replaced
temporarily by Michael Craig; suffice to say he cannot really compare
with the usual lead. He does his best but he doesn't make a mark – a
fact not helped by the collection of very famous British actors that
surround him. The usual old cad, Leslie Phillips steals his scenes with
his usual performance. Likewise Justice does well with only limited
screen time. Sims and Fraser are instantly recognisable but I was never
really convinced they were strippers – if they were then they were
certainly the least erotic 'erotic dancers' that I've ever seen! The
support cast shows the omnipresent John Le Mesurier in a minor role as
well as appearances for Nicholas Parsons, Beckwith and a cameo for a
young looking Peter Sallis (of Summer Wine and Wallace &amp; Gromit fame).Overall this is a fairly broad film that never really hits the mark.
The plot mixes a story about a sick boy with a load of detached sexual
humour and neither of them really got me into the film. Laughs are
pretty thin on the ground even if it does have a broadly comic air to
it. The cast is impressive on paper but it is only a couple of them
that manage to make an impact without much to work with in terms of
material (Phillips steals scenes with his usual personae more than
scripted lines). The downside of this cast is that the supposed 'lead'
is totally lost and becomes the least interesting of all those
involved.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Things are all change at the hospital when Sir Lancelot Spratt
announces his retirement. However Dr Hare is distracted already
suffering with illness before being placed on the ward with jaundice.
It is here where he meets nurse Sally Nightingale and woes her away
from Dr Hinxman – only to have her do a runner with some other man,
ditching the both of them. With Hare broken hearted, Dr Burke suggests
they head away for a few weeks and decide upon an experimental medical
commune testing cold remedies. Of course the fact that two of the other
'guinea pigs' are exotic dancers don't help the two horny doctors abide
by the rules, bringing them into conflict with the strict and
professional staff.With this being the fourth film in the Doctor series, nobody can really
complain that they don't know what they are getting themselves into.
And so it is with the usual mix of flirtatious humour and shambolic
plot that this film opens and continues in that fashion. Early on the
film establishes that this is about the usual antics of the
women-loving doctors, and that's about the lot of the plot. It very
much depends on your sense of humour – if you like fairly basic, Carry
On type of stuff then you should at least be amused by this. This is
not to say that it is inventive or witty, because it isn't and most of
it just treads along a fairly ordinary road without really making more
than the most basic of efforts. Like another reviewer noted, it makes
for a good 'wet Sunday afternoon' film because it is nicely dated and
has a comic air to it even if it has few actual laughs. If anything the
actual plot (involving Hare) bogs down the film, while the other more
bawdry scenes at least have a sense of fun.In this film in the series Dirk Bogarde stepped out and was replaced
temporarily by Michael Craig; suffice to say he cannot really compare
with the usual lead. He does his best but he doesn't make a mark – a
fact not helped by the collection of very famous British actors that
surround him. The usual old cad, Leslie Phillips steals his scenes with
his usual performance. Likewise Justice does well with only limited
screen time. Sims and Fraser are instantly recognisable but I was never
really convinced they were strippers – if they were then they were
certainly the least erotic 'erotic dancers' that I've ever seen! The
support cast shows the omnipresent John Le Mesurier in a minor role as
well as appearances for Nicholas Parsons, Beckwith and a cameo for a
young looking Peter Sallis (of Summer Wine and Wallace &amp; Gromit fame).Overall this is a fairly broad film that never really hits the mark.
The plot mixes a story about a sick boy with a load of detached sexual
humour and neither of them really got me into the film. Laughs are
pretty thin on the ground even if it does have a broadly comic air to
it. The cast is impressive on paper but it is only a couple of them
that manage to make an impact without much to work with in terms of
material (Phillips steals scenes with his usual personae more than
scripted lines). The downside of this cast is that the supposed 'lead'
is totally lost and becomes the least interesting of all those
involved.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>