<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ski Troop Attack</original_title><imdb_rating>2.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Roger Corman</director><genre>Action</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
An American patrol has to cross behind enemy lines by skis in order to blow up an important railroad bridge...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Michael Forest</actor><actor>Frank Wolff</actor><actor>Wally Campo</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4627372/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (winner55)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Another moment when the low rating for a film at IMDb doesn't make
sense.A tight, taut, tough-minded little war movie, this is Corman on a low
budget at his absolute best. Most of Cormans problems in his early
years derived from a lack of knowing where to cut scenes and move on,
and a fatal dependence on the performances of inadequate actors. The
editing here is very crisp - even the use of documentary footage is
handled well, although its grain admittedly never meshes with that of
the film as a whole. And while the acting remains unexceptional, it
never becomes excessive in an amateurish way, and it fits with the
overall gritty realism of the picture.Corman benefits here from a surprisingly strong story and script that
leaves its thematic issues open to interpretation. The issues receive
temporary resolution by the end the hard way - through combat, as is
most often the case in a war.I'm not saying this is a forgotten masterpiece, but it is certainly
worth a view, and at 63 minutes hardly threatens to tax one's patience.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Ski Troop Attack (1960) *** (out of 4) Ultra low-budget Roger Corman flick about a group of Americans (on
skis) stuck behind German lines. The film is certainly very silly but
at the same time it remains very interesting throughout. Considering
Corman only took two weeks shooting this thing it's rather amazing at
how good it came out looking. There's some very nice cinematography and
the locations are great. There's really nothing overly special about
this film but it does contain some nice action and a rather unique
story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
During the war in Europe a small band of allied soldiers moving through
enemy territory on skis tries to steer clear of the enemy as they try
to complete their mission of blowing up a train bridge.By the numbers Roger Corman film notable for its winter setting. Its
also is a minor legend in that the attacking German army was played by
the local high school ski team. Its an entertaining little film that
over comes its been there and done that feel simply because of its snow
bound setting. Frankly I remember the film simple because of the snow.
Worth seeing simply for that reason.6 out of 10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0020737/comments</url><from>from Hee-Haw country</from><name>Zontar-2 (anacanapanastan@webtv.net)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
In a snowy German forest, stranded GI's observe stock WWII footage and
evade the enemy. Aside from some testy exchanges with a frosty
fraulein, the stick-figure characters bark war-comic banalities (though
the script's feverish dialogue and structure might have made a swell
comic!). The troop's captain is constantly baited by his smug,
war-happy sargeant. One assumes a showdown will ensue, but the budget
must not have allowed for even modestly choreographed fistcuffs. The
equally anticlimactic finale has the soldiers destroying a bridge
that's "an impossible target from the air." (??!) Bereft of stuntwork
or even a passable master shot, the lucky viewer is left with a jumble
of grimacing-face close-ups and mismatched model train footage that
even Al Adamson would disown. Roger Corman always blames this dog's
shortcomings on production snafus...yet a rookie director employed most
of the same cast,crew, and locations for BEAST FROM HAUNTED CAVE (shot
back-to-back with SKI TROOP), and that schlocker turned out OK.
Corman's apparent strategy was to grab as much footage in as little
time possible and hope to cobble together something watchable in post.
As a result, many scenes look interchangeable, and there's little
dramatic flow. You can make a good cheap war flick with a tiny cast
(BATTLE OF BLOOD ISLAND, '60) and scant action (UNDER FIRE, '57), but
this sucker should be avoided like a cloud of mustard gas.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur28236017/comments</url><from>from New England</from><name>Matthew_Capitano</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A detail of skiing Army Rangers tries to thwart enemy patrols in World
War II Germany.The American bush-wackers foil a few operations before they run out of
food and decide to raid the private home of a beautiful young woman
(Sheila Carol). After they kill her chickens and loot her belongings,
the soldiers shoot her in the back and hit the road.... our heroes.
Sheila also appeared in 'The Incredible Petrified World' (1958), listed
in the opening credits as Sheila Noonan.Directed by Roger Corman, but you wouldn't know it. Not because Corman
is so good and this movie is so bad, but just the opposite. The value
of Corman's work is always a dubious commodity, but this film is
actually pretty good. The soundtrack features an interestingly remote
musical score by Fred Katz.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8977071/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>drystyx</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This is a very average war film. We follow a small group of soldiers on
skis.For low budget, this works very well. Of course, what Corman and others
call low budget is still much more than most of us will ever get our
hands on.We get the story of 5 men, but it soon becomes 4, so 4 characters are
followed through. They stray just slightly off the common stereotypes,
but not much. We have the leader and second in command at some odds,
with a split between the other two men aligning with the two leaders.We get the excitement of the film feud with the two other men as well,
much as minor characters cajole each other in films like "Escape From
Fort Bravo" and "Warpath". This one has the Norhterner-Southerner
reference, and we feel either both will perish, or both will survive.The uniforms and vehicles are different, and the scenery makes this
unique in war films. Not a great film by any stretch, but not close to
the worst.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1877697/comments</url><from/><name> (Dcole@ziplip.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Considering Roger Corman shot this in two weeks, it's an amazingly
good-
looking film.  Quite suspenseful and action-packed with a unique
setting --
the
ski troops we had in the German mountains.  Holds interest all the way
through
and never betrays a low budget.  Very worthwhile.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1877697/comments</url><from/><name> (Dcole@ziplip.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Considering Roger Corman shot this in two weeks, it's an amazingly
good-
looking film.  Quite suspenseful and action-packed with a unique
setting --
the
ski troops we had in the German mountains.  Holds interest all the way
through
and never betrays a low budget.  Very worthwhile.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1877697/comments</url><from/><name> (Dcole@ziplip.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>