<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Crack in the Mirror</original_title><alt_title>Drame dans un miroir</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Richard Fleischer</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Three performers for six roles: this is the game of the film. A melodrama about two love triangles. In the first...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Orson Welles</actor><actor>Juliette Gréco</actor><actor>Bradford Dillman</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1095979/comments</url><from>from New York City, USA</from><name>sdiner82 (sdiner82@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
One of the outstanding--albeit forgotten--films of the early 1960s,
CRACK IN THE MIRROR is a sizzling, frankly sexual, twist-filled drama
with Orson Welles, Juliette Greco and Bradford giving the performances
of their careers. (Make that the "two" performances of their careers!)
In the first story, lower-class lovers Ms. Greco and Dillman are so in
lust that they plan an intricate murder to rid themselves of Ms.
Greco's dull husband, Mr. Welles. Now here's the twist. When they are
put on trial for manslaughter, the distinguished judge is portrayed by
Mr. Welles. And unbeknownst to him, a fellow detective (Mr. Dillman)
and Mr. Welles' wife, the lustrous Ms. Greco, are also in heat and
plotting to do away with him. To say anything more about this highly
original, superbly-acted thriller would do it a disservice. Just SEE
it, and savor three actors at their best (under Richard Fleicher's
brilliant direction) in a film long-overdue for the praise it deserved
some 40 years ago. Rating: ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Although not always successful,"crack in the mirror" which is despised
in France where the action takes place (it's one of the flaws of the
movie: why locate the action there and make the viewer believe he is in
Paris by using some words here and there :"Monsieur Le Président"
"Monsieur Le Commissaire" "Monsieur Le Juge" and so on?)is in need of
reassessment Richard Fleischer was always a brilliant thrillers maker
.Many of his works are models of the genre,and during his whole career
(if we except his dismal last decade ,roughly the years following
"Solyent green" ):"the clay pigeon","trapped" and "follow me quietly"
are early ;"compulsion" and "crack" are middle period ; "The Boston
strangler" and " 10 Rillington Place are late (and perhaps his most
brilliant achievements in the field).I would not place "crack" as high as the others though.But this is a
bizarre intriguing movie,which does not look like any other
movie.Perhaps the two stories told in parallel (and played by the three
same leads,which was not common at the time ) are there to hide the
banal side of the subject (man/woman/lover triangle) ,but there are
stunning flashes of inspiration:the mirrors which appear with the cast
and credits;Lawyer Orson Welles entering the room where the old man was
slain ,where the movie almost verges on the fantasy and horror genre
-not unlike that scene in "follow me quietly " when the dummy comes
alive" ;the same lawyer ,pleaing against the accused woman (and double
crossing his colleague who was his wife's lover),his voice sounding
like God's ;this sequence also mirrors the final of "compulsion" ,his
precedent (and superior effort)where Welles plays a similar part.The
fact that Bradford Dillman appears in both movies too adds to this
strange similarity.Juliette Greco is the only French artist of the whole movie (unless
some -very- supporting actors count);she was primarily a Chanteuse,but
oddly ,when she sings a love songs in front of the nuns/wardens ,she
does not sound at all like she does when she sings in French;a question
of language maybe;or maybe she was dubbed for the part of the working
-class woman for I only recognize her voice when she portrays the
bourgeois lady.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The pale chinky eyed beauty of Juliette Greco had always intrigued me.
This movie of ill-starred love, lust and violence with gripping
courtroom scenes (complete with re-enactment of the crime at the
site)etched itself uncomfortably into my memory. That Greco often stars
as a tragic anti-heroine may have something to do with her origins in
the Languedoc region of France of unhappy history (cf. the Albigensian
persecutions).The handsome young Bradford Dillman is a great foil to Greco's acting
talents. Another under-appreciated actor, he reveals his great depth in
other films such as Circle of Deception, where he portrays a betrayed
secret agent used as a pawn by his superiors and Compulsion, where he
plays a megalomaniacal intellectual out to prove the validity
Nietzche's idea of a "superman" who is privileged to cull the human
race of "unworthies" (based on the play "The Rope" of which Hitchcock
made an earlier execrable film version).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The pale chinky eyed beauty of Juliette Greco had always intrigued me.
This movie of ill-starred love, lust and violence with gripping
courtroom scenes (complete with re-enactment of the crime at the
site)etched itself uncomfortably into my memory. That Greco often stars
as a tragic anti-heroine may have something to do with her origins in
the Languedoc region of France of unhappy history (cf. the Albigensian
persecutions).The handsome young Bradford Dillman is a great foil to Greco's acting
talents. Another under-appreciated actor, he reveals his great depth in
other films such as Circle of Deception, where he portrays a betrayed
secret agent used as a pawn by his superiors and Compulsion, where he
plays a megalomaniacal intellectual out to prove the validity
Nietzche's idea of a "superman" who is privileged to cull the human
race of "unworthies" (based on the play "The Rope" of which Hitchcock
made an earlier execrable film version).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3447130/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Deusvolt</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>