<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>A Breath of Scandal</original_title><alt_title>Un scandale à la cour</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>USA</country><director>Michael Curtiz</director><producer>Titanus</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>You'll Find Yourself in a Whirlpool of Wine, Women and Wonderful Fun!</synopsis><actor>Sophia Loren</actor><actor>Maurice Chevalier</actor><actor>John Gavin</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1318093/comments</url><from>from New York, New York</from><name>trpdean</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Molnar is one of the greatest comic/romantic playwrights Hungary ever
produced - and that is no mean feat since that is that nation's
specialty. For generations, people have loved Carousel (made from
Molnar's play "Liliom"), loved Grace Kelly's last film "The Swan" (from
Molnar's play of that name), loved "The Guardsman" made famous by
Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontanne and many others. I myself delighted in
Maggie Smith and Christopher Plummer in Lily in Love, from yet another
Molnar play.The story has been described on this site as frothy - but in fact so
are most of the great romantic comedies - so are Bringing Up Baby, so
is Roman Holiday, so is Noises Off and My Man Godfrey and The
Philadelphia Story and Libeled Lady and the exquisite Midnight and
Nothing Sacred and all the Doris Day comedies and .... If a comedy is
NOT frothy, there are problems.Although this movie is as lavish as any you'll ever see - absolutely
beautiful, with spectacular scenery and sets, stunning costumes, and a
top notch cast -- including a stupendous Sophia Loren matched by a very
handsome John Gavin - with Isabel Jeans and Maurice Chevalier and
Angela Lansbury largely repeating their wonderful persona from Gigi and
The Reluctant Debutante -- and even has a delightful song (sung by
Maurice Chevalier) and an appealing story -- it's flat.I have to suspect that part of the reason may sadly be the age of those
who created and directed it. The great director Michael Curtiz (himself
Hungarian - and famous for Casablanca and many other great films,
beloved in Hollywood - e.g., read David Niven's book "Bring on Empty
Horses", quoting Curtiz's charming and curious English) -- -- was 76
when he directed this -- and the play was translated by one of the
century's top American playwrights, Sidney Howard, but he was then 69.
And I suspect that they were both sadly past their primes.This is one of the few movies I've ever seen, where I actually thought,
"oh no, the direction is sinking this".The cast is top of the line, but somewhat mistaken. First (and not
fatal), Sophia Loren (just eye-popping in this film) simply does not
look at ALL as if she could be the daughter of Isabel Jeans and Maurice
Chevalier. A combination of accent, complexion, stature, just causes
any viewer to think she must be the product of some liaison by Jeans
with an Italian - yet we are in fact told that her parents have never
strayed. Either Loren should have had Italian actors as parents or
Chevalier and Jeans should have been given a French or English actress
to play their daughter.The bigger problem (as others have mentioned) is the pairing of John
Gavin and Sophia Loren. John Gavin is one of the most intelligent,
handsome and personally charming men in Hollywood - extraordinarily
talented, he has served as the American Ambassador to Mexico (Latin
American studies was his major at Villanova University), and has been
quite wonderful in movies such as Psycho, Midnight Lace, Spartacus and
many others.Unfortunately, in this film, Gavin is stiff - for which I must blame
the direction. Gavin's forthright, quite understated, honorable, appeal
don't work for this film where his character comically goes through
periods of wild lust, despair, anger, frustration with the encrusted
ways of the Empire (much of the play seems clearly to have been
political comment on the Empire's fussy ways) - and Gavin appears
somewhat interested/somewhat annoyed throughout. Offhand, I can't think
of another Gavin attempt at comedy. Gavin seems to be in an a drama
while everyone else is playing comedy.Gene Kelly was made for this picture - notwithstanding the age
difference with Loren (less of a difference than most at the time -
e.g., Cooper-Hepburn in Love in the Afternoon, Stewart-Novak in
BVertigo or Bell Book and Candle, etc.) -- in fact Gene Kelly's even
FROM Pittsburgh like the character!). Kelly is pushy, certain of his
charm (and usually right), lusty, slightly overstated - all perfect for
this character. Rock Hudson would also have been fine (one can easily
imagine his playing it perfectly from his Doris Day comedies). But not
stoic heroic John Gavin. The movie has its quite funny lines of dialogue, but they're rushed or
said under the breath. Again, the direction is the problem. Another problem is that the DVD does not synchronize the voices and
lips very well - so there is a distancing effect throughout the movie.Sadly (given the result), no expense has been spared - spectacular
palaces, amazing public squares, beautiful cabarets, a dizzying array
of stunning costumes - this is one of the most beautiful movies you'll
ever see.This movie should have been another Gigi - it had all the trappings -
Angela Lansbury is wonderful, Chevalier is his strikingly charming
self, Isabel Jeans voice and manner are pitch perfect, and Loren is,
well, almost unimaginably voluptuous and a wonderful comic actress.I enjoyed it, but you'll find yourself thinking "what's the missing
ingredient here?" and I think it's the direction. A pity when so much
was so clearly committed by the studio, actors (obviously on location
for a long time), and crew.Incidentally, it's interesting that only one person posted a review on
this site before 2005 - I suspect that few saw this movie on its
release and so far as I know, it was not released in videocassette
before its release in DVD. The DVD is beautiful - but as I mention, the
lip-synching is slightly off.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0406143/comments</url><from/><name>raskimono</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This bantam weight of a comedy really has not much going for it. It is
so light you could knock it down with a feather. I was so bored I
decided to do some crossword puzzles while listening to the dialog and
missed absolutely. Princess/Royalty Sophia is expelled from the court.
She wants to marry a well to do royal but an indiscretion with an
American visitor, the always bland for extremely good looking John
Gavin - well, he's not really bland: He just speaks in a monotone way
and doesn't vary his technique much - threatens to derail the impending
nuptials. Poor second-billed Maurice Chevalier in a role he would play
many time again as the cantankerous old matchmaker after perfecting it
in Gigi dawdles through the movie singing sweet melodies that move
absolutely no one. Wide Screen cinematography and Technicolor is
exquisite and the costumes worn by Sophia define her figure to goddess
like status. But when in a romantic comedy you are rapturing over the
sets and costumes you know something is wrong. P.S. Poor Michael
Curtiz!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Sophia Loren--in a succession of lavish gowns, her hair tinted a
honey-brown--looks every inch the princess in this surface-pretty
remake of 1929's "His Glorious Night", adapted from Molnar's play
"Olimpia". An American businessman from Pittsburg travels overseas and
falls in love with mercurial royalty from Ruritania; she has breached
protocol by even being seen with this "peasant", so in order to keep
him quiet she agrees to spend a weekend with him in the country. Wily
Maurice Chevalier, as Sophia's father, gets to sing a little and make
eyes at the ladies, and his polished comic timing is a welcome relief
to the empty, useless bantering of the young lovers. As Loren's gallant
guy, stiff John Gavin talks as if he's being dubbed by a ventriloquist
(he has no music in his voice). Sophia doesn't have the witty lines of
the older players (nor that of Angela Lansbury as a competitive
Countess), though she gives more to this puff-piece than most actresses
would have. A few funny lines do lighten the load, yet it's largely
forgettable. ** from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11050066/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>aussiebrisguy</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is a really beautiful and charming film with a wonderful cast.
Sophia Loren has never looked more lovely in the role of Princess
Olympia alongside the handsome John Gavin in the role of Charlie
Foster. Maurice Chevalier is absolutely delightful as Prince Philip as
is his on-screen wife Isabel Jeans in the role of Princess Eugenie. The
settings are simply beautiful in different palaces around Vienna such
as the Belvedere and Schoenbrunn. The Austrian countryside is also
delightful. I loved the music as well. A young Angela Lansbury also
makes an appearance as the devious Countess Lina. It is a lovely and
enchanting film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0492993/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>cinders63</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

A lot of talent was wasted in this uninspired remake of 'His Glorious
Night', based on a Molnar Play. The lovely Sophia Loren is beautiful to
look
at as a spirited Ruritanian princess falling in love with the stereotyped
brash American industrialist. There are no new ideas here. Visually, it's
appealing, but with all the talent involved, it should have been much
better.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5770688/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>Nick Zegarac (movieman-200)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Michael Curtiz's A Breath of Scandal (1960) is a glittering
featherweight romantic comedy set in Austria circa 1907. It stars the
voluptuous Sophia Loren as Olympia, a princess living in exile because
of her scandalous romantic indiscretions. Not that she's suffering any.
There's a huge castle to romp around in, extensive grounds to go riding
on and a quaint little hunting cottage for time spent away from the
family. It's there that Olympia accidentally meets and then attempts to
seduce Charles Foster (John Gavin), the handsome American engineer. She
feeds him a false name, takes off the bottom of his pajamas and even
tries to have him tuck her in bed – shameless! Foster, as it turns out,
has business with Prince Philip (Maurice Chevalier) – Olympia's father.
But before any of this superficiality can develop, Olympia finds that
she has been given a reprieve from the Emperor to move to Vienna and
marry Prince Ruprecht (Carl Hinterman). The cast is rounded out by
Isobel Jeans as Olympia's stuffy, two-faced mother, Princess Eugenia
and Angela Lansbury as Countess Lina, who is given precious little to
do except insinuate that some tidbit of protocol has been breached,
thereby exiling Olympia to her country estate once again.Despite a lavish on-location backdrop, eye popping costumes, some
stunning cinematography and a charming score, the film really doesn't
develop beyond its cloistered romantic trappings. Chemistry between
Gavin and Loren is near zero despite the fact that they are two of the
most gorgeous individuals ever seen on the screen. The one note of
distinction that helps make the whole tired cliché palpable is Maurice
Chevalier's recap of the divine boulevardier he played in 'Gigi' two
years before. He's an elegant, suave and ultimately final note of
aristocratic class in an otherwise deadly dull production.The anamorphic widescreen transfer from Paramount is generally a
blessing. Despite modest color fading and some age related artifacts,
most of the print simply glows with the lavish excesses of Technicolor.
Flesh tones can appear slightly pasty at times, but over all are
accurate. Contrast levels are bang on. Blacks are deep and solid.
Whites are generally clean. The audio is Mono as originally recorded.
Occasionally it seems to bloom or distort, making Loren's lines
inaudible, but overall there is some nice mixing to be had –
particularly when Chevalier warbles the title track in a seedy Can-Can
café. There are NO extras.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur21108884/comments</url><from>from Bolton, Ct./Jersey City, NJ; United States</from><name>eschetic-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Sidney Howard's translation of Ferenc Molnar's celebrated Viennese
trifle, OLYMPIA could manage only 39 performances at Broadway's Empire
Theatre from October 16 of 1928, but at a moment when lavish
middle-European sex comedies were in fashion following the Oscar
winning success of GIGI (15 May 1958), it seemed the nearly ideal
chance to use the very French Maurice Chevalier in another
comic-worldly European role, even if he was to pretend to be a very
Viennese Austrian prince.In point of fact, the film was the brainchild of Italian producer Carlo
Ponti as a vehicle for his wife, Sophia Loren; one of four interesting
films she released that year, starting with the HELLER IN PINK TIGHTS
(if the very German Marlene Dietrich could make a classic Western in
DESTRY RIDES AGAIN, why not the very Italian Sophia?) and ending with
her ultimately Oscar winning performance in LA CIOCIARA (aka TWO
WOMEN). Joining Loren and Chevalier above the title (with the then
always winningly nasty Angela Lansbury below it) was the very American
John Gavin (remember what a 1920's "Arrow Collar Man" was supposed to
look like? Gavin had those looks wed to a personality once reputedly to
have prompted his sister to refer to him as "Mr. Park Bench").This seemingly bizarre international group (hardly the first or last
time such casting would be attempted) requires no more suspension of
disbelief than the basic premise - not so far from real life as many,
unfamiliar with the actual loves and marriages of both Austrian Emperor
Franz Joseph and his one-time heir, Franz Ferdinand or royals of our
own century might suppose - of a royal falling in love (in this case
through a series of misunderstandings) with a commoner.The casting of John Gavin as the commoner however, while not calling
upon him to attempt anything beyond his range of comfort, caused the
greatest variation from the original play in making the love interest
not an Austrian officer but a visiting American businessman. For the
most part the rewrite works, even though credited
adapters/screenwriters Walter Bernstein &amp; Karl Schneider (said to have
had help from Ring Lardner, Jr. - only Molnar and Howard receive screen
credit!) occasionally slips up in knowing only the "history" learned on
stage or screen (the reality of the tragedy at Mayerling he has a
character refer to had little or nothing to do with the romantic
fantasy told in the once popular play and movie). Impeccably set and costumed in the most lavish possible style, the film
offers audiences willing to go along a charming hour and a half
vacation from reality - only ultimately marred by the changing times
and tastes which allow us to question the silly imposed "romantic happy
ending." The film would be far better had the producer and writers had
the courage to allow duty to prevail (as it had, ironically, in the
supposedly more frivolous make believe world of THE PRISONER OF
ZENDA!). Loren herself would be involved in another romantic
turn-of-the-century farce which found a more satisfying resolution to a
similar situation five years later in LADY L - with another American,
Paul Newman!).Still, established Hollywood director Michael Curtiz, nearing the end
of a 50 year career that included everything from CASABLANCA to WHITE
Christmas was a decent choice to pull all these international elements
together, and if the musical element (two very nice songs by minor
names) weren't quite Lerner &amp; Loewe, they were almost exactly what the
romantic trifle called for - especially when Chevalier sings and the
orchestra swells.Far from perfect, but also far from the worst in a very good year for
Carlo Ponti and Sophia Loren. Worth taking a look at if you're in the
mood for romantic illusion from a generally first rate - even
occasionally out of place cast. The supporting players are uniformly
superb.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3727426/comments</url><from>from New Zealand</from><name>selffamily</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
As has been mentioned before, the sets, the scenery and the cast are
beautiful, if mismatched. Sophia Loren is an actress I admire greatly,
and one I think is underrated, having been cast in many roles for her
looks, but this does her no favours. The story is lightweight, frothy
and could have been fun, but the casting is wrong - as someone has
mentioned before, she could hardly have been a child of her parents.
The 'royals' are a conundrum - when is Hollywood going to learn that
royalty don't behave like middle class hosts or hostesses - my shock at
hearing Julie Andrews, as the queen in princess diaries say "I must go,
I have a press conference, I can't keep them waiting" has never abated,
the royals are above all that, and they certainly don't check tables or
supplies when hosting a party. I think the casting was definitely a
problem, a blend of so many nationalities in supposedly a European
country, and while Princess Anne of Great Britain was a great horseman,
I can't see it having been permitted when this film was supposedly
based.(and the commentator was American?) That aside, the constant
irritations of implausibilities and the bad, BAD scripts made this film
mostly unwatchable. The American guy was OK (if forgettable), Sophia
was OK, as were each of the cast individually,but what they had to deal
with was desperate. It's a shame, this could have been highly
enjoyable, as much fun as any lightweight film of that era. But someone
was very lazy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12799576/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>santill28</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This movie has Sophia, at her MOST beautiful, as a princess, playing
with love, and generally causing trouble. One of my favorite scenes is
her shooting out of the castle, at different targets. one of the most
beautiful women ever, in a pretty good role, with fantastic costumes,
in Vienna. What more could you want? Good supporting cast, beautiful
scenery, and reasonable direction. A nice journey into fantasy land,
and, not a bad period piece. The male lead is even pretty good, and, it
has Maurice Chevalier, in a very interesting role as assistant to the
king/prince. It really gets into the different time frames other people
move at, compared to the United States I love this movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11849571/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>krdement</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
but if you want a funny romantic comedy to go along with them - look
out; you are in trouble with this film. I knew this film was going to
be iffy when Sophia Loren was taking pot shots at a bicycling mail
carrier in the opening sequences. Subsequent jokes all center on her
penchant for shooting people and other inanimate objects around the
château where she is in exile. People fear to approach her for fear
they will get shot. NOTE she is apparently trying to shoot people!
Funny, huh?Sophia gets better when she contrives to meet John Gavin. After
Sophia's mildly humorous overnight attempts to seduce Gavin in the
hunting lodge, it's all downhill until the end. After that night,
Sophia receives forgiveness from the emperor, and she is able to return
to Vienna. Her character is transformed from vamp of the nobility to
staid fiancée of the Prussian prince. Thereafter, she and Gavin are
acting in some light, romantic drama, while the rest of the cast
struggles to maintain the comedy. The comedy all centers on the efforts
of Sophia and her parents to hide her indiscreet meeting with Gavin
from the emperor's top "morality cop." That aspect of the film is
occasionally mildly humorous. But whenever the overly- earnest Gavin
and the now staid Sophia intrude, the light drama takes over and the
film goes flat. Unfortunately Gavin was never meant to appear in
comedies; he has no sense of comic timing or delivery.I can recommend this film only for die-hard Sophia fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11849571/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>krdement</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
but if you want a funny romantic comedy to go along with them - look
out; you are in trouble with this film. I knew this film was going to
be iffy when Sophia Loren was taking pot shots at a bicycling mail
carrier in the opening sequences. Subsequent jokes all center on her
penchant for shooting people and other inanimate objects around the
château where she is in exile. People fear to approach her for fear
they will get shot. NOTE she is apparently trying to shoot people!
Funny, huh?Sophia gets better when she contrives to meet John Gavin. After
Sophia's mildly humorous overnight attempts to seduce Gavin in the
hunting lodge, it's all downhill until the end. After that night,
Sophia receives forgiveness from the emperor, and she is able to return
to Vienna. Her character is transformed from vamp of the nobility to
staid fiancée of the Prussian prince. Thereafter, she and Gavin are
acting in some light, romantic drama, while the rest of the cast
struggles to maintain the comedy. The comedy all centers on the efforts
of Sophia and her parents to hide her indiscreet meeting with Gavin
from the emperor's top "morality cop." That aspect of the film is
occasionally mildly humorous. But whenever the overly- earnest Gavin
and the now staid Sophia intrude, the light drama takes over and the
film goes flat. Unfortunately Gavin was never meant to appear in
comedies; he has no sense of comic timing or delivery.I can recommend this film only for die-hard Sophia fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>