<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Das schwarze Schaf</original_title><alt_title>Fais ta valise Sherlock Holmes</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>West Germany</country><director>Helmut Ashley</director><producer>Bavaria Film</producer><producer>Bavaria-Filmkunst</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
Father Brown tries to solve some murders.
</synopsis><actor>Heinz Rühmann</actor><actor>Karl Schönböck</actor><actor>Maria Sebaldt</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8975912/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>martinbijkerk</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Except the characters and the fact that it is a detective story, this
movie has not much to do with the original father Brown. In fact this
is a very German movie which is slightly based on Father Brown storiesIf you see this film without regard of the period/place it was made,
you might find the storyline and acting terrible backdated. However:
this movie fits perfectly in the German 60's era of somewhat fuzzy
detective "thrillers" after stories of Edgar Alan Poe and other English
writers. For that era I find "Das schwarze Schaf" and also the second
father brown movie "Er kann's nicht lassen" better than average.The feeling of those movies (and especially the both Father Brown
films) rely very much on the big-band jazz sound of Martin Boettcher,
who was regularly asked to compose soundtracks during that period
(later, Boettcher would compose the famous Winnetou soundtracks).As conclusion: Do not watch this movie if you want to see the Father
Brown of the stories. Do not watch it if you hate backdated films. For
all others it is an old but nice movie, typically for it's era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6180623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>shoombah</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
But it's entertainment any way. With that classy early cool jazz back
ground Music. It takes place in Ireland. It seems Father brown has to
solve mysteries . When one church member is found dead, With the aid of
his house servant played by Lina Carsten,He stats cluing in only to
discover that it was another member of the church. So the murderer is
fighting the police, in an abandon place. Father brown shows up and
begs him to stop. He ends up getting the murderer with the murders
daughter , he got from a pub.The bishop is peed off with him about the
publicity so he send him to another parish, He also has another problem
. He has a model of a church that he wants to see built of his parish ,
but, no one will finance him cause he keeps moving.He ends s up going
to another Parish, somewhere in Ireland, with a friend live there, who
owns, a motel or hotel. He gets involved in another murderer with a
theatrical troupe, in which Nazi surviving Carl Schonbock is a part of
it. One of the associates , of the troupe , gets murdered. Fritz Rasp s
up ,another survive, As Sir Kingley. Has something to do with the
plot.Then Carl Shonbock gets murdered.Father brown only discovers that
Schonbock had a twin brother. He murdered his other twin. End up
getting killed himself. That solves the problem but makes Fathers
problem worse .He gets kick out of another parish only to get on a ship
of fools for America to solve a problem, Ha! Ha!ha! Ha! Ha! . This
might not be the greatest early 60's classic of Germany,but, until
Turner classic movies and Warner home video change the policies against
showing any more actors that work under Hitler , to punish them, unless
their films a international classic. Father brown is not.If you can
find this it would be a good collectors film.If your like me into the
golden age of German film making 1930 to 1960. The big corporates
dictator are appeasing these political correctionist , who should be in
prisoner kick out of the United states, for their continued wall street
rating. You see a message is being sent out that films made before or
during or right after The Nazis can't make money. You would not even
see this film at wall mart or Fye. 08/13/11 3:45pm
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0202302/comments</url><from>from Amsterdam, The Netherlands</from><name>jan onderwater</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

Maybe I am spoiled by Alec Guiness as G.K Chesterton's creation Father
Brown, but though Heinz Rühmann tries hard he does not make a very
convincing one. Rühmann is not helped much by a so-so script that hardly
captures the atmosphere, let alone the intelligent and complicated plots of
the Chesterton's stories. Emphasis in this adaptation is very much on Father
Brown himself rather than on a good detective story. It takes quite a while
for this Father Brown to find out what solution to the murder case is; the
viewer is way ahead of him.(5/10)Helmut Ashley's direction is only adequate, as is the cast, which all
amounts to a very deathly film.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0202302/comments</url><from>from Amsterdam, The Netherlands</from><name>jan onderwater</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

Maybe I am spoiled by Alec Guiness as G.K Chesterton's creation Father
Brown, but though Heinz Rühmann tries hard he does not make a very
convincing one. Rühmann is not helped much by a so-so script that hardly
captures the atmosphere, let alone the intelligent and complicated plots of
the Chesterton's stories. Emphasis in this adaptation is very much on Father
Brown himself rather than on a good detective story. It takes quite a while
for this Father Brown to find out what solution to the murder case is; the
viewer is way ahead of him.(5/10)Helmut Ashley's direction is only adequate, as is the cast, which all
amounts to a very deathly film.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0202302/comments</url><from>from Amsterdam, The Netherlands</from><name>jan onderwater</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>