<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Neotpravlennoye pismo</original_title><alt_title>La lettre inachevée</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Soviet Union</country><director>Mikhail Kalatozov</director><producer>Mosfilm</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Four geologists are searching for diamonds in the wilderness of Siberia.
</synopsis><actor>Tatyana Samojlova</actor><actor>Yevgeni Urbansky</actor><actor>Innokenti Smoktunovsky</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12073420/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>wheeler-benjamin</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Saw this at Tribeca Film Festival in Spring 2007, and was absolutely
floored. I walked out of the theater afterword amazed at what I'd seen
and thrilled that such an amazing film existed and had been maintained
by a tiny number of appreciators in such excellent quality for so long.The story is not the strong point of the movie. Rather, as with Terence
Malick films, the story is just a starting point for the film, which is
another beast entirely. What shines and carries the film from scene to
scene is the cinematography. I didn't know if this was happened
elsewhere at the time, but I didn't expect to see hand-held camera work
in a 1959 Russian film, let alone the kind of early spinning,
impossibly-filmed shot that appears early in the film. Later, there is
a sequence that makes me long to know how they created the opportunity
to film in such conditions.If you've read this far, you must track down this movie. My
understanding is that Francis Coppola has a California archive maintain
the only copy in the Americas, and that it's usually shown just one a
year.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8719213/comments</url><from/><name>Fpi</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This is a totally excellent man vs. nature drama. An outstandingly
dramatic soundtrack is coupled with some of the most powerful and
unique visuals I've ever seen. If you thought Tarkovsky was a one-shot
in the Soviet Union when it came to beautiful yet haunting images,
you'll definitely think again after this movie. The characters and the
story are perhaps not too well developed, but this somehow adds to the
sense of not being totally in control, which is important here. It's
nothing short of a tragedy that this movie is totally unknown; it would
probably have been a candidate of reaching IMDb's top 50 if it were.
Those looking for unknown classics should hunt this one down at all
costs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2902696/comments</url><from>from NYC</from><name>SONNYK_USA</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Welcome to Siberia, circa 1959 (in perfectly restored, glorious Black
and White).Although this story revolves around four 'pioneers' dropped into a vast
wilderness to search for a rumored vein of diamonds (aka 'the Diamond
Pipe'), the real star of the movie is cinematographer Sergei Urusevsky
("Soy Cuba," "The Cranes Are Flying").Urusevsky is master of composition, dolly shots, and hand-held
photography (when necessary). The way he frames his close-ups of the
actors practically allows the audience to see into their souls.Of course, it helps that he's shooting a top-notch Russian cast,
including actress Tatyana Samojlova ("The Cranes Are Flying") whose
character 'Tanya' is desperate to survive the troubling events that
befall the group. Tanya is also the lone female and commands the
attentions of two men in the rock-sampling group (though one is
unrequited).In addition, the visual elements are underscored aurally by composer
Nikolai Kryukov's ("The Forty-first") evocative score, although he does
amp up the music a bit too much in a couple of scenes. Not unusual for
the time period, so set your appreciation meter back to the 50's and
you won't be as bothered as I was.The title of the film refers to not one but two letters that figure
into the plot. One is a long, personal letter that is referred to in
voice-over from time to time throughout the film, while the other is a
love letter thought to be hidden away until it accidentally comes to
light.The plot is very straightforward so I won't spoil any surprises by
detailing it here, suffice to say that the main attractions of this
film are the artistic cinematography, the strong cast, and the
director's choice to foreshadow plot elements by overlaying fiery
images over his hardcharging trekkers.If you've never seen any films by director Mikhail Kalatozov ("The Red
Tent," "Soy Cuba," "The Cranes Are Flying"), then this one is probably
as accessible as any and with a new restoration to boot, practically a
MUST-SEE.The ending alone is worth the price of admission, so check it out
festival goers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17699578/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>chaos-rampant</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Director Mikhail Kalatozov and his loyal companion, cinematographer
Sergei Urusevsky, two years after the dazzling visual tour-de-force of
THE CRANES ARE FLYING, venture into the frozen wastelands of Siberia
for a harrowing adventure on loss, purpose and redemption. An
expedition of diamond hunters is dropped in the Siberian plateau with
the mission of discovering a rumoured diamond vein. In the course of
the movie diamonds acquire a further symbolic aspect as the purpose in
life. As the expedition is befallen by a raging fire and forced to make
a hazardous escape through burning logs, saving the map which points to
the location of the much sought-after diamonds becomes a struggle to
preserve purpose and meaning in a world that defies it. As the
surviving members of the expedition stagger through the charred
landscape, amidst billows of smoke and torrents of rain, nothing there
to answer their pleas and curses but the echo of their voices, the
world seems indifferent to their plight.The star of the movie however is Urusevsky's cinematography. Kalatozov
fails to harness his tremendous visual talent as he did in THE CRANES
ARE FLYING, certain scenes flailing for attention but lacking the
dramatic pull to justify them, but still someone who likes movies for
their pictorial quality, for the endless possibilities of capturing
images with a photographic lens and moving inside a thridimensional
canvas; such a person will be left in awe and admiration of what
Urusevsky achieves. His rapid tracking shots through branches of trees,
as though the nature conspires to ensnare the protagonists, the amazing
clarity of the closeups, the maize of hand-held shots thrusting the
viewer right there in the middle of the action, the beautiful dutch
angles transforming the geography of the landscape into something that
can only exist for and by the camera.Although the plot has its heart in the right place, much like its
predecessor, it suffers from being too overwrought and from lapsing
into moments of melodrama. Plot threads that are emphasized early on,
like Sergei's unrequisite love and the growing tension with Tanya, are
never really resolved and come to a screeching halt when the fire
erupts. Traditional Soviet values, like the leader's dream of a Diamond
City and the portrayal of civilization as a collective good, don't
chime with my sensibilities. The score is often jarring and obtrusive
but that's 50's cinema for you.Overall this is a visually marvellous film aimed at the cinephiles who
can appreciate such things.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9987799/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Michael Neumann</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This robust survival adventure follows a team of Soviet geologists
stranded in the wilderness of Siberia after a forest fire severs their
communication link with civilization. The opening dedication to
Socialist heroes everywhere and the noble sacrifices made by each
character carry the story dangerously close to propaganda, but the
intensity of their ordeal (through smoke and fire, over snow and ice,
across mountains and tundra) thankfully overwhelms the political
simplicity of the script. Unfortunately, it also overwhelms the initial
hints of tension between each of the four characters (three male, one
female) after the struggle to survive becomes paramount. The sense of
isolation and exposure is numbing; the film was directed with a strong
sense of visual drama (including more than one knockout montage),
showing everything an audience would ever want to know about being lost
in Siberia.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0305809/comments</url><from>from Buenos Aires, Argentina</from><name>Andres Salama</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This relatively unknown 1959 movie from Soviet director Mikhail
Kalatozov is a great adventure film. A guide and three geologists go to
the virgin forests of Central Siberia in order to find diamonds. The
geologists include Sabinin, the older leader, the young, nerdy Andrei
and the pretty Tania, who is Andrei's fiancé. Soon, the guide will
start having strong feelings toward Tania (the movie seems to imply you
should never include a beautiful woman in an otherwise all-male
expedition). Diamonds will be eventually found, but before they can
return to civilization, the team will be engulfed by a vast forest
fire, and they will die one by one. This film may be nothing more than
a paean to muscular Soviet man (and woman), but it is very well done.
The black and white photography is astonishing; there is a particular
scene of the young couple running through the forest at high speed that
is extremely beautiful; at times, the scenes are so realistic one
wonders how they did this (did they actually put the actors next to a
real forest fire?)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A quite ridiculous film about diamond hunters in Siberia by the
extraordinary director/cinematographer team of "I Am Cuba" and "The Cranes
Are Flying." Needless say, the camerawork in the bizarrely surreal and
barren Siberian locations is UNBELIEVABLE (the continuous takes are longer
than any other film in history except for "I Am Cuba")  but the film
itself
is too directly tied to dramatic 'adventure story' conventions to
transcend
into pure poetry like "Cranes" and "Cuba." There is a spectacular scene
shot
with the main actors amidst a raging forest fire and another one shot
during
an ice-storm. Most definitely worth transferring to DVD (there isn't a
true
film fan that wouldn't be flabergasted by the cinematography) but not by
the
same ones (Hen's Tooth) who did such a mediocre job on the transfer of "I
Am Cuba."    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A quite ridiculous film about diamond hunters in Siberia by the
extraordinary director/cinematographer team of "I Am Cuba" and "The Cranes
Are Flying." Needless say, the camerawork in the bizarrely surreal and
barren Siberian locations is UNBELIEVABLE (the continuous takes are longer
than any other film in history except for "I Am Cuba")  but the film
itself
is too directly tied to dramatic 'adventure story' conventions to
transcend
into pure poetry like "Cranes" and "Cuba." There is a spectacular scene
shot
with the main actors amidst a raging forest fire and another one shot
during
an ice-storm. Most definitely worth transferring to DVD (there isn't a
true
film fan that wouldn't be flabergasted by the cinematography) but not by
the
same ones (Hen's Tooth) who did such a mediocre job on the transfer of "I
Am Cuba."    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>