<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Little Shop of Horrors</original_title><alt_title>La petite boutique des horreurs</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Roger Corman</director><producer>Santa Clara Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
A clumsy young man nurtures a plant and discovers that it's a bloodthirsty plant, forcing him to kill to feed it.
</synopsis><actor>Jonathan Haze</actor><actor>Jackie Joseph</actor><actor>Mel Welles</actor><rt_rating>6.2/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>91</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Here's a movie that's gone from cult classic to just plain classic. For
me, it's one of the few "cult classics" I saw when it was released and
then first shown on television. I loved it then, and I love it now.Forget the musical re-make made in the 1980s. It couldn't hold a candle
to the original."Original" is what this is, too. and nowadays, it's great to have it on
DVD in which the audio is clear and the picture pretty sharp.I have always particularly enjoyed the many humorous lines delivered by
Mel Welles, who plays the flower shop owner. He is the real comedian of
the cast, although the plant does quite well as do the two leads played
by Jonathan Haze and Jackie Joseph. The latter two are a little more
subtle in their comedy. All the characters in here are totally whacked, from Haze's
hypochondriac mother to Dick Miller's flower-eating character to the
Jewish mother who always has a dead relative to moan about and to the
dentist and his patient. The latter, of course, is Jack Nicholson,
making his movie debut and looking about 16 years old.In the end, though, what one remembers most is the plant demanding,
over and over, to "Feeeeeed me!!" For that, the plant and the film never fail to make me laugh.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1148823/comments</url><from>from Oz</from><name>Ben_Cheshire</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Funny, sexy black comedy shot by "King of the B's" Roger Corman on a
landmark budget of 27 000 and in landmark time of only 2 days! Its the
funniest movie i've seen from 1960 or before, and between this fact, the
fact that it is black comedy, and the fact that it has the charm  and lack
of pretension of a cheaply made horror movie, its no wonder it has such a
huge cult following.It has the incredibly sexy Jackie Joseph, one of the most buxom lasses i've
ever seen, and many risque scenes, which, along with the jazzy soundtrack
and black humour, give this a much freer feel than any studio picture of the
era, or any picture before. Its humour hasn't aged a bit - and feels quite
modern compared to most humour of the day.As an added curio, this features Jack Nicholson in his first ever appearance
in a feature film (he was in one short film before it), as the nerdy,
masochistic patient who squeals with delight when the dentist is drilling
holes in his mouth and pulling teeth. Though its only a five minute part,
its a great part.The movie is filled with an edgy humour that the remakes (including the
broadway musical, which the 1986 film was based on) are too conservative
for. I thoroughly recommend it to you.Corman went on to become one of the most important producers of the century,
since he provided opportunities to many young filmmakers in the 70's, whose
projects the major studios would never have invested in, and so we would
have been deprived of the talents of Peter Bogdanovich, Francis Ford Coppola
(The Godfather, Apocalypse Now), Martin Scorcese (Taxi Driver, Raging Bull),
Jonathan Demme (Silence of the Lambs) and many others. Corman taught them
how to just go out and make a good movie, and make it cheaply - and his
major qualification to be able to teach them this, in my opinion, is that he
made Little Shop of Horrors.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1725295/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Snake-666</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This charming little B-movie tells the story of Seymour (Jonathon Haze), a
good hearted yet rather slow boy, who works at a flower shop owned by Gravis
Mushnick (Mel Welles). During his spare time Seymour develops a new type of
plant, which he names Audrey Junior after a woman he likes (Jackie Joseph).
Unfortunately this particular plant feeds off human blood and when Seymour
can no longer feed it on his blood, the plant itself forces him to look
elsewhere for food.This delightful horror-comedy was remarkably shot in just two days and was
originally intended as a sequel to director Roger Corman's ‘Bucket of Blood'
(1959). However, ‘The Little Shop of Horrors' stands out in its own right as
a charming and inventive low-budget horror movie. Throughout the movie we
meet a whole variety of weird and wonderful characters including a man who
eats plants (played by Dick Miller who would also work with Jackie Joseph in
‘Gremlins' (1984)), a sadistic dentist, a masochistic dental patient (an
early performance from Jack Nicholson) and a woman who can't go a day
without a family member passing on. Despite (or maybe because) of the
overall absurdity of the movie, ‘The Little Shop of Horrors' manages to be
strangely captivating yet portray an air of darkness in the right
places.Roger Corman directed this movie very well considering his resources and
complimented the fairly tight screenplay written by Charles Griffith. The
special effects were not of that high a standard but, considering the budget
and shooting time one, can hardly have anything negative to say about that.
The appearance of the plant as it grows throughout the movie may not be that
great but overall it takes nothing away from the viewers enjoyment. Perhaps
a little bit more could have been done to represent the plants movement more
realistically but, even so, this is just a minor flaw of an otherwise great
film. The performance from the three main stars was delightful. Though the
acting was hammed up in places the movie never lost its comical charm and
some slightly dramatic performances towards the end helped create an
unsuspected eeriness in the dying moments.Surprisingly ‘The Little Shop of Horrors' was virtually ignored on its
initial release but eventually attained a cult status due to continuous TV
play. For those of you who doubt its classic status ‘The Little Shop of
Horrors' has now spawned a Broadway musical, a high-budget musical remake
and even a Saturday morning children's TV programme. Short (around 68mins)
but very entertaining, I recommend this to fans of quirky horror comedies
and general horror fans alike! The movie features good direction, a well
written story, interesting and likeable characters and some excellent
one-liners. My rating for ‘The Little Shop of Horrors'
8/10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

'The Little Shop Of Horrors' is one of the movies that Roger Corman's
reputation as the "king of the quickies" is founded on. Filmed in two days
on a budget less than Spielberg's dinner money, this is one of the all-time
b-grade camp classics. While the humour is extremely dated the concept is
very black and contemporary. Charles B. Griffith probably deserves as much
credit for this movie as Corman. Writing this, 'A Bucket Of Blood', 'The
Wild Angels' and 'Death Race 2000' has ensured  him movie immortality!
Corman semi-regular Jonathan Haze may not be as fondly remembered as Dick
Miller, but he is well cast as the klutzy Seymour Krelboyne, "father" of
the
blood thirsty exotic plant Audrey, and Mel Welles hams it up as his
tyrannical boss Mushnick. But the show is stolen by Miller as a flower
eating hipster, and an astonishingly fresh faced Jack Nicholson as a
masochistic dental patient (a classic bit!), as much as Audrey herself.
Forget the crappy 80s musical version, stick with this, the real deal. It
is
pretty creaky in places but still a lot of fun!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

If there is ONE movie that made Roger Corman THE king of low-budget
quickies, it's The Little Shop of Horrors!! Practically no budget and shot
in two days this movie still looks very decent now, almost 45 years later.
That's quite an effort if you ask me and it's good to see that this movie
finally received the status of immortal cult movie. This is a very charming little movie, to say the least. The story is simple
but it keeps you alert all the time ( originally, it was meant to be a
sequel to Bucket of Blood ) but it's the characters that steal the show.
Every character that walks through the screen is exceptional and hilarious.
We've got a guy who feeds on flowers, an old lady who loses a family member
every day, a mother with a fetish for diseases, a masochistic undertaker who
visits the dentist and almost has an orgasm ( legendary appearance by Jack
Nicholson in one of his first roles ) and a whole bunch of others...Too much
to list, actually. Jonathan Haze is brilliant as the dumb florist assistant
in love. He created a new type of plant and that causes a whole lot of
trouble...and comedy. Watch Little Shop of Horrors for it's value in cult cinema, maybe. Or
because Roger Corman is an interesting director who deserves to be checked
out. Or you could watch it to see where Jack Nicholson started his
impressive career a long time ago. But - most of all - watch it because it's
an adorable little movie with very funny sequences and a lot of low-budget
charm. The 80's musical version by Frank Oz is also worth a look but it
doesn't come close to this original version.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Mushnick's is a small florists in skid row – a dead end part of town
that everyone knows about but nobody wants to know about. Business is
not great, in fact it is awful – nobody wants to buy flowers when they
can't be sure where their next meal is coming from. However the
cleaning boy has nurtured a strange new plant up from seed and it seems
to be getting interest. When he discovers it needs a few drops of blood
to make it grow Seymour is the toast of the town with his employer very
grateful for the increased revenue the visitors bring. However as it
grows it begins to need more than a few drops and soon he is heading
down a terrible, dark road.Like many viewers I suspect, I came to this film after seeing the
musical remake; as such I assumed that this would be a straight film in
the b-movie genre that Corman is famous for. However I was taken by how
amusing this film was because really this is as much a horror comedy as
the musical is. From Seymour's alcoholic mother to the cop so hard that
even the death of his son is met with a shrug, the whole film is full
of darkly comic touches that drew some nice laughs from me. This comic
approach helps the film because really it is a silly plot and the fact
that the script was tongue-in-cheek meant it was easier to swallow, if
you pardon the choice of words. As a horror it doesn't really work but
it does have a slocky property that Corman films tend to have – not
high quality but low budget, b-movie fun.The cast match the material and all buy into the joke, watching them
also shows that the cast in the musical are really pretty much just
impersonate the actors here. Haze is enjoyably geeky and convinces
throughout. Welles is funny and plays up to his ethnic caricature well.
Corman regular Miller hasn't really got much to do but his face is
always a ruggedly familiar and welcome sight. Joseph is not great but
her performance suits the b-movie genre – likewise Campo and Warford
(who are very funny as Dragnet style cops). Nicholson is pretty funny
and was a curious find in a small cameo.Overall this is not a great film but it is a great b-movie horror.
Never taking itself seriously means that it can be darkly funny and
take the audience along for the ride. To me it is just as funny as the
musical even it is a different type of humour and it is worth checking
out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0278527/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Hitchcoc</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I remember seeing this on a weekly television show called Chiller, when
I was in high school. It was one of those local celebrity things, with
an emcee presiding over whatever horror movies were in the library of
that particular station. I realized quickly, what an offbeat flick this
was. It was utterly hilarious with its moments of masochism, the man
eating plant, Audrey one and two, and all the other things that Seymour
must deal with just to keep going. The plant controls him and it is a
hilarious plant. The black and white neutral staging of the plant is so
much better than the flashiness of the musical (though I do like some
of those songs). The smallness of this film is what helps make it work.
Everyone is a caricature. Jack Nicholson's proudest moment. No wonder
he is such a wack, spending all that time in his formative years with
Roger Corman. The acting works because it is a period piece. No matter
how much we try to reproduce the fifties, it always falls short of just
seeing the fifties. It's like Dragnet without the strange suits and the
slang of the time. It's just more honest because they weren't trying to
reproduce it. I haven't watched this in some time, so I think I'll
leave my computer and sit down and watch it again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0865972/comments</url><from>from Chyby, Poland</from><name>HumanoidOfFlesh</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Roger Corman's "The Little Shop of Horrors" is a perfect example of a
fun,low budget cult film.It's very inventive black comedy that will keep
you
entertained.The film was shot on a budget of $27000 in a period of just
two
days.The direction is amazing,the acting is excellent(Jack Nicholson
really
steals the show as the world's most masochistic patient Wilbur Force)and
there are some wonderful moments.All in all if you like Roger Corman's
cheapies give this one a look.A must-see!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1229491/comments</url><from>from Fayetteville, GA</from><name>Bruce Cook (brucemcook@windstream.net)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
What a movie! It's got (A) an infamous reputation, (B) a cult
following, and (C) the pride of knowing it inspired both an
off-Broadway musical comedy and a big-budget movie musical.All this from a Roger Corman movie that was shot in only two days! It's
all about a nerdy flower store clerk who boosts business in a skid row
store by displaying a talking, meat-eating plant he calls Audrey, Jr.
(named after the girl he loves). The owner of the shop is played by Mel
Welles, who went on to direct "Lady Frankenstein" in Italy. The
screenplay was written by Charles Griffith, who also plays a hold-up
man and provides the voice of the carnivorous plant ("Feed me! I'm
hungry!") He later had to sue to receive credit when the stage play
became a hit.Young Jack Nicholson is a masochist who visits his dentist for fun.
Dick Miller is a customer who buys flowers and eats them. Jonathan Haze
stars as the clerk who serves the hungry plant until it's big enough to
eat the store (although the box of the prerecorded tape shows the
now-famous Nicholson holding the plant).Despite the film's seventy-minute running time, it's crowded with
black-comedy gags; they overlap each like roofing shingles. The first
one is a quick spoof of "Dragnet's" typical kick-off narration, after
which things get increasingly frantic until the plot finally swallows
its own tail and vanishes altogether. Critics initially scoffed at
Corman's "two-day movie", but now they refer to it as "one of Corman's
best efforts". A computer-colorized version is available if you'd like
to see what a carnivorous gilded lily looks like.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

              Roger Corman made this film in 1960 and was able to produce
this film on a shoe string and secured unknown actors like Jack Nicholson
(Wilbur Force), " Chinatown",'74, and Jonathan Haze (Seymour Kreilboind),
"The Terror", '63, with Boris Karloff and once again Jack Nicholson. 
Seymour was fantastic in this film, with his Jewish jokes and on going Punch
Lines throughout the picture.  Jackie Joseph (Audrey Fulguard), "The Split",
'68 played a way out good looking gal trying to please everyone, including
the Hungry PLANT !   Wilbur Force played a great patient in a Dentist office
who just simply LOVED PAIN AND SUFFERING and needed almost every tooth in
his mouth PULLED for the JOY of IT !   If you want to see a very young Jack
Nicholson starting out in pictures, this is a must see film
!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

              Roger Corman made this film in 1960 and was able to produce
this film on a shoe string and secured unknown actors like Jack Nicholson
(Wilbur Force), " Chinatown",'74, and Jonathan Haze (Seymour Kreilboind),
"The Terror", '63, with Boris Karloff and once again Jack Nicholson. 
Seymour was fantastic in this film, with his Jewish jokes and on going Punch
Lines throughout the picture.  Jackie Joseph (Audrey Fulguard), "The Split",
'68 played a way out good looking gal trying to please everyone, including
the Hungry PLANT !   Wilbur Force played a great patient in a Dentist office
who just simply LOVED PAIN AND SUFFERING and needed almost every tooth in
his mouth PULLED for the JOY of IT !   If you want to see a very young Jack
Nicholson starting out in pictures, this is a must see film
!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-biodrowski/</url><url>http://cinefantastiqueonline.com/2010/08/the-little-shop-of-horrors-a-50th-anniversary-celebration-of-1960/ /m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1922560</url><name>Steve Biodrowski</name><from>Cinefantastique</from></reviewer><comment>Whether the film fully lives up to its reputation is another matter, but there is no doubt that The Little Shop of Horrors has earned its small place in cult movie history.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/digitalwatch/rifftraxlsoh.shtml /m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1827755</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>Aside from all this surface nonsense, there's something interesting about the film (perhaps all the emphasis on eating and mouths).</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/alex-sandell/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1126483</url><name>Alex Sandell</name><from>Juicy Cerebellum</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>A campy Corman classic. Drink some beers and have fun with it!</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1445045</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1426999</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/randy-shulman/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1293056</url><name>Randy Shulman</name><from>Metro Weekly (Washington, DC)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rich-cline/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1207058</url><name>Rich Cline</name><from>Shadows on the Wall</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-palermo/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1132773</url><name>Mark Palermo</name><from>Coast (Halifax, Nova Scotia)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=746578</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>/m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=743539</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>eFilmCritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dragan-antulov/</url><url>http://reviews.imdb.com/Reviews/212/21243 /m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=765341</url><name>Dragan Antulov</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
7/10
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117792654.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1757930</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/80562/the_little_shop_of_horrors.html /m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1479877</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=105390 /m/1012514-little_shop_of_horrors/comments.php?reviewid=1193734</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>