<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Trials of Oscar Wilde</original_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Ken Hughes</director><producer>Viceroy Films Ltd.</producer><producer>Warwick Film Productions</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
At the height of his fame (his plays being much celebrated in London in the 1890's), Oscar Wilde...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Peter Finch</actor><actor>Yvonne Mitchell</actor><actor>James Mason</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2955724/comments</url><from>from Tunbridge Wells, England</from><name>James Hitchcock</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
It is sometimes said of London buses that you can wait ages for one and
then two come along at once. So it is with films about Oscar Wilde. The
world waited sixty years for a film about him, and then two came along
in the same year, "The Trials of Oscar Wilde" starring Peter Finch and
"Oscar Wilde" starring Robert Morley. There was, of course, a third
version in the late nineties, "Wilde" starring Stephen Fry.I have never seen the Morley film, but "The Trials" has a lot in common
with "Wilde". Both tell the same story of Wilde's friendship with the
handsome but spoilt young aristocrat Lord Alfred Douglas ("Bosie"), and
of how Wilde was pressured into bringing an ill-advised libel suit
against Bosie's father, the Marquess of Queensberry, who had accused
him of sodomy. As a result of the failure of that lawsuit, Wilde was
arrested, charged with gross indecency and sentenced to two years
imprisonment. Although the two films acknowledge different source
material, "Wilde" is clearly indebted to "The Trials"; the two films
have a number of scenes in common. In places the dialogue is almost
word-for-word the same.There are, however, a number of differences of emphasis. "The Trials",
as its name might suggest, places a greater emphasis on the legal
aspects of Wilde's case, with a greater number of courtroom scenes.
(The word "trials" clearly has two meanings here; it is used both in
its legal sense and in the sense of "sufferings"). It omits, however,
details of Wilde's life in Paris after his release, and places less
emphasis on his relationship with his wife Constance and with his
children.There are some notable acting performances in "The Trials", especially
from James Mason as Queensberry's lawyer Edward Carson and Lionel
Jeffries as the splenetic Marquess himself, a man eaten up with rage
and hatred; I preferred Jeffries to Tom Wilkinson who played this role
in "Wilde". John Fraser, on the other hand, was not as good as Jude Law
as Bosie. Peter Finch was a gifted actor, but I certainly preferred
Fry's interpretation of the title role. Whereas Fry made Wilde witty,
but also kindly, sensitive and generous, Finch's Wilde came across as
too much the dandy, a man who, although capable of impulsive
generosity, often used his wit as a mask to hide his true feelings.
Only towards the end of the film, when he realises that he is in danger
of imprisonment, does he become more emotional.The greatest difference between the two films is that "The Trials" does
not actually admit that Wilde was a homosexual. The impression is given
that he may well have been the victim of unfounded gossip, of a
deliberate conspiracy led by Queensberry to blacken his name and of
perjured evidence given by the prosecution witnesses in court. In
reality, there can be no doubt that Wilde was gay, and the Stephen Fry
version of his life is quite explicit on this point. Queensberry's
accusations were largely true, and in denying them Wilde perjured
himself. It has become a received idea to say that he was the victim of
the ignorant prejudices of the Victorian era and to congratulate
ourselves (rather smugly) that we are today altogether more liberal and
enlightened. This attitude, however, ignores the fact that for all his
talents and his good qualities Wilde had a strongly self-destructive
side to his nature. As some of his lovers were below the age of
consent, if he were living in the first decade of the twenty-first
century rather than the last decade of the nineteenth, he might
actually receive, given contemporary anxieties about paedophilia, a
longer prison term than two years. Even if he avoided a jail sentence
for sex with minors, he would certainly receive one for perjury.It is precisely because "Wilde" is more honest about its subject that
it is the better film. Peter Finch's Wilde is the innocent victim of
other men's villainy; Stephen Fry's Wilde is a tragic hero, a great man
undone by a flaw in his character. Although he is more seriously flawed
than Finch's character, however, he is also more human and lovable, and
his story seems more tragic."The Trials", however, probably went as far as any film could in
dealing with the subject of homosexuality. For many years it had been
taboo in the cinema; a film on this subject would have been unthinkable
in the Britain of, say, 1930, or even 1950. By the early sixties the
moral climate had become slightly more liberal; the influential film
"Victim", which some credit with helping to bring about the
legalisation of homosexual acts between consenting adults, was to come
out in 1961, a year after "The Trials". In 1960, however, homosexuality
was still a criminal offence, and there was a limit to how far it could
be freely discussed in the cinema. Seen in this light, "The Trials",
although in some respects disappointing, can be seen as a brave attempt
to tackle a sensitive topic. 7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0383429/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>raymond-15</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

First of all I like the way the authentic witticisms of Oscar Wilde have
been woven into the script.  His sarcastic and pointed remarks derived from
a keen observation of the morals, pomposity and hypocrisy of late Victorian
England make for intelligent and amusing dialogue between the
characters.Peter Finch (Oscar Wilde) delivers lines with a certain flourish, but I
think he could be even more flamboyant for such a man was Wilde.  John
Fraser plays the moody Bosie as Oscar's current lover with a balanced
mixture of effeminate charm and petulance.  Best acting role is that of
Lionel Jeffreys as the Marquis of Queensbury.  Make no mistake his character
comes through loud and clear.  He gives a remarkable portrayal of his utter
disgust when his 21 year old son Bosie defies him and continues his
relationship with Oscar, a man of middle age and married.  All London is
gossiping and there is much clicking of tongues.
Mrs. Wilde played by beautiful Yvonne Mitchell stands by in utter dismay and
disapproval.The courtroom scene gives Oscar the opportunity to deliver more witty lines
and to describe his inner feelings about true love...interesting because one
is not too sure what he is about to say next.  One gets the feeling that
Oscar has chosen the path of self-destruction...or is he just being his
theatrical self?After he does his prison sentence with hard labour he is supposed to look
tired and ill, but I fail to notice much of a change in his demeanour.  He
should be much paler with a worn down look.  This would command more
sympathy.  Oscar's sexual adventures around the streets of London are not
discussed to any extent nor portrayed in this film.  If they had been given
more prominence we would perhaps have felt justified in agreeing with the
jury's decision.  As it is , the sordid details of his sexual encounters are
played down and because the film is presented in this way we feel rather sad
that this great playwright both loving and generous should suffer so much at
the hands of those who tried to destroy him.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7088558/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jasperisit</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
For a movie made in 1960, The Trials of Oscar Wilde was probably ahead
of its time, given the general taboo against open discussion of
homosexuality in that era. Just guessing, but it also may have gained
the inordinate attention of the censors (such as the old Catholic
Legion of Decency). I first became aware of it only the other day
(Sept. 2005), when it was shown on Turner Classic Movies here in the
USA. I can't believe this was the first time that a relatively tame,
45-year-old movie has been shown on American TV, but I wonder. The
movie tiptoes diplomatically around the "elephant in the room," but its
central theme and the intent of the producers are clear enough for
adult moviegoers. (I can't remember the word "homosexual" being uttered
in the dialogue, but there were unmistakable surrogates, such as
"sodomite.") As a heterosexual, far be it from me to ask this question,
but notwithstanding Peter Finch's fine performance in the lead role,
isn't his movie "Wilde" a more masculine portrayal than the historical
Wilde? Perhaps this was also a necessary concession to the time in
which it was made. In any case, I also offer this spelling nitpick: the
Encyclopaedia Britannica (1982) refers to Wilde's nemesis as the
"Marquess of Queensberry," not "Queensbury." Also, the rules of boxing
are the "Marquess of Queensberry rules."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2321404/comments</url><from>from Some garret in France, surrounded by strange sounds.</from><name>OscarBewildered</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I can't find fault with one thing. My favourite film. I love Wilde, and
this
really just captured everything. I found this accurate, witty and
touching.
The court case in particular moved me, as did Finch's portrayal of the man
himself. This is excellent and has stood the test of time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1275551/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>matthew-58</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

One never quite believes the character given a rather masculine portrayal
by
Peter Finch is involved in a love affair with the young Lord Alfred
Douglas,
but the tentative treatment of the film's subject matter is understandable
since homosexuality was still illegal in Britain at the time of its
release.
More importantly, however, is how effectively the film relates the story
of
a man who is ruined by a society which can be so hateful.  Although Wilde
is
portrayed at first as an arrogant and indulgent celebrity, as his love for
his family and his torn loyalties are revealed it becomes hard for one to
feel no sadness as he is made to pay with public disgrace and a jail
sentence.  John Fraser is perfectly cast as the spoilt and manipulative
Douglas.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Peter Finch gives a top drawer performance in the title role of the
Trials of Oscar Wilde. It's the story of a man who was a celebrity
raconteur and playwright and his fall from grace because of Victorian
mores about homosexuality.Today a man like Wilde would not be compelled as Victorian society did
compel homosexuals to marry and have children and deny to the world who
they were and how they love. Just think that a century later after the
controversy surrounding Wilde, we are discussing gay marriage and it's
being legalized in many countries. Wouldn't it have all been simpler if
Oscar had been allowed to marry Bosy.When the film opens Wilde is already a successful author of many plays
and stories and maybe the most quoted man of wit in his time. He's
married with two children, but he's got a side life as a gay man. He's
got to take his partners where he finds them, a lot of street kids for
the most part. And then he falls head over heels for Lord Alfred
Douglas played by John Fraser. Fraser is the son of the Marquis of Queensbury, the same guy who
thought up the rules for prize fighting. He's a rough and crude man
played with relish by Lionel Jeffries. Of course the thought of a gay
son is an abomination to him. Can't be that young Bosy is gay, it's
that Wilde guy he's hanging out with.Queensbury calls Wilde a "sodomite" and Wilde foolishly decides to sue
him for libel. And then the trials take place, first the civil suit and
then the criminal trial because sodomy was indeed a criminal offense
back in the day.I often wonder why the real Wilde did not just deal with Queensbury in
one of his plays. In real life and in the film Queensbury was a boorish
lout who could have so easily been caricatured and laughed out of
relevancy. Queensbury retained as his attorney Edward Carson, maybe the best
barrister of his day. Later on he led the Ulster contingent in
Parliamant and was probably the man most responsible for those six
counties of Northern Ireland remaining in the United Kingdom.Let's just say that Oscar Wilde uttered one witticism too many during
his time on the witness stand and James Mason who gives a great
performance as Carson just moves in for the kill. With an international gay movement in full swing now Oscar Wilde and
his story may seem quaint to some, but it is relevant today to show
that it wasn't that long ago that being who you were was a crime. And a
reminder of where gay/lesbian/bi-sexual/transgender folks will be if
our hard won rights even as incomplete as they are yet are ever allowed
to recede.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1529727/comments</url><from>from Manchester, UK</from><name>tim clarke (cafeuk@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The relationship between Oscar Wilde and Bosie, has already developed and
is
in full flow when this film begins, so we are almost immediately immersed
into the war of hate between Bosie and his homophobic and severely
disapproving father. Bosie's father appears to disapprove of his son
merely
because of his son's lack of manliness, and despises Oscar Wilde because
of
what he perceives as Wilde's role in perverting his son. But the
resentment
is also clearly due to the fact that Bosie's father just cannot connect
with
his son on any level (well portrayed in this film) and it is Wilde that
appears to steel that genuine place in Bosie's heart. This just eats away
at
Bosie's father, and so he attempts to destroy the relationship between
Bosie
&amp; Wilde in any way he can. But the more he tries, the more he pushes his
son
away, into the arms of Wilde.Peter Finch plays Oscar Wilde admirably and he convinced me that this
could
have been the real Oscar Wilde. John Fraser plays Bosie acceptably -
although i think it's his clean 'nice boy' looks that help him pull this
role off more than his acting talent. Bosie's father, the Marquis of
Queensbury is played by Lionel Jeffreys and he displays the cantankerous
side of the character well. The courtroom scenes could have been tenser,
and
i dont think James Mason (as one of the barristers) delivers his lines
with
quite the same passion of some barristers I've seen. It is in one of the
courtroom scenes, that quite apart from his relationship with Bosie, the
true extent of Wilde's promiscuity with regard to young men is exposed,
which was the one point for me in the film that I felt slight disgust at
Wilde, although his promiscuity still didn't justify in my opinion what
then
happened to him. I'm just glad that society has become more tolerant
nowadays, in some parts of the world.The film is approximately two hours long, is packed with Oscar Wilde witty
one liners, which made the film very funny at times. On second viewing,
the
film was even more enjoyable. Shot in 1960, I watched it for the first
time
here in the UK on Monday 7th Jan 2002 on Channel 4 who played it as an
afternoon matinee, and the quality of the copy they played was superb -
crystal clear. All in all, the film was a joy to watch.I would highly recommend it, as it illustrates the relative intolerance of
the times in England at that time. There are no sensual scenes in the
film,
so its 'safe' to watch for everyone. I say this because I know that a
friend
of mine recently stopped watching the latest Oscar Wilde film (with
Stephen
Fry, released 1997) as soon as he realised that it contained some male
nudity &amp; stuff, which he said he was personally uncomfortable with. And
the
1960 film doesn't lose anything for not having any sexual stuff in it,
believe me. Please watch it, if you get the chance.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4303406/comments</url><from>from Illinois</from><name>pekinman</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Ken Hughes film 'The Trials of Oscar Wilde' may at first appear to be
one of those cheesy Technicolor costume dramas when in fact it is a
gripping and finely acted account of the appalling treatment Oscar
Wilde received at the hands of the English justice system at the end of
the 19th century.Peter Finch is superb as the eponymous hero and is totally committed to
the role and turns in one of his best performances on screen. The
supporting cast is also quite good if more generalized in their
characterizations, more a fault of the screenplay than the performers.
There is one especially fine supporting performance from Lionel
Jeffries as the maniacal Lord Queensbury. Jeffries plays Queensbury as
a crazed brute, a type of man we can no longer countenance in these
days, though I suspect they are still out there waiting for their
chance to pounce on those who they fear and do not understand.Sonia Dresdel is Lady Wilde, Oscar's dotty mother at the end of her
life. It's a small part but is quietly powerful. Other people in
Wilde's life, Constance, his wife, and Ada Leverson, his stalwart
friend and life-long supporter, are tantalizingly glimpsed but little
is revealed of their inner workings. But this isn't a film about them
but about the actual trials and much of the film is spent in
courtrooms. This might sound boring but it isn't.James Mason appears in the first trial as the defending witness, for
Lord Queensbury, and a more vicious, narrow-minded lawyer could hardly
be found, even these days.The technical credits are competent if nothing special; the music,
melodramatic in a soap-opera-ish way, the sets plush and too clean. But
somehow the power and tragedy of Wilde's story comes through all the
gilding of the script, peppered with some of Wilde's wiser quotes,
well-placed, naturally, in the text. There is nothing preachy or
moralistic which is a relief, compared to the highly politicized
scripts being written since this film was made.It is interesting to note Nicholas Roeg as the camera operator. He
wasn't the cinematographer but I detected a few Roeg-ish touches in a
couple of the more meditative scenes.This is not a film to be sluffed off as old-fashioned simply because
there are no sex scenes or vulgar language or violence. The psychic
violence suffered by Oscar Wilde was quite sufficient enough and this
is a memorable film, worth having in the collection.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
One should always consider the possibility that had Oscar Fingal
O'Flaherty Wills Wilde not fallen inconveniently in love with Lord
Alfred Douglas he might now be remembered only as a relatively minor
Irish playwright with a propensity for presenting other people's bon
mots as his own.His ascent to his unassailable position as the
Theatre's great gay martyr is at least to some extent the result of his
treatment at the hands of the British judicial system. As unpleasing as
it may be to sophisticated 21st century thought,the "homosexual act"
-as gay love was referred to in Victorian law books - was considered a
crime and the "abominable crime of buggery" was punishable by Life
Imprisonment.Queen Victoria refused to endorse laws proscribing
Lesbianism because she not only had never heard of it but she refused
to believe its existence.Aware of all those facts Oscar Wilde chose to
sue his lover's father for libel after the Marquess of Queensberry
referred to him as a "somdomite" (sic).It says much for his chutzpah if
not his intelligence. Mr P.Finch is a fine,sensitive if rather louche
Oscar,clearly besotted with the pretty but insubstantial John Fraser.Mr
L. Jeffries pushes the boat out a bit as the Marquess of
Queensberry,very much an aristocrat of his time with a zealot's hatred
of homosexuality as only an old public school man can have.Mr J.Mason
is suitably ruthless as his barrister,cold of heart,tongue and eye.
This is a handsome film,a typical superior British product of its era,
requiring its audience to stay awake and keep off their mobile phones.
If you require an instant fix it isn't for you. Wilde may ultimately
have been a victim of his own ego,but the Marquess of Quennsberry must
be spinning in his grave over his own contribution to his old enemy's
immortality.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1582207/comments</url><from/><name>Registered_User</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

After seeing this fabulous turn-of-the-century courtroom drama, I am
inspired to read everything I can lay my hands on of this man's work. The
unjust and embarassing ordeal he underwent was petty and totally unthinkable
in today's tolerant society. Like many misunderstood artists, Wilde was
percieved as a "pervert" by the public for his so-called escapades. Save it,
Nineteenth-century England. We are not dealing with Michael Jackson. This
film contains one scene in particular that makes my skin crawl. Oscar is
coming home once his bail is paid for and walks in on a crude auctioneer
(think Bert from Mary Poppins as a vile a-hole) selling his prized
possessions. I was outraged for him! And yet, Wilde maintains a dignified
demeanor throughout. You were too good for them, Oscar!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1582207/comments</url><from/><name>Registered_User</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

After seeing this fabulous turn-of-the-century courtroom drama, I am
inspired to read everything I can lay my hands on of this man's work. The
unjust and embarassing ordeal he underwent was petty and totally unthinkable
in today's tolerant society. Like many misunderstood artists, Wilde was
percieved as a "pervert" by the public for his so-called escapades. Save it,
Nineteenth-century England. We are not dealing with Michael Jackson. This
film contains one scene in particular that makes my skin crawl. Oscar is
coming home once his bail is paid for and walks in on a crude auctioneer
(think Bert from Mary Poppins as a vile a-hole) selling his prized
possessions. I was outraged for him! And yet, Wilde maintains a dignified
demeanor throughout. You were too good for them, Oscar!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1582207/comments</url><from/><name>Registered_User</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>