<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Scent of Mystery</original_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Jack Cardiff</director><genre>Mystery</genre><synopsis>
A vacationing Englishman (Denholm Elliott) stumbles upon a plot to kill a young American tourist (Beverly Bentley) in Spain.
</synopsis><actor>Denholm Elliott</actor><actor>Peter Lorre</actor><actor>Beverly Bentley</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0549076/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>whitesheik</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I love the IMDb. Where else can you get people commenting on a film
they clearly haven't seen in the way it was first exhibited. Only one
commenter claims to have seen it. The others saw a seventy-minute
butchered version taped with a video camera aimed at a
seventy-millimeter movie screen which is the ONLY time it ever aired on
TV (in other words, it was never "sold" to TV). Scent of Mystery was a
true oddity, but one I adored. The camera-work and sound recording were
unbelievably brilliant, and the film was a lark. The smells were
dispensed to each seat via a tube and by the time of the LA run they'd
figured out how to "clean" the air between smells and it worked very
well. As to Holiday in Spain, here we have people making comments when
they clearly know not of what they speak. When Scent flopped big-time,
it was sold to the Cinerama corporation. The film was converted into
three-panel Cinerama, cut by twenty-five minutes (making its plot
completely incoherent - of course, this is the version people are
commenting on - well, not exactly - their commenting on the shortened
version which was further shortened for its one-time TV showing),
narration by Elliot was added (terrible), and the intermission point,
which in the original was sublime, was moved up by twenty minutes and
made no sense at all. Given that all but one of the commentators here
have only seen the dreck that they showed on TV (completely faded print
and missing sixty percent of its image), well, I find it a bit galling.
The Todd AO image was and is stunning, the director of the film was the
great cameraman, Jack Cardiff. And the sound - amazing eight track
Todd-Belock sound system which, to my mind, has never been bettered.
Not by Dolby, not by DTS, not by anything. And, just in case you think
my memory may be faulty, I have just this day watched a
seventy-millimeter print of the film, the shortened (but not as short
as TV) Holiday in Spain - and that sound blew me away.So, at this time, Scent Of Mystery is a lost film. It's never even been
printed down to 35mm. It is uncertain whether any 70mm elements survive
for the uncut Scent - there are 70mm elements (and even YCMs) for
Holiday in Spain. If the uncut neg can be found, I am here to tell you
there are plans afoot for a DVD.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0187135/comments</url><from>from Hollywood</from><name>elvis-30</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I was at the premiere in Hollywood (1960) - A first-date thing ......Didn't know what to expect .. but the pipe tobacco and peach smells
(among SEVERAL more) were astounding! Each time you smelled the
perfume... you KNEW something bad was going to happen! .....I don't know how they did it, maybe a hose or fan mounted on the seat
in front of you, but when the scene changed, the smell did too !! NEET!If I remember correctly, the program LISTED all the smells you would
encounter during the film as well.Needless to say, the food smells probably helped the concession stand
because the lines were a mile long !!My date was NOT impressed... (should have made her buy popcorn!)Too bad, This film followed the 3-D craze and is now gone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0956267/comments</url><from/><name>Bruce Elliott (brucebox@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Sent Of Mystery is not a bad film, though basically the answer to a trivia
question it's still fun.Over the years there had been various attempts at filling a movie theater
with smells linked to the film being shown. Around 1915, a silent
exhibitor
distributed a tinted newsreel of the Rose Parade that came with Flit guns
of
rose sent so that the theater ushers could walk the isles pumping perfume
while the film was being shown. In 1940, the Clark Gable &amp; Spencer Tracy
vehicle `Boom Town' subjected certain unfortunate audiences to the smell
of
crude oil pumped into the theater's ventilation system. This went over so
poorly, that nobody tried anything like for years.The `Smell-o-vision' used in Sent Of Mystery was an elaborate system that
had vials of several scents within a rotating drum beside each theater
seat.
These drums were rotated on silent cues actually recorded onto the film's
magnetic soundtrack. Each sent was puffed at the patron via compressed
air,
and in the system's real innovation, each sent was then nullified by
another
puff of fresh air when the scene was over. It was an elaborate gimmick
that
would have made Mike Todd Sr. or William Castle proud. In the film, it was
used to great affect to identify the killer with a particular kind of pipe
tobacco and at the climax the audience is were alerted to his presence
before he is seen on screen! Unfortunately this crucial scene is
meaningless
without the scent and one is left to wonder how the hero is able to
identify
him, but at least the film does have a fun cameo by Liz Taylor at the
end.Scent Of Mystery later went into wider release under the more pedestrian
title of `Holiday In Spain', and under that name it was eventually sold to
TV. Around 1983 the film surfaced again when it aired in several US cities
and on MTV as part of a cross-promotion with 7-11 convenience stores,
which
was when I saw it. The 7-11 stores sold a package containing coupons and a
foldout card that came with a sheet of scratch-n-sniff decals. As
broadcast,
the film's `scent points' were marked with a flashing number at the bottom
of the screen, which was the viewer's cue to peel &amp; paste the
corresponding
decal onto their card, which was decorated with images from the film that
could be followed like a board game. This included the peach blossoms, the
cask of wine, the cooking onions, and the distinctive tobacco.
Unfortunately, this broadcast gimmick blew the films surprise by making it
more like the `Odorama' used in John Waters' `Polyester.'Other than the aforementioned John Waters film, the only other use of
scented cinema that I'm aware of in recent years is in an attraction at
Disney's California Adventure theme park. Those experiencing the Omni-max
film `Sorin' Over California' experience a pine scent as they `fly' over
the
Sierra forests and an orange scent as they `glide' over orchards of the
Central Valley. It seems the `Smellies' are just one of those ideas that
will never catch on.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0747450/comments</url><from>from Omaha, Nebraska</from><name>LarryCinerama (lkarsten@ops.org)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

I saw this movie with the smells.  Since the smells in many cases served as
clues, it would be confusing without them.  The machine that generated the
smells was located in the lobby for examination by theater goers.  The
smells were introduced to the theater using a compressed air system and
after a few examples, the audience recognized the noise (which was minimal)
and commented to each other "Here comes another one"  All in all not really
a very good movie but a fun experience.  I don't really see how this could
ever have been anything more than an experiment.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0023515/comments</url><from>from Woodhaven, NY</from><name>againsam</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

There was a race to get smells into films at this time.  It was won by the
Walter Reade organisation in late 1959 with a documentary called "Behind The
Great Wall", which added smells after the film was completed, in a process
called aromarama.  "scent of Mystery" was produced by Mike Todd Jr. in 70mm,
with the smells to be used as clues to the mystery.  It was a lighthearted
romp, beautifully shot in Spain, with Elizabeth Taylor as a guest star.  It
has never been revived, or put out on video.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5876717/comments</url><from/><name>kosmasp</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This is very silly and should not under any circumstances be taken
seriously. Any attempt to not follow that advice will lead into the
inevitable result of you not liking the movie at all. Actually of you
dreading the movie. And it's comedy might be considered poor taste,
it's acting poor too.But it is silly and simple for a reason and it stays true to that
formula til the end (even if it has hits and misses throughout). The
main character with his conviction of knowing more than he actually
does helps the movie a lot. Also Mr. Lorre in a role that we are not
used seeing him, is great too. All in all, a crime comedy, that might
not be something to really recommend ... But still funny to watch
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317890/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Anne Sharp</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Some movies created to be used with in-theater tricks such as 3-D or
Sensurround or whatever are entertaining to watch even without the gimmick.
This isn't. The young Denholm Elliott makes a most unengaging leading
man/narrator, and though Peter Lorre as his dirty old man sidekick perks
things up a bit it's basically a low octane assemblage of corny gags and
sub-Hitchcockian intrigue. Still, it's the film that inspired John Waters'
classic Odorama classic "Polyester," which is quite a claim to fame in
itself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317890/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Anne Sharp</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Some movies created to be used with in-theater tricks such as 3-D or
Sensurround or whatever are entertaining to watch even without the gimmick.
This isn't. The young Denholm Elliott makes a most unengaging leading
man/narrator, and though Peter Lorre as his dirty old man sidekick perks
things up a bit it's basically a low octane assemblage of corny gags and
sub-Hitchcockian intrigue. Still, it's the film that inspired John Waters'
classic Odorama classic "Polyester," which is quite a claim to fame in
itself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317890/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Anne Sharp</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies.tvguide.com/scent-mystery/review/116946 /m/scent_of_mystery/comments.php?reviewid=1938833</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/4
					</rating><comment>This beautifully photographed mystery/chase film takes its cast through the Spanish landscape, but the real star of the picture is "Smell-O-Vision."</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?_r=1&amp;res=9C04E5DF1E38E333A2575AC1A9649C946191D6CF&amp;scp=3&amp;sq=scent%20of%20mystery&amp;st=cse /m/scent_of_mystery/comments.php?reviewid=1938832</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>As theatrical exhibitionism, it is gaudy, sprawling and full of sound. But as an attempt at a considerable motion picture it has to be classified as bunk.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794675.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1&amp;p=0 /m/scent_of_mystery/comments.php?reviewid=1938831</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>The picture -- with or without the smells -- is a fun picture, expertly directed by Jack Cardiff.</comment></review></movie>