<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Spartacus</original_title><imdb_rating>8.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Stanley Kubrick</director><producer>Bryna Productions</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Biography</genre><synopsis>
The slave Spartacus leads a violent revolt against the decadent Roman empire.
</synopsis><actor>Kirk Douglas</actor><actor>Laurence Olivier</actor><actor>Jean Simmons</actor><rt_rating>8.2/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>96</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3338050/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Miles Charrier</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is Kubrick's farewell to Hollywood. I would have liked to be a fly
on the wall. I don't believe for a minute that it was a cordial parting
of the ways. I mean, Kubrick never returned, never! With "Paths of
Glory" Kubrick gave Kirk Douglas, not just his best part as an actor,
but his best movie. By the time Douglas called Kubrick to "take over"
"Spartacus" Douglas was already a huge star with too much saying in the
matter. Look at it, it's clear. "Spartacus" is more Douglas than
Kubrick. Great fun to watch, yes, absolutely. A terrific script by
black listed Dalton Trumbo. Some fight sequences unequalled in the
history of film. Look at the fight between Douglas and Woody Strode and
compare it to the ones in "Troy" or "Gladiator" for that matter. It is
sad an embarrassing to realise how low we've fallen. Computer generated
images or not. The cast is unbelievable but it's clearly not Kubrick's.
The casting of his movies was part of his master plan. He would cast a
Ryan O'Neil as Barry Lyndon for instance so he can blend perfectly with
the magnificent tapestry, without adding any colours of his own. The
same can be said of Keir Dullea, in 2001, a robotic non entity in a
showdown with a voice. When he needed actors to be at the very pinnacle
of his universe he went to Peter Sellers, Malcolm McDowell or James
Mason. Even the casting of Tom Cruise made a lot of sense. He used the
star and his wife to talk about the dreamlike powers of betrayal. In
"Spartacus" Tony Curtis, plays Antoninus, a teacher of the classics. A
campy idea never seen in a Kubrick film, before or since. To be fair,
there are some spot on, brilliant pieces of casting. Charles Laughton
is, as usual, superb. Peter Ustinov, terrific. Laurence Olivier manages
to give a multifaceted portrait of weakness, fear and greed. Jean
Simmons makes the reason to survive totally believable. But the cutesy
love scene between her and a shiny muscular, coiffed Spartacus is truly
terrible. As a final blow, the scene is enveloped in a sticky, corny
music theme. Having said all that. Don't you dare missing this epic.
I'ts Kubrick's goodbye to Hollywood and like everything else that the
master said or do, he really meant it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
From what little I've read of this film it was lucky to have been made
at all. Some very big talents had some very big egos and those egos
clashed repeatedly. Original director Anthony Mann was replaced by
Stanley Kubrick by Producer/Star Kirk Douglas among other clashes.But the result was all worth it. The stars all give top notch
performances, but the mark of a really great film is the memorability
of each individual in the ensemble. To give a few examples, Charles
McGraw as the sadistic trainer at the gladiatorial school, John Dall as
Sir Laurence Olivier's protégé, and John Ireland as Kirk Douglas's
fellow gladiator trainee are all memorable in the brief roles they
have.Kirk Douglas wisely opts for a straightforward interpretation of a hero
in the title role of Spartacus. He's a BC everyman, born into a world
which hadn't heard anything about human rights, he knows and feels he's
not just cattle. Catch the alternating scenes of Douglas and Sir
Laurence Olivier addressing the slave army and the Roman Army. Olivier
with his years of Shakespearean training coming across as the tyrant to
be, and Douglas in simple prose talking about the slaves fighting for
their hopes and dreams. Very effective.The plot concerns a revolt at a gladiatorial school which mushrooms
into a crisis for the Roman Empire. Political factions led by Olivier
as Crassus and Charles Laughton as Gracchus seek to use the slave
revolt to further their own ends. Laughton as always is a wonder. It's a bit of unusual casting for him
because his parts are usually those of very tortured souls. His
Gracchus is a sly rogue, but a decent man. One of my favorite movie
lines of all time is delivered by him addressing the Roman Senate where
he says he'll "take a little republican corruption for a little
republican freedom." Another sly rogue in the film is Peter Ustinov who won the first of his
two Oscars as Batiatus the owner of the gladiatorial school. Like so
many others I'm sure in those days, he's just trying to come out on the
winning side when doing so could be a life or death situation.Jean Simmons as Varinia, beloved of Spartacus, has the only woman's
part of any substance. But when was Ms. Simmons bad in anything. One of
the most underrated and under-appreciated actresses in the history of
film.The lessons about man's desire for freedom and to control his own
destiny are eternal and valid. And this film will be also.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Widely acclaimed for his serious ambitions and his uncompromising
perfectionism, Stanley Kubrick has won for himself a unique degree of
artistic freedom...Based on a true story of a slave revolt in 73 B.C., Dalton Trumbo's
script mixes the melodrama with some quite moving moments... The film
depicts the Roman era, the brutality of the slave system, gladiator
combat and the decadence of Roman senators... What emerges from the
screen is a passionate statement on behalf of freedom and men who are
willing to die to overthrow oppressive governments...The credit for the film's style belongs to Stanley Kubrick, who handles
scenes of intimacy and scenes of gigantic sweep with equal attention,
illustrating the violence, brutality and corruption of both, the
masters and the slaves, raising the question of freedom which justify
the human cost...Kirk Douglas plays Spartacus the idealistic noble slave who believes he
must struggle forever against tyranny and just by opposing tyranny he
inspires his followers with his example...Spartacus' character, from a violent primitive rebel who hamstrung a
foreman with his teeth, into a gladiator who fought desperately for
life in the arena, into a revolutionary able to unite an amorphous mass
of slaves and deserters, into a force which succeeded to defeat Rome's
best trained armies, into a charismatic leader (with a vision) who
forces a long-awaited revolt against the Roman empire...Two political rivals (Crassus and Gracchus) use the slave uprising
threat to manipulate the Roman senate for their own ends: Crassus (played powerfully by Laurence Olivier) extorts 'a fee,' the
dictatorial post of First Consul, Commander of all the legions of Italy
as his price for releasing Rome from Spartacus... Crassus sees the
defeat of Spartacus' army as a chance for him to seize power of the
empire for himself... He tries to make the slaves betray Spartacus...
He tries to win the love of Varinia, not merely to possess her, but as
a form of victory over Spartacus... In his last confrontation with
Spartacus, he is seen losing all his delusions of grandeur as he stands
deeply wounded by the total disregard in which Spartacus holds him...Charles Laughton plays, with expertise, Gracchus, a generous Roman
politician, soft and rich, able to get his Julius Caesar (John Gavin)
elected leader of the Praetorian Guard to annoy Crassus' ambitions...The first hour of "Spartacus" contains many of the film's best moments
: The operation of the gladiatorial school and its training program is
impressive and also expressive... The gladiators school is tough but
fair: The men are oiled, bathed, shaved, massaged and trained to
fight... They are never allowed to kill... And for their good
performances, they are even rewarded with the companionship of a young
lady... In this degrading manner Spartacus meets Varinia (Jean
Simmons-lovely as ever) and it is his love for her and his hatred for
his captors that inadvertently sparks off an uprising and the
gladiators break out...Particularly effective is the scene in which Crassus and his
"capricious over-painted nymphs" (Nina Foch &amp; Joanna Barnes) ask to be
entertained by the sight of two pairs fighting to the death... The
scene summarizes the injustice of the situation, the cruelty of bondage
and the insurrection becomes a triumph easy to understand...Nominated for six Academy Awards, and winning for Cinematography,
Costume Design, Art Direction and Supporting Actor—Peter Ustinov. the
motion picture contains no chariot races and no orgies but it still
imparts the grandeur and the decay of ancient Rome... With a stirring musical score by Oscar nominee Alex North, "Spartacus,"
is masterfully directed by Kubrick...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1236364/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>John von K</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The darkest historical epic. No dancing girls, no chariot races, filmed in
sombre browns and reds.  Nominally directed by Kubrick but Douglas, as a
very 'hands on' producer was responsable for the operatic sweep of the film.
I was astonished when revisiting the film in 1991 at the cinema at the
bravery of the project-to have the hero cry several times, once even out of
self pity and with a heart rending ending! The film has depth and weight,
the characters are well drawn. The performances are almost flawless, Douglas
managing as actor to create tension in each scene-Olivier, not withstanding
his eyerolling mannerisms is perfectly cast. The minor parts are richly
drawn-gravel voiced Charles McGraw, Herbert Lom and Woody Strode. The
cinematography and music are flawless. Only John Dall as a very modern
Glaberus and John Ireland as Crixus seem out of place.  Ironically, despite
the downbeat tone of the film it is impossible to watch it without being
uplifted through your tears of compassion. Unofficialy remade as
Braveheart...watch one after the other and you'll see the similarities in
mood, theme and even the battle choreography. Spartacus would be my 'desert
island' movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0339245/comments</url><from>from Adelaide, Australia</from><name>Richard Kerslake</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

As a historical epic, 'Spartacus' stands out from the crowd.The film has the basic theme of 'force' versus 'an idea'. One man -
Spartacus- has the idea of freedom, which is pitted through his slave army
against the entire force of the Roman Empire.In Spartacus's eventual defeat, force seems to be victorious, but we know
with hindsight that it is Spartacus' idea that finally prevails, albeit
long
after his death, with the abolition of slavery.  As the opening narration
makes clear, as a young man Spartacus would dream of the death of
slavery -
"two thousand years before it finally would die." Kirk Douglas gives an
inspiring performance as the brutalised and uneducated slave rising above
his degradation to find love, leadership and high ideals.The film closely interweaves the fate of Spartacus with that of Roman
politics. His slave rebellion contributes to the fall of Gracchus, the
main
Republican advocate, and the corresponding rise of authoritarian Crassus.
In
a way, Spartacus is portrayed as a catalyst for a new era of Roman
dictatorship under the Caesars; by suppressing his slave rebellion, Rome
sets itself irrevocably on a path away from Republic and freedom, and
perhaps confirms its eventual downfall. Some historical licence, no doubt;
but a thought-provoking concept.Unlike many other Roman epics such as 'Ben-Hur' and 'The Robe', the film
does not have a Christian motif. However, 'Spartacus' epitomises the
triumph
of the human spirit in a way that few movies do. Even after his death, not
only Spartacus' son but his spirit lives on,if only in man's perennial cry
for freedom. The slave leader's resolve, and his will to freedom, remain
true to the end.Considering that it was made in 1960, the film's confronting of hard
themes
is notable. For example, we have the hint of forbidden homosexual/
bisexual
desires from Crassus to Antoninus; the seeming death and failure (but
perhaps ultimate victory)for the hero, who traditionally should triumph;
and
unpleasant scenes involving battlefields and rows of crucified bodies.The movie is helped by an excellent cast, an evocative score and Stanley
Kubrick's direction. The sets and costumes also show great attention to
detail, so that ancient Roman society comes alive.Overall a most entertaining and inspiring movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3731311/comments</url><from>from Beyond The Cosmos</from><name>Arriflex1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
As most are undoubtedly aware, this is the film that the director
virtually expunged from his repertoire. But why did Stanley Kubrick
really disown SPARTACUS(1960)? The answer can be summed up in two
words: absolute control. Kubrick wanted total administrative as well as
artistic authority over the making of the film about a revolt of
gladiators and slaves in ancient Rome.But you will notice that Bryna Productions not only financed SPARTACUS
but also an earlier film directed by Kubrick, PATHS OF GLORY(1958).
Bryna was Kirk Douglas' film company and, as most filmgoers know, he
was the star of both films. Besides having all the money to make the
films, Douglas had artistic vision as well. Only three weeks into what
would prove to be an incredibly complex and arduous production, Douglas
fired venerable director Anthony Mann (RAW DEAL, RAILROADED, THE NAKED
SPUR, MAN OF THE WEST, etc.) from SPARTACUS. With only two days notice,
Kubrick was hired to replace him.Shooting PATHS OF GLORY, Douglas had confined his criticisms and
objections to Kubrick's failed rewriting of the script (they went with
the original screenplay). Douglas' complaints and artistic influence
were far greater on SPARTACUS, much to Kubrick's chagrin. Though the
director craved autonomy over every aspect of the film, Douglas would
not budge. A tense compromise was reached, yet ultimately Douglas had
the last word. Kubrick saw himself as just a hired gun. And he would
never allow himself to be placed in this position again.Later, both men would complain about the film's outcome and each other.
They never made another movie together. But SPARTACUS is no uneven patchwork of divergent ideas. The film is
cohesive and arresting. At the restored version of three hours and
eighteen minutes, there is practically no dead footage in the film.
Dalton Trumbo's screenplay is surprisingly economical, with sharply
drawn characters placed against the sweeping historical majesty and
violent sociological tumult of ancient Rome. Quite plainly, the
gloriously inventive music by Alex North is among the greatest scores
ever written for a motion picture. And despite Kubrick's bad
experience, he managed to guide the actors towards creating outstanding
work ( a best supporting Oscar for Peter Ustinov). He even transformed
the very real enmity between Laughton and Olivier into an on-screen
asset. His other contributions were considerable also (the large scale
and power of the battle sequence, for example). In the end, for the
film at least, the clash of giant egos proved fortuitous.
Recommendations: for greater insight and detail on this and Kubrick's
other films I urge you to seek out Jan Harlan's excellent documentary,
STANLEY KUBRICK: A LIFE IN PICTURES, and Vincent LoBrutto's exhaustive,
highly informative biography, STANLEY KUBRICK. For the producer's views
on SPARTACUS and its director, take a gander at Kirk Douglas' very
candid autobiography, THE RAGMAN'S SON.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4569240/comments</url><from>from High on a Plane</from><name>bb_org</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A very moving and compelling story of epic proportions. The plot is
relentless, propelled by a dazzling screenplay. Kubrick draws some of
the greatest performances of the cast, and fills the screen with images
that fascinate throughout. Well paced for a movie of this magnitude.To those who complain of anachronisms and poetic license with
historical events, I say to them, 'Remember, it is a movie.' To be
truly accurate, the cast would be delivering their lines in Latin and
ancient Greek, with English subtitles. Whatever Kubrick might lose with
historical inaccuracies, he gains far more in his ability to convey the
story to the viewer. Even though it is over forty years old, the film
tells us more of the present day than it does of the past.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0361658/comments</url><from>from Sacramento, CA</from><name>Miyagis_Sweaty_wifebeater (sirjosephu@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Spartacus (1960) was a director for hire gig for Stanley Kubrick. Kirk
Douglas was in a pinch for his next film project. He was making an epic
film about a slave in the roman republic who rebels against his
masters. Anthony Mann stepped down from the director's chair and Mr.
Douglas needed someone to take over. Enters Stanley Kubrick. Although
he has little creative input (i.e. script and story wise) he manages to
make a compelling movie with his keen eye and directorial abilities.Filmed in a grand scope and in such great detail, Spartacus is eye
candy for fans of epic film making. I can only imagine what the film
would have been like if he had total control over the project. Kirk
Douglas is the man as Spartacus, Tony Curtis is quite good as his
sidekick, Charles Laughton is wise and witty as the elder senator,
Peter Ustinov is a hoot in his role as the poor victim of fortunate
(and unfortunate) circumstance and Sir Laurence Olivier shows why he
was the premier actor of his day as Crassus.Highly recommended for Kirk Douglas fans and Stanley Kubrick philes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6847823/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edimdb-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I think the movie is quite good; what I want to add to the comments
already made is just this: The commentary (on the DVD) by screenplay writer Dalton Trumbo is
great. Kirk Douglas said it was the greatest analysis of film-making
ever. He explains the purpose of every scene, very openly and honestly
critiquing the changes the actors made, for (in his estimation) better
or worse.There is another track of commentary by the actors. The actors had an
unusual degree of latitude in re-writing their lines and forming their
characters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7059410/comments</url><from>from Serbia</from><name>fedor8 (fedor8@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Watched it again, nearly twenty years later, and I can't say I warmed
to it much. I certainly didn't expect Ancient Rome to be shown in such
a dark way as in "Caligula" (especially not in 1960), but the story of
the slaves who rebelled goes into the other extreme: it's pure
Hollywood nonsense, unfortunately. Spartacus isn't bloodthirsty or
ruthless enough; he is more like Moses than an ex-slave/gladiator. Out
of all the slave women in Ancient Rome, Olivier has to have the one,
i.e. has to fall for the exact same one that Spartacus loves. That is
just a little too corny for my taste. The first third, with the
training and the rebellion, is actually good, but from then on the pace
is much too slow, there are some needless scenes, and the movie gets
increasingly unrealistic. Plus, the ending is a downer. ("Braveheart",
which is similar in its basic premise, length, and that it has also a
downer ending, grips you; "Spartacus" does nothing of the sort.) The
casting is very good, though, with Olivier and Ustinov being
particularly good. I see nothing here that would suggest that the best
director of all time is behind the camera. Then again, Kubrick was only
hired to direct this; i.e. this film wasn't one of his
produce/direct/write projects. Also, it was years before he developed
his unique style. It's his next movie. "Lolita", that started a string
of major classics.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7059410/comments</url><from>from Serbia</from><name>fedor8 (fedor8@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Watched it again, nearly twenty years later, and I can't say I warmed
to it much. I certainly didn't expect Ancient Rome to be shown in such
a dark way as in "Caligula" (especially not in 1960), but the story of
the slaves who rebelled goes into the other extreme: it's pure
Hollywood nonsense, unfortunately. Spartacus isn't bloodthirsty or
ruthless enough; he is more like Moses than an ex-slave/gladiator. Out
of all the slave women in Ancient Rome, Olivier has to have the one,
i.e. has to fall for the exact same one that Spartacus loves. That is
just a little too corny for my taste. The first third, with the
training and the rebellion, is actually good, but from then on the pace
is much too slow, there are some needless scenes, and the movie gets
increasingly unrealistic. Plus, the ending is a downer. ("Braveheart",
which is similar in its basic premise, length, and that it has also a
downer ending, grips you; "Spartacus" does nothing of the sort.) The
casting is very good, though, with Olivier and Ustinov being
particularly good. I see nothing here that would suggest that the best
director of all time is behind the camera. Then again, Kubrick was only
hired to direct this; i.e. this film wasn't one of his
produce/direct/write projects. Also, it was years before he developed
his unique style. It's his next movie. "Lolita", that started a string
of major classics.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/spartacus  /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1949464</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Thrilling epic is too intense for the youngest.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dan-jardine/</url><url>http://djardine.blogspot.com/2010/08/spartacus-usa-1960-stanley-kubrick.html /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1921519</url><name>Dan Jardine</name><from>Cinemania</from></reviewer><rating>
72/100
					</rating><comment>While it suffers from some of the flaws of epics of this era-such as an overly sanitized portrait of life at the time, and anachronistic visions of fashion and lifestyle-Spartacus also boasts some stirring action and intelligent dialogue</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-christopher/</url><url>http://entertainment.timesonline.co.uk/tol/arts_and_entertainment/film/film_reviews/article6424576.ece /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1826368</url><name>James Christopher</name><from>Times [UK]</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Douglas is terrific as the iron-jawed slave fuelled by righteous fury.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/peter-bradshaw/</url><url>http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/2009/jun/05/spartacus-kirk-douglas-kubrick /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1826359</url><name>Peter Bradshaw</name><from>Guardian [UK]</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>The great-granddaddy of Ridley Scott's Gladiator hasn't lost any muscle tone after nearly half a century, and Kirk Douglas's direct, unpretentious performance as the great slave-rebel Spartacus is more engaging than ever.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-french/</url><url>http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/2009/jun/07/spartacus-kirk-douglas-kubrick /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1826357</url><name>Philip French</name><from>Observer [UK]</from></reviewer><comment>One of the greatest Hollywood epics.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies.sky.com/review/spartacus /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1826314</url><from>Sky Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>It is in the observation of human detail, and in many memorable little scenes that the film scores most heavily over other epics, and in which it finds an inner strength.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.totalfilm.com/reviews/dvd/spartacus /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1826305</url><from>Total Film</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>One of the last truly great Roman epics.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=108589&amp;section=review /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1676891</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Arguably the greatest sword 'n' sandal movie of them all.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-villarreal/</url><url>http://www.azstarnet.com/accent/192670 /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1654928</url><name>Phil Villarreal</name><from>Arizona Daily Star</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>More than a standard good vs. evil drama, the movie is about a hero's inner struggle to persevere in carrying out an ideal that's almost certain to lead to his demise.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/11368_SPARTACUS /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1630944</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>This may be the most literate of all the spectacles set in antiquity.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>http://www.dvdtown.com/reviews/spartacus/4067 /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1554846</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
9/10
					</rating><comment>...notable not only for its expected sword play and scenery, but for the genuine complexity of its characters, their relationships, and their political intrigues.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/75109/spartacus.html /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1479744</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Asurprisingly apt companion piece to Paths of Glory in its consideration of the mechanisms of power.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=15843 /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1427310</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>Decades later, it's still one of the most intelligent and stirring histrical epics to have come out of Hollywood, serving as a model for future generations of filmmakers.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steven-d-greydanus/</url><url>http://www.decentfilms.com/sections/reviews/2018 /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1384750</url><name>Steven D. Greydanus</name><from>Decent Films Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>The comparative frankness of the politics, sexuality, and violence, and especially the downbeat third act and memorable finale give it a dramatic heft beyond its predecessors.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-a-smith/</url><url>/m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1350814</url><name>Michael A. Smith</name><from>Nolan's Pop Culture Review</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>A true spectacle. The restored version rates a 5</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/luke-y-thompson/</url><url>http://www.lytrules.com/archives/00000401.html /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1287828</url><name>Luke Y. Thompson</name><from>LYTRules.com</from></reviewer><comment>All in all, where the movie is flawed, it's due to following the cinematic conventions of the era.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kim-newman/</url><url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/review.asp?FID=132672 /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1282060</url><name>Kim Newman</name><from>Empire Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Though this stuff could have been directed by anyone, the greatness of Spartacus is in the stretches everyone remembers.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/spartacus.shtml /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1281671</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Many scenes ring passionate and rousing, while others are campy and silly, and somehow they all work together.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Spartacus /m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1223428</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Director Stanley Kubrick was obviously just collecting a paycheck for this one, though he stages some intricate battle scenes. Too bad he obviously couldn't have cared less about the lame love story and political machinations behind the scenes.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nick-davis/</url><url>/m/1019544-spartacus/comments.php?reviewid=1187712</url><name>Nick Davis</name><from>Nick's Flick Picks</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Rousing in patches, but kitschy in so many others - a mixed bag.</comment></review></movie>