<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Space Men</original_title><alt_title>Le vainqueur de l'espace</alt_title><imdb_rating>3.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Antonio Margheriti</director><producer>Titanus</producer><producer>Ultra Film</producer><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
In the 21st century Ray Peterson, reporter for the Interplanetary News, is assigned to write a story aboard a space station...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Rik Van Nutter</actor><actor>Gabriella Farinon</actor><actor>David Montresor</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4627372/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (winner55)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Very odd sci-fi film. Filled with quirky little details of some
historical interest: The film is Italian and overdubbed in English; but
if you watch the actors' lips carefully, they are mouthing the English
words; so the film was intended for an English language market from the
start.The writers assume that the Russians will win the space-race of the
time, hence the reporter refers to the spaceship crew as "cosmonauts).The film claims to be shot in Technicolor; this simply cannot be the
case. Occasionally the color red shows through, but much of it does
look black and white. When Technicolor washes out, it takes on a light
blue tint - other processes get very blue, light green, or, as here,
simply washed out all together.Gabriella Farinon is very easy to look at; she later did a very pretty
spread for the Italian edition of Playboy Magazine (1975)(some of it
can be searched for on the 'net), but her film career went pretty much
nowhere.The year is 1960; that may make this the first film ever to depict a
black male as extremely intelligent, brave, wistfully philosophical,
and treated by the other crew members as simply another crew member, no
reference to race whatsoever. I'm afraid that would make this one of
the most important films ever made, in terms of social history (which
doesn't mean it's a good film - it isn't).Director Antonio Margheriti, AKA Anthony M. Dawson, was extremely
prolific; however, a filmography search, both here at IMDb and on
Google, only discovers his fantasy films, and a small handful of
westerns; but I remember his name popping up on almost every other
spaghetti or sauer-kraut western produced in the '60s, at least until
Sergio Leone came along (and radically changed that genre).Yes, I can see the influence of this film on Kubrick's 2001; but beyond
the film's essential pessimism, it's unclear why Kubrick would be
impressed by a film so poorly made.My viewing confirms a previous reviewer's note that the explosion of a
spaceship is represented with brief stock footage of a car blowing up
in a parking lot. Why?! Not the lowest budget imaginable for such a
film can excuse this gaff - it would have been more effective to take
the spaceship miniature and toss it on the ground - and then step on
it.Yet despite flaws like this, the writers seem to be determined to
deploy science and technology (at least as it was popularly known at
the time) in a fairly realistic manner.A real stew of a film, made of leftovers as yet not fully cooked.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

'Space Men', directed by Anthony Daisies (aka Anthony M. Dawson of 'Cannibal
Apocalypse' infamy), is a low budget, and I mean LOW budget, 60s Italian sci
fi adventure. Anyone expecting a stylish gem ala Mario Bava's 'Planet Of The
Vampires' will be sorely disappointed, and anyone expecting an Ed Wood
worst-movie-ever-made laughfest will also not get what they expect. This
movie is neither of the two, but if you take it for what it is - basically a
simple 40s style pulp plot with special effects a smart 12 year old could
build in their own backyard - it is a fairly enjoyable slice of
silliness.The wonderfully named Rik Van Nutter ('Thunderball') plays an arrogant (but
actually quite decent underneath) space reporter who is sent as an observer
on a space mission. He clashes with the arrogant (but actually quite decent
underneath) ship Commander (Alain Dijon - 'La Dolce Vita'). The two also vie
for the affections of the lovely Lucy (Gabriella Farinon) in between trying
to save Earth from possible destruction by an out of control space ship.
Yes, it's that kind of movie. Entertaining enough but nothing
special.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0199855/comments</url><from>from Saint Clair, Pennsylvania</from><name>Rich Meyer (muzik@ptd.net)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

I kinda like Assignment Outer Space.  It's a real simple little sci-fi flick
with your typically bad Italian effects.  One scene made the movie for me
though.There's a scene where an astronaut tries to escape a crash by jumping down
to one of Mars' moons (strangely similar to the big budget Mission to Mars).
 Suddenly, there's an explosion when his ship hits.  Unfortunately, the
person handling the mattes was apparently sleeping that day, because you see
an explosion in front of a bunch of buildings and behind a Chevy.  Here we
are in deep space near the Red Planet and there's a Chevy on a street in
Italy.  One of the most jarringly funny scenes I ever saw in a grade z
movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0976573/comments</url><from>from Milwaukee, Wisconsin</from><name>davidemartin (davidemartin@cs.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

I saw it on a Saturday matinee double feature sometime in the '60s.  And
then completely forgot the name of it.  The one thing I remembered was the 
spaceship with the dead crew and the deadly forcefield that destroyed any
ship remotely near it.  Which of course was not enough to base a search
on.And it didn't help that I thought Ed Platt played a role in it, as the
spaceman who dies trying to stop the deathship.     I lucked out when I bought a $5 DVD of it on a lark and, lo and behold, it
was the film I'd been looking for!Anyway, if you want to see a great example of a scifi space flick prior to
2001, give this a try.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I only wanted to see this movie because it looked like charming 60's
Sci-Fi and, most importantly, because it was the first film directed by
Antonio Margheriti (A. Dawson) who would later become one of Italy's
most reliable horror/western/crime filmmakers. "Assignment: Outer
Space" is a pretty insignificant and poorly produced science-fiction
romp, but it's entertaining and you can clearly detect the enthusiasm
of both director and cast-members. The first half is boring and filled
with clichés, but the second half and particularly the climax offers
some amusing, albeit textbook space adventure. The recently (October
2005) deceased Rik Van Nutter plays a pulpy reporter on board of a
routine space mission and falls in love with the only female crew
member, who's actually sort of like involved with the captain of the
mission already. This results in a somewhat hostile relationship
between all the passengers, until they all have to get over their
personal troubles and prevent an unmanned ship to crash down on earth.
The sets and special effects couldn't look more amateurish, still I
think this actually ADDS to the charm of these kind of movies. In case
you don't like fake planets made out of carbon or astronauts on
strings, this certainly isn't your movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0278527/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Hitchcoc</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I, too, got this in a collection. As my son and I watched it, we
thought it would never end. The slow talking, slow moving presentation.
The overt seriousness of everything. The long dull explanations and
speech making. It just never ends. Not to mention, "Why is it exactly
that Earth is going to be destroyed?" I guess we just need to take
their word for it. The acting is so stiff. The reporter guy is such a
loose cannon. He has his own agenda. He is given way too much
responsibility for a guy there just to report the facts. Then there is
the romance. The captain has virtually no personality, yet is admired
by the token woman on the flight. When things don't work, we don't know
why exactly. We don't really know why throwing things at a power source
is enough to disrupt the force field or whatever. It's just so inane.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11111365/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Ivan Bradley (Ivan_Bradley)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Thanks to junk-monkey (liam@merriol.freeserve.co.uk) for the review I
read on one screen while watching the movie on the other. Read his
excellent review for proper details. This is just a "me too' rider on
that.A quandary on the scoring: 3 out of 10 for stand-alone entertainment,
but 7 for teaching value. It's great for analysis.I'm teaching my 9 yr old daughter the basics of film-making, and so far
this is the best "how to do a low budget job without spending money on
a continuity girl" effort I've yet found. You really _could_ make this film at home with a few mates, a roll of
black paper and the contents of a junk radio surplus store for props
and scenery. You'll also need some fishing line and a couple of plastic
construction kits with burning candles stuck up their orifices, some
mud and a source of smoke - a cigar, or a pinch of dry ice. Because of
that, for the stated instructional purpose, I loved the film. and even
though it's not "Dark Star," it must have helped pave the wayThe kid's about to do a remake starring teddy bears and a washing-up
liquid bottle with fins stuck on. It should be no less convincing.I downloaded it from a public domain collection. Would I buy it? Probably not for more than £1.00
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2478692/comments</url><from>from Portland Oregon USA</from><name> (nenslo@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
I found that this movie actually slows down time. It seemed to take a
lot longer to watch than its actual running time. I was impressed in
good and bad ways by certain aspects of the movie: good in that it
placed a black man in a major and very sympathetic (though ultimately
tragic) role, bad in that it was nearly incoherent in every major
dramatic moment. The occasional "stirring philosophical monologues"
which being in space seems to inspire were truly baffling head-
shakers. The most impressive thing of all, and the one I will recall
long after the rest of the movie has faded in my memory, was an effect
sequence so cheesy that the explosion of a spaceship over one of the
moons of mars was emphasized by cutting in a half second of footage of
an explosion occurring BETWEEN TWO CARS IN A PARKING LOT. I went back
and looked at it very carefully to confirm this. I couldn't help
feeling that, like the Russo-American pastiches Voyage to a Prehistoric
Planet and Voyage to the Planet of Prehistoric Women, the model shots
might have been swiped from a slightly better film made in another
country. The director is also responsible for my all-time favorite
sci-fi film, The Wild Wild Planet, which seems to have everything this
one lacks, including a Butterfly Dance. I don't think even a Butterfly
Dance would make me want to see this, or even a few minutes of this,
again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6998072/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>cieloliquido</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Kubrick didn't think Marghriti's movies were so silly. Watch them
carefully and you will find 2001.Hear the desolation of the space, when Rick swims for the first time in
the space.Pay attention to the mad space ship that kills its crew.Follow the beginning, when the spacemen wake up: not so different from
the awakening of 2001.Watch all his science fiction movies carefully and you will find 2001.think he had no money and this is the first experiment, the first
Italian sci-fi movie.Margheriti deserves much more respect.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1348982/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>ephiriel</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I caught this one on the late-night movie screening...who knew that i
would
walk away from it not knowing wether i had actually enjoyed it?...but in
the
end i decided that i had enjoyed it.the story line is not bad....the staging &amp; effects were low budget. But
the
things i enjoyed most though were the "disintegration" scenes, the "space
craft landing/take-off" scenes, the "jumping out of the spacecraft" scenes
&amp;
who could not forget the final heroic scene before they all go hurtling
into
Earths' atmosphere???i would have rated it more than 4.6... probably around the 6-7 mark for
this
one :)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1348982/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>ephiriel</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I caught this one on the late-night movie screening...who knew that i
would
walk away from it not knowing wether i had actually enjoyed it?...but in
the
end i decided that i had enjoyed it.the story line is not bad....the staging &amp; effects were low budget. But
the
things i enjoyed most though were the "disintegration" scenes, the "space
craft landing/take-off" scenes, the "jumping out of the spacecraft" scenes
&amp;
who could not forget the final heroic scene before they all go hurtling
into
Earths' atmosphere???i would have rated it more than 4.6... probably around the 6-7 mark for
this
one :)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>