<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Il sepolcro dei re</original_title><alt_title>La vallée des pharaons</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Fernando Cerchio</director><producer>Explorer Film '58</producer><producer>Comptoir Français de Productions Cinématographiques (CFPC)</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Cleopatra, after the civil war that followed the assassination of Caesar, met with Marc Antony in Assyria where they planned the defense of Egypt against the Romans...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Debra Paget</actor><actor>Ettore Manni</actor><actor>Erno Crisa</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The film talks about Keops , alias Nemorat . Keops was the second
pharaoh of four dynasty from ancient Egyptian empire , and he made the
great pyramid of Gyze that bears his name . He is succeeded by Kefren
who built the sphinx Gyze and the pyramid of the same name . After goes
on pharaoh Micerinos. Three pharaohs have pyramids on Gyze : Keops,
Kefren and Micerinos.The movie centers upon scheming Kefren ( Erno Crisa ) and his dark
schemes to inherit Egyptian empire . Nemorat ( Conrado Pani )is
poisoned , and his wife ( Debra Paget ) is doomed to die with him into
the pyramid . Her lover ( Ettore Manni ) designs a plot to free her by
means of a potion. Before he will have to face a lot of dangers and
risks until obtain his objective . The film blends drama , adventures ,
love and hokey historical events . Direction by Fernando Cerchio is
professionally made , he directed many ¨ sword and sandals¨ and epic
films . Cinematography is well realized and Giovanni Fusco's musical
score is good . Set design and Egyptian time production design are
spectacular . Debra Paget is wonderful , support cast is nice , there
are American actors as Robert Alda ,though mostly are Italian players
as Andrea Bosic , Rosalba Neri..among others . Rating: 5,5/10 average
but entertaining .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

The beautiful young Sushila (Debra Paget) is forced into a political
marriage with young Pharaoh Nemorat in order to consolidate power. However,
the young Pharaoh is beset with mental illness and the marriage becomes
dangerous, all the while the chief advisor Kefren (a menacing Erno Crisa)
and his scheming mistress plot to destroy the unstable pair.  The girl is
framed for an attempt on the vulnerable king's life and sentenced to death. 
Meanwhile, her sympathetic would-be lover, the handsome physician Resi
(Ettore Manni in one of his best roles)concocts a scheme to save her by
drugging her to appear dead and reviving her later when they can escape. 
However, she is sealed into her former young husband's tomb with the air
supply rapidly running out.  The action plot proceeds at a brisk pace and
holds viewers interest which is increased by well-acted parts with
attractive players, great costumes and sets.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3233848/comments</url><from>from Cieszyn, Poland</from><name>Marcin Kukuczka</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The 1950s and 1960s were probably the times in the cinema history that
for long will be associated with sword and sandal epics, not only those
made by Hollywood studios but also by the Italian producers whose
careers did not spread worldwide. Since the famous Cinecitta Studios
near Rome grew popular for colossal American epics, such directors like
Carlo Ludovico Bragaglia or Fernando Cerchio also took a chance to make
movies of the genre with an attempt to depict historical periods in
their own way, sometimes more original, sometimes more influenced. And
in this way, we had movies like ANNIBALE, ERODE IL GRANDE, GIUSEPPE
VENDUTO DAI FRATELLI, and many others. IL SEPOLCHRO DEI RE, sometimes
misleadingly translated as CLEOPATRA'S DAUGHTER, is perhaps the least
popular of them but appears to convey something rare. To make my
comment clear, let me introduce short headlines before each paragraph.WHAT IS SO RARE ABOUT "CLEOPATRA'S DAUGHTER?" Let me say one significant thing: this movie builds a strong bridge
between Hollywood epics and Italian ones, like ANNIBALE did. This time,
the link is not the well built male star, a pioneering actor of the
genre, Victor Mature, but beautiful, subtle actress who must have made
this epic a vehicle to be seen in 1960, Debra Paget. The beautiful
Lucia from DEMETRIUS AND THE GLADIATORS and the unhappy Lilia from THE
TEN COMMANDMENTS plays the main role here, the role of exotic Shila
from a faraway kingdom of Assyria. And the effect is sheer delight. She
is absolutely brilliant in the role of the Assyrian princess - Egyptian
hostage who becomes the wife of Pharaoh but is soon, due to jealousy
and sick ambition, accused of assassination and sentenced to cruel
fate... SPOILER: But as long as there is romance, there is hope of
survival, there is room for justice, for punishing the wicked and for a
happy end... WILL THE LEADING ACTRESS MAKE YOUR DAY?It is true that the film was and still is worth seeing due to Debra
Paget who makes the story interesting and the whole film pretty
enjoyable to watch. The rest of the cast have their moments, but
moments of strength and weakness as well. Among better ones, I would
mention the famous Italian actor of that time, Ettore Manni. However,
generally these are average performances. It is only Debra Paget who
will make your day. TOO MUCH HAUNTED BY MORE COLOSSAL EPICS?If you expect this movie to stun you like some American movies of the
time, I once again refer to what I have already said: it is more
ANNIBALE than THE TEN COMMANDMENTS. Due to low budget, this film can
mostly offer interior sets, some are clearly fake, the costumes mix the
dynasties ruling in Egypt throughout centuries. The same can be said
about historical accuracy. The movie is rather an adventure than
history. Moreover, its content is built upon previous American films.
Resi (Ettore Manni), the surgeon, for instance, reminds me much of
Sinuhe, particularly in the scene when Pharaoh accuses him of healing
the poor. Ambitious Kefren is pretty much like Rameses from DeMille's
film, the only difference being the fact he is not the Pharaoh's son.JUST A FEW WORDS AT THE END...Not to make my comment too wordy because it is not one of those movies
that can be analyzed in more details, I'll put this in a nutshell: IL
SEPOLCHRO DEI RE is a film for epic buffs, for people who already have
some knowledge of the genre. Then, this may be understood in the right
way being seen as one among many others. Otherwise, the movie will be
an average adventure for you that you will see and will soon forget.
Unless, we take into consideration one more aspect that everyone will
find impressive: Debra Paget. 5/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4156245/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>clearwoodlouis</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I remember this film being on TV as a movie, which my mother didn't
like, so I never got a chance to see it for over 40 years until now. I
notice that this Italian movie is probably not about Cleopatra's
Daughter at all. Debra Paget somewhat fresh from "The Ten Commandments"
again revisits ancient Egpyt in this classic. The title of the Italian
original is "Sepolchro dei re," "Sepulchre of the King" shows that this
film could be about a New Kingdom pharaoh (16th to the 11th centuries
B.C.) rather than about a Ptolemaic one (4th to the 1st centuries
B.C.). I liked the film, and I was glad to be finally able to see it. A
famous reviewer says that the film is sadistic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
After her role as Lilia opposite John Derek in Cecil B. DeMille's The
Ten Commandments, roles started getting scarce on the big screen for
Debra Paget who as I write this review is the last living of the major
players left from that classic. Look at her credits, she did a lot of
television after that and like so many of her contemporaries, mostly
male though, went to Italy for big screen sand and sandal epics. But
Cleopatra's Daughter is in no way like the Elizabeth Taylor classic
that came out three years later. For if you remember in that fairly historically accurate film,
Cleopatra had no daughter with Julius Caesar or anyone else. She had a
son who disappeared after her overthrow, but no daughter. Assyria as a
kingdom was no more by Cleopatra's time and there were no more Pharoahs
ruling Egypt. Other than all this, Cleopatra's Daughter is a film of
great veracity, NOT.Cleo's kid played by Paget goes to live with the Assyrian royal house
who bring her up like their own, but now the new ruling house of Egypt,
presumably the one left there by Augustus has conquered Assyria and to
cement their usurping dynasty, the Queen Mother who really runs things
wants Debra to marry her idiot Pharoah son who is a real Mama's boy.Paget's got eyes for the royal physician Ettore Manni, but there's
folks with designs on the throne. She's implicated in the poisoning of
the Pharoah and sentenced to be put to death and buried in the great
tomb of Cheops which he has constructed (another historical anomaly).
Manni in a bit lifted from Romeo and Juliet gives Paget a potion that
will fake death and his task is to get her out of the tomb once it's
sealed up. Breaking in isn't easy and Manni gets some grave robbing
professionals to help him do it.If you think this is all ridiculous enough, it gets even worse, but I
won't reveal any more. I think that most Hollywood performers who went
to Italy to revive their sagging careers did their worst work there.
Only Clint Eastwood made a career from spaghetti westerns, no one did
it from gladiator films.All that was needed was for June Allyson to come on doing a chorus of
the Cleopatterer song that she did in Till The Clouds Roll By.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
After her role as Lilia opposite John Derek in Cecil B. DeMille's The
Ten Commandments, roles started getting scarce on the big screen for
Debra Paget who as I write this review is the last living of the major
players left from that classic. Look at her credits, she did a lot of
television after that and like so many of her contemporaries, mostly
male though, went to Italy for big screen sand and sandal epics. But
Cleopatra's Daughter is in no way like the Elizabeth Taylor classic
that came out three years later. For if you remember in that fairly historically accurate film,
Cleopatra had no daughter with Julius Caesar or anyone else. She had a
son who disappeared after her overthrow, but no daughter. Assyria as a
kingdom was no more by Cleopatra's time and there were no more Pharoahs
ruling Egypt. Other than all this, Cleopatra's Daughter is a film of
great veracity, NOT.Cleo's kid played by Paget goes to live with the Assyrian royal house
who bring her up like their own, but now the new ruling house of Egypt,
presumably the one left there by Augustus has conquered Assyria and to
cement their usurping dynasty, the Queen Mother who really runs things
wants Debra to marry her idiot Pharoah son who is a real Mama's boy.Paget's got eyes for the royal physician Ettore Manni, but there's
folks with designs on the throne. She's implicated in the poisoning of
the Pharoah and sentenced to be put to death and buried in the great
tomb of Cheops which he has constructed (another historical anomaly).
Manni in a bit lifted from Romeo and Juliet gives Paget a potion that
will fake death and his task is to get her out of the tomb once it's
sealed up. Breaking in isn't easy and Manni gets some grave robbing
professionals to help him do it.If you think this is all ridiculous enough, it gets even worse, but I
won't reveal any more. I think that most Hollywood performers who went
to Italy to revive their sagging careers did their worst work there.
Only Clint Eastwood made a career from spaghetti westerns, no one did
it from gladiator films.All that was needed was for June Allyson to come on doing a chorus of
the Cleopatterer song that she did in Till The Clouds Roll By.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>