<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Dil Apna Aur Preet Parai</original_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>Kishore Sahu</director><producer>Mohan Pictures</producer><genre>Musical</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Kusum Rai lives a wealthy lifestyle in scenic Kashmir with her widowed dad, Basant. Her dad had helped his friend's widow...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Raaj Kumar</actor><actor>Meena Kumari</actor><actor>Nadira</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15893490/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>vikramaditya-sharma</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Well one gets kinda easy on the rating , for the sheer respect of the
movies times...lack of technology and respect for the crew and cast.The music is mind blowing, my favorite being the title track -- dil
apna aur preet parai, the more popular and rememberable being -- ajeeb
dastaan hai yeh.ALL in all ...a lazy Sunday afternoon...preceded by a great lunch...can
make the ideal setting for this movie.Also get your parents to sit in with u, in case u r clueless about the
songs i mentioned...and you will get into the groove! Goodnight, and
good luck!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22238372/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>jmathur_swayamprabha</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Director Kishore Sahu gave Indian cine-lovers many good movies
especially in the black and white era. One such classic movie is Dil
Apna Aur Preet Paraaee (1960) starring Raaj Kumar, Meena Kumari and
Naadira. This movie not only tells a heart-conquering love story but
also underscores the significance of the noble medical profession.Kind-hearted orphan girl Karuna (Meena Kumari) joins a hospital as a
nurse and comes into the contact of Dr. Sushil Varma (Raaj Kumar).
Since both possess hearts of gold, filled with mercy, kindness,
benevolence and humanity; they start liking each other (in fact, loving
each other within their hearts). However Dr. Sushil has to marry Kusum
(Naadira) due to the obligations of her father upon himself and his
family. Proud (of her father's wealth), sniffy and nagging wife Kusum
makes life hell for not only Dr. Sushil but also his widow mother
(Pratima Devi) and his younger sister Munni (Baby Naaz). On the other
hand, heartbroken Karuna suddenly comes to know of Dr. Sushil's silent
love for her. Then she does not have any option but to shed tears over
this cruel joke played by the destiny with both of them. She tries to
quit the hospital but can't. When Kusum comes to know that her husband
loves Karuna within his heart, her womanly jealousy crosses all the
limits. Finally the movie reaches its happy ending with the union of
the lovers.Dil Apna Aur Preet Paraaee (the heart is own and the love is the
other's) takes the viewer to the era when love of a male and a female
was not express but silent. Still the loving hearts have always been
able to listen to the silent calls of each other. And that love is
reliable even on the screen. The scene in which Karuna sees her name
written by Dr. Sushil on pieces of paper and on neutral things and she
is able to listen to the love-filled sighs coming from his heart,
echoing her name only, is just superb. Anybody who has loved someone in
his / her life can identify with this scene.Besides, medicine has always been considered a noble profession (though
now it is also a means to earn more and more money only for the
majority of the people involved). And this movie emphatically
underscores this fact that the people joining this profession whether
as doctors or as nurses, should understand that their patients have
greater right on their lives as compared to their own right and the
right of their family members. The family members of such people have
to adjust to the occupational demands of them and should not be
irritating or resenting towards their activities, else they won't be
able to do justice to their duty and their profession. Through the
characters of various patients admitted in the hospital ward, the
moviemaker has stressed the need for the doctors and the nurses to keep
unlimited patience while dealing with them, in addition to the kindness
and sympathy which the patients require from them.To make the movie as an entertaining one, the director has infused
humour through some patients which is over the top at places. All the
same, this movie is filled with sentiments and it shows that emotional
bonds can develop in any setting between the people suffering from
common pains. It's a movie which deeply moves the viewer at many
places. And it also underscores the fact that if the life-partner is
non-understanding, supercilious and irritating; he / she may not only
snatch success from the other one but also make life worse than hell
for her / him.Performance wise assessing, Raaj Kumar has given a very impressive
performance in this movie without any overtones. Meena Kumari has not
only scored in the acting department but she has looked quite beautiful
too. It's definitely one of her best movies. Om Prakash impresses in
his cameo (as a patient). Shammi (as another nurse who is Karuna's
close friend), Pratima Devi as Dr. Sushil's mother, Baby Naaz as his
younger sister, Kumar as the head of the hospital etc. have done
justice to their roles. However, it's mainly Naadira's movie, perhaps
her best and the most memorable one. No viewer can forget her knockout
performance as the proud, ill-mannered and nagging woman.Shankar-Jaikishan has given unforgettable music in this movie with the
beautiful and touching lyrics having been penned by Hasrat Jaipuri and
Shailendra. The music of this movie boasts of Lata's immortal song -
Ajeeb Daastaan Hai Yeh Kahaan Shuru Kahaan Khatam. The title song is
another gem in Lata's voice. Other songs - Sheesha-e-Dil Itna Na
Uchhalo, Andaaz Mera Mastaana, Mera Dil Ab Tera O Saajna, Jaane Kahaan
Gayi, Itni Badi Mehfil Aur Ek Dil etc. are also quite good.
Picturization of the songs is also highly impressive.Technically the movie is good. It's not unduly long also. Though most
of the scenes are either in the hospital or in the household, the
scenes containing the river are quite beautiful. The cinematographer
has excelled like anything in the picturization of the title song. And
finally, the climax has been picturized sensationally.All in all, director Kishore Sahu has done a remarkable job. It's a
movie which will be liked by all - the people involved in the noble
profession of medicine, the viewers liking romantic musicals, the
social drama audience and the movie buffs in general as well. It's a
precious gem from the black and white era of Bollywood. Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22238372/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>jmathur_swayamprabha</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Director Kishore Sahu gave Indian cine-lovers many good movies
especially in the black and white era. One such classic movie is Dil
Apna Aur Preet Paraaee (1960) starring Raaj Kumar, Meena Kumari and
Naadira. This movie not only tells a heart-conquering love story but
also underscores the significance of the noble medical profession.Kind-hearted orphan girl Karuna (Meena Kumari) joins a hospital as a
nurse and comes into the contact of Dr. Sushil Varma (Raaj Kumar).
Since both possess hearts of gold, filled with mercy, kindness,
benevolence and humanity; they start liking each other (in fact, loving
each other within their hearts). However Dr. Sushil has to marry Kusum
(Naadira) due to the obligations of her father upon himself and his
family. Proud (of her father's wealth), sniffy and nagging wife Kusum
makes life hell for not only Dr. Sushil but also his widow mother
(Pratima Devi) and his younger sister Munni (Baby Naaz). On the other
hand, heartbroken Karuna suddenly comes to know of Dr. Sushil's silent
love for her. Then she does not have any option but to shed tears over
this cruel joke played by the destiny with both of them. She tries to
quit the hospital but can't. When Kusum comes to know that her husband
loves Karuna within his heart, her womanly jealousy crosses all the
limits. Finally the movie reaches its happy ending with the union of
the lovers.Dil Apna Aur Preet Paraaee (the heart is own and the love is the
other's) takes the viewer to the era when love of a male and a female
was not express but silent. Still the loving hearts have always been
able to listen to the silent calls of each other. And that love is
reliable even on the screen. The scene in which Karuna sees her name
written by Dr. Sushil on pieces of paper and on neutral things and she
is able to listen to the love-filled sighs coming from his heart,
echoing her name only, is just superb. Anybody who has loved someone in
his / her life can identify with this scene.Besides, medicine has always been considered a noble profession (though
now it is also a means to earn more and more money only for the
majority of the people involved). And this movie emphatically
underscores this fact that the people joining this profession whether
as doctors or as nurses, should understand that their patients have
greater right on their lives as compared to their own right and the
right of their family members. The family members of such people have
to adjust to the occupational demands of them and should not be
irritating or resenting towards their activities, else they won't be
able to do justice to their duty and their profession. Through the
characters of various patients admitted in the hospital ward, the
moviemaker has stressed the need for the doctors and the nurses to keep
unlimited patience while dealing with them, in addition to the kindness
and sympathy which the patients require from them.To make the movie as an entertaining one, the director has infused
humour through some patients which is over the top at places. All the
same, this movie is filled with sentiments and it shows that emotional
bonds can develop in any setting between the people suffering from
common pains. It's a movie which deeply moves the viewer at many
places. And it also underscores the fact that if the life-partner is
non-understanding, supercilious and irritating; he / she may not only
snatch success from the other one but also make life worse than hell
for her / him.Performance wise assessing, Raaj Kumar has given a very impressive
performance in this movie without any overtones. Meena Kumari has not
only scored in the acting department but she has looked quite beautiful
too. It's definitely one of her best movies. Om Prakash impresses in
his cameo (as a patient). Shammi (as another nurse who is Karuna's
close friend), Pratima Devi as Dr. Sushil's mother, Baby Naaz as his
younger sister, Kumar as the head of the hospital etc. have done
justice to their roles. However, it's mainly Naadira's movie, perhaps
her best and the most memorable one. No viewer can forget her knockout
performance as the proud, ill-mannered and nagging woman.Shankar-Jaikishan has given unforgettable music in this movie with the
beautiful and touching lyrics having been penned by Hasrat Jaipuri and
Shailendra. The music of this movie boasts of Lata's immortal song -
Ajeeb Daastaan Hai Yeh Kahaan Shuru Kahaan Khatam. The title song is
another gem in Lata's voice. Other songs - Sheesha-e-Dil Itna Na
Uchhalo, Andaaz Mera Mastaana, Mera Dil Ab Tera O Saajna, Jaane Kahaan
Gayi, Itni Badi Mehfil Aur Ek Dil etc. are also quite good.
Picturization of the songs is also highly impressive.Technically the movie is good. It's not unduly long also. Though most
of the scenes are either in the hospital or in the household, the
scenes containing the river are quite beautiful. The cinematographer
has excelled like anything in the picturization of the title song. And
finally, the climax has been picturized sensationally.All in all, director Kishore Sahu has done a remarkable job. It's a
movie which will be liked by all - the people involved in the noble
profession of medicine, the viewers liking romantic musicals, the
social drama audience and the movie buffs in general as well. It's a
precious gem from the black and white era of Bollywood. Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22238372/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>jmathur_swayamprabha</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>