<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La française et l'amour</original_title><imdb_rating>6.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Michel Boisrond</director><producer>Paris Elysées Films</producer><producer>Films Metzger et Woog</producer><producer>Auerbach Film Enterprises</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis/><actor>Jacqueline Porel</actor><actor>Pierre-Jean Vaillard</actor><actor>Darry Cowl</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The seven stages in the life of the modern Frenchwomen are disclosed by
seven directors in a witty way: (1) Childhood: a girl asks her parents
how the children are born and the adults do not know how to explain.
They discuss the subject with her teacher and friends and find an
unreasonable explanation. (2) Adolescence: A teenager flirts and kisses
many boys and her parents are worried about her behavior. (3)
Virginity: A young hairdresser is in doubt whether she shall go to bed
with her fiancé. She decides to spend her first night with him before
their wedding and they go to a hotel. However, she hesitates and her
fiancé surprisingly decides to wait for a next time. (4) Marriage: A
recently married couple travels by train to Paris for their honeymoon.
During the trip, their marriage is affected by jealousy and
selfishness. (5) Adultery: After ten years of marriage, a twenty-nine
year-old woman is frustrated with the attitudes of her husband. When
they have dinner with another couple, a young man flirts with the
married woman and they have a love affair. When her husband discovers
that his wife has a lover, his reaction is totally unexpected. (6)
Divorce: A married couple realizes that they are now only friends and
their relationship has no longer sex drive. They decide to have an
amicable divorce, but her mother, their friends and the lawyers spoil
their friendship. (7) The Single Woman: A Don Juan seduces women to
take advantage. However, when he meets a saleswoman that lives with an
old lady and a repressed friend, he seduces both women and ends in
prison.The seven segments of "La Française et l'Amour"have funny and also
dated moments, but in general they are entertaining. My favorite is the
first one ("Childhoo"), the fifth ("Adultery") and the sixth
("Divorce"). It is funny to see how a modern society in 1960 is do
dated fifty-one years later. My vote is seven.Title (Brazil): "A Francesa e o Amor" ("The Frenchwoman and the Love")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This is one of the innumerable portmanteau films which flooded the
European market during the 50s and 60s. I haven't watched that many of
them and, actually, have a few on VHS which I still need to check out!
It isn't anything special, really, but certainly passes the time
agreeably enough - featuring some amusing animation during the narrated
linking sequences.None of the seven directors creates a classic with his individual
segment - but, as is to be expected, some episodes are better than
others: the funniest is the first by Decoin about the dilemma parents
face when it is time for them to explain to their children how babies
are born; the fourth segment by Clair is fairly sophisticated but
rather lacks the wit of his best work; the fifth by Verneuil concerns
adultery, with the two men involved played by Paul Meurisse (the
husband) and Jean-Paul Belmondo (the lover); the sixth episode by
Christian-Jaque about the surmounting legal problems of a couple about
to divorce (despite their mutual consent to it!) is delightfully
enacted by Annie Girardot and Francois Perier; the rest are watchable
but not especially rewarding.By the way, though the film is supposed to be 143 minutes long, the Fox
Lorber DVD ran for only 132!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is an interesting film because like several other European films
of the 1960s it's an anthology--directed by several different people.
However, unlike many such films, this one actually plays almost like
one long story instead of a collection of short films--especially
because in a few stories, the characters appear to be the same--just
older. Each story is about a different aspect of love--such as
curiosity, marriage, infidelity and divorce. They all purport to be
about women, though without the men in the film, none of these stories
would have worked! Now compared to American films of 1960, this film
might have seemed a tad bawdy. After all, it talked about adultery,
premarital sex and the like, though a few American films of the day
actually were beginning to address these issues as well--just not quite
as quickly and directly as this film. Though, even for the supposedly
open French, it was cute to see that the French parents, too, struggled
with telling their kids the true facts of life. Also, while the film
could seem a bit amoral in not openly condemning adultery, the film
also seemed to affirm marriage in the cute segment where divorce
lawyers and a nosy mother managed to ruin a perfectly good divorce.Overall, the directing, writing and acting were all very good and I
really had a hard time telling that they actually used multiple
directors, as they all seemed well integrated into the film and were
universally entertaining.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is an interesting film because like several other European films
of the 1960s it's an anthology--directed by several different people.
However, unlike many such films, this one actually plays almost like
one long story instead of a collection of short films--especially
because in a few stories, the characters appear to be the same--just
older. Each story is about a different aspect of love--such as
curiosity, marriage, infidelity and divorce. They all purport to be
about women, though without the men in the film, none of these stories
would have worked! Now compared to American films of 1960, this film
might have seemed a tad bawdy. After all, it talked about adultery,
premarital sex and the like, though a few American films of the day
actually were beginning to address these issues as well--just not quite
as quickly and directly as this film. Though, even for the supposedly
open French, it was cute to see that the French parents, too, struggled
with telling their kids the true facts of life. Also, while the film
could seem a bit amoral in not openly condemning adultery, the film
also seemed to affirm marriage in the cute segment where divorce
lawyers and a nosy mother managed to ruin a perfectly good divorce.Overall, the directing, writing and acting were all very good and I
really had a hard time telling that they actually used multiple
directors, as they all seemed well integrated into the film and were
universally entertaining.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/liebelei_1936/comments.php?reviewid=1401026</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117792573.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/liebelei_1936/comments.php?reviewid=1746427</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/80387/liebelei.html /m/liebelei_1936/comments.php?reviewid=1481237</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nora-sayre/</url><url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/mem/movies/review.html?title1=&amp;title2=Liebelei&amp;reviewer=&amp;v_id=29172&amp;pdate=19330702&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/liebelei_1936/comments.php?reviewid=1389460</url><name>Nora Sayre</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=105306 /m/liebelei_1936/comments.php?reviewid=1149127</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>