<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Swiss Family Robinson</original_title><alt_title>Les Robinsons des mers du sud</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Ken Annakin</director><producer>Walt Disney Productions</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Family</genre><synopsis>
A Swiss settler family is shipwrecked on a desert island.
</synopsis><actor>John Mills</actor><actor>Dorothy McGuire</actor><actor>James MacArthur</actor><rt_rating>6.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>83</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0522062/comments</url><from>from Seattle</from><name>notmicro</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

IMBD refused to post this in the "Trivia" section, so I'll add it as a
comment:  note that throughout the film, the men are often shirtless;
however their pants and shorts are always carefully tailored to cover their
navels, like Barbara Eden's harem-pants in "I Dream of
Jeannie".If you have access to the DVD, it is very well worth it to watch the
special-features documentaries and interviews on disc 2.  What the actors
and crew went through to make this thing is incredible!  The many animals
used are mostly nasty and potentially very dangerous.  That no one got
disemboweled by a zebra or ostrich kick, or a tiger-claw, is a miracle; let
alone the face-off scene with the hyenas!  Wrestling an anaconda chest-deep
in a mosquito and leech-infested swamp is probably not a role most actors
dream of.  James MacArthur was told by the snake's handler to just dunk the
snake's head under water when it started to constrict him; apparently it
worked, as he lived to tell the tale!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0371125/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon</from><name>kolob (dan6305@earthlink.net)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is one of Disney's best efforts.  Beautiful scenery, great
soundtrack music, and a hard-working cast add much to this compelling story
of a shipwrecked family.  To me this film is an exception to the
less-weighty fare that Disney was wont to produce over the years.  I like
Disney flicks, but this is one I can go back and watch when I want to get
lost in an idyllic setting (with beautiful soundtrack music to establish
the
mood).  You've gotta love those coconut bombs!  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3747472/comments</url><from>from michigan</from><name>mhrabovsky1-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Pure Disney magic! What a movie....might just be the greatest Disney
film of all, might throw in "Pollyanna" and "Song of the South" in
there as close competition. What is there not to like? Beautiful
photography and a perfect casting of Dorothy McGuire as the mother who
is the glue that holds the family together along with the suave British
actor John Mills (Hayley's father) as the dad of the family. Great
opening scene of foundering ship nearly stuck on a reef during violent
storm...family quickly recognizes they will be on the island for the
long haul and makes it an island paradise complete with a tree house
that the Hilton hotel chain could rent out for big bucks. Family makes
use of every scrap of fabric, wood, powder, and weapons as they
struggle to survive the hazards of the island they are stranded upon.
How in the world did the Disney team transport all of the animals onto
that small island for this wonderful film? Zebras, elephants, snakes,
tigers, and throw in an ostrich too for a family fun filled ride
picnic. Only thing I wondered about was how the entire crew of pirates
seem to be madeup of asians....most pirates in films are usually
caucasians. Tommy Kirk, Kevin Corcoran, who flew into Tobago days after
finishing "Pollyanna" and James McArthur play splendid roles as the
three sons who grow up physically and discover themselves as young men
on the island. Love the scenes of the watering hole complete with a
natural water slide and swinging vines to traipse back and forth on.
Janet Munro plays the stranded girl, rescued by McArthur and Kirk, and
becomes a tug of war for affection between the two. Just the scenery
alone on the island and the lagoons makes me want to visit the filming
sight. This is a timeless classic, watch it a couple of times a year
and it is just as entertaining the second time as the first. Wish
Disney would re-release this film to theatres so you could see it on a
big wide screen, preferably Imax. Movies just do not get any better
than this one. Perfect film for family viewing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1767238/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, CA</from><name>Kirsten</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I loved this movie growing up, and had to get the recent DVD.  It's great!
The extras are wonderful and the movie is even better.  I love Disney
movies, but some of the older live-action movies get annoying to me after
awhile.  This one doesn't.  I love to imagine myself on that island with
all
the animals and fighting pirates.  It's great.  I definitely recommend
it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2866060/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas, NV</from><name>Doramius</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Anybody that votes or has voted less than a 5 on this has either lied about
watching it or has gotten a little to caught up on political correctness, or
has found poor taste in movies.  Basically, if you were orphaned at birth
and nobody adopted you and became a neo-nazi, this MAY be something you
won't find interesting.This is among the early Disney Classics &amp; Greats.  A great cast put into a
pirate tale that brings the whole family together.  Though the screenplay is
a bit old and the music sounds as if its from 'Gone With The Wind', what
else would you expect from the time this was made?  A family is shipwrecked on an uncharted island and they make do with the
means and supplies they have.  They build an exotic home on what seems like
an island paradise.  In an effort to get a better idea of where they are and
what they have to deal with, the older two sons go out on an exploration of
the island.  While around the other side, they meet up with pirates holding
two hostages.  They take the youth hostage per the captive father's request
and head on back to the camp to notify their parents and prepare if the
pirates happen to come their way.  There is a wonderful action battle that brings classic excitement to all
those young and old.  In the true form of a Disney Classic, the storyline
and character development is done beautifully.This is one of those items you'd go to the theater to see on the BIG SCREEN
multiple time if it were available again.  Definite add to the
collection.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
SWISS FAMILY ROBINSON is the ultimate family adventure film from
Disney, photographed on the island of Tobago for some lush scenery and
exotic settings. But that tree house rules!! Everyone's favorite
fantasy is this sort of adventure whereby a shipwrecked family finds
refuge on what appears to be a deserted island, only to find that
they're not exactly alone.DOROTHY McGUIRE and JOHN MILLS play the parent roles (played originally
by Thomas Mitchell and Edna Best in the B&amp;W '40 version), and the kids
are played with equal skill by Kevin Corcoran, Tommy Kirk and JAMES
MacARTHUR, who excels as the oldest son.There's some rough going when the pirates invade, but it's all done in
true Disney style and you know there's going to be a happy ending.Summing up: The kind of film the whole family can enjoy. A lot more
visually appealing than the old B&amp;W version filmed on RKO sound stages.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10575163/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>lawrence_elliott</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a Disney adventure film at its best. Excitement, adventure, far
off exotic places, shipwrecks, pirates - all the ingredients for a
thrilling recipe of family ties that bind (love), and respect for a
father who protects and leads his family to battle the hostile elements
of the outside world in order to survive.Tigers in pits, wild animals domesticated, outside fresh air away from
all civilization, this is a movie for the whole family to watch
together, preferably on a big screen at a theatre, where the producers
designed to have it seen in the first place.This movie is fun, exciting and scary with pirate ships and uphill
battles that make this one worth owning.I remember my Dad took me to see this film when I was 7 years old and
the nostalgia of security of family rooted in a firm grounding and
foundation of family tradition, for me made this film a memorable one
for all time. I hope you enjoy this one too for old time's sake.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0417992/comments</url><from>from CA</from><name>PeachHamBeach</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
En route to New Guinea, a ship is chased into a hurricane and ends up
deserted by its crew and wrecked against the rocks of an island in the
Indian or Pacific Ocean. The only passengers remaining on board the
crippled vessel are a Swiss family who have been fleeing from possible
entanglement in war due to the dealings of Neopoleon.There are a father (Sir John Mills), a mother (Dorothy McGuire) and
three boys, Fritz (James MacArthur), Ernst (Tommy Kirk) and little
Francis (Kevin Corcoran). Although Mother believes a ship will come
along any time and rescue them from the island, Father feels its best
to avoid trying to use fire or any means of getting attention lest the
pirates that attacked them before should return to finish the job.Slowly, the family begins to realize what a beautiful place God put
them in, for whatever His reasons. There are lots of cool animals,
beautiful waterfalls, lush greenery, plenty of food. Eventually, the
men build a wonderous tree house, and anything they could need or wish
for is right there. Should they bother going on to New Guinea??? Mother
still thinks its practical compared with living on the island, and
besides, with no other people living there, how will her sons ever know
what it's like to be married and have families of their own??? The two
eldest sons, Fritz and Ernst, talk their parents into letting them sail
the coast of their island, to find out if there are any ports, towns or
options that will speed their rescue and get them to New Guinea. They
don't find anything except the same blasted pirate band who gave them
problems before, and this time the cutthroats have taken an Englishman
and his "grandson" Bertie for ransom. The Robinson boys manage to get
the grandson out of danger, and soon find out that Bertie is not a boy,
but a girl named Roberta, who fearing being victimized by the ruthless
pirates, chopped off her red hair and wore boys clothing.Immediately, an often hilarious rivalry for the girl's affection begins
between Fritz and Ernst. Ernst spouts off dorky quotes from famous
authors while Fritz rolls his eyes and just does his thing. I had a
HUGE crush on Fritz when I was a kid...I guess you could call him one
of my retro-babes!!! On Christmas, the boys and Roberta reach the tree
house and the family begins preparations for facing the pirates, who
undoubtedly will come along looking for Roberta. The battle with the
pirates is made ceaselessly entertaining by the tiger pits, the coconut
bombs, the pirate bells, the snares, the rigged bridge, logpile and of
course, the gun and sword fighting.Some family films, even ones I like, can be boring sometimes, or too
full of Pollyanna-ism...but SWISS FAMILY is really action packed and
entertaining. I never get bored.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1588706/comments</url><from>from Orlando, Florida</from><name>Pepper Anne</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The Swiss Family Robinson is one of the best family adventure films, and
definitely one of Disney's finest family films. Based on the Johan Wyss
novel is the story of a British family shipwrecked during a storm,
interuppting their migration to New Guinea.Not sure of how long they will be stranded or the whereabouts of the
remaining crew (Disney ambiguously glosses over the issue of whether the
crew is dead, but given the presence of sharks in the ocean and the tenacity
of the storm the caused the wreck, I think it's safe assume they're night),
they make the new island their home. Any young kids would probably love this
aspect of the movie, the thought of having the jungle where you get to play
in the river and build one of the most gnarliest treehouses (oddly complete
with many modern conveniences despite the lack of electricity, etc). I would
imagine that the actors who played the three brothers (Disney regulars, of
course) had a lot of fun filming this movie. (Note: They recreated the
treehouse for a walk-through tour at the Orlando Walt Disney World theme
park).But, as Mother Robinson (Dorothy MacGuire) suggests, their jungle abode
should only be considered temporary, because they can't forget that they are
the only ones on the island. Being the typical maternal Disney character,
she worries staying on the island provides no life and no opportunity for
the three sons, Francis (MacArthur), Ernst (Kirk), and Francis (Corcoran),
especially because there are no other girls there other than Mother. But the
boys and their father (Sir John Mills) are also aware that they must also
question whether it is a good idea to stay there because the pirate ship
that they keep seeing. Pirates and treehouses? Oh, this is a good adventure story! The only way
they can tell whether they're on a peninsuala (Enrst suggests there is or
was a land bridge because of the presence of many different animal species
in one area) or an island is if the two oldest brothers try sailing around
it. And that's where they run into a gang of pirates who have taken a
British diplomat and his kid hostage. Saving them would make the Robinson
boys pirate targets for sure, and their family, too. But, it seems like the
Robinsons are ready for anything. Who's scared of a little machette-weilding
pirate, eh?This is a fantastic adventure film for younger children, though they may
tend to get bored by some of the dreamy conversations between Mother and
Father Robinson as they discuss their son's prospects and other concerns
about the island. But, it is often non-stop adventure and looks like a lot
of fun (like the Ostrich racing scene). Present, however, are some of the Disney stereotypical elements. The
pirates, the villains, are Asian (I don't even think the pirate actors use a
real language) and the good guys are the British. The female characters
don't do any strong arm work and often engage in conversations limited to
domestics (family life, nothing too intelligent). When Roberta is revealed
to be a girl, all of a sudden anything she did that was macho while in
disquise, vanishes and she becomes a helpless girl (it is Francis and Ernst
who have to wrestle the snake and Roberta freaks at the sight of a lizard
and so forth). Despite all of that, this is exemplary of what good old-fashioned adventure
tales were made of, so younger boys would definitely be drawn to those
elements, and hopefully, younger girls as well. Pirate chases, monster
treehouses, snake wrestling. It's good times. And surprising for an older
Disney film, has very little singing numbers. Skip on the remake of the 'The
Swiss Family Robinson' and check this one out. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6534931/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>coolcowboyken</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
"Swiss Family Robinson" is a classic! It's my all time favorite film by
Walt Disney. I like the storyline and characters. It's a feel good
adventure. One thing I always liked about this movie is the family was
like a real family, no one perfectly got along. The boys had their own
fights with each other. The rivalry between Fritz (James MacArthur) and
Ernst (Tommy Kirk) who both want the girl, Roberta (Janet Munro)is
funny and good. This is better than most Disney live action films. As a
child this was my favorite film, and I still find it great today.
Having been born way after the movie first came out, I'm still taken in
by this timeless adventure. I think the whole cast did a great job and
it's good to be able to sit down with a bowl of popcorn and enjoy this
with family. The 2-Disc DVD is a must have for any fan of "Swiss Family
Robinson", It has all kind of features and making videos with the cast
and crew.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6534931/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>coolcowboyken</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
"Swiss Family Robinson" is a classic! It's my all time favorite film by
Walt Disney. I like the storyline and characters. It's a feel good
adventure. One thing I always liked about this movie is the family was
like a real family, no one perfectly got along. The boys had their own
fights with each other. The rivalry between Fritz (James MacArthur) and
Ernst (Tommy Kirk) who both want the girl, Roberta (Janet Munro)is
funny and good. This is better than most Disney live action films. As a
child this was my favorite film, and I still find it great today.
Having been born way after the movie first came out, I'm still taken in
by this timeless adventure. I think the whole cast did a great job and
it's good to be able to sit down with a bowl of popcorn and enjoy this
with family. The 2-Disc DVD is a must have for any fan of "Swiss Family
Robinson", It has all kind of features and making videos with the cast
and crew.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/common-sense-media-editors/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/swiss-family-robinson  /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1950356</url><name>Common Sense Media Editors</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Good intro for kids reluctant to watch old movies.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=16180 /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1922430</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>There's something for everybody in this Disney's live action adventure made for the entire family, which may explain why it was the most commercially popular film of 1960.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,828719,00.html /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1801250</url><from>TIME Magazine</from></reviewer><comment>The Swiss Family Robinson, like most of Walt Disney's screen versions of the children's classics, is good Disney and bad culture.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/alistair-harkness/</url><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=137636&amp;section=review /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1801249</url><name>Alistair Harkness</name><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>It's no Pirates Of The Caribbean but the spirit of adventure, and Disney's high production values, means that there's still some fun to be had watching this wholesome family adapt to island life.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steven-d-greydanus/</url><url>http://www.decentfilms.com/sections/reviews/1649 /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1484148</url><name>Steven D. Greydanus</name><from>Decent Films Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Chock-full of exotic locations and animals, desert-island DIY ingenuity, and high-spirited excitement, with a poignant subplot involving the rivalry of the two elder sons.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/douglas-pratt/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1400142</url><name>Douglas Pratt</name><from>DVDLaser</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>The escapist atmosphere is still difficult to resist.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-plath/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1397259</url><name>James Plath</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Classic family adventure with pirates and animals on an exotic island. What's not to love?</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C05E5DD1531EF3ABC4C51DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1390463</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment>It's hard to imagine how the picture could be better as a rousing, humorous and gentle-hearted tale of family love amid primitive isolation and dangers.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rich-cline/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1364269</url><name>Rich Cline</name><from>Shadows on the Wall</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>unrealistic disney fun</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dan-fazio/</url><url>http://losangeles.citysearch.com/review/15781553/editorial/ /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1198231</url><name>Dan Fazio</name><from>Citysearch</from></reviewer><rating>
6/10
					</rating><comment>Should be called Swiss Army Robinson.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Swiss-Family-Robinson /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=313292</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>With mom's parasols and dad's water wheel inventions, this family looks like the original inhabitants of Gilligan's Island. Of course, this is not meant to be a comedy...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-rhodes/</url><url>http://reviews.imdb.com/Reviews/53/5320 /m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=18855</url><name>Steve Rhodes</name><from>Internet Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>It has atmosphere, wild animals, pirates, and most of all, an awe-inspiring sense of wonderment about creativity in general and about inventions in particular. Director Ken Annakin fashions an imaginative and special movie.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1412635</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1394502</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jon-niccum/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1293238</url><name>Jon Niccum</name><from>Lawrence Journal-World</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=1216562</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rebecca-murray/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=845259</url><name>Rebecca Murray</name><from>About.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/joshua-tyler/</url><url>/m/1020736-swiss_family_robinson/comments.php?reviewid=760295</url><name>Joshua Tyler</name><from>CinemaBlend.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>