<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Risate di gioia</original_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Mario Monicelli</director><producer>Titanus</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
On New Year's Eve, an insecure, struggling actress (Anna Magnani) has nothing to do. When a colleague invites her to a New Year's party...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Anna Magnani</actor><actor>Totò</actor><actor>Ben Gazzara</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3192976/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, USA</from><name>marcosaguado</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The pleasures of this tragicomedy are constant and long
lasting.
Anna Magnani, after her Oscar, back at home with her old pal Toto. They
even
do a bit of one of their old music-hall routines.
Mario Monicelli's sensational style makes the film as funny, sad today as
it
was then.
Remember, Monicelli is the man behind that other Italian gem "Big Deal At
Madonna Street" There is mix of Billy Wilder and Martin Scorsese and if
you
saw the film you know what I mean.
Funny, bitter, funny.
Anna Magnani plays a movie extra, with delusions of Kim
Novak.
Not to be missed!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16641058/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>Daniele Pinto</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A friend had a wonderful idea. After the depressing presence of the
Italian entries at this 2007 Venice Film Festival, he suggested to get
together around a table with good food and wine a watch a movie, an
Italian movie and not one of the usual masterpieces that we all talk
about all the time. He chose Mario Monicelli's "Risate Di Gioa" with
Anna Magnani, Totò and Ben Gazzara. Oh my God! All of a sudden it
became one of my favorite films of all time. It all takes place during
a New Year's eve in Rome and I'm at a loss for words trying to explain
the brilliance of this dark "minor" Italian comedy. A blonde Anna
Magnani plays a film extra at the Cinecitta studios and Totò a petty
thief in white tie and tails. Funny, moving, extraordinary in some many
ways. Why have we moved so far away from this? Can somebody explain it?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1001033/comments</url><from>from Washington DC</from><name>nbott</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I just had the extreme pleasure of seeing this classic comedy at a special
retrospective at the National Gallery of Art. Anna Magnani almost steals
the
movie from our man Toto. Ben Gazzara is wonderful as a small-time crook who
is stuck with Toto as his accomplice as they plan to steal small items
during the New Year's festivities in town. However, our heroine constantly
seems to be messing up the best laid plans of our  two criminal friends.This film uses the time-honored technique of having the audience identify
with some real sympathy with our characters but we must laugh as everything
goes wrong with everyone's plans for both the New Year's eve celebration,
the robbery plans and life in general.I do not know if this film is on video or if any of the classic films with
Toto are on video. However, anyone who values great comedic filmmaking
should make the effort to see this film. It simply does not get better than
this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3490627/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>francescocura</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This film is probably the best showcase of the comedic capacities of
acting genius Anna Magnani. Here she's paired up with Italian actor
Toto', who's considered the most representative Italian comedian of all
times. The chemistry between the two is the source of a splendid chain
of events that allow the two actors to explore a multitude of highs and
lows...almost like in a carnival. Monicelli's intricate story line is a
rarity in the world of comedies. Intelligent, entertaining and
hilarious, the film contains the only example (on camera) of what Anna
Magnani and Toto' would do in Rome during the 1930's: "Avanspettacolo".
The two sing on a small stage at one of Rome's fashionable parties: all
done with immense presence and class; the result is a magnificent
theatrical moment between improvisation and highly refined performing
skills. Definitely a must for those who love quality comedies.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17402599/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Ubaldo Martinez</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
New Year's Eve in Rome. Three lonely character who lie about their
solitude to everyone even to themselves. Deep down is that solitude and
a a sense of rejection what throws them together. Magnani, as a blonde
film extra that has Kim Novak as her model, Totò as a pathetic, old
petty con-man and Ben Gazzara as a young, good looking and relatively
inept thief, will join forces at cross purposes in a film that is,
simultaneously, outrageously funny and deeply moving. Anna Magnani had
already won an Oscar for "The Rose Tattoo" and this was a return home
and a a new chapter in her collaboration with her old friend Antonio De
Curtis, known as Totò. They are magic together and Mario Monicelli
knows how to choreograph the sequences for this two amazing artists.
The crowded scenes inside a Hotel Restaurant during the party leading
to midnight and a new year are absolutely sensational. Not to be
missed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10070859/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Yolanda Rodriguez</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film 40 years ago as "The Passionate Thief" and it still
makes me laugh when I think about it, which is often. Anna Magnani's
appallingly delusional "blonde" actress is unforgettable as she, with
her old standby Toto, blunder their way through this pathetic
misadventure worthy of a New Year's Eve. Ben Gazzara's con man/thief is
juicy and sexy enough to make any woman his accomplice, willing or
accidental, and the tragic-comic tension between Ms. Magnani and the
thief is pure comedy. This film really belongs in the category of Billy
Wilder films and why it is not better known is beyond me. Given a
choice, I would be hard pressed to decide whether The Passionate Thief
or Die Fledermaus is my favorite New Year's party. I cannot recommend
this film enough, especially to fans of Bunuel and Wilder.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10070859/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Yolanda Rodriguez</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film 40 years ago as "The Passionate Thief" and it still
makes me laugh when I think about it, which is often. Anna Magnani's
appallingly delusional "blonde" actress is unforgettable as she, with
her old standby Toto, blunder their way through this pathetic
misadventure worthy of a New Year's Eve. Ben Gazzara's con man/thief is
juicy and sexy enough to make any woman his accomplice, willing or
accidental, and the tragic-comic tension between Ms. Magnani and the
thief is pure comedy. This film really belongs in the category of Billy
Wilder films and why it is not better known is beyond me. Given a
choice, I would be hard pressed to decide whether The Passionate Thief
or Die Fledermaus is my favorite New Year's party. I cannot recommend
this film enough, especially to fans of Bunuel and Wilder.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10070859/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Yolanda Rodriguez</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ted-shen/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/20476_PASSIONATE_THIEF.html /m/passionate-thief-the/comments.php?reviewid=1972417</url><name>Ted Shen</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>