<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Amazing Transparent Man</original_title><alt_title>L'incroyable homme invisible</alt_title><imdb_rating>3.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Edgar G. Ulmer</director><producer>Miller Consolidated Pictures (MCP)</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
A crazed scientist invents an invisibility formula. He plans to use the formula to create an army of invisible zombies.
</synopsis><actor>Marguerite Chapman</actor><actor>Douglas Kennedy</actor><actor>James Griffith</actor><rt_rating>5/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>40</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0100872/comments</url><from>from Westland, MI, USA</from><name>Matt Huls (cowman777@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Before viewing this 1960 drive-in hit, keep in mind that it is not really a
serious attempt at science fiction.  Many critics and viewers have panned
this movie because they expected some sort of INVISIBLE MAN-style plot with
good acting and plenty of special effects.  But if it was high-quality
cinema they were looking for, then why in the hell did they choose to watch
a movie with a title like "THE AMAZING TRANSPARENT MAN"?Viewers with no expectations, a good sense of humor, and an open mind will
probably enjoy this bizarre little sci-fi romp.  The whole mad
scientist/escaped prisoner/invisible Nazi story is beyond befuddling, but it
is so unbelievably far-fetched that you'll be entertained
anyway.THE AMAZING TRANSPARENT MAN does a nice job at not dawdling on boring fake
science jargon (a shortcoming that most sci-fi yarns of this era suffer
from) and somehow manages to dole out one outrageous scene after another
during its unusually short running time.  Within the course of 58 minutes,
you will witness invisible fist fights, invisible robberies, atomic blasts,
jailbreaks, in-your-face anti-nuclear-weaponry overtones, and a whole
barrage of people stealing from and/or deceiving one another.  Every single
character either betrays or holds one another hostage at some point during
the picture.If you're in the mood for something that is so goofy and so off-the-wall
that it defies description, then I suggest you run out the VHS cut-out bin
nearest you and pick up this movie.  Trust me, you'll be glad you
did.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0381265/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>Infofreak</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Why are people so down on this modest but enjoyable movie? Beats me. Joey
Faust (what a name!), safecracker, is busted out of the pokey and made an
offer - turn invisible and steal radium for a mad scientist/soldier planning
on setting up an invisible army to conquer the world. Joey goes along with
it but quickly decides to use his powers for what comes naturally - stealing
lots of do re mi. This causes conflict as you can imagine, and then his
invisibility goes on the fritz. Faust is played by Douglas Kennedy who
played one of the cops in 'Invaders From Mars', the baddie is James Griffith
who had a bit part in Kubrick's 'The Killing', and the movie was directed by
Edward G. Ulmer who made the strange Lugosi/Karloff classic 'The Black Cat'
back in the 1930s. 'The Amazing Transparent Man' won't change your life, but
it's entertaining enough. Worth a look for fans of 1960s/60s b-grade
thrillers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1388629/comments</url><from>from West Virginia</from><name>Bucs1960</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Another early black and white sci-fi film with some promise........at least
in the beginning.  Mad dictator "wanna be" springs bank robber from prison
to use him in his plan for taking over the world with an invisible army. 
Sound outrageous?  You bet!  The sets are cheesy, the story is pretty
stupid, the actors either overact or can't act at all, the ending is over
the top.......these are all part of the elements that make low budget films
fun to watch.  Besides, it was directed by Edgar Ulmer, who did some
fascinating work.  But for some reason, this one is disagreeable.There are holes in the plot as big as Rhode Island and there is something
very sleazy about all the actors, even though a couple of them are mainstays
of "B" films, and in the case of Ivan Treisault, "A" list big productions
("Notorious", for example.)And there is that constant bickering........it
seems that 75% of the dialogue is shouted.  The special effects......well,
I've seen worse, much worse, even though you can see the wires.  We've seen
wires in films before.  So what is it that makes this little programmer
unpleasant?  It just doesn't seem to gel but I don't know why.  Maybe it was
that Wurlitzer organ in the middle of the living room! So catch it on MST3K
with Mike and the 'bots.....without them, it is pretty damn
dismal.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3824745/comments</url><from>from Vulcan</from><name>mstomaso</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Some aspects of Ulmer's Amazing Transparent Man are, in retrospect,
pretty funny. James Griffith's poorly mimed fight with an invisible
man, the occasional continuity disasters, and the infrequent
technobabble are examples. This is not, however, quite funny enough or
cheesy enough to have been good MST3K fodder. Underlying the mediocre
special effects, the occasionally overblown dialog, and the uneven
performances, the story line presents an interesting take on the
invisible man theme.The heavy, played without much verve by James Griffith, is an ex-Nazi
spy who looks and speaks like Mr. Rogers. His plan, involving all
manners of extortion, involves forcing refugee German scientist (Ivan
Triesault) to use radiation to turn an escaped convict safe-cracker
(Douglas Kennedy) invisible. His goal is ostensibly to steal money and
radioactive materials to further his experiments. In the role of his
co-conspirator and femme fatale we find Marguerite Chapman.Chapman and Kennedy have some on-screen chemistry which is used to good
advantage in the film, but Chapman's performance is below par. Kennedy
does well in a role which used his experience well. Griffith's
performance, given his credentials, is surprisingly poor. The ancient
and experienced Triesault, the class of the acting talent in this film,
steals the show to an extent, but is also the only really sympathetic
character in the lot.The movie has a somewhat plodding pace at first, but the character
development is good enough to draw the audience in. The Amazing
Transparent Man is no action film, but once the action begins, it
doesn't really let up until the nicely climactic end. Despite all of
the bad press this film has received here on IMDb, this film really
isn't a bomb, and I recommend it to sci-fi and low budget b movie
buffs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4103048/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>FranklinTV</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
A title like "The Amazing Transparent Man" does have you seriously
wondering on how poor the movie you are about to watch will be - - for
a start, he can't even achieve invisibility (only transparency), so
what is 'amazing' about that? But the opening titles suggest you might get something a bit better
than you were bracing yourself for. It's quite a good mood setting,
with the music involving a cello grinding 4 repeating notes ominously.
The other give away is that in the opening credits, the directors and
producers names are shown in running-writing style - clearly both
artists. And the opening prison escape bit is good, as well as the
police checkpoint scene, and they involve some nicely framed external
shots.In fact its all looking like this might be a surprisingly enjoyable
film, until the escaped safe-cracking crim Faust (played by Douglas
Kennedy) has his first real indoor talking scene. And then you realize
that for some reason only known to him, Mr Kennedy plays Faust like
some "John Wayne" cowboy. Why a safe cracker would also be a swaggering
tough guy who looks like he is ready to say "Ok Pilgrim" is a constant
annoyance which does tend to cripple the film. Anyway - - I don't think I'm giving much away to point out the early
setup in the film when Krenner (the Bad Guy) says something like "Dr,
make sure the radioactive material is kept away from the beam, or else
we will all blow up", and then Dr Ulof repeating something similar back
to Krenner five minutes later - - clearly, something is eventually
going to go wrong along these lines much later in the film, and they
really don't want you to miss it.The other annoying thing about this movie is how quickly the characters
(Faust, Krenner, Dr Ulof, Laura (the bad guys girl), and Julian (the
bad guys hired help)) seems to keep swapping alliances and personality,
all as a result of some simple statement that would even make a daytime
soap opera blush.(eg: a "But your son is dead" has Julian swapping
sides without a thought that "Hey, maybe she is lying because I have a
gun pointed at her?").So, the film is not too strong on the logic of how and why the
characters act and respond. When combined with its over-earnestness,
the final sentence uttered in the film, instead of being the deep and
meaningful thought provoker the director and producer obviously
intended, resulted in me chuckling for quite a while after the closing
credits finished.Ultimately - The Amazing Transparent Man is better than its title
suggests, but not something to recommend.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

A prisoner is freed by people who want him to do a job for them -- he
doesn't know what it is, just that he'll be "free", but he finds himself
the
subject of a weird experiment.  He eventually turns "transparent" because
of
radiation treatments, and the guys who are doing it to him are Nazis out
to
conquer the world with an invisible army (?!!!?).  They want him to use
his
transparency to rob military bases of plutonium for building their army,
but
he eventually goes back to his stock and trade -- bank robbery.  When his
floating bag finally attracts notice, he starts to flash in and out of
visibility -- cool scene.  Decent photography, tight direction redeem this
seeming 5 day quickie.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The Amazing Transparent Man is very similar to The Invisible Man and
one main difference with this movie is that involves the Atomic Age,
radiation etc.A criminal who has escaped from prison is made invisible by a mad
scientist and gets him to steal nuclear fuel to help with future
experiments. Things go wrong when he robs a bank though as becomes
visible and is also dying through radiation poisoning.This movie has some good special effects considering the low budget.
Highlights include the "one man" fights.The cast includes Douglas Kennedy (The Land Unknown) and Marguerite
Chapman (Flight To Mars).The Amazing Transparent Man is worth watching if you get the chance. A
great way to spend just under an hour.Rating: 3 stars out of 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Given the total low-budget look of the film, the indifferent
performances of the entire cast, the lack of credibility from scene to
scene, and the overall amateurishness of acting and direction, it's
merciful that this film directed by Edward G. Ulmer is only 58 minutes.DOUGLAS KENNEDY (looking a bit flabby and tired) is the lead, a man who
has just escaped from prison and has a girlfriend (MARGUERITE CHAPMAN)
waiting just outside for a quick getaway. After that, all plausibility
is over, as she takes him to the home of a mad Army Major who is
housing a scientist able to make objects invisible.The wounded Major seeks some sort of revenge for his wounds and
envisions an army of invisible men, but Kennedy advances another
idea--a bank robbery with him stealing into the vault while invisible.
Reluctantly, the doctor agrees to the plan--but the plot takes a few
twists when things don't go as smoothly as planned.No one in the film gives a performance worth remembering, and the mad
scientist played by IVAN TRIESAULT is worst of all in a key role. In
one crucial scene he appears to be reading his dialog off cue cards as
he recites the ingredients of his experiment.To say DOUGLAS KENNEDY is wooden is to be charitable. The same can be
said for Miss Chapman who has absolutely no chemistry with the leading
man.All of it looks like it was put together in five days with some very
primitive special effects. Considering that Edward G. Ulmer did direct
some very successful scary films at Universal, this is nothing less
than a disaster.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169553/comments</url><from>from North Hollyweird</from><name>reluctantpopstar</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
You have to grade on a curve with movies like this. At least a little
bit. I'm sorry, this is not a mainstream Hollywood picture. This is an
independent, low budget piece of fare for the Drive-Ins of 1959.Nothing on offer here but pure entertainment. At least, that is what
the intent of the filmmakers is, in spite of some heavy-handed attempts
to throw in an anti-nuclear message. But that seems no more than an
afterthought, and not the main point. So, the question is, was I
entertained by this movie? Yes. I sure was. It is certainly not a science fiction masterpiece.
This is a fun, low-budget action potboiler which uses a science fiction
gimmick to sell the movie. The acting is a bit over-the-top, but not
inappropriately so. Ulmer is one of my favorite cult directors and he
does workmanlike duty with what must have been very limited resources.
One of the more enjoyable '50's Drive-In movie leftovers, and its 59
minutes (making it a TRUE B-movie, by the way) will fly by. Silly but
enjoyable. If you must take your science fiction seriously, then stay
away.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Paul Krenner, a would-be criminal kingpin, hooks up with a safe-cracker
named Joey Faust. Through extortion and force, Krenner has coerced a
scientist to develop a process of making animals and people
transparent. Krenner's idea is to use this discovery to create and army
of invisible men to do his bidding. His more immediate plan, though, is
to make Faust invisible so he might steal the radium needed to continue
the experiments. But Faust has different ideas about how to use his
invisibility – most of which involve bank robbery.First I'll mention the relatively small list of positives I found in
The Amazing Transparent Man. I think the basic idea behind the movie is
interesting. The notion of an invisible master criminal who could
literally rob a bank in broad daylight presents some interesting
possibilities. The other positive element of the movie is the film's
score. The central musical theme that gets repeated throughout The
Amazing Transparent Man is successful in creating the desired ominous
atmosphere.Unfortunately, however, the list of negatives is huge. While the movie
may present some interesting plot ideas, the execution leaves a lot to
be desired. In general, director Edgar G. Ulmer was as good as any
director at working with a low budget to make interesting and
entertaining movies. That's not the case here. The Amazing Transparent
Man never overcomes the limitations of its low budget. Bad acting, a
poor script, ridiculous dialogue, ambiguous character motivation, and
uninteresting sets are just he beginning of the many problems readily
apparent in the movie. Honestly, I could go on and on, but what's the
point? This is low-rent film-making at its worst.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Paul Krenner, a would-be criminal kingpin, hooks up with a safe-cracker
named Joey Faust. Through extortion and force, Krenner has coerced a
scientist to develop a process of making animals and people
transparent. Krenner's idea is to use this discovery to create and army
of invisible men to do his bidding. His more immediate plan, though, is
to make Faust invisible so he might steal the radium needed to continue
the experiments. But Faust has different ideas about how to use his
invisibility – most of which involve bank robbery.First I'll mention the relatively small list of positives I found in
The Amazing Transparent Man. I think the basic idea behind the movie is
interesting. The notion of an invisible master criminal who could
literally rob a bank in broad daylight presents some interesting
possibilities. The other positive element of the movie is the film's
score. The central musical theme that gets repeated throughout The
Amazing Transparent Man is successful in creating the desired ominous
atmosphere.Unfortunately, however, the list of negatives is huge. While the movie
may present some interesting plot ideas, the execution leaves a lot to
be desired. In general, director Edgar G. Ulmer was as good as any
director at working with a low budget to make interesting and
entertaining movies. That's not the case here. The Amazing Transparent
Man never overcomes the limitations of its low budget. Bad acting, a
poor script, ridiculous dialogue, ambiguous character motivation, and
uninteresting sets are just he beginning of the many problems readily
apparent in the movie. Honestly, I could go on and on, but what's the
point? This is low-rent film-making at its worst.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/amaztrans.shtml /m/amazing_transparent_man/comments.php?reviewid=1767733</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>Even something this ridiculous has its inventive charms, not least of which are the wonderfully chintzy invisibility effects.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/ulmer.htm#Transparent /m/amazing_transparent_man/comments.php?reviewid=1354390</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>One of Ulmer's grimmest works, a heartfelt anti-war statement</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/amazingtransparentman.htm /m/amazing_transparent_man/comments.php?reviewid=793781</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>I found myself enjoying this cheapie...</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/amazing_transparent_man/comments.php?reviewid=751613</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Even Ulmer can't help this one</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/amazing_transparent_man/comments.php?reviewid=1424001</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9A05E1DD1539EE32A25753C3A9659C946091D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/amazing_transparent_man/comments.php?reviewid=1390487</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>