<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>From the Terrace</original_title><alt_title>Du haut de la terrasse</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Mark Robson</director><producer>Linebrook</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
An ambitious young executive chooses a loveless marriage and an unfulfilling personal life in exchange for a successful Wall Street career.
</synopsis><actor>Paul Newman</actor><actor>Joanne Woodward</actor><actor>Myrna Loy</actor><rt_rating>4.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>38</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Although based on a John O'Hara novel, "From the Terrace" is another
'Young Philadelphians': a smart, heavy-going family melodrama, set from
the late forties to the late fifties, with Newman as an angry young
opportunist from Philadelphia… Again the moral (which undoubted1y attracted him) is that the drive for
wealth and power corrupts innocence and love… Here there's more of a
motivation, the old reliable one: his father hates him... He tells his
cold, nasty father (Leon Ames), "All I ever wanted was to be friends
with you," then defiantly rejects the family's fairly substantial steel
mill… He wants more—to make $5 million by age forty, to be better than
his old man…On his way up the cynical path to Wall Street, he ignores his marriage,
driving his once-sweet wife (Woodward) to bitchery and into the bed of
an old flame… He works intensively to become a high financier, but
suddenly realizes how empty his life is; unlike Tony Lawrence ("The
Young Philadelphians"), he drops out completely, leaving his failed
marriage and flourishing career to marry a wholesome small-town woman…Newman battles valiantly with incredible soap opera contrivances,
crises and inflated dialog, but he loses… He's worst in his scenes with
the decent young woman (Ina Balin), because the relationship is
improbable, their talk about love is slow, and he's not convincing as
the shy, gentle lover… We've seen him earlier as sexually confident and
aggressive, and besides, Newman is not very good at expressing
tenderness… He's excellent at the beginning, indicating bitterness toward his
father with contemptuous facial expressions, although here, as
elsewhere, his tendency to show tension or self-absorption by blinking
and looking away during conversations is overdone…But with Woodward, he and the film really come to life… During their
first meetings, as he comes on strong and she resists, the antagonism,
flavored with overtones of desperate sexuality, reminds us of "The
Long, Hot Summer." Then, in their marriage, the roles are reversed: he
becomes immersed in business, and she becomes sexually frustrated,
creating a highly-charged tension between them… There's a beautifully acted scene near the end when, like Maggie the
Cat, she pathetically flaunts her sexuality at him and he merely sits
there with a world-weary look… Ironically, Woodward make the wife so
vital and pathetic that it's hard to accept her as a bitch, and the
ending makes little sense...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3318884/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>oliverpenn</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
As a youngster, I saw Paul Newman and Joanne Woodward in person, a few
years after they finished this picture, in New York. They were
appearing on Broadway in a comedy called "Baby Want A Kiss," and I was
passing by Sardi's on 44th Street, I believe. First to come out was
drop dead gorgeous Joanne, still wearing her FROM THE TERRACE hairstyle
(shoulder-length pageboy flip) &amp; dark movie star sunglasses,
accompanied by two men in suits. She ignored the crowd who screamed,
"Joanne, over here!" "Hi, Joanne!" Next, Paul Newman came out (two
suited men on either side) as he held a cocktail glass in his hand.
Obviously on his fourth or fifth drink, he looked like Alfred Eaton in
TERRACE. But, unlike Joanne, he smiled and flashed the bluest eyes I've
ever seen! He even toasted the screaming crowd. Women AND men were
fainting unashamedly.Personally, I loved FROM THE TERRACE. I was just fascinated by all the
glamour, wealth, sex, adultery and sheer drama (especially between Leon
Ames (Paul's father) and Newman.Joanne as Mary St. John was a stone nympho, similar to Susanne
Pleshette's over-sexed character in another John O'Hara book-to-film, A
RAGE TO LIVE.It was just a joy to see Woodward wear all those fabulous clothes and
look spectacular in those hairdos and 60's makeup (it was all in the
eyes!) After getting propositioned on the dance floor, Mary rebuked the
man who knew "all about her..." donned a tremendously long white satin
coat and "floated" like a regal queen to the limo (hair in a French
Roll and a tiara!) Gorgeous.Yes, she was an adulteress, but what was a "hungry" girl like her to do
when her husband didn't want to touch her?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0260508/comments</url><from>from Missouri</from><name>Casey-35</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Reading the comments on this movie tells me a lot about our culture at the
dawn of the 21st century. Yes, by today's standards this movie seems to
move
slow and a is little dull. It was made before pornography passing for
entertainment was permitted. It contains lots of subtlety and innuendo. It
was considered racy when it was made.One of my favorite scenes is when Mrs. Eaton is talking to her husband on
the phone about her lover. You never see the lover in the scene, but at
the
end, you realize he's been in the bed all along. Another favorite scene is
when Mrs. Eaton meets her husband's lover for the first time. It is in the
car afterward that she asks what this woman call's Mr. Eaton.The only disappointment is the superficial way the film treats marriage.
No
children are involved in this marriage and it only deals with how the
husband and wife consider their lives. It tries to make a case for divorce
and treats the subject far too lightly. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0028288/comments</url><from>from Connecticut, United States</from><name>merrywood</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This engaging 1960 Hollywood production anticipated a coming decade of
changing values in America.  Its script teeters a bit, emphasizing a bit
more the strain of the love conflict rather than the story's real essence.
This is an easy mark for critics standing by with sharp knives who may then
view it as superficial.  However, its real drama depicts the changing
generations of an America where at one time successes was measured only by
the bank account and social prominence and not by integrity, the
ramifications of truth in character.  Here, we see the contrasting generations in conflict.  The Old Guard
embraced expediency and placed the home and its values second to business
success.  Once in a while, a young man came along with enough awareness to
see the lie in this doctrine.   FROM THE TERRACE is in its pure essence the
story about such a young man.  
	This was done with a bit more success a few years before in THE MAN IN THE
GRAY FLANNEL SUIT but this drama is certainly worthwhile seeing.   It is
well cast and played with production values that at the time were the best
that Hollywood could offer.   This includes an outstanding music score by
Elmer Bernstein.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0173674/comments</url><from>from Baltimore, Maryland</from><name>Tracee</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

[Spoiler Alert]
Paul Newman has many more famous roles...but for some reason, this is one of
my all time favorite movies of his. It comes on the Love Stories, AMC, or
TCM cable channels every here and now...or you could just buy it like I
did.He's nice, determined, well-meaning Alfred Eaton, who starts off with lofty,
wealthy ideas about what is important in life...the right woman, the right
career, the right friends...and showing them all how important he can be
when he has them. Ultimately, he learns that what is important is only what
feels right to him alone.I love his story of personal discovery as much as his love affair story with
Natalie. Alfred and Natalie have this beautiful scene where they are saying
goodbye, they're barely touching, but it's the most painfully romantic thing
to see.Paul Newman and his wife Joanne Woodward have some excellent scenes in this
movie also with real good comeback dialogue. He's the hardworking, decent
man and she's the desperate-to-impress and just plain desperate society
wife. She self-righteously and hurtfully accuses him of adultery with a girl
with no guts when she's been sleeping with her ex-fiancee all along. She
actually calls her lover and arranges a tryst while her husband is in the
room!!!! She has guts!!!! Unbeknownst to her, Alfred has exhaustingly if
unaffectedly (if you can look unaffected and disgusted at the same time,
that is) done his best to makes her invisible in the room, but she probably
just becomes invisible without any real effort on his part to make her so by
that point. Their voices just have the most impactful tones...especially
when they get to play off of each other. I can play their final scene over
and over again where she says she won't give him a divorce and he says,"Any
further communication between you and me will be through legal channels." He
has the most genuine smile on that handsome face in that moment than through
the entire movie!!!!!This movie is actually pretty long, but not a moment is wasted. It all comes
together in the end when Alfred finally chooses what he actually wants
instead of what he's supposed to want.Maybe it's because it's so subtle and not at all like a "movie" that it
seems to be largely overlooked by everyone except me and 20 other people.
Paul Newman is one fine, naturally classy actor, I say.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1326087/comments</url><from/><name>umb50</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is a wonderful movie. Gorgeous Newman, bitchy Woodward, sad Loy,
great performances all around, with fabulous sets and costumes. Plus a
wonderful story about the marriage of two of the beautiful people, with
lots of sex and scandal and romance and fun bitchiness throughout. They
had to tone down the sex in the book of course, for a 1960 movie, but
if you read between the lines you will be amazed how sexy this movie
really is. If you like movies about the rich and how they once lived,
even if it's all fantasy, you will like this. Oh yes it's all kind of
silly looking at it today, but they don't make movies like this
anymore. Watch it for the sheer fun of it. But don't take it seriously.
Just let yourself lay back and wallow.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0406900/comments</url><from>from Washington DC</from><name>hawktwo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I guess they butchered the book to keep the movie within 2 hours.  The book
has subtleties and plots that make this an INTERESTING chronicle of life in
the 20th century for a typical upper class white male.  This movie is not
interesting.  This features a good cast -- Newman and Woodward and Patrick
O'Neal.  Newman takes the harder path to success, wins the girl of his
dreams (Woodward) and should live happily ever after.  For some reason he
falls head over heels with a girl 20 years his junior and his wife decides
at the same time to return to college boyfriend O'Neal.  The movie somehow
manages to make Woodward look like a tramp and Newman like a long-suffering
man.  In reality they are both cheating.  So I guess hollywood couldn't
admit that there was a guaranteed network of prep school and clubs for the
white protestant male.  They had to rewrite the book to make it appear like
Newman struggled.  Then the entire WW2 sequence so important to the plot of
the book is skipped which means we have a happy ending instead of a man who
ends up a pathetic loser.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1955408/comments</url><from>from Santa</from><name>Ronni</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Not all the acting in this movie works, Paul Newman is too reserved in his
acting at times and the others too; but then there are steady moments
where
the intelligent script addresses real issues about American Society.Issues that are still relevant today.  Chasing 'success' at what price;
mixed feelings among all the players of the local play; natural
attractions
turning into betrayal and games.  Every dumb thing that still goes on in
relationships in our sadly repetitive american society.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1026181/comments</url><from>from Newport Beach, California</from><name>Michael O'Riley</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Paul Newman is doing his angry young man thing here, and Joanne Woodward is
wonderful as she goes from rebellious rich brat to shrewish, slutty
harridan.  It's beautifully filmed with lots of sumptuous sets  and it's
obvious that a good part of the budget went to costumes.  If you like
movies
with boozy, unhappy rich people who do little more than snipe at each
other,
you've got to see "From the Terrace."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9149435/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jhuffman-5</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
John O'Hara;s writings, and there are many, seldom got translated to
film well. Ten North Frederick and A Rage to Live are other efforts
that are not worthy of the novels. O'Hara had better luck on the stage
with plays like Pal Joey but his great novels just were just too big
and detailed to make the move. He had a hand in the screenplay for this
movie so he does share some of the blame. His great success as a writer
flows from his great knowledge of the U.S. and its sexual mores in from
say 1900 to 1920. This is a time when people apparently did not have
sex but O'Hara makes it plain they did and made an effort to do so.
Recommend his writings but the films failed and that is just so tragic.
A critic once wrote that O'Hara's novels are like huge ancient ruins
that when stumbled upon, the discover can not determine why they were
built. That remark was written about 20 years after his death just
about the time that all artists fall out of favor before their merits
are rediscovered and the value of their work is confirmed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9149435/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jhuffman-5</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
John O'Hara;s writings, and there are many, seldom got translated to
film well. Ten North Frederick and A Rage to Live are other efforts
that are not worthy of the novels. O'Hara had better luck on the stage
with plays like Pal Joey but his great novels just were just too big
and detailed to make the move. He had a hand in the screenplay for this
movie so he does share some of the blame. His great success as a writer
flows from his great knowledge of the U.S. and its sexual mores in from
say 1900 to 1920. This is a time when people apparently did not have
sex but O'Hara makes it plain they did and made an effort to do so.
Recommend his writings but the films failed and that is just so tragic.
A critic once wrote that O'Hara's novels are like huge ancient ruins
that when stumbled upon, the discover can not determine why they were
built. That remark was written about 20 years after his death just
about the time that all artists fall out of favor before their merits
are rediscovered and the value of their work is confirmed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9149435/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jhuffman-5</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=13068 /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1811333</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Just as disappointing as the other John O'Hara novel made into a movie that year, Butterfield 8 with Liz Taylor, but without that film's melodramatic juice, though Paul Newman is well cast as the ambitious, upwardly mobile man in moral crisis.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/terrace/review/123956 /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1735416</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
2/4
					</rating><comment>Another failed attempt to adapt one of John O'Hara's sprawling novels for the screen.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117791144.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1735415</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>From The Terrace builds up to one big cliche.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/67129/from_the_terrace.html /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1475954</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Robson's film is still highly watchable, with Paul and Joanne pretending their marriage is on the rocks, and all sorts of machinations in the boardroom and the bedroom.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9E01E6D71638EF32A25755C1A9619C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1389934</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>This is a handsome picture, well-performed and emotionally intriguing as it describes the rise of a young business man and the corrosive dead-lock of his loveless marriage.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/walter-chaw/</url><url>http://filmfreakcentral.net/dvdreviews/fromtheterrace.htm /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1170709</url><name>Walter Chaw</name><from>Film Freak Central</from></reviewer><rating>
1/4
					</rating><comment>An epic winker that uses, in its best moment, a rocking dinghy as a euphemism.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chireader.com/MovieCaps/F/FR/15992_FROM_THE_TERRACE.html /m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=7689</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>A tolerable (if interminable) piece of mediocrity from 1960.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/from_the_terrace/comments.php?reviewid=1266697</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>