<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Cape Canaveral Monsters</original_title><imdb_rating>2.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Phil Tucker</director><producer>Compagnia Cinematografica Montoro (CCM)</producer><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
When a couple are killed in an auto accident their bodies are immediately inhabited by extraterrestrial beings...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Scott Peters</actor><actor>Linda Connell</actor><actor>Jason Johnson</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0570008/comments</url><from>from New England</from><name>Son of Cathode</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Invaders from outer space keep destroying our missile launches.
The
amazing Phil Tucker does it again, condensing genre fiction
into
prophetic, visionary melodrama. In his groundbreaking "Robot
Monster,"
he encapsulated the '50's paranoid cine-obsession with
rapidly-
evolving, ungodly technology, before all the other movies
happened.
Here, Tucker sums up the troubled and schizophrenic decade with
a
surprisingly frank and intimate portrayal of what all the
repressed
hysteria was really about: Sex, of course. Our two lead aliens,
who
are painted largely as bickering Commie spies from Mars, are
entirely
sexual beings who have a raw, passionate relationship which
includes
much bickering and power play and may very well include rough
sex.
They're so lusty, they even have their cover-alls unbuttoned at
the
top, very odd behavior for 50s Scientists, Commies or Martians.
When
they kidnap earthlings for experimentation, it is two hardy,
handsome
teenage couples, just ripe for breeding and raping and torturing. Male
alien
not only kills male teenager, but
dismembers him to gain a new arm. A more brutal and brilliant
patriarchal metaphor cannot be imagined. Female alien (the
wenchlike
yet still wildly alluring Katharine Victor, in one of her
most
shockingly lusty roles, covering much of the same ground as in
the
same year's incredible "Teenage Zombies"), lusts after both male
and
female teens, and alludes more than once to having either desired
or
attempted rape on one or all. Here, Victor plays a most disturbed,
but
not unimaginable, psycho-sexual 50's mother, who wants to both mate with
and
mutilate her own "children". (She's also just adorably nasty.) As in "Robot
Monster," the scientific sage of the piece is of a
strongly Germanic background. Some agitated animation, a
floating
pancake in a bubble, some cool opticals and thoughtful
montage
sequences, as well as a fertile and zesty script, make this a
beloved
bookend to Tucker's "Robot Monster," surely his two shining gems,
and
two Grade-Z masterworks.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"Robot Monster" is the single greatest bad science fiction film of all
time. As much as I love Ed Wood films, they occasionally contain slow
spots. "Robot Monster" on the other hand, is nonstop entertainment from
beginning to end. Unfortunately, its the only film by Phil Tucker to
have entered certified cult status, as his other films are widely
unavailable. This is a shame, because "The Cape Canaveral Monsters" is
just as insanely enjoyable. Tucker's direction hasn't improved one bit,
but that doesn't mean the film is ever boring.There are too many hilarious aspects to this film. The central idea
(aliens take over dead human bodies, hide out in a cave and try to
sabotage the American space race) isn't only cliché, its illogical to
the extreme. The plot is, unsurprisingly, littered with the most
unsubtle anti-communist propaganda imaginable.Still, there's reasons why I'm convinced Phil Tucker may have been onto
something rather post-modern here. The acting is so bad, the dialog so
horrible no one in their right mind could take it seriously, plus
there's a running gag about one of the aliens trying to reattach their
arm, maybe Tucker had created an ahead of its time satire. Either way,
"The Cape Canaveral Monsters" is sheer genius, plain and simple. (8/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Cape Canaveral Monsters, The (1960)* (out of 4) A couple aliens from an unknown planet come to Earth where they cause a
young couple to crash their car. The aliens then take over their bodies
with plans to destroy a place where they are setting off missiles. The
aliens are against the missiles so they begin to shoot them out of the
sky so it's up to a couple other teens to try and save the day. Rumor,
myth or truth, it's said that director Phil Tucker attempted suicide
after the horrible reviews of his film ROBOT MONSTER. Who knows how
much of that is actually true but this thing here is just about as bad.
Those art house crowds would be best to stay away from this thing but
if you enjoy bad movies then this one here is about as bad and as
stupid as you can get. For starters, the plot makes very little to no
sense because the screenplay, also by Tucker, never takes any time to
explain what the missiles are being used for and we never really get to
know why the aliens want to destroy them. The movie runs 68-minutes and
the entire story just jumps around without too much logic. One minute a
couple teens will get kidnapped and then the very next scene we have
their friends, somehow, knowing the aliens took them so they go to find
them. There's never any reasoning as to what's going on and this
includes some rather silly devices used by the aliens to control the
teens. One of the dumbest things is a running joke about the male alien
constantly having his arm ripped off. I'm not sure if this was meant as
comedy but it does separate this film from countless other sci-fi
flicks from this era because the sight of a severed arm wasn't too
common in 1960. The car crash at the start of the film was actually
filmed fairly well as the camera was placed in the back seat as the
"wreck" happened. That's about the best thing that can be said about
this film. I wouldn't say this movie is as enjoyable as ROBOT MONSTER
but it would certainly make a decent double-feature with that film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15234153/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mikemc1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
How can any horror fan growing up with horror flicks of the late 50's
through mid 60's ever deny films like The Cape Canaveral Monsters,
Attack of the 50ft Woman, Amazing Colossal Man, etc.? Excellent
drive-in horror! We start with a seemingly innocent couple who are
driving to a rocket lauch. BUT... A spaceship lands while they're
enroute. And this radioactive alien (who's just a hairy white man made
to look big) contaminates them and turns them into The Cape Canaveral
Monsters. Then, they go on this mission with a laser shooting missiles
and satellites when they are launched from Cape Canaveral. It's really
quite fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This is a lesser-known effort than the same director's notoriously
awful ROBOT MONSTER (1953) but it actually proves somewhat better, if
still in no way a good film. It may well be the first zombie picture to
receive a sci-fi slant (thus predating George A. Romero's regrettably
landmark NIGHT OF THE LIVING DEAD by 8 years!}), but the monsters' use
here is really no different than the various 'alien takeover' ploys we
had seen and would continue to see until that particular fad burnt
itself out! What is different is that the zombies were rendered so in a
car crash, so that the victims are all scarred, bloody and literally
torn to pieces (one of them keeps losing an arm throughout)!; their
real form, then, is nothing more than a glowing speck which enters the
human body through the brain.The titular site, of course, is the U.S. rocket-launching base and the
aliens are here to sabotage their every effort to breach outer
space...which they do by shooting an unwieldy bazooka straight at the
shuttle (at one point, the man does it while one-armed and hits the
bull's-eye regardless – so much for his partner's whining that he
should restore his other limb, of course by finding another human
donor)! By the way, one of the film's main founts of amusement is the
aliens' evident contempt for one another! – incidentally, they
occasionally report to their intergalactic superior, who appears on
their monitor in the form of a floating pancake!! At the base, we have the usual motley crew of military brass, rookie
scientists and the obligatory German expert, who comes with a
geeky-but-cute niece who throws the Doc into a fit by flirting with the
young man on his time! The two lovers have to cut loose in order to
enjoy some quality time together, meeting with another couple to have
themselves a picnic-by-moonlight; however, the hero is too immersed in
his work not to notice the static on his pal's radio, which means that
a transmitter is being illegally operated in the vicinity (and which,
he reasons, may have something to do with the rockets going haywire)!
While he and his girl go snooping around, the other two are abducted by
the aliens to their cave hide-out and placed half-dangling into what
appears to be a sink while the girl is undressed to then be wrapped in
a plastic sheet (in preparation for her being transmitted into space),
while the boy's body makes for a plastic surgeon's dream as the
bruised-up alien pilfers whatever takes his fancy from him – assuming
that, if he looks good, he should be less conspicuous when roaming
outside! Hero and heroine are soon in the aliens' clutches themselves, but he
manages to escape simply by passing his watch in front of the controls:
I have to wonder, at this stage, what would have happened had the
leading man not been Physics-savvy! He lands in the home of a hillbilly
(who appears before long toting a gun in his pyjamas) and calls the
authorities – again, since he is who he is, we do not get the usual
wasting-of-time with the hero attempting to make the cops believe his
story! Even so, the pace of the 68-minute film is rather slow, being
even stopped dead in its tracks at the climax so as to allow most of
the cast (including the eminent scientist, who is actually present in
some group-shots but not others!) – captured by the aliens by means of
a paralyzing gun! – to methodically work out, via mathematical
equations, what would cause an explosion from the materials at their
disposal inside the cave! Again, the film is nothing to write home about and yet it does contrive
a circular twist ending which was totally unexpected and downright
cynical for such a low-brow offering! For the record, this viewing came
by way of an old and quite hazy TV transmission that is continually
interrupted for ad-breaks (though these were somewhat haphazardly
eliminated afterwards).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
The alien invaders using the recent dead is a whole sub-genre of films
from Plan Nine From Outer Space to Invisible Invaders and this film
filmmakers looking to save a buck by not having to come up with a
monster suit. Sadly almost every film from genre are really bad. Sure
some of them are fun bad, but they are still bad.Such is the case with Cape Canaveral Monsters. This little mistake has
floating balls of light taking over the bodies of a recently deceased
couple in order to sabotage the US space program.(and we thought the
commies were bad)Dumb it is, fun its not.This is one to avoid-a warning I send out even to bad film lovers-this
is just the wrong sort of bad.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169553/comments</url><from>from North Hollyweird</from><name>reluctantpopstar</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
As a certified Ed Wood fan, I had been meaning for some time to track
down the works of Mr. Phil Tucker. But, they had eluded me, except for his disasterpiece, his Citizen
Kane, his Plan Nine From Outer Space, Robot Monster, which I have seen
on DVD, and also had the good fortune to see on the big screen, in its
3-D version no less! So, finally, Netflix allowed me to stream one of his other epics, THE
CAPE CANAVERAL MONSTERS. I have to say, it was almost worth the wait.
Fans of the celluloid leavings of Ed Wood, Jerry Warren and Richard
Cunha will be right at home here. This is a pure gold-plated turd, full of the hi-jinx beloved by
aficionados of low-budget 50's sci-fi swill. Aliens, mad scientist,
stupid gadgets, cheap-arse monsters, they are all here. Perfect
mindless viewing for a boring Saturday afternoon. Not sure if this presentation is available on DVD, but if it is not,
then it really should be. Somebody get right on that, will ya?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169553/comments</url><from>from North Hollyweird</from><name>reluctantpopstar</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
As a certified Ed Wood fan, I had been meaning for some time to track
down the works of Mr. Phil Tucker. But, they had eluded me, except for his disasterpiece, his Citizen
Kane, his Plan Nine From Outer Space, Robot Monster, which I have seen
on DVD, and also had the good fortune to see on the big screen, in its
3-D version no less! So, finally, Netflix allowed me to stream one of his other epics, THE
CAPE CANAVERAL MONSTERS. I have to say, it was almost worth the wait.
Fans of the celluloid leavings of Ed Wood, Jerry Warren and Richard
Cunha will be right at home here. This is a pure gold-plated turd, full of the hi-jinx beloved by
aficionados of low-budget 50's sci-fi swill. Aliens, mad scientist,
stupid gadgets, cheap-arse monsters, they are all here. Perfect
mindless viewing for a boring Saturday afternoon. Not sure if this presentation is available on DVD, but if it is not,
then it really should be. Somebody get right on that, will ya?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2169553/comments</url><from>from North Hollyweird</from><name>reluctantpopstar</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>