<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Le dialogue des Carmélites</original_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Philippe Agostini</director><producer>Champs-Élysées Productions</producer><producer>Titanus</producer><synopsis/><actor>Jeanne Moreau</actor><actor>Alida Valli</actor><actor>Madeleine Renaud</actor><rt_rating>6.3/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>83</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5627456/comments</url><from>from Germany</from><name>m_imdb-209</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Please note that movie, book and opera are based on the Novel "Die
Letzte am Schafott" ("The Last at the Scaffold" or "The Song at the
Scaffold") by Gertrud von le Fort.The German writer and poet lived from 1876 until 1971. She has written
many books (for details check www.gertrud-von-le-fort.de).Some of her other works have also been rewritten as movies or theatre
plays, e.g. "Das Schweigen am Himmel" by Dallmayr, which you can also
find in the IMDb database. This film is based on her book "Am Tor das
Himmels".If you liked the movie - as I am sure you undoubtedly will - you may
want to check for a performance of the opera. Not surprisingly, this
opera is staged quite often.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0484367/comments</url><from>from Rio, Brazil</from><name>jgcorrea</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Cinema has not been insensitive to Georges Bernanos , who ranks alongside
with other great Catholic 20th-century writers, most notably Graham Greene,
André Gide and Paul Claudel. One of Robert Bresson's masterpieces,
'Mouchette,' was adapted from Bernanos.  'Sous le soleil de Satan' turned
out to be another interesting adaptation . But his most famous play is this
Dialogue, a period piece which is an eloquent libel against  repression on
any cult freedom, no matter what kind of creed. Though the picture cannot
be
compared to the magnificent opera that composer  Francis Poulenc extracted
from the same text, it does record, with sincerity, the tragic episode when
nuns, during the Terror regime, in the French Revolution, willingly became
martyrs in the name of Christian faith and  freedom of belief. Maybe
revolutions cannot help being gruesome, but must they suspend belief beyond
the rescue of the soul(s)?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6053588/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>oliver-177</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
George Bernanos, the royalist French writer, prepared in 1947 a
screenplay for a film that never was made, Les Carmélites. (Bernanos'
screenplay was based on a 1931 historical novel by Gertrud von Lefort,
Die Letzte am Schafott.) The old-fashioned word for screenplay in
French is "Dialogue." This "Screenplay for The Carmelites," (Dialogue
Des Carmélites) was published shortly after Bernanos' death in 1948. Francis Poulenc wrote an opera, which premiered in 1957, using
Bernanos' very words (but not all of them). Poulenc's opera is one of
the most important of the XX Century, and it is an intoxicating blend
of austere religion and sensuous music. The opera is mostly about fear:
the fear of a young girl, Blanche, who enlists as a Carmélite novice to
find a refuge from crippling anxiety, just when religious orders are
threatened during the French Révolution. The opera is called Dialogues
des Carmélites (plural), and it is available on DVD in many versions.Now, back to the movie. This is NOT the aborted movie that Bernanos
wrote his dialogue for. Actually, the text of this screenplay is not
faithful to Bernanos' stylized words. This movie - which was shot after
the opera's première - is much more realistic than Bernanos'
screenplay, or than the opera. This is not a great movie. Seen on its
own, it is almost dull. But it helps one appreciate the opera better.
One understands more clearly than in the opera why Mother Marie does
not join her sisters during the final slaughter, for instance. Where
the opera is very much about Blanche, and very much about anxiety, the
film is about the loss of religious freedom during political upheavals
(less gripping, but interesting too). The idea of "exchanging deaths"
which is capital in the opera and in Bernanos' text, is not as
primordial in the film. The movie helps us detect an unfortunate recent tendency to camp up the
opera. The atmosphere of the earliest recording of the opera (Dervaux -
EMI) is quite similar to that of the film: restrained, dry-eyed.
Nowadays, the opera is often closer to the hysterical atmosphere of
Queen of Spades, or even Elektra, if you follow me. Nowhere is it more
apparent than with the character of the old prioress. In the movie, she
is underplayed by sweet and poignant Madeleine Renaud. In a 3,000 seat
opera house, she is often played as a hammy grotesque these days (great
singer-actresses such as Helga Dernesch and Anja Silja were
particularly awful this way). If I were to stage the opera, I would
have the cast sit through the movie, for sure, to help them ensure
balance. Back to the movie: Madeleine Renaud is wonderful, as I said. Jeanne
Moreau is compelling in the role of Mère Marie (a larger, more
fleshed-out role than in the opera). Alida Valli, with her whiskey and
cigarettes voice and her sensuous gaze is an odd choice for the new
prioress. (Her scenes with Pierre Brasseur bring back memories of Eyes
without a Face.) Pascale Audret is not as good as Blanche: too pretty,
too sane.This movie will be of great interest for those who love Poulenc's
opera, and for fans of Jeanne Moreau and Alida Valli. Otherwise, it is
low-key historical entertainment with a simplistic anti-revolutionary
message.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6053588/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>oliver-177</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
George Bernanos, the royalist French writer, prepared in 1947 a
screenplay for a film that never was made, Les Carmélites. (Bernanos'
screenplay was based on a 1931 historical novel by Gertrud von Lefort,
Die Letzte am Schafott.) The old-fashioned word for screenplay in
French is "Dialogue." This "Screenplay for The Carmelites," (Dialogue
Des Carmélites) was published shortly after Bernanos' death in 1948. Francis Poulenc wrote an opera, which premiered in 1957, using
Bernanos' very words (but not all of them). Poulenc's opera is one of
the most important of the XX Century, and it is an intoxicating blend
of austere religion and sensuous music. The opera is mostly about fear:
the fear of a young girl, Blanche, who enlists as a Carmélite novice to
find a refuge from crippling anxiety, just when religious orders are
threatened during the French Révolution. The opera is called Dialogues
des Carmélites (plural), and it is available on DVD in many versions.Now, back to the movie. This is NOT the aborted movie that Bernanos
wrote his dialogue for. Actually, the text of this screenplay is not
faithful to Bernanos' stylized words. This movie - which was shot after
the opera's première - is much more realistic than Bernanos'
screenplay, or than the opera. This is not a great movie. Seen on its
own, it is almost dull. But it helps one appreciate the opera better.
One understands more clearly than in the opera why Mother Marie does
not join her sisters during the final slaughter, for instance. Where
the opera is very much about Blanche, and very much about anxiety, the
film is about the loss of religious freedom during political upheavals
(less gripping, but interesting too). The idea of "exchanging deaths"
which is capital in the opera and in Bernanos' text, is not as
primordial in the film. The movie helps us detect an unfortunate recent tendency to camp up the
opera. The atmosphere of the earliest recording of the opera (Dervaux -
EMI) is quite similar to that of the film: restrained, dry-eyed.
Nowadays, the opera is often closer to the hysterical atmosphere of
Queen of Spades, or even Elektra, if you follow me. Nowhere is it more
apparent than with the character of the old prioress. In the movie, she
is underplayed by sweet and poignant Madeleine Renaud. In a 3,000 seat
opera house, she is often played as a hammy grotesque these days (great
singer-actresses such as Helga Dernesch and Anja Silja were
particularly awful this way). If I were to stage the opera, I would
have the cast sit through the movie, for sure, to help them ensure
balance. Back to the movie: Madeleine Renaud is wonderful, as I said. Jeanne
Moreau is compelling in the role of Mère Marie (a larger, more
fleshed-out role than in the opera). Alida Valli, with her whiskey and
cigarettes voice and her sensuous gaze is an odd choice for the new
prioress. (Her scenes with Pierre Brasseur bring back memories of Eyes
without a Face.) Pascale Audret is not as good as Blanche: too pretty,
too sane.This movie will be of great interest for those who love Poulenc's
opera, and for fans of Jeanne Moreau and Alida Valli. Otherwise, it is
low-key historical entertainment with a simplistic anti-revolutionary
message.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6053588/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>oliver-177</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/xan-brooks/</url><url>http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/2010/apr/08/no-greater-love-review /m/no-greater-love/comments.php?reviewid=1879081</url><name>Xan Brooks</name><from>Guardian [UK]</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Whyte is not here to pry or probe too deeply. He simply records the day-to-day routine of these cloistered inhabitants.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sukhdev-sandhu/</url><url>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/culturecritics/sukhdevsandhu/7567544/No-Greater-Love-review.html /m/no-greater-love/comments.php?reviewid=1878893</url><name>Sukhdev Sandhu</name><from>Daily Telegraph</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Falls between the fly-on-the-wall probing of a Molly Dineen documentary and the more transcendental approach of Into Great Silence, Philip Gröning's portrait of the Grande Chartreuse monastery in the Swiss Alps.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-parkinson/</url><url>http://www.radiotimes.com/servlet_film/com.icl.beeb.rtfilms.client.simpleSearchServlet?searchTypeSelect=5&amp;frn=49859 /m/no-greater-love/comments.php?reviewid=1878853</url><name>David Parkinson</name><from>Radio Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Having spent a decade preparing the project, Whyte captures the humanity of the nuns, whether they are doing their chores, shopping online for groceries, playing ceilidh music or singing sublimely in the chapel.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-parkinson/</url><url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/review.asp?FID=136779 /m/no-greater-love/comments.php?reviewid=1878828</url><name>David Parkinson</name><from>Empire Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>The sisters' insights into a life of seclusion, contemplation and intercession are courageous and compelling, while the revelations about self-discovery, doubt and divine consolation are laudably frank and deeply moving.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/trevor-johnston/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/88496/no-greater-love.html /m/no-greater-love/comments.php?reviewid=1878827</url><name>Trevor Johnston</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>No Greater Love knows what spirituality looks like but, pleasantly calming though it is, can't really take us inside.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nigel-andrews/</url><url>http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/889dd72a-4269-11df-8c60-00144feabdc0.html /m/no-greater-love/comments.php?reviewid=1878822</url><name>Nigel Andrews</name><from>Financial Times</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>The austerity can be wearing. At times you send up a prayer to Poulenc to come and set these Carmelites to music.</comment></review></movie>