<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Unforgiven</original_title><alt_title>Le vent de la plaine</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>John Huston</director><producer>James Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
The neighbors of a frontier family turn on them when it is suspected that their adopted daughter was stolen from the local Kiawa tribe.
</synopsis><actor>Burt Lancaster</actor><actor>Audrey Hepburn</actor><actor>Audie Murphy</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10408116/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>jpdoherty</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Released through United Artists THE UNFORGIVEN (1960) is an engaging
drama set on the Texas Panhandle of the American west. Nicely
photographed in Panavision and colour by Franz Planer it was skillfully
directed by John Huston, who it has to be said, was something of a
stranger when it came to directing westerns. Written for the screen by
Ben Maddow it was based on the novel by prolific western writer Alan
LeMay ("The Searchers"). Burt Lancaster not only headed a fine cast but
he was also producer of the project with his partners Ben Hecht and
James Hill.Lancaster is Ben Zachary the inscrutable and patriarchal elder son of
the Zachary family who are raising cattle on their barren land.
Together with his two brothers Cash (Audie Murphy), Andy (Doug McClure)
and his partner Zeb Rawlins (Charles Bickford) they are preparing to
drive their herd to market. Then, appearing out of the blue one day
comes an old sword wielding saddle tramp (James Wiseman) who begins to
spread the story that the Zachary brothers sister Rachel (Audrey
Hepburn) is in reality an Indian who was adopted by Ma Zachery (Lillian
Gish) as an infant. On learning this the local Kiowa tribe want her
returned to them resulting in the Zachary's unbridled resistance
leading to an all out battle to the death.Performances generally are excellent throughout! Lancaster as usual is
superb and gives a perfectly measured portrayal of the man left with
all the decisions. Audrey Hepburn in the most unusual role of her
career is also excellent though her London accent does sneak out now
and then. But the surprise performance comes from Audie Murphy who,
eschewing his matinée B picture cowboy image is quite amazing as the
Indian hating brother ("hellfire Ben we can kill them before
breakfast"). This was the actor's second best ever performance! The
other being his brilliant portrayal as the young troubled Yankee
trooper in "The Red Badge Of Courage" (1951) which was also directed by
his director here - John Huston. Also notable is the appearance of
Lillian Gish (1893/1993) as the mother. The female star of such great
silent classics "Birth Of A Nation" and "Intolorance" is terrific as
Mattilda Zachary an old woman who for years has concealed a crucial
secret. But it is curious that John Saxon's striking portrayal as the
half breed Johnny Portugal gets to be written out of the picture! His
part looked very promising in the early stages of the movie but all of
a sudden and without any reason he disappears and is never seen again.Adding greatly to the atmosphere is the marvellous score by Dimitri
Tiomkin. With an attractive and lingering main theme the piece was a
minor hit in the early sixties when a cover version was recorded by
piano duo Ferrante &amp; Teicher. Also there is some exciting cues for the
cattle and horse sequences and ominous music underlines the scenes for
the Indian attacks on the Zachary's humble sod cabin. It is one of the
composer's best scores! Unfortunately however it is not very well
recorded. There is a pervading echo quality from the music throughout
the picture which at times is a tad irritating. Tiomkin conducted the
score in Rome with an Italian orchestra.THE UNFORGIVEN wasn't a particularly well liked movie by critics. Even
Huston himself didn't like it. But over the years it has slightly
gained a cult following and gets better with each viewing. For me its
high production values, its great cast, performances and its racist
undertones make it a compelling movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2904081/comments</url><from>from Kentucky</from><name>aimless-46</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Not to be confused with Clint Eastwood's 1992 film "Unforgiven", "THE
Unforgiven" is a 1960 John Huston film that is almost worthy of joining
Eastwood's as one of the top ten westerns of all-time. That it falls
slightly short of that status could be because Huston withdrew from the
project in post-production, after the studio insisted on toning down
his message of racial tolerance to give the film more commercial
appeal. Although this tampering tends to cloud his political message,
it is still there if you do conduct a little analysis. "The Unforgiven"
does lay claim to the distinction of being the most ambitious western
of all time.Based on an Alan LeMay novel, as was John Ford's "The Searchers", "The
Unforgiven" presents the flip side of the search for a missing sister.
Here it is an Indian looking for his sister who was abducted as a baby
by a white man and then adopted by his family. The obvious complaint is
that the Indians are the villains in both films, by a kind of damned if
you do-damned if you don't logic. But there is a distinction as the
little girl in "The Searchers" was abducted when she was nine years old
and she retained a desire to be reunited with her white family. The
girl in "The Unforgiven", Rachel (played by Audrey Hepburn), has only
known her adopted family.John Huston once said that a good story should have "excitement, color,
spectacle and humor, adventure, high drama, tragedy, good conversation,
truth and irony". Even the studio version of "The Unforgiven" does a
pretty good job of bringing all these elements to the screen. The most
obvious sign of studio tampering is the inconsistency in John Saxon's
character (Johnny Portugal), a half-breed who is often harassed by the
local cowboys and is meticulously set up to be Ben's (Burt Lancaster)
rival for Rachel's affections. But Portugal mysteriously disappears
from the film by the half-way point and there is no attempt to resolve
his situation with Ben and Rachel.Ben is the eldest son of a ranching family. Audie Murphy is the middle
brother Cash. Doug McClure is Andy, the youngest brother. Lillian Gish
is their mother Mattilda. Since their father's murder by the Kiowas
Murphy has been a violent racist.The film's title refers to the attitude of Abe Kelsey (Joseph
Wiseman-later to play Dr. No), a bearded half-crazy avenger who has
tormented the family for many years, ever since his son was abducted by
the Indians and Ben's father refused to trade Rachel for Abe's son. The
twist is that only Wiseman and Gish know that Rachel's biological
parents were Indians, everyone else (including Rachel) believes that
she was the only survivor of a massacred settler family.Rachel has grown up to be a loving and happy young woman. Huston's
intention is to demonstrate that one race is not inferior to another;
that while cultural differences are very real, there is no biological
reason for racism. When Rachel's actual parentage is revealed it
divides the family; Cash leaves to go on a wild bender, the other two
brothers distance themselves from Rachel and she from them, and the
surrounding settlers shun the family.One scene is absolutely riveting, Rachel is comforting the mother
(played by June Walker) of the boy she was to marry. Walker slowly
looks up at her and then suddenly goes absolutely ballistic. Hepburn's
stunned reaction appears to be absolutely genuine, as if Huston had
altered the script and not told her about the change.Interestingly, the climax actually occurs just after this and before
the final shoot-out. The Indians come to the homestead to take Rachel.
She attempts to join them, reasoning that they will spare her family
once they have her. Ben physically restrains her and has Andy shoot one
of Indians, rendering Rachel's intended sacrifice useless because the
Indians will now attack to avenge the killing. But more important, this
demonstrates to Rachel that they still consider her their sister, the
first sign of this since everyone learned of her Indian parentage.You can quibble that Hepburn is physically miscast, at a minimum they
should have made her hair darker, but the story requires that the
character look "non-Indian" as she has been successfully passing for a
white girl for many years. Watch for the scene where she is on the
corral fence watching the cowboys break horses. She simply glows in
this shot. How ironic that someone who was so closely associated with
high fashion and glamor would look her most beautiful as a dusty tomboy
and a dirty-faced flower girl.My only real criticism of the film is the moronic nature of the final
shootout. There was no need for a war party, a handful of Indians would
have been better. Otherwise this is a thoughtful and entertaining story
that moves along briskly as Huston nicely crafts a number of rounded
characters. He utilizes a variety of camera angles and positions, which
enhance the story without drawing attention to the technique. Lancaster
is excellent as man of character and conviction who manages to convey
the conflict between brotherly love for his adopted little sister and
the growing sexual attraction between them. Gish is amazing and Murphy
turned in the best performance of the whole ensemble, playing against
type and showing an unexpected range..Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This classic film from one of the greatest directors of the 20th
century boasts an incredible cast: Audrey Hepburn, Lillian Gish (silent
films), Burt Lancaster, Audie Murphy (war hero), a young Doug McClure,
all of whom show classic acting at its finest. Go beneath the dialogue
and watch the body movements, facial expressions and withheld, unspoken
emotion of these superb actors (esp Gish and Lancaster). Check out the
incredible performance of the wraith-like, howling itinerant evangelist
(Joseph Wiseman) who seems to know the "secret". The score by Dmitri
Tiomkin is terrific, with a minimum of Hollywood-style Native American
drumming (and flute playing. Indeed, the music played by the Kiowas
during the "break" was fascinating. Although the story is set in 1800s
Texas panhandle, the theme is universal and hard-hitting: racism, and a
family divided by their differing views. I found the portrayal of the
Kiowa culture to be accurate, esp the use of costumes and rituals.
Remember, this film was made in 1960, a time when racial intolerance
was rarely put on film, and the fair presentation of Native Americans
was almost non-existent. Indeed, this is why Huston wanted this
project. Remarkably, this film is NOT pro-Indian or pro-settler, rather
it's an honest depiction of a clash of cultures. My only
disappointment, a minor one, was that the film ended rather abruptly
for my taste, almost as if they ran out of film. But then again, I'm
not a director! I found interesting background on the making of this
film at dvdverdict.com
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0635941/comments</url><from/><name>jack.hunter</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I believe this western to be one of the most overlooked western films of
the
period.  When one looks at the westerns made before 1960 it is
difficult
to find many that come close to comparing with the realism, adult themes
and
complex characterisation of this film.  I have viewed this film multiple
times over a period of years and enjoy it more with each viewing.  The
movie
is brilliantly cast with especially great performances from Charles
Bickford
(Zeb Rawlins), Joseph Wiseman (Abe Kelsey), Lillian Gish (Mattilda
Zachary)and June Walker (Hagar Rawlins).  This western has it all;
uniformly
wonderful performances from the entire cast, excellent dialogue, and a real
look and feel of the western frontier.  I give this film a 9 out of
10.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
When the weird Abe Kelsey (Joseph Wiseman) with his saber appears in
the Zachary's ranch threatening the matriarch Mattilda Zachary (Lillian
Gish) and her stepdaughter Rachel (Audrey Hepburn), she does not tell
to her sons Ben (Burt Lancaster), Cash (Audie Murphy) and Andy (Doug
McClure). Later, when Rachel comments about him, Ben and Cash
unsuccessfully chase him in a sand storm. Meanwhile, Kelsey poisons the
relationship of the Zachary's family with their neighbors and the
Indians Kiowa disclosing that Rachel would be a Kiowa baby stolen years
ago in a raid by Kelsey himself and Mattilda's husband, when her
parents were killed. Later, he wanted to trade Rachel per his son,
captured by the Kiowa, but the old Zachary did not accept his proposal.
The racists' neighbors turn their backs to the Zachary's family, while
the Kiowa siege them in their house while trying to bring Rachel back
to their tribe."The Unforgiven" is a western about the impressive intolerance between
Caucasians and Indians in the beginning of the colonization of North
America by the whites. The story is very well developed, with the usual
outstanding direction of John Huston. Joseph Wiseman has a magnificent
performance in the role of a despicable villain, a revengeful man
capable of destroying many lives. Burt Lancaster is also great in his
leadership, while Lillian Gish is amazing in the role of a protective
mother. Audrey Hepburn and John Saxon are convincing as Indians. My
vote is eight.Title (Brazil): "O Passado Não Perdoa" ("The Past Does Not Forgive")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This film, The Unforgiven, as opposed to Clint Eastwood's classic is
taken from a novel by Alan LeMay who also wrote The Searchers. Both
stories are about the post Civil War Texas frontier. But in this one we
have the Indians seeking out one of there's who's been taken by whites
and raised as one of their own. The person in question is Audrey
Hepburn who's been raised by Lillian Gish as her own daughter and
sister to her three sons, Burt Lancaster, Audie Murphy, and Doug
McClure.It was an unwritten law of Hollywood that no one shoots a film in
Monument Valley except John Ford. So John Huston made due with Durango
in Mexico which had become a favorite western location site also.
Huston got some good performances out of his cast although he had many
problems. Audrey Hepburn fell off a horse and was injured for a few weeks. Audie
Murphy nearly drowned in a river. Topping it all off, according to a
recent biography of Burt Lancaster was the fact that Lillian Gish
served as a kind of back seat driver to John Huston. She was forever
telling him that D.W. Griffith did this or that a different way. But
apparently Ms. Gish was satisfied with the finished product because she
acclaimed Huston as another Griffith when it was over.The story really gets going when some Kiowas come knocking on Lillian
Gish's door demanding Audrey Hepburn's return. When it's discovered
that Hepburn in fact is an Indian, the reaction of the neighbors and
some of the family is to send her back. Lancaster, Gish, and McClure
aren't having it though.The Unforgiven was butchered in the editing department. One role that
was mostly left on the cutting room floor apparently was John Saxon as
a halfbreed named Johnny Portugal. Standing out though is Joseph
Wiseman as the crazy ex-cavalryman now turned preacher who has a hate
for Audrey Hepburn. Why he does you'll have to see the film, but it's
an interesting problem.Its parts, its individual performances make The Unforgiven an uneven
film where the whole is not greater than the sum of those parts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1174539/comments</url><from>from www.moviemoviesite.com</from><name>JoeytheBrit</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The Unforgiven is a reversal of John Ford's The Searchers. The pivotal
character in both films is a young woman stolen from her people as a
babe, and both films involve to different degrees a long search by her
family to get her back. In The Searchers, the Indians were the
kidnappers – in The Unforgiven it is the white man. But The Unforgiven,
an intelligently written and thoughtful film, reverses more than just
the roles of the representatives of the conflicting races – it also
reverses the perspective so that it is those who have been wronged who
are portrayed as the bad guys, and the thieves and killers, desperately
defending a morally indefensible stance, who are the heroes. It's a
curious position for the film to take because it tempers any sympathy
the viewer might feel for the members of the Zachary family, whose
young daughter Rachel (Audrey Hepburn), is the now fully-grown child
stolen from the Kiowa after a massacre of one of their villages.
Perhaps it is meant as a comment on the inhuman treatment of Native
American Indians by white settlers in the 19th Century, or as an
observation on the nature of racism, which is the central theme that
forms the core of the movie, and of the power of film – and any other
form of media – to twist people's perception of right and wrong. The
Indians come across as the villains even though they are only ever
victims. It is this paradox at the core of the film that makes it so
fascinating while also clearly managing to alienate a large proportion
of its audience.There are a lot of flaws in this film and a lot of curious choices, not
least the relationship between vigorous patriarch figure Ben Zachary
(Burt Lancaster) and young Rachel, which is little short of incestuous
even though the couple are not blood relatives. Audrey Hepburn, while
giving a spirited performance, is as unbelievable as an Indian
half-breed as you would expect her to be. She's always enjoyable to
watch, but you're always aware of the effort you're having to put in to
maintain that suspension of disbelief necessary to truly get into any
character. The rest of the cast give terrific performances, especially
Audie Murphy as another of the Zachary clan battling with his innate
racism and Joseph Wiseman as a superbly sinister one-eyed drifter who,
like the Indians, becomes another innocent victim of the Zachary clan.
Murphy has a largely unsympathetic role in this film and, as he gives
one of the best performances of his career, it's a wonder he wasn't
offered more work in the same vein. John Saxon has a role that seems to
be important but which eventually goes nowhere – his character could
have been dispensed with completely with no noticeable loss to the
coherence of the storyline, although he is given a hip name and a
rather cool chase scene.Huston's direction is as professional and assured as expected. He
didn't make many westerns, but he displays a natural skill for
capturing the deceptive desolation of the sprawling landscapes – even
though this film strangely lacks the epic sweep that its subject matter
might suggest – and enhancing genre staples while exploring more adult
themes than were the norm in the late 50s. Many of his characters are
shot from a low angle so that they are framed by a huge sky, a
technique reminiscent of 30s Soviet techniques. Perhaps it's a common
practice in western movies but, if it is, it is surely one that has
never been used as much in one film as it is in this.This isn't a film to be dismissed lightly. Yes, there are flaws in many
areas, but they fail to detract from the many strengths the movie
possesses, and from the themes and subtexts that make this so much more
than just another western. Don't let this one pass you by.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0752019/comments</url><from>from KENT, ENGLAND</from><name>Walter Gibson</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I am in no way criticizing the film by saying this, but what kind of accent
is that by Audrey Hepburn. It's not that her performance is bad, no, it's
great. But Audrey Hepburn could never sound like she should be in a western.
She does seem to try hard at it, but she can't shake away the French/Posh
English/Cockney accent. But who really cares in the end. It must be really
difficult for an actress to look really good on the set of a western, with
all that dust and everything, but she looks real good.Another reason why I like this movie is because of Audie Murphy. Sure, ol'
Burt is a pro at this kind of thing, but he'll never be as cool as Audie
Murphy. He's the one with the most conflicts, "My sister, an injian!?!?!",
then he goes off drunk to his girlfriend Georgia. When she begs him to marry
her,
"I'm Drunk, but I not THAT drunk." Ha! Ha! The film also has genuinely tense and frightening moments, and we owe most
of these moments to Joseph Wiseman, playing Abe, the guy with the sword. He
didn't even blink, and that eye just stares right at you, but seems to be
out of focus at the same time like it's looking right through you. It
wouldn't be that surprising to see something like that in recent films,
because they've done psychos and demon-possessed aplenty since the
seventies. But in 1960, it probably was real scary.Saying it like the 'injians': FILM GOOD, YOU GO, SEE FILM.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2585859/comments</url><from>from Texas</from><name>nanksy</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I have read the comments posted about this remarkable movie and have to
wonder if the writers watched the movie. If they did it reflects an
appalling lack of historical knowledge. Audrey Hepburn plays Rachel
Zachary, a Kiowa Indian girl stolen during a raid on a Kiowa camp. Abe
Kelsey,(Joseph Wiseman)says it was a vengeance raid because renegade
Indians had massacred some settlers. He says, "we killed and we killed
til we had to lay down tired of the killin." It did not matter whether
the village they raided had anything to do with the killing of
settlers, or not. Will Zachary, who does not appear in the movie,
prevents Abe from killing a tiny Indian girl and takes the baby to his
wife who is grieving the loss of her own newborn girl. Will is later
killed by the Kiowas in an attempt to retrieve the baby. Rachel is
raised as a white girl by Matilda Zachary, (Lillian Gish) a cultured
Southern woman who hates the desolate North Texas ranchland where she
has finally settled after many moves to escape the vengeful Abe Kelsey.
He "rides vengeance" on the Zachary's because Will would not give him
the girl to trade for a son that he refuses to believe is dead and not
captured. Matilda, in an effort to hold back the ugliness of the
country and it's people, has taught all of her children to read and to
have an appreciation for classical music. Cash brings her a piano when
he returns from a cattle drive, which she later plays to "make
Medicine" against the Indians. Ben Zachary (Burt Lancaster) and his
brothers, Cash (Audie Murphy) and Andy (Doug McClure) have made
themselves and their neighbors rich by rounding up the plentiful supply
of wild cattle that roamed Texas after the end of the Civil War and
driving them to the railheads in Kansas. All of the people of the
region share a common hatred of Indians and half-breeds. That is where
the title "The Unforgiven" comes from. A vicious back and forth war has
been waged for the vast amount of land along the Red River and the
Indians have been defeated and placed on Reservations in Southern
Oklahoma. Up until the early 1900's there is a legal bounty on Indians
just as there is on coyotes. The Kiowas and the Comanches in particular
are considered by the settlers to be less than human. With no real
knowledge of the culture and traditions of their enemies there are a
lot of mistaken ideas about Indians. This is evidenced when the women
are told to strip Rachel and look at her body. The belief at that time
was that Indians had no body hair. Ben and his brothers do not know
that Rachel is not their sister until they find a buckskin page from
the Kiowa Book Of Days in their dugout cabin after they return home
from the hanging of Abe Kelsey. Mother confesses, and Cash, who is an
extreme example of the local hatred toward Kiowas, leaves his family to
face the Indians alone. Rachel, who has hidden a guilty love for Ben,
who she believed was her brother, tries to go out to her Indian brother
and stop the killing. Knowing that there is no way that Rachel can fit
in as a native, and realizing that he loves her, Ben prevents her from
going by killing a messenger from the Kiowas who is under a white flag.
The story ends with the death of Matilda, atoning for her sin of first
stealing and then concealing the origins of her adopted daughter, the
return of Cash to aid his family and the death of Rachel's true brother
by her hand. All of the family has made their choice. Rachel will marry
Ben, there is no other possible match for her now that it has been
revealed that she is Indian, and the Zachary family will stand alone
until times and attitudes change. The only flaws I found in the movie
were minor. There was no explanation of how Ben was able to read the
Indian signs on the buckskin page left in the cabin. There was not
enough development of the character of the Kiowa Chief so that the
expending of blood for the sake of one girl seemed excessive. One had
to assume that the Indians were trying to regain some of their pride by
retrieving the stolen girl and were willing to die for that reason but
that was not explained in the script. The movie is beautifully filmed.
The supporting cast was exceptional. Audie Murphy gave the performance
of his life. A movie well worth watching if taken at face value.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2325608/comments</url><from>from Staten Island, NY</from><name>Marc (captainblackadder)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I can't figure it out. Why does everyone love The Searchers? John Wayne's
young sidekick in that film, and his absurd romance, sink the film like a
stone. This film, which deals with a number of the same issues - racism,
kidnapping, mass slaughter, etc. - treats them with greater seriousness and
to better effect. There's wonderful moral ambiguity to The Unforgiven, an ambiguity which was
obviously built into the story from the beginning ... so we need not pat
ourselves on the back by rooting for the Indians in this one and thinking of
ourselves as so much wiser than the filmmakers. When a lot of Kiowa get
killed during the course of the film it is unsettling, partly because one
thinks in real life that their fighting tactics would be better, but mostly
because it is upsetting to see so much bloodshed.There are better westerns than this film - Open Range, Valdez is Coming,
Destry Rides Again, The Long Riders, The Cowboys - but that doesn't stop The
Unforgiven from being a first-rate movie filled with suspense and
fascinating characters. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2325608/comments</url><from>from Staten Island, NY</from><name>Marc (captainblackadder)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I can't figure it out. Why does everyone love The Searchers? John Wayne's
young sidekick in that film, and his absurd romance, sink the film like a
stone. This film, which deals with a number of the same issues - racism,
kidnapping, mass slaughter, etc. - treats them with greater seriousness and
to better effect. There's wonderful moral ambiguity to The Unforgiven, an ambiguity which was
obviously built into the story from the beginning ... so we need not pat
ourselves on the back by rooting for the Indians in this one and thinking of
ourselves as so much wiser than the filmmakers. When a lot of Kiowa get
killed during the course of the film it is unsettling, partly because one
thinks in real life that their fighting tactics would be better, but mostly
because it is upsetting to see so much bloodshed.There are better westerns than this film - Open Range, Valdez is Coming,
Destry Rides Again, The Long Riders, The Cowboys - but that doesn't stop The
Unforgiven from being a first-rate movie filled with suspense and
fascinating characters. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2325608/comments</url><from>from Staten Island, NY</from><name>Marc (captainblackadder)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-w-phillips-jr/</url><url>http://www.goatdog.com/moviePage.php?movieID=796 /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1498042</url><name>Michael W. Phillips, Jr.</name><from>Goatdog's Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>This film ... comes draped in the hair shirt of revisionism, but in reality it's an unrepentant throwback to the "good old days" when the only good Indian was a dead Indian.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/unforgiven1960.htm /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1354227</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>Considering how Huston and Lancaster have artistic disagreements over filming, it surprisingly still turned out relatively well.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-sanford/</url><url>/m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1301736</url><name>James Sanford</name><from>Kalamazoo Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Terrific Western with a strong message</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1415429</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kirk-honeycutt/</url><url>/m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1552968</url><name>Kirk Honeycutt</name><from>Hollywood Reporter</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/81046/the_unforgiven.html /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1519077</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9800E2DD123AEF3ABC4F53DFB266838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1389853</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/23944_UNFORGIVEN_HUSTON.html /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1236892</url><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=109742 /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=1147646</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117796026.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1022373-unforgiven/comments.php?reviewid=181890</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>Director John Huston and cameraman Franz Planer have teamed to provide an intelligent use of the medium for eye-pleasing effects...</comment></review></movie>