<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Jis Desh Men Ganga Behti Hai</original_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>Radhu Karmakar</director><producer>R.K. Films Ltd.</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Musical</genre><synopsis>
Orphaned lives a poor lifestyle in Central India and makes living singing songs. One day he comes to the assistance of an injured man...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Raj Kapoor</actor><actor>Padmini</actor><actor>Pran</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2792808/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Gowri</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Once again, Raj Kapoor produces a nice and touching movie.The movie has a basic theme: dacoits against the law. But in between
those two barriers is Raju (Raj Kapoor), a simple and honest fellow,
who is pure as the Ganga River...hence the title. He is a dafli wala.The story begins when the Sardar of a gang of Dakkus is shot by a
police officer. When Raju passes by, singing in a quite jolly way, the
Sardar points a gun at him, and tells Raju to take out any weapons that
he has. Raju reaches into his bag and takes out his most powerful
weapon...a fork. Yes, a fork, obviously Raju isn't a very violent
person. In fact, he ties the wound, and feeds the man. When the Sardar
becomes unconscious, Raju is worried. When he hears sounds outside, he
comes out and says, "Khabardaar, mein police officer hoon" (Don't dare,
I'm a police officer). Misunderstanding this, the dakkus kidnap Raju.Here he has to prove to the unbelieving dacoits and their families that
he is indeed just a dafliwala, and not a police officer. He shows off
his talent, and some believe him and some don't.One of the people who don't believe Raju is Rakka (Pran). He is very
suspicious and is annoyed at Raju. Why is he annoyed, you ask? Because
the village girl that Rakka wants to marry, Kammo (Padmini) starts to
like Raju. And just as predicted, they want to get married. Kammo
explains to him that the dakkus aren't bad, and that they just want to
make the rich and the poor equal.Ha, and Raju believes it.But he soon finds out about their ruthless crime, especially Rakka, who
kills a little boy and the brand new groom of a wedding where they were
to steal. Raju can't take it any more, and he decides that he has a lot
of problems to solve, not just with the dakkus, but with the police
too...who he thinks stoop just as low to stop crime. His journey of
love and justice starts here.So that's basically the plot. Actingwise, many were impressive. Raj
Kapoor, as usual, suited and flawlessly played his role. It's nice to
know that he produced a movie with such a nice theme. And Pran was no
less, he played his role with just as much intensity, and...I'm sad to
say...had a better hair style than our Raj. Hey, but that's okay right?
Lalita Pawar was very nice, and she also made me cry. Padmini overacted
in a few parts, but her role was not too influential so it didn't
really matter that much.And last but not least...the music! Beautiful. Every bit of it, from
the songs to the background score. Shankar Jaikishan once again makes a
perfect soundtrack for Raj Kapoor. Lata, as usual, sang her heart out,
captivating ours' as well. "O Basanti", "O Maine Pyar Kiya", "Begani
Shaadi Mein", and "Kya Hua" are especially beautiful. The classic "Aa
Ab Laut Chale" is magnificently sung by Mukesh, pierces the
emotions...along with Lata's silk like voice in-between the stanzas.
"Mera Naam Raju" and "Jis Desh Mein Ganga" are also classics sung by
Mukesh. "Hum Bhi Hain" is also a must-listen.The movie is touching and satisfying with every element of drama. I
rate it an eight out of ten. I would have rated it higher if there
weren't a few deaths that were a bit unnecessary...but I guess the
director can't change the story. Watch the movie! A classic!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2081542/comments</url><from>from Heraganahalli, India</from><name>Herag Halli</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
"Hothope Sachayi Rahti Hai, Jaha Dil Me Safayi Rahti Hai-Hum Wus Desh
Ke Vasii Hai-Hum Wus Desh Ke Vasii Hai-Jis Desh Mai Ganga Bahti Hai.
This song should be a National Anthem. Written by Shailandra and
Composed by Shankar-Jaikishan (late) the masters of melody in the
hey-days of the Indian Cinema--this title song tells the beauty of the
land an the people. Some fine acting by Padmini (late) and Pran as a
dacoit. Olden days the songs of the movie made tremendous impact wheel
before th movie was released. Raj Kapoor at that time was not known for
his showmanship as in later years. But he was putting his stamp of
quality for the RK Banner. The movie has some incredible black and
white photography by Radhu Karmarkar seen to be believed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19586377/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>dc-sfnv</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
heart touching movie.i liked pad-mini 's dialog 'oye hoy hoy hoy ' .i
can't forget this throughout life. raj k always did something
innovative in his movies. this movie also has the theme of changing the
heart of a bad man . pad-mini looked much pretty and energetic in the
movie.she was attractive and sensuous in movie. songs is one of the
prominent feature of movies of raj . singer's heart touching voice does
the justice with the song 'aa ab lout ch-ale'.Leta's voice 'aa re 'in
between the song makes it more beautiful. the other songs 'mera name
---','kya hoe' and 'mene 'were pretty enough.pad mini fulfills the
requirements as a substitute of previous actress .
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0000684/comments</url><from>from Eugene, Oregon</from><name>davo</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I'd rate this as one of my favorite Raj Kapoor films, even though he
didn't direct it, right up there with Shree 420. I like the music a
lot, especially, the drumming and percussion. The dancing is pretty fun
too, particularly when Padmini and Chanchal are jumping around
together. I also liked the water ballet sequence, when the women are
leaping into the the pool. This movie had a number of the elements I
appreciate in a Raj Kapoor film, besides the music: the river symbolism
is well-developed,and Raj plays one of his trademark simple,
good-hearted tramps who prevail despite the odds -- without TOO much
melodrama (which I don't care for.) I tend to prefer earlier films,
both from Raj Kapoor specifically and from Bollywood in general -- from
the sixties on they get too westernized for my taste, and the dacoit
setting here places the story squarely in Indian territory. I also
liked Padmini's spunky energy, and her repeated exclamation "Hoi hoi
hoi!" (whatever that means, I'd like to know,) it really got stuck in
my head!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0000684/comments</url><from>from Eugene, Oregon</from><name>davo</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I'd rate this as one of my favorite Raj Kapoor films, even though he
didn't direct it, right up there with Shree 420. I like the music a
lot, especially, the drumming and percussion. The dancing is pretty fun
too, particularly when Padmini and Chanchal are jumping around
together. I also liked the water ballet sequence, when the women are
leaping into the the pool. This movie had a number of the elements I
appreciate in a Raj Kapoor film, besides the music: the river symbolism
is well-developed,and Raj plays one of his trademark simple,
good-hearted tramps who prevail despite the odds -- without TOO much
melodrama (which I don't care for.) I tend to prefer earlier films,
both from Raj Kapoor specifically and from Bollywood in general -- from
the sixties on they get too westernized for my taste, and the dacoit
setting here places the story squarely in Indian territory. I also
liked Padmini's spunky energy, and her repeated exclamation "Hoi hoi
hoi!" (whatever that means, I'd like to know,) it really got stuck in
my head!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0000684/comments</url><from>from Eugene, Oregon</from><name>davo</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>