<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Die Bande des Schreckens</original_title><alt_title>Scotland Yard contre le masque</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>West Germany</country><director>Harald Reinl</director><producer>Rialto Film</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis/><actor>Joachim Fuchsberger</actor><actor>Karin Dor</actor><actor>Fritz Rasp</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0102677/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>John Seal</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This early entry in Rialto Film's krimi cycle may not have the most
interesting story, but it does have much to recommend it. After master
criminal Clay Shelton (gaunt Otto Collin) is executed by the hangman of
London, his 'ghost' returns from the dead and starts murdering those
responsible for his conviction. It's up to Chief Inspector Long of
Scotland Yard (handsome Joachim Fuchsberger) to solve the mystery and
end the serial killings, not to mention win the hand of fetching
secretary Nora Duncan (Karin Dor). Though the narrative is rather
plodding and fairly predictable, Die Bande des Schreckens benefits
tremendously from fabulous black and white cinematography by Albert
Benitz, who got his start shooting 'mountain films' with Leni
Riefenstahl back in the 1920s. His work here is truly exquisite, taking
full advantage of black and white stock's unique qualities, and Tobis'
PAL DVD does it full justice. There's also a spare but quite memorable
score from Heinz Funk, and Collin makes for a memorable, Mabuse-like
villain.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Another one of the German Edgar Wallace series. This time a master
criminal is caught as he attempts to rob a bank. A shoot out occurs and
a police officer is shot. Sentenced to die all of those responsible are
summoned to the man's cell where he threatens to do them all in. After
he is gone corpses begin to turn up and it soon becomes clear, even
though it shouldn't be possible, that the dead man is alive and well
and taking his revenge. Good film in the series isn't always the clear
plot-wise, but for what it fudges in plotting, it makes up in mood with
great black and white photography that makes everything thing much more
mysterious. Say what you will I really liked this a great deal. Worth a
look if you come across it
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Another one of the German Edgar Wallace series. This time a master
criminal is caught as he attempts to rob a bank. A shoot out occurs and
a police officer is shot. Sentenced to die all of those responsible are
summoned to the man's cell where he threatens to do them all in. After
he is gone corpses begin to turn up and it soon becomes clear, even
though it shouldn't be possible, that the dead man is alive and well
and taking his revenge. Good film in the series isn't always the clear
plot-wise, but for what it fudges in plotting, it makes up in mood with
great black and white photography that makes everything thing much more
mysterious. Say what you will I really liked this a great deal. Worth a
look if you come across it
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>