<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Seishun zankoku monogatari</original_title><alt_title>Contes cruels de la jeunesse</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Nagisa Ôshima</director><producer>Shochiku Ofuna</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Kiyoshi is a brooding young man who treats women solely as objects. Makoto is a young woman who is just reaching her sexual awakening...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Yûsuke Kawazu</actor><actor>Miyuki Kuwano</actor><actor>Yoshiko Kuga</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1658265/comments</url><from/><name>craigwill</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Oshima's film about adolescents in Tokyo was made in 1960 and is
extraordinarly prescient: the picture he portrays of teenagers is far in
advance of Swinging London and the Summer of Love in San Francisco. His
teenage protagonists not only have sex together, but are involved in a
sex-crime scam where the girl acts as a decoy for middle aged men to be
blackmailed for trying to solicit her sexual services. The treatment of
adolescent sexuality is far ahead of its time:Oshima gives us an accurate
picture of teenage sexual activity that was unthinkable at the time.
Brilliantly shot in cinemascope and exquisitely lit, the film is visually
arresting. The sequence where the male lead eats an apple over his
sleeping
girlfriend's sleeping body is one of many highlights. A little known
masterpiece by one of the masters of twentieth century Japanese cinema.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6915354/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (sugrr1123)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
See Cruel Story of Youth. It is an amazing film. Oshima Nagisa is
probably best known for his avant garde work- films like "In the Realm
of the Senses" and "Diary of a Shinjuku Thief"- but his earlier work is
more compelling, if less sensational. This film tells the story of
Makoto and Kiyoshi, two youths who suffer from the social malaise
typical of their generation. They express their frustration in violent
and poetic ways, which makes up the substance of the film's narrative.
But putting all that aside, it's beautifully filmed and by it's end,
completely heartwrenching. The color contrast is almost unprecedented-
bright reds and blues set against pitch blacks. At times it has the
sensibility of a yakuza film- violence abounds and Oshima makes use of
sharp pans typical of that genre, giving it a very cool, retro feel. At
it's core it's a love story, but of a sort that modern audiences will
probably never see in a contemporary film. It shows love as the
cruelest thing imaginable, making it difficult to watch at times, but
in the end, impossible to forget.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19394337/comments</url><from>from Tokyo</from><name>Irina Pismennaya</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
"Cruel story of youth" seems to me a hard movie to give any judgment
about. Trying to watch at the events of the drama from the point of
view of the time (historically), I see not more than a Japanese version
of "lost generation" drama. The ideals of parents passed away in the
recent war, the new aims were not created – is it not a universal
generation crises of searching your own way in life? While watching the
movie, I asked myself if it is necessary to search for any hidden
message of the director… if there is one…The characters and events are described in a very direct, comparable to
the animation speed and simplicity way (that was one of the points
which I could dare to compare with the "trash-movie" stylistic). There
is a lot of "beating directly into the face" full of disguise scenes
(for the year 1960 the movie is full of violence and sex – what I guess
was pretty "fresh" and not known at that time). The message of the
director was delivered in the right way, no doubt that the movie drew
public attention – that is the other point which I appreciate in
director's work.Now to the heroes (or anti-heroes, as I think a lot of people would
tell): the main heroes of the drama present the whole collection of
sins and all kinds of misbehavior. The antipathy to them is growing
with every their word and step. The two try to fight the way through to
the future and… fail. There is no one around (false existence or
practical non-existence of a good example neither in society nor in
their own family) to give them the right answer on: what to do to be
happy? As Kiyoshi says: "We only sell ourselves in order to go on
living. No matter how I fight it, that's what the world is like." Isn't
life disappointing? Love and death are linked in quite an extravagant way in this movie,
resulting in a kind of "romantic antiromantic". What is left at the
end? A symptom of a lost generation's aimlessness and moral bankruptcy
(and lost innocence)… No doubt, "Cruel story of youth" is a very
expressive movie the main topic of which could get up-to-date anytime
(as it is well known that times pass – men and problem stay the same).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a curious film, definitely of its time, but not from France.
The two lovers Kyoschi and Makoto have a devil may care attitude about
things. At times, you want to shake the female lead (Makoto) and tell
her to be more responsible. Kyoschi is sometimes just this side of
brutal to her, both physically and psychologically. The film reminds me
a bit of "Rebel Without A Cause" and even "Breathless", which is more
than likely intentional. For a Japanese film, it is fairly gritty. My
only complaint is that most of the characters besides the two star
crossed/unfortunately matched lovers are underwritten. I wonder if
anyone thought at that time to show this film to youths in Japan, to
let them know that falling in love is not always the true path to
happiness. An interesting, fully watchable film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5659357/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>plan2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is an interesting story about how stupid and self-destructive
people—young people in this case—can be. This movie was released in
1960, but look around and it's clear that the issues it brings
up—although in a somewhat overly melodramatic way—continue to be
relevant today, and probably always will be as long as human beings
exist. The previous reviewer has the right to their negative opinion,
but I think they missed the big picture, perhaps they are just too
young to know any better. Besides following a good storyline, it is also well-shot. The
cinematography is crisp. And the overall nature of the photography
gives the film a fantastic and hermetic quality. It's gritty, and
obviously seeks to be realistic, but it has the feel of a fable or a
morality tale.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2067905/comments</url><from>from Japan</from><name>cteavin-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Not the best film for it's time; I've not seen anything else from this
director, so I can't comment on that aspect of the film....I had to remind myself several times while watching that this film is
almost fifty years old. Elements of the story remind of today,
especially the "scams" and the gritty aspect of teenage relationships
and sexuality; at the same time I could never suspend my disbelief over
the age of the actors -- they in no way resembled a high school girl or
a college boy. The editing is a mess; I'm guessing that the director
was attempting something artistic. The story, however, is very good.
(Unfortunately the translation I watched mistranslated several scenes
and so took the punch out from the delivery.)I could recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see some of the
grime of post-war Japan. But if you watch this film leave your modern
sensibilities at home: Joan Collins said that she was rapped by the man
that later became her husband and that seemingly topsy turvy attitude
about sex and relationships is a large part of this film: the
definitions were different, sex was novel on the big screen and peoples
perspectives were not the same as today and I see no point in
complaining about the gaps; I feel it's better to acknowledge them,
think about how they might have been viewed and then look past them to
the story the director was trying to tell.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0386919/comments</url><from>from Freiburg, Germany</from><name>Martin Riexinger</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Kiyoshi is a student with a completely immoral attitude towards women (and
other things too). His young lover Makoto seeks adventure with him. Unlike
her younger sister, a former left winger she doesn't bother about changing
the society but she just wants fun, but the completely egotist attitude of
her lover brings about ruin for both.the beginning of the film which is ingenious and visually very inspiring
is
followed by a rather mediocre middle part, where their method of gaining
money by luring middle aged men into a trap is described excessively.
Nevertheless you don't get to know if the first scene of the film is
already
a part of that profession or a mere accident.But now watch the film for yourself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
I know that many consider this film to be a classic and my very low
score will most likely trigger a lot of "not helpful" votes, but I just
didn't like this film at all. I understand that the film is in many
ways a Japanese film version of the important French film BREATHLESS,
but like BREATHLESS, the leading characters are so unpleasant I had a
hard time sticking with the film--though with THE CRUEL STORY OF YOUTH
the characters a lot more unpleasant and slimy.The girl is an idiot high schooler who slavishly follows after a
college student who treats her like garbage. He rapes her twice at the
beginning of the film and in return, she devotes herself to him!! The
guy, in addition to being a rapist, is a violent user. The loves to
fight and sleep around and does little to hide it from the girl.
Considering that neither seem to ever go to class and don't have jobs,
they earn money by setting up men to try to rape the girl--at which
point the guy jumps out and beats up the men and takes their money. It
sounds like a match made in heaven, right?! So why make the American
title of the film "THE CRUEL STORY OF YOUTH"? What's cruel about the
story--both characters choose to be evil and choose their fates. It
isn't like they are somehow victims (though the film does try to paint
it that way). Their lives are pointless and selfish. Rape, abortion,
extortion, indifference--after a short time I found myself getting very
tired of the whole thing and, oddly, when the film had it's supposed
sad ending, I was thrilled! I say good riddance and bring me a film I
can care about--not this nihilistic and nasty little film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1221528/comments</url><from/><name>Todd Mason</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
I got very little from this film, other than it furthered my impression
of Oshima as a misanthrope with very little of substance to offer about
the human condition he has so little feeling for, nor the people he
apparently reviles. It is, indeed, a Cruel Story, as one iteration of
the English title would have it, but it doesn't even have the cheap
thrills offered by Oshima's best-known film in the US, usually referred
to here as IN THE REALM OF THE SENSES, but does share a remarkably ugly
cinematographic color scheme (this might be a function of the prints
and transfers I've seen, but both films in my viewing have been heavily
into a reddish wash), fitting well with the remarkably ugly spirit with
which both were offered. Not too impressed with the performances,
either.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0314798/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>Roy Teng</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

I watched this movie during an international film course at my university
and I will not forgive them for making me watch this!
Did I miss something because I thought this movie was just a complete
waste
of my time. You can't relate to any of the characters; the women are dumb
and easy, the men dumb and ruthless. The beginning especially was
terrible:
a girl who almost gets raped is saved by a man who later rapes her
himself.I was like... huh??? What's the point in watching this for educational
purposes at the university? Why not watch good old Japanese comedies
instead
(e.g. Juzo Itami's movies)? I was irritated that I wasted time with this
movie.
Advise:Just figure out what movies YOU like and stay away from this one!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0314798/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>Roy Teng</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

I watched this movie during an international film course at my university
and I will not forgive them for making me watch this!
Did I miss something because I thought this movie was just a complete
waste
of my time. You can't relate to any of the characters; the women are dumb
and easy, the men dumb and ruthless. The beginning especially was
terrible:
a girl who almost gets raped is saved by a man who later rapes her
himself.I was like... huh??? What's the point in watching this for educational
purposes at the university? Why not watch good old Japanese comedies
instead
(e.g. Juzo Itami's movies)? I was irritated that I wasted time with this
movie.
Advise:Just figure out what movies YOU like and stay away from this one!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0314798/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>Roy Teng</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>