<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Let No Man Write My Epitaph</original_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Philip Leacock</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
In this sequel to "Knock On Any Door", the residents of a Chicago tenement building band together to insure that the son of Nick Romano does not follow in his father's footsteps...to the electric chair.
</synopsis><actor>Burl Ives</actor><actor>Shelley Winters</actor><actor>James Darren</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3692943/comments</url><from>from São Paulo, Brazil</from><name>adsqueiroz</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
What a film! A classic or a thriller, I don't know, but it sure is one
of those films for you not to miss. It is already one of my favorite
classics. A story that makes you understand how it is important to
pursue a dream, a dream of not letting a child follow the footsteps of
a criminal father. A story that teaches us some important values. It is
a struggle for life and an excellent opportunity for us to think about
this problem. Drugs, violence and alcohol are some of the matters that
make this film an important issue to discuss about. Good casting and
acting also help to make this film a must-see. It is a classic worth
watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0520798/comments</url><from>from Houston, Texas</from><name> (mctoomey@email.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is one of my all-time favorite films. A classic inner city drama
which
draws you into the lives of the characters, their strengths and
weaknesses.
A solid cast brings to life the struggles of a group of, for lack of
words,
losers who band together to help a young man escape a life of poverty
filled
with drugs, alcohol, and violence. This movie is rarely on TV so if you
get
the chance, don't miss it. Watch for the climactic final scenes which
feature Burl Ives going "through" (as opposed to breaking open) a bolted
door, then "absorbing" six rounds from a .38 before throttling heroin
pusher
and all-around bad guy, Ricardo Montalban. As an added treat, the great
Ella
Fitzgerald sings in her role as, of course, a singer. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0568099/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>marcslope</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Kind of a cross between "West Side Story" (though it's Chicago's West
Side) and "Golden Boy" without Clifford Odets' lyricism, this
sleaze-obsessed melodrama benefits from location filming that shows how
awful the Chicago slums looked in 1960 and a motley, oddball cast.
James Darren is the sensitive hood/concert pianist (and though he's
proficient at the keyboard, he's hardly the prodigy the script makes
him out to be), being raised by Shelley Winters at her Shelley
Wintersiest, screaming and sobbing and unhinging easily. She and an
assembly of longtime slum pals, including an uninteresting Burl Ives as
a drunken ex-judge, are trying to give the kid a decent upbringing amid
all the squalor. There are also Ricardo Montalban, excellent as an
insidiously evil-charming dope peddler; Ella Fitzgerald, who gets to
act a bit and isn't bad; and Jean Seberg, not quite credible as the
Lake Shore girl Darren loves. The direction is uninspired, and the
screenplay a little contrived (when it wants us to know Ives loves
Winters, it just has him confess to the camera), but what's fascinating
is the brio with which the filmmakers depict all the sex and violence
and addiction and grimness. It's as if they were trying to show how
grownup they are by thrusting all that misery in your face. It moves
fast, and if your attention starts to wander, be assured, Shelley
Winters will be erupting again soon.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
James Darren (as Nick "Nicky" Romano) grows up innocently, in the slums
of Chicago. He's the illegitimate son of the original "Nick Romano",
from "Knock on Any Door" (1949). Gin-medicating mom Shelley Winters (as
Nellie Romano) does the best she can raising Mr. Darren; she hopes his
musical talent will help him to achieve a better life, unlike his
father. Ms. Winters, to her credit, organizes a nurturing group of
deadbeats. Chief among them is boozing co-dependent judge Burl Ives (as
Bruce M. Sullivan). Together, they raise Darren well, but the Chicago
underworld threatens to drag him down… Interesting "sequel" (of sorts); actually, this is an adaptation of
Willard Motley third novel, "Let No Man Write My Epitaph", which was a
follow-up to his first, "Knock on Any Door". The earlier film starred
John Derek and Humphrey Bogart, and lacked much of the realism needed
to accurately tell the story. There are some allusions to the earlier
film; the shot of the adult Romano (Darren) ascending a stairway
recalls the earlier film, as does a picture of the original Romano.
This film is much better scripted; and, importantly, Chicago denizens
could be shown selling, and using, Heroin. The drug use becomes a very
big part of the picture.This film isn't without flaws; and, for most of the early running time,
it teeters so close to plodding, soapy melodrama, you might get
disenchanted. However, growing characterizations from the three leads,
and nice location photography, enhance the production. Additionally,
there are good supporting performances; from, for example, smarmy
Ricardo Montalban (as Louie) and legless Walter Burke (as Wart). And,
of course, Ella Fitzgerald (as Flora) sings beautifully.Around the time (at about 1:11) Mr. Ives has a saloon scene with Ms.
Fitzgerald in the background (after a fix), the film really takes off.
Situations become significantly more obvious. Darren, Winters, and Ives
have big dramatic, well-played scenes. The intensity of the film
heightens, to quite a very exciting conclusion. ******* Let No Man Write My Epitaph (1960) Phillip Leacock ~ James
Darren, Shelley Winters, Burl Ives
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4515977/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>LadyRagweed</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I was pleasantly surprised by all of the comments on this film. I
haven't seen it for many, many, years, probably 15 or more. However, I
remember it well and had believed for a long time that I was the only
one who knew of it's existence. *laughing* This is one of my favorite
Shelley Winters movies. And of course Miss Ella Fitzgerald was an added
treat. I first saw it when I was about 15 (mid-1970s), so you can
imagine what an impact it had on me. I'd had a crush on James Darren
from his role in the television series "The Time Tunnel". I wish I
could find it on video or DVD somewhere; but that's unlikely. I was
just looking over the credits and saw a couple of familiar names;
Bernie Hamilton(who starred in a lot of the so-called Blaxploitation
films of the seventies) and Jeanne Cooper,whom I adored in the
seventies as Mrs. Chancellor in the popular soap, "The Young and the
Restless". Try as I might, I cannot remember them in the film. Which is
why it is a must I see it again! *Laughing* I'll be armed with "TVio"
and "VCR" the next time it makes it's appearance on cable....TCM are
you listening???!! Miss "P"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0128459/comments</url><from>from Tecumseh ok</from><name>bux</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

In this sequel to "Knock On Any Door" (1949) we find Nick Romano's
illegitimate son being raised by his mother and a band of well intentioned,
but flawed  residents of a tennement slum.  Winters as his drug addicted
mother, and Montalban as her pusher are stand-out performances.  It is a
gripping scene, when young Nick walks in on his mother and her pusher and
catches them "in the act.."  Seldom appears on TV, but well worth
catching. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
(Some Spoilers) Powerful story about life on the other side of the
street. In this case the shoddy and crime ridden slums of Chicago
personified in the movie as West Madison Street.Hard working waitress and sometime B-girl Nellie Romano, Shelley
Winters, has been trying to keep her young and talented son Nick Jr,
James Darren, out of trouble since her common-law husband "Pretty Boy"
Nick ended up frying in the state electric chair. "Pretty Boy" gunned
down a cop outside a nightclub back in 1948 when Nick Jr was less then
a year old. Keeping his mouth shut not to implicate his gangster
friends "Pretty Boy" Nick paid for what he did with his life.It's when Nick Jr just couldn't take the razzing anymore from his
high-school classmates about his both dead father and hard working
mother that he started to get himself into trouble defending them and
their backgrounds: A hard working and sacrificing, for her son, mother
and a convicted and executed for murder father.With the help of a number of people from the neighborhood including
local barfly and former circuit judge Bruce Sullivan, Burt Ives, young
Nick has his life turned around as he starts to practice with his piano
keys not with his fists. Playing up a storm and bringing people
listening literally to tears, whenever he bangs and tinkers the ivory
keys, Nick is soon destined to become one of the great ones: Another
musical genius on the piano like Rubinstein Pederewski or Richter.It's when Nellie meets, at the dive she's working at, hoodlum Louie
Ramponi, Recordo Montalban, that things for her and young Nick started
really going sour. Bailing Nick out of prison for an act of juvenile
delinquency, a fist fight, Louis starts to work on his mom Nellie in
getting her hooked on dope. Having a front as a both flower dealer and
bookie Louie's real source of income, that he of course keeps from the
IRS, is pushing junk or dope in the neighborhood.As Nellie's life went to pot her son's was picking up with Nick being
discovered, with the help of Judge Sullivan, by multi-millionaire and
music lover Grant Holloway, Philip Ober. Grant's daughter the classy
and beautiful Barbara Holloway, Jean Seaberg, got so hung up on Nick's
music, not his boyish good looks, that she became his girlfriend,
Nick's first, without him even having a chance to ask her out for a
date. A star struck Barbara even proposed to Nick before he had a
chance to pinch himself to see if he was dreaming or not!It's when Nick came home to Madison Street unexpectedly, to tell his
mom the good news, that he found to his horror Nellie, with Louie
helping her shoot up, strung out on the big "H" heroin. Running away in
disgust Nick gets a gun from the local friendly and legless neighbor
newspaper peddler Wart, Walter Burke, and crashes into Louie's flower
shop to pay him back for what he did to his mom.***SPOILER ALERT***Overpowered by Louie and one of his goons Wally,
Jack Bryan, Nick is tied up and about to be shot up with a possible
"hot load" of heroin not only turning him into a junkie but having him
buried next to his long dead father Nick Senior whom he's never met!
It's then that the outraged and bear-like Judge Sullivan comes on the
scene and at the cost of his own life single-handedly puts an end to
Louie Ramponi's crime empire by putting an end to him.Hard hitting and effective the movie "Let No Man Write My Epitaph" goes
where no other film, back then in 1960, dared to go. The movie shows
how dope or drugs are used by slime-balls like Louie Ramponi to keep
people enslaved and under their control. Also in the movie is jazz
legend Ella Fitzgerald as the downtrodden and suicidal Flora who just
happens to be one of Louie's many drug addicted customers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8878150/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Lorddavud1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This film is one of the favorite memories from my childhood. My memory
said that Sal Mineo was in it, so I was a little surprised to see that
it was actually James Darren. Not as good an actor as Sal, but a good
looking kid, who could sing. Shelley Winters is beautiful in it, but
very needy. Ella is a bonus. Burl Ives is bigger than life. And, you
get to see Ricardo Montalban as a pre Mr. Roarke, pre Chrysler New
Yorker ("Fine Corinthian leather"), bad guy. The climatic finale has
stayed with me all these years. I always thought it was an older movie,
but I guess it was just the genre and the cinematography. A little
hokey, by today's standards, but a classic none the same.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8928639/comments</url><from>from Pittsburgh, PA</from><name>Jeff Grunden</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
With the recent death of Shelley Winters, all the principals in this
movie are now gone, with the exception of Montalban. Having looked it
up, I had forgotten what a fine cast it had, including the surprise of
Ella Fitzgerald playing a heroin-addicted blues singer. Sadly, although
this was a remake of a previous film, this great film could not be
remade or even updated for today's market---simply because our society
has changed to where the story in this picture (compelling as it is)
would no longer be something people would consider important or even
divisive. This plot could not even make the producers of Jerry or Maury
take notice. Still, this picture will always be one of my two or three
personal all-time favorites, and I will recommend it to anyone who
reads these words I write: This is greatness that Hollywood can
create...when it really wants to.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20848266/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ramblinjack1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Based on African-American novelist Willard Motley's book (1958) of the
same name (title from 19th century Irish Patriot Robert Emmet's famous
execution speech, see below). This story takes up the plight of two of
the original characters from "Knock" and illustrates the frustrations
of a group of residents living on "lower class" East Madison Street in
Chicago, circa late 1950's.Nellie Romano (Shelly Winters) is a single Mother bringing up her only
son Nick (James Darren), a promising young piano virtuoso.
Unfortunately, they and their neighborhood friends are each burdened
with the sad fate that "for the wrong turn sometime earlier" they must
endure their chosen lot in life. But this tale is not a sappy
string-together story of separate woes; rather (in the beginning) an
optimistic hope for the future if the pieces of the puzzle fall just
right.Of course, our 'extended family' realize early that the chances of the
puzzle's success are remote, as they only have their personal disasters
to judge success. There is Nellie's sad story, a past the whole
neighborhood knows of, save Nick and the "defrocked" Judge (Burl Ives)
who has commuted his own sentence to the bottom of a bottle rather than
a court of law. Also a prostitute (Jeanne Cooper), an ex-prizefighter
(Bernie Hamilton), the smack addict (Fitzgerald) and a paraplegic
(Walter Burke) who in their own way try their best to make each other
happy.Along the way they careen into the lower tiers of an immoral society of
disreputable scum-bags, including racketeer Louie Ramponi (Montalban).
What transpires next is the 'family' banding together for survival; but
the question is, are they strong enough to escape a 'bottomless pit'
without even a knotted rope for escape? Maybe the apple of everyone's
eyes, young Nick can.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20848266/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ramblinjack1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Based on African-American novelist Willard Motley's book (1958) of the
same name (title from 19th century Irish Patriot Robert Emmet's famous
execution speech, see below). This story takes up the plight of two of
the original characters from "Knock" and illustrates the frustrations
of a group of residents living on "lower class" East Madison Street in
Chicago, circa late 1950's.Nellie Romano (Shelly Winters) is a single Mother bringing up her only
son Nick (James Darren), a promising young piano virtuoso.
Unfortunately, they and their neighborhood friends are each burdened
with the sad fate that "for the wrong turn sometime earlier" they must
endure their chosen lot in life. But this tale is not a sappy
string-together story of separate woes; rather (in the beginning) an
optimistic hope for the future if the pieces of the puzzle fall just
right.Of course, our 'extended family' realize early that the chances of the
puzzle's success are remote, as they only have their personal disasters
to judge success. There is Nellie's sad story, a past the whole
neighborhood knows of, save Nick and the "defrocked" Judge (Burl Ives)
who has commuted his own sentence to the bottom of a bottle rather than
a court of law. Also a prostitute (Jeanne Cooper), an ex-prizefighter
(Bernie Hamilton), the smack addict (Fitzgerald) and a paraplegic
(Walter Burke) who in their own way try their best to make each other
happy.Along the way they careen into the lower tiers of an immoral society of
disreputable scum-bags, including racketeer Louie Ramponi (Montalban).
What transpires next is the 'family' banding together for survival; but
the question is, are they strong enough to escape a 'bottomless pit'
without even a knotted rope for escape? Maybe the apple of everyone's
eyes, young Nick can.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>