<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hadaka no shima</original_title><alt_title>L'île nue</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Kaneto Shindô</director><producer>Kindai Eiga Kyokai</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Deals with the intolerably hard life of a family of four, the only inhabitants of a very small Japanese island in the Setonaikai archipelago...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Nobuko Otowa</actor><actor>Taiji Tonoyama</actor><actor>Shinji Tanaka</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4549277/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Garranlahan</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I was living next to the Seto Naikai (Inland Sea) at the time this
movie was made, and marvel at its matchless, eclectic choice of images
and atmosphere to convey the ambiance of the time and place. The
photography, music, and restrained acting are perfection itself. The
lack of dialogue helps, rather than hinders, its beautiful, simple
story. It has captured a Japanese way of life and culture (actually
lived by the director---the movie was made as a tribute to his parents)
forever and in the very highest artistic sense. The movie is so
genuine, so sympathetic to its participants and subject matter, that
the viewer is softly, irresistibly, drawn in to share their travails.
For years it has been a wonder to me why this classic film has been
forgotten. Of the thousands of movies I have seen in my lifetime, this
is the finest.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1425910/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>M. Lepik-Stahl</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I was surfing on the t.v. and came across this incredible "little" film on
a
French Canadian station.  As there is no dialogue and the story is so
human
and pure, it is truly the most universal picture I've seen.  I defy anyone
not to be moved by the challenges which the characters face, the realism
in
the minimalist acting and the beauty of the simplistic black and white
camerawork.
I've never heard of this film, but I will tell all my friends about
it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0602237/comments</url><from>from Boston, USA</from><name> (pzzz@acunet.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I came to the internet searching for information on this movie.  Not only
did I find it, but I found a comment that mirrored my own
experience with the movie.  I too saw it in my student days, nearly 30
years
ago, in a Friday-night "cinema" series in the student union theater.  I see
it's listed as B&amp;W; I remember it in color -- maybe colorized it in my
head?
No dialog, just music and environmental sound; gorgeous photography of the
island, the sea, the brutally hard work ferrying water for the crops on the
terraces.  And we follow that work for a long long time; we go through
impressed, to irritated (why don't they move to town for chrissake), to
rage
at being made to sit through this for so long, to numb resignation.  So
we're right where the characters are.  Writhing in my seat, hoping it will
come to an end.  And then the brief scene that left me stunned, that made
sense of all that lead up to it, two seconds of film that explain us in the
universe.  Like William, I've never met anyone else who's seen this movie.
And I don't know if I could sit through it again.  But I'm sure glad I did
back then.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6327870/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>j-hoyles</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Amazing! Let me join the happy few who saw this film when it first came
out. It was in Paris. I was a student. It was L'Ile Nu I think. And I
have never forgotten it and never seen it again. That's over 40 years
ago! And now it is coming out on DVD and most people will never have
heard of it. So my dear golden oldies who were young in 1961, rejoice
and tell everyone. This is pure cinema with no frills, worthy of
comparison with Dreyer, Bresson and O'Flaherty and a lovely companion
piece to Shindo's ONIBABA. That onibaba grass stayed with us over the
years as did that naked island. Talking of films lost but not
forgotten, I can draw a comparison with MERE JEANNE DES ANGES (same
subject matter as Ken Russell's THE DEVILS)which I saw in Leipzig in
about 1962 and which I have never seen since. What a coincidence! That
Polish film (MOTHER JOAN OF THE ANGELS)is also coming out on DVD. Real
poetic cinema is trickling through the mishmash.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0214998/comments</url><from>from San Diego, USA</from><name>sansay</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I saw this movie twenty years ago and I still remember it fondly. It should
be part of the training of movie directors to see and analyze this
movie.
The naked island (as it was named in France) shows the hard struggle of a
fisherman's family to survive in a very harsh environment. It is very
emotional yet does not call on any modern artifice to carry the message.
The
music will stay with you forever.
My only regret is that I can't get a copy to show my children what movie
making can be.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0520495/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Ontario, Canada</from><name>Evan Wm. Cameron</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
If you have ever wondered what a film would be like that exemplifies
how the tools of the craft can be used to do powerfully what no other
art can do, this film answers the question. It is among the most
carefully wrought, least encumbered yet profound movies ever made. The
fact that it has long been unavailable in America and Europe in any
accessible format reflects very sadly upon us all. (Addendum 15 March
2008 for those of you with region-free players: the English
distributor, Eureka, has thankfully released the original widescreen
version of the movie in PAL format in its 'The Masters of Cinema
Series', #12, with an optional commentary by Shindo and his composer,
Hikaru Hayashi. Available from Amazon.uk.)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0161835/comments</url><from>from new york</from><name>William Reynolds (billr@tao.agoron.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I remember this film from my student days. I saw it in an uptown, shabby,
art house theatre (when art meant porn) in Philadelphia. I was amazed. As I
recall, it is a film without dialog. Not silent, but no dialog. Black and
white, but singularly visual. Three, maybe four characters with self-
effacing directing and camera work, it was as intimate as small off-Broadway
theatre. I've seen nothing since as cinematic, or moving. No one I've ever
met, has seen it. But I remember it vividly.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0986307/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>Insp. Clouzot</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Probably one of the most moving movies in the history ; the more so because
of the simplicity of the movie: no dialogs, B&amp;W, a very slow pace and non
professional actors. But from the first to the last minute it is about fate
and courage and man.
Do see it. You'll understand.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0182842/comments</url><from>from france</from><name> (cathvince@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Probably one of the most simple and still moving movies ever seen. No words.
No special effects. A family: human beings that live and work and suffer and
die and live.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17699578/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>chaos-rampant</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Okay, we have a loving tribute here, personal for director Kaneto
Shindo as portraying the life of his parents. We have the rural
hardship, and dogged persistence for live in a place where water is
painfully hauled over a steep cliff, and we have the quiet cinematic
language that describes it. But also describes a life of simple pleasures. Shindo observes both
closely, with sympathy.The narrative thread of The Naked Island flows with the slow and dull
repetition of life itself - if the movie is dull and monotonous it is
because life is dull and monotonous and with a handful of fleeting
moments of pleasure and joy scattered among the daily routine of making
ends meet. In that sense, the artificiality that some reviewers have
spoken of (certainly Shindo's decision to include no dialogues and the
film almost silent save for a few natural sounds and voices) touches
upon the heart of the thing.The film follows the cycle of the seasons as the family tries to
survive in the small island and it is by using the renewal of nature as
a backdrop that Shindo draws emphasis on the periodic nature of life
and time - the snake that eats its tail. The theme of renewal and the
cycle of life and death is further symbolized through long, repetitious
sequences of the man and wife transporting irrigation water in large
buckets through the steep steps of a hillside and even further as
Shindo ends the film cyclically with the same aerial shot that opened
it.The other major triumph for the great Japanese director is the visual
language he employs to tell the simple and languidly paced story. This
is probably a point that will only interest the avid film buff but I'm
fairly sure it's that kind of person only that will seek out such a
film anyway. The cinematography consists of full images, superb staging
and framing of the (little is the truth) action, images as much
beautiful in the subject they present as in the presentation of the
subject itself and vibrating with honesty and clarity of vision. As
with Kurosawa in DERSU UZALA, The Naked Island captures the essence of
'life as lived in' - the texture, the mood, the smell.Combined with the symbolism he has carefully planted within the film,
The Naked Island is a complete depiction of life on both macrocosmic
and microcosmic levels. Of a very specific kind of life the truth is
(rural life in a Japanese island in the 30's) but in the larger scheme
of things and in the things that actually matter, what is true of one
man is true of many.In an age where directors are content to just wink at their audiences
with a sense of smug satisfaction, presenting us with cynic and
gimmicky films, swapping emotional catharsis for surprise 'twists',
doing away with honest character portrayals in favour of decorating
characters with random quirks, having forgotten visual storytelling in
favour of redundant voiceovers, shaky cams or self-consciously, witty
dialogue; in an age like this, The Naked Island seems to come from
another planet, alien to the mentality and ethics of modern cinema as
much as its bucolic subject matter is to modern city life. It's
definitely not something that will appeal to most but those that will
set out looking for it will not be disappointed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17699578/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>chaos-rampant</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Okay, we have a loving tribute here, personal for director Kaneto
Shindo as portraying the life of his parents. We have the rural
hardship, and dogged persistence for live in a place where water is
painfully hauled over a steep cliff, and we have the quiet cinematic
language that describes it. But also describes a life of simple pleasures. Shindo observes both
closely, with sympathy.The narrative thread of The Naked Island flows with the slow and dull
repetition of life itself - if the movie is dull and monotonous it is
because life is dull and monotonous and with a handful of fleeting
moments of pleasure and joy scattered among the daily routine of making
ends meet. In that sense, the artificiality that some reviewers have
spoken of (certainly Shindo's decision to include no dialogues and the
film almost silent save for a few natural sounds and voices) touches
upon the heart of the thing.The film follows the cycle of the seasons as the family tries to
survive in the small island and it is by using the renewal of nature as
a backdrop that Shindo draws emphasis on the periodic nature of life
and time - the snake that eats its tail. The theme of renewal and the
cycle of life and death is further symbolized through long, repetitious
sequences of the man and wife transporting irrigation water in large
buckets through the steep steps of a hillside and even further as
Shindo ends the film cyclically with the same aerial shot that opened
it.The other major triumph for the great Japanese director is the visual
language he employs to tell the simple and languidly paced story. This
is probably a point that will only interest the avid film buff but I'm
fairly sure it's that kind of person only that will seek out such a
film anyway. The cinematography consists of full images, superb staging
and framing of the (little is the truth) action, images as much
beautiful in the subject they present as in the presentation of the
subject itself and vibrating with honesty and clarity of vision. As
with Kurosawa in DERSU UZALA, The Naked Island captures the essence of
'life as lived in' - the texture, the mood, the smell.Combined with the symbolism he has carefully planted within the film,
The Naked Island is a complete depiction of life on both macrocosmic
and microcosmic levels. Of a very specific kind of life the truth is
(rural life in a Japanese island in the 30's) but in the larger scheme
of things and in the things that actually matter, what is true of one
man is true of many.In an age where directors are content to just wink at their audiences
with a sense of smug satisfaction, presenting us with cynic and
gimmicky films, swapping emotional catharsis for surprise 'twists',
doing away with honest character portrayals in favour of decorating
characters with random quirks, having forgotten visual storytelling in
favour of redundant voiceovers, shaky cams or self-consciously, witty
dialogue; in an age like this, The Naked Island seems to come from
another planet, alien to the mentality and ethics of modern cinema as
much as its bucolic subject matter is to modern city life. It's
definitely not something that will appeal to most but those that will
set out looking for it will not be disappointed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17699578/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>chaos-rampant</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>