<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Akibiyori</original_title><alt_title>Fin d'automne</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Yasujir么 Ozu</director><producer>Sh么chiku Eiga</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A widow try to marry off her daughter with the help of her late husband's three friends.
</synopsis><actor>Setsuko Hara</actor><actor>Y么ko Tsukasa</actor><actor>Mariko Okada</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6257947/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Daniel Vazquez</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Ozu's common themes of ageing, filial ties and modernisation are as
present here as in many other of his films. But in this film, as well
as the melancholy and gentleness we are accustomed to, there are large
doses of comedy which makes this film far more accessible for the
uninitiated.The story centres around a widow (Setsuko Hara) and her daughter (Yoko
Tsukasa). The daughter doesn't want to get married because she wants to
care for her mother, whereas the mother wants her daughter to marry
even though she realises she'll be left alone. So far everything is
extremely familiar. Except that in this case the dead husband's friends
get involved, trying to find suitors for both mother and daughter, thus
creating comical situations, causing family tensions, and finally
necessitating for the daughter's friend to step in and sort out the
mess.All in all highly recommended for anyone who wishes to try out this
highly prestigious director, and a strong reminder for fans of why we
love him so much.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3608743/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, CA, USA</from><name>Ed Uyeshima</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Even though the comparison is obviously intentional, Yasujiro Ozu's
1960 film is really a variation on his classic 1949 father-daughter
drama, "Late Spring". He goes further with this parallel by having the
wondrous Setsuko Hara, who played the daughter in the original film,
play the mother in this one, even though only eleven years have
elapsed. Gone is the alternately feisty, flirtatious and petulant
manner that marked her earlier performance as Noriko, and in its place
is that remarkable stillness and quiet warmth in her portrayal of Akiko
that marked the best of Hara's later performances. She was barely forty
during filming, yet she carries the gravitas of her role with uncommon
ease. What remains consistent between her two performances is the
unearthly devotion which ties the characters intractably to the world
in which they have grown accustomed.Ozu wrote the quietly perceptive script with longtime collaborator Kogo
Noda, and the filmmaker's trademark touches - the narrative ellipses,
the lack of melodrama, the low camera angles - are all here in their
emotionally resonant glory. This time, the character of Akiko has such
an easy sisterly bond with her daughter Ayako that neither has an
interest in dating or marriage. While Akiko's situation is more or less
accepted by society, Ayako's single status is a point of consternation,
especially for three friends of Akiko's late husband, all of whom
express feelings of unrequited love for the unavailable Akiko. They are
jointly intent on finding Ayako a suitable husband and find one in
Goto, a young, well-mannered bachelor with a suitable career. Akiko,
however, demurs at the possibility of matrimony which leads the story
through its inevitable paces.Y么ko Tsukasa is pretty and affecting as Ayako, though honestly no match
for the younger Hara in the earlier film. More of that uninhibited
spirit is present in Mariko Okada, who plays Ayako's friend and
colleague Yuriko. She has a terrifically abrasive and amusing
confrontation with the trio of embarrassed matchmakers, and the result
comes across as a bit of an imbalance to the viewer now since Yuriko's
Westernized independence is more compelling than Ayako's more innate
diffidence. Adding more to the comedic aspects of the story, Shin
Saburi, Nabuo Nakamura and Ryuji Kita play the matchmaking trio almost
like a Shakespearean comedy troupe. Interestingly, Ozu uses a decidedly
Italianate-sounding score to underscore the action, a nice
unpredictable touch. This well-preserved film is not as essential as
"Late Spring", but it is a worthy addition to Ozu's filmography.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13588546/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>crossbow0106</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This story is basically a retelling of the excellent "late Spring",
except now the always engaging Setsuko Hara plays the mother in the
film rather than the daughter. The daughter, the beautiful Ayako played
by Yoko Tsukasa, is being told its time to marry. Three friends of her
late father (essentially uncles) attempt to arrange a suitable partner
for her. Ozu has updated his films before and he always manages to keep
them fresh. This time, it is both humorous as well as poignant. A great
addition to the story is Ayako's best friend Yuriko, a spitfire who
isn't afraid to speak her mind. I especially like the relationship of
Akiko (Hara) and Ayako as mother and daughter. They seem very
comfortable with each other. In the previous "Late Spring", there was
more tension. That is what gives "late Spring" the nod as the better
film, it is a masterpiece. In this film the acting is uniformly good to
great and there are some standout scenes, especially between the always
beautiful, gifted actress Setsuko Hara and Yoko Tsukasa. There is also
a great scene between Yuriko and the three men who are trying to find a
suitor for Ayako. By all means, watch this film, but don't miss "late
Spring". This film is available on the 5 disc "Late Ozu" set and both
the film and box set are highly recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14908520/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>GyatsoLa</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
One of many great movies by Ozu, this is an apparently simple comedy (a
comedy that puts a smile on your face rather than guffaws of laughter)
but with depths of feeling and sadness that are, as always with Ozu
movies, so unexpected. Although not by any means a 'major' or 'serious'
movie, its full of touches that show what a masterly director he was.Arranged marriages have a bad name for many people - I was very
surprised on a recent trip to Kyoto to be told that they are still
quite common - but this is a movie that shows that they are as full of
the complexities and pitfalls of conventional romance. The story
revolves around the clumsy attempts of three well meaning men to help
out the wife of their late friend by acting as matchmakers for his
daughter. Its complicated by the fact that all three of them were in
love with the mother in their early years - unsurprising as the mother
is played by the always luminous Setsuko Hara. The daughter is less
than impressed by the matchmaking, especially when the men decide to
set up one of their number with her mother.The plot is in many ways very similar to Ozu's wonderful 'Late Spring',
which starred many of the same actors. But while Late Spring was full
of thematic richness and drama, this movie is a lot simpler, but is
equally bitter sweet at the end. The happiness of the older characters
at marrying off the younger generation is matched with an awareness of
the loneliness of old age. Its also worth noting that the usual
imaginative Ozu camera angles in this movie are matched with gorgeous
colour and lovely set design.One point of interest for this movie is that it was clearly intended as
a crowd pleaser. For those who think that Ozu is too 'arty', this movie
shows why he was hugely popular with ordinary cinema-goers in Japan and
remains so to this day. His simple stories resonated deeply with
Japanese people at a time of great change, but his genius is in the
universality of these movies - they have never truly dated, the are as
insightful and fascinating as ever.In summary, this is not a movie in itself that will convince the
doubtful about Ozu's right to be considered one of the all time great
directors, but it is a delightful movie for any cinema lover (or for
that matter, anyone interested in Japanese culture) to enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7065831/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>zzhou5</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
just a simple family story rendered so touching: a mother and a
daughter were confronted with choice of life when the father died. The
dilemma involves the conflict of traditional Japanese values and modern
individuality.The story ends with the mother's self-sacrifice for the daughter's
happy marriage. The disintegration of a family to embrace the new
generation's happiness, in my eyes , is always cruel but inevitableThe film is tinged with nostalgia and subtle feelings. The end is my
favorite: the mother's expression, half sad and suddenly lighted up...
quite an antidote to the Hollywood's Happy-end
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11522148/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>samhill5215</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Of Ozu's trilogy on marriage Japanese style this one is my favorite. In
fact many of my comments apply to the other two, Late Spring (1949) and
Early Summer (1951). All three deal with the concept of marriage as
seen in traditional Japanese society and even though to my western eyes
it seems antiquated, Ozu manages to present it as a sensible,
inherently logical way to pair two people. But what ultimately attracts
me to his work is his presentation. The plot unfolds in a slow,
languorous way. It's linear but with gaps in time which are fully
explained so that we are not left guessing as to intervening events.
What we see and hear is the important stuff. We, in essence, are
eavesdropping on intimate family conversations, the kind of things
discussed at every dinner table, things important to a family but more
or less irrelevant to the outside world. Somehow Ozu makes that
interesting. Naturally the actors play an important part and the
presence of two of my favorite Japanese actors, Setsuko Hara and Chisu
Ryu, in all three are a definite plus. So why is this one my favorite?
Humor and lots of it. The first two are rather serious, drama-filled
works where the characters exhibit much angst. Late Autumn on the other
hand is light and airy, there's a bounce to it, and it's filled with a
lot of sexual innuendo that is completely absent from the others. It's
as if Ozu was saying to us that the post-WWII years was a time for
Japan to buckle down to the serious work of rebuilding society. By 1960
the joy of living had returned to his country. It could afford the
bumbling of three well-meaning and occasionally lecherous men whose
efforts at match-making were only half successful.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16605446/comments</url><from>from Denver, CO</from><name>theskulI42</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Well, it was bound to happen eventually: The more films I viewed from
noted Japanese auteur Yasujiro Ozu, there was going to come a time when
my well of interest ran dry. I have now seen ten of his films, and Ozu
seems unique among filmmakers, even the most praised, by being
essentially the anti-Billy Wilder. Where Wilder's mind was so
brilliantly scattered that he did pictures in nearly every conceivable
genre, and did them well, Ozu was always more interested in mining
different stories out of the same cloth, hopping from patch to patch on
a quilt of nuanced familial drama. Where Wilder branched out, Ozu dug
his roots in deep. He had an exclusive stable of actors, comprising
some of the most talented and, like their helmsman, subtly versatile
actors in the business, including the transcendent Chishu Ryu and the
great Sestuko Hara, appearing here as the mother to the always-adorable
Yoko Tsukasa, essaying the role that Hara herself brought to life in
Late Spring. Ryu has the remarkable ability to present to us a man of
any age with very little in the way of physical alterations (in the
span of five years, he played father, brother and grandfather to Hara
and was utterly convincing in all). Hara has the exact opposite gift:
That of an ageless wonder. Early on in Late Autumn, a comment is made
that Hara and her daughter Tsukasa look more like sisters than
mother-daughter, and it's absolutely true. In the eleven-year span from
Spring to Autumn, Hara has swapped roles but kept the same face, and
she brings her A-game yet again, looking more weary and fatigued than
ever before.But there's a problem. Where Ozu's style had always seemed evocative
and direct, here is seems...stilted and awkward. The use of direct
address in discussions seems disjointed and stiff. What felt
emotionally confrontational in Late Spring comes off here as almost
amateurish, merely content to blandly cut back and forth between one
talking head and another. The fact that he's done that all his career
perhaps says something about this film as an individual entity. Or
perhaps it's just become all too familiar. When you're looking to
derive a myriad of tales from the same few thematic points, there's
always the danger of indifference; having the same actors play similar
characters doing similar things in similar ways in movies with similar
titles, it's a testament to his brilliance that he managed to make it
more than one film, but here, it all just strikes of creative
exhaustion: He's seemingly run out of stories to the point that he's
now reworking the similar stories he's already done, as this is almost
directly a remake of his 1949 masterpiece Late Spring, except mostly
from the female perspective. While it appears to be a monumental shift
for such a gradual director (I still remember first experiencing Tokyo
Story and being so startled by its singular tracking shot that I was
shaken to my core), actually far too little is new. Most of the motions
and emotions we are presented with were all essentially inferred in
Late Spring, and this seems if nothing else, an unnecessary diversion
to a place we're already been.Now this is not to say that the film is a complete dud. Everyone
involved is so talented that they can't help but stumble into several
moments of effective heartstrain, most notable the touching restraint
of the final shot, but I just can't shake the feeling that with Late
Autumn, instead of hopping to a new stitch on the quilt, he's stepping
right back onto trampled-down, treaded ground. Where Late Spring
presented this story and devastated me, going right to my heart and
laying me out flat. To Late Autumn I'm a bit more...subdued. I never
connected to the characters or the situation in any tangible or
meaningful way, and my response to the film was less "Holy crap" and
more "ho-hum".{Grade: 6.5/10 (B-/C+) / #24 (of 34) of 1960}
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16605446/comments</url><from>from Denver, CO</from><name>theskulI42</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Well, it was bound to happen eventually: The more films I viewed from
noted Japanese auteur Yasujiro Ozu, there was going to come a time when
my well of interest ran dry. I have now seen ten of his films, and Ozu
seems unique among filmmakers, even the most praised, by being
essentially the anti-Billy Wilder. Where Wilder's mind was so
brilliantly scattered that he did pictures in nearly every conceivable
genre, and did them well, Ozu was always more interested in mining
different stories out of the same cloth, hopping from patch to patch on
a quilt of nuanced familial drama. Where Wilder branched out, Ozu dug
his roots in deep. He had an exclusive stable of actors, comprising
some of the most talented and, like their helmsman, subtly versatile
actors in the business, including the transcendent Chishu Ryu and the
great Sestuko Hara, appearing here as the mother to the always-adorable
Yoko Tsukasa, essaying the role that Hara herself brought to life in
Late Spring. Ryu has the remarkable ability to present to us a man of
any age with very little in the way of physical alterations (in the
span of five years, he played father, brother and grandfather to Hara
and was utterly convincing in all). Hara has the exact opposite gift:
That of an ageless wonder. Early on in Late Autumn, a comment is made
that Hara and her daughter Tsukasa look more like sisters than
mother-daughter, and it's absolutely true. In the eleven-year span from
Spring to Autumn, Hara has swapped roles but kept the same face, and
she brings her A-game yet again, looking more weary and fatigued than
ever before.But there's a problem. Where Ozu's style had always seemed evocative
and direct, here is seems...stilted and awkward. The use of direct
address in discussions seems disjointed and stiff. What felt
emotionally confrontational in Late Spring comes off here as almost
amateurish, merely content to blandly cut back and forth between one
talking head and another. The fact that he's done that all his career
perhaps says something about this film as an individual entity. Or
perhaps it's just become all too familiar. When you're looking to
derive a myriad of tales from the same few thematic points, there's
always the danger of indifference; having the same actors play similar
characters doing similar things in similar ways in movies with similar
titles, it's a testament to his brilliance that he managed to make it
more than one film, but here, it all just strikes of creative
exhaustion: He's seemingly run out of stories to the point that he's
now reworking the similar stories he's already done, as this is almost
directly a remake of his 1949 masterpiece Late Spring, except mostly
from the female perspective. While it appears to be a monumental shift
for such a gradual director (I still remember first experiencing Tokyo
Story and being so startled by its singular tracking shot that I was
shaken to my core), actually far too little is new. Most of the motions
and emotions we are presented with were all essentially inferred in
Late Spring, and this seems if nothing else, an unnecessary diversion
to a place we're already been.Now this is not to say that the film is a complete dud. Everyone
involved is so talented that they can't help but stumble into several
moments of effective heartstrain, most notable the touching restraint
of the final shot, but I just can't shake the feeling that with Late
Autumn, instead of hopping to a new stitch on the quilt, he's stepping
right back onto trampled-down, treaded ground. Where Late Spring
presented this story and devastated me, going right to my heart and
laying me out flat. To Late Autumn I'm a bit more...subdued. I never
connected to the characters or the situation in any tangible or
meaningful way, and my response to the film was less "Holy crap" and
more "ho-hum".{Grade: 6.5/10 (B-/C+) / #24 (of 34) of 1960}
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16605446/comments</url><from>from Denver, CO</from><name>theskulI42</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>