<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Surprise Package</original_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Stanley Donen</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis/><actor>Yul Brynner</actor><actor>Mitzi Gaynor</actor><actor>Noel Coward</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Charlton Heston in his memoirs said that when he was signing for his
part in Touch of Evil it was mentioned that Orson Welles was going to
be playing the sheriff, but that Universal still hadn't selected a
director. Well says Heston, why don't you get Orson Welles to direct.
Duh, says the studio heads, that's a splendid idea.On Surprise Package with none other than Noel Coward in the cast, why
didn't they get him to take charge of the whole thing. It is amazing to
me that with all the talent in this project a better product didn't
emerge. This is a caper film involving a deported U.S. gangster played by Yul
Brynner now living on a Greek island trying to steal the crown of the
exiled King of Anatolia played by Coward. Along for the ride is Mitzi
Gaynor as Brynner's moll and the baddie played by George Coulouris from
the People's Republic of Anatolia, the gang that overthrew the king.
The director is Stanley Donen from a novel by humorist Art Buchwald.Brynner is terribly miscast in his part. A gangster I can believe him
as, but he just has no flair for comedy. There were some comic moments
in the King and I, but that's overall, a serious part. Coward looks
bored by the whole thing, I wish he had scripted and directed it also
and he probably wished he did too. George Coulouris was his usual
menacing self.Mitzi Gaynor was a fine musical talent who came along just when musical
films were ending. She was probably grateful for a number or two in
this film. Jimmy Van Heusen and Sammy Cahn wrote the title tune which
she sings as well as Noel Coward. Can you imagine if he had contributed
some musical number as well?The script has some topical references to the Cold War, the Appalachian
underworld gathering, rigged quiz shows, etc. etc. that Yul and the
cast comment on.It also would have been nice since this takes place in the Greek
Islands to have splurged for some technicolor.If you see it, try to view it as a curiosity. Someone should have
whispered in ears of the studio heads at Columbia the way Charlton
Heston did at Universal.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11317797/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Psalm 52</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This film is a pleasant diversion and very funny. Brynner is passable
as a Mafia gangster who is deported to a Greek Isle. Coward is a
deposed king who lives on said island and wants to sell a valuable
crown he kept. Then there's a corrupt chief of police, a bumbling spy
who explains when caught by Brynner ... "Of course, I am spying on you.
That's my profession. I'm a spy!" There's also two government types
from the deposed king's homeland &amp; in the middle Ms. Gaynor. Now, I
never heard of her and don't recall her acting, but she's the center of
this film. She wins over all the various characters and devises some
interesting solutions to Nico's constantly interrupting monetary
problems. I'm really proud of myself for seeing it and being pleasantly
entertained.This film is reminiscent in it's subject and feel as an Argentinian
film of the same era "La Cigarra no es un bicho."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11317797/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Psalm 52</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This film is a pleasant diversion and very funny. Brynner is passable
as a Mafia gangster who is deported to a Greek Isle. Coward is a
deposed king who lives on said island and wants to sell a valuable
crown he kept. Then there's a corrupt chief of police, a bumbling spy
who explains when caught by Brynner ... "Of course, I am spying on you.
That's my profession. I'm a spy!" There's also two government types
from the deposed king's homeland &amp; in the middle Ms. Gaynor. Now, I
never heard of her and don't recall her acting, but she's the center of
this film. She wins over all the various characters and devises some
interesting solutions to Nico's constantly interrupting monetary
problems. I'm really proud of myself for seeing it and being pleasantly
entertained.This film is reminiscent in it's subject and feel as an Argentinian
film of the same era "La Cigarra no es un bicho."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>