<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Onna ga kaidan wo agaru toki</original_title><alt_title>Quand une femme monte l'escalier</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Mikio Naruse</director><producer>Toho Company</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
This is the story of Mama, a.k.a. Keiko, a middle-aged geisha who must choose to either get married or buy a bar of her own...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Hideko Takamine</actor><actor>Tatsuya Nakadai</actor><actor>Masayuki Mori</actor><rt_rating>8.2/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317122/comments</url><from>from austin</from><name>jacqui chen (jacqui_chen@juno.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This is my first Naruse film and, boy, what a treat it is! Hideko Takamine
is simply brilliant in her evocation of a madame in the ginza bar district,
where businessmen go in the after-hours for drinks, flattery, and anything
else they can get their hands on.Takamine's Keiko is a woman bound by social constraints: an aging mother
who
needs allowance from her daughter to get by, a brother who must be saved
from prison because he forged legal documents, a nephew who needs money for
operation, rich businessmen and corporate owners who want her body in
exchange for petty patronage...Despite all these attempts to stifle her, to drain her body, labor, and
emotions for all their worth and resource, Keiko emerges from life's
disappointements and heartbreaks the strong individual she tries to be. Her
refusal to be defeated by family, men, the institution of the ginza bar and
survival itself is reflected in many elements. The playful music, for
example, discourages us from reducing the film to yet another tearjerking
festival. Keiko herself is an intelligent and sophisticated commentator on
her life as a particular kind of "fallen woman". Throughout the film, there
are moments of narration and commentary on the ginza bar-mystique. Here we
witness a resilence and self-respect so tremendous that the notion of
"feminism" of Mizoguchi's women have to be reconsidered."Coming back was as bleak as a cold day in Winter. But certain trees
bloom...no matter how cold the wind." WHEN A WOMAN ASCENDS THE STAIRS is a
great testament to Takamine's acting wizardry and Naruse's sensitive
treatment of the social construction of women - a particular way of
brutalizing the individual.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0065227/comments</url><from>from Korea</from><name>liehtzu</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Beautiful film about a ginza bar girl approaching the age of thirty - an
age
at which, she claims, a girl of her profession can either "get married or
open a bar of her own." It is a film about how her quest for one and then
the other ends in disappointment. Most significantly, though, it is a
vehicle through which filmmaker Naruse expresses his view that life is a
vicious cycle of disappointments at every turn, a fate which no human
action
to fight it can deter.
The film is breathtakingly shot in widescreen black and white, adding to
the
film's already bittersweet poignancy. It's a wonderful piece of cinema - a
quietly rewarding and remarkably unforced masterpiece. "When a Woman
Ascends
the Stairs" is, quite simply, a thing of beauty and brilliance, and it is a
great work of art. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0491610/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, B.C.</from><name>Howard Schumann</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Widowed Tokyo bar hostess Keiko is in her thirties and thinking about
her limited choices. She could open her own bar but this would require
financial help from clients and perhaps favors she is unwilling to
give, or she could get married, but that would mean breaking a vow to
her late husband that she would never love another man. Mikio Naruse's
When a Woman Ascends the Stairs is an exquisite character study about a
woman caught in a trap of financial obligations who is forced to
perform a job she dislikes in order to stay afloat. It is both a
depiction of one woman's courage and perseverance and a commentary on
the limited opportunities for women in Japan with little education or
family connections. Hideko Takamine is unforgettable as Keiko, the
beleaguered hostess who is affectionately called "mama" by the younger
barmaids.Keiko is a graceful and charming woman who wears a traditional kimono
but is under pressure by her devoted manager Kenichi Komatsu (Tatsuya
Nakadai) to modernize her wardrobe and upgrade her living arrangements
to keep up with growing Western influences. Of the many men in her
life, three monopolize her attention: Mr. Fujisaki (Masayuki Mori), Mr.
Sekine (Daisuke Kato), and Mr. Minobe (Ganjiro Nakamura). Each
relationship starts out with promise but each leads to severe
disappointment. She receives a marriage proposal from Mr. Sekine that
turns out to be bogus. She tells Mr. Fujisaki that she loves him but
promised her husband she would not remarry. Nonetheless, she is crushed
when she learns that he has been transferred to Osaka.The film complements the dramatic action with Keiko's inner dialogue.
Backed by a cool jazz score that evokes the mood of Tokyo streets in
the early evening, she contemplates how most women in Tokyo are going
to their home when her work is first starting. In another sequence she
muses, "Around midnight Tokyo's 16,000 bar women go home. The best go
home by car. Second-rate ones by streetcar. The worst go home with
their customers." As Keiko struggles financially to help her aging
mother, her brother who must pay a lawyer to stay out of prison, and
her nephew who needs an operation, she knows that she would be better
off if she would relax her standards, but she will not compromise her
integrity. The stairs she must climb each night to her bar become a
symbol both of her triumphant determination and her personal tragedy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3608743/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, CA, USA</from><name>Ed Uyeshima</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Just as Akira Kurosawa, Kenji Mizoguchi and Yasujiro Ozu seemed
destined to be recognized as the troika of classic Japanese cinematic
masters, here comes the work of a filmmaker who has been under the
radar to Westerners all these years, Mikio Naruse. The Criterion
Collection is giving Naruse his due with the release of his
provocatively titled 1960 melodrama, a fine piece of work that strikes
me as a cross between Ozu's elliptical narrative style and deliberate
pacing and Douglas Sirk's sense of Baroque-level dramatic
sensibilities.Sharply written by Ryuzo Kikushima, the net result is a clear-eyed yet
humanistic glimpse into the after-hours bar scene in post-WWII Tokyo's
Ginza district with the primary focus on Keiko, a hostess to whom
colleagues refer affectionately as "Mama". Her existence is a daily
struggle as she depends on her companion-seeking businessman clients to
finance the bar in which she works, and concurrently, confronts the
fear of aging in a highly competitive field, all the while standing on
her high moral ground to avoid the unsavory pitfalls of others in her
profession. Although she is barely in her thirties, she feels pressured
to make an imminent choice between opening her own bar and getting
married for security. Even more than Ozu, arguably the most sensitive
of Japan's film-making elite, Naruse shows with uncompromising clarity
how women are consigned to their subservient roles in a male-dominated
society.As she keeps up appearances as part of not only her job but also as her
emotional suit of armor, Keiko faces the temptations of four men in
particular, all far from ideal, but each promises some aspect of hope
for her to get out of her desultory existence. Meanwhile, she faces the
machinations of younger hostesses out to get their share of the money
and fulfill their dreams of security. Naruse takes his time in setting
up the various character situations in the first half, which makes the
film feel a little more plodding than it should be, but the pace and
dramatic tension pick up in the second half when Keiko's desperation
becomes more palpable. It's fortunate that Naruse cast his longtime
leading lady Hideko Takamine in the highly complex role of Keiko, as
her multi-layered performance is a model of emotional precision. A
beautiful actress with a look of often haunting passivity, she subtly
provides the emotional tether among all the vividly rendered characters
in her orbit.The four men are skillfully portrayed by actors familiar to anyone with
a passing knowledge of classic Japanese cinema - Ganjiro Nakamura
("Floating Weeds") as the aged executive in need of a mistress; Daisuke
Katô ("Yojimbo") as the cherubic bachelor who is not what he appears;
Tatsuya Nakadai ("Harakiri", "Ran") as the younger bartender/manager
who worships Keiko from a distance; and Masayuki Mori ("Rashomon",
"Ugetsu") as the married lover unable to leave his family. As
intriguing counterpoints to Keiko, Reiko Dan plays the flirtatious
Junko with Western-style abandon, and Keiko Awaji makes the ambitious
Yuri a tragic, pitiable figure. The film is complemented by a cool,
jazz-piano score by Toshirô Mayuzumi, absolutely the right touch for
the slightly tawdry urban setting. As with several Criterion releases
of classic Japanese cinema (like Ozu's "Tokyo Story" and Nakahira's
"Crazed Fruit"), film scholar Donald Richie provides rich commentary on
an alternate track in the 2007 DVD. There is also an illuminating 2005
interview with Nakadai on Naruse and the film-making process, as well
as the original theatrical trailer. Four insightful essays, including a
glowing tribute to Naruse by Takamine, are included in a 38-page
booklet accompanying the DVD package.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0442119/comments</url><from>from Upstate New York</from><name>Red-125</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Onna ga kaidan wo agaru toki (1960), directed by Mikio Naruse, was
shown in the United States under the title "When a Woman Ascends the
Stairs." The film stars Hideko Takamine, Naruse's muse, as Keiko, the
Mama-San of a Tokyo bar.Although the IMDb plot summary says that Keiko is a geisha, that isn't
accurate. Geishas do appear briefly in the movie, but Keiko is actually
a bar hostess. As portrayed in the movie, bar hostesses are neither
geishas nor prostitutes. Geishas still wear the traditional costume,
whereas the bar hostesses are dressed in western fashion. The role of
the bar hostess is to flatter the male customers and provide company,
but not sex. In fact, Keiko has been celibate since the death of her
husband. These women have a fairly good income, but they usually don't have much
cash, because they are expected to live and dress fashionably, and most
of their money goes for rent or clothes. The title "When a Woman Ascends the Stairs" refers to Keiko's thoughts
as she climbs the stairs that lead to the bar at which she works.
Although Keiko doesn't hate her work, she doesn't enjoy it either. It's
a job, and her options as a woman are limited in the Japanese
male-dominated society. (Even though Keiko, as Mama-San, has some
authority over the other women, the real power resides in the male
owner of the bar and his manager.)The plot of the film resolves around the choices the protagonist must
make as she attempts to achieve some measure of happiness and financial
stability. As would be expected, these goals are difficult to
accomplish for a woman in her situation.Director Naruse returns in this film to his favorite
theme--working-class women who must choose among options that aren't
very palatable. What makes this film his masterpiece--in my
opinion--are the courage and depth of character that Keiko
demonstrates.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2066951/comments</url><from>from Chapel Hill, NC, USA</from><name>David (davidals@msn.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Finding Naruse Mikio films has been very, very tough, and after seeing
this I'd say it's a tragedy. This is among the most gorgeous dramas
I've seen - a brooding and dark melodrama, shot in velvety black and
white, with stunning widescreen photography. Based upon my viewing of this and one other Naruse film (to date), I'd
say that Naruse's worldview is considerably more cynical than Ozu or
Mizoguchi (both of whom he seems to often draw unfavorable comparisons
with, from the relatively few critics to have dug into his work) - the
strength of women will be taken for granted, or abused by a hostile
world regardless of shrewdness, intellect or beauty, and there is a shy
jaded quality to this film that gives it an engaging intensity, that
while not nearly as subtle, objective or cerebral as Ozu, IS definitely
more passionate. Here, and also in the earlier LATE CHRYSANTHEMUMS,
Naruse's women are idealized, heroic - symbolic in a larger sense of
outsiders or rebels (of any variety) in a social milieu that values
discretion and certain forms of conformity above all else.If you can find this film, I highly recommend it - more of Naruse's
work should be made available outside of Japan.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1278281/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>tnamwong</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Keiko, also known as mama, is one of those truly unforgettable characters
who you swear must exist somewhere out there in the real world.  She is
both
strong, graceful and intelligent. This film has an outstanding lead and
supporting cast, and ofcourse a great story centering on the day by day
account of the life of a bar woman who struggles to maintain her pride.
Don't worry, this movie's initially slow pace blossoms with enough twists
and surprises to captivate and reward modern viewers.Other characters to compare Keiko to is Junko, a much younger bar girl, who
manages to work the system to her financial advantage.  Komatsu, Keiko's
manager, a young man smitten by Keiko's enchanting beauty and is reduced to
just imagining a future alongside his beloved.  Both Junko and Komatsu's
youth prove to be of great contrast to Keiko and her wisdom of thiry years.
Unlike Keiko, Junko can imagine and realize her simple but dead end dream
of
opening a bar in exchange for her dignity.  Komatsu's wishes are as empty
as
his hands as he plays bartender in a run down club.  He, alongside other
people who are part of Keiko's life will slowly switch roles from friends,
patrons and protector, Komatsu, into those who will contribute to the
torture in Keiko's life.  Just as rice was the center of Seven Samurai,
money is the heart of this film.  Ultimately, the heroine can rise above
everything, everyone and ascend the stairs to Bar Carton
again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1530907/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>poe426</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Reality, particularly for working women on their own, could be harsh
back in the day. I know, because I witnessed it firsthand, on a daily
basis. Being poor, my mother had to make a trek- on foot, because there
was no money for bus fare- of 20 miles a day to and from a factory job
that left her hunched from decades spent bent over a sewing machine.
Watching WHEN A WOMAN ASCENDS THE STAIRS, I was reminded (again) of her
selfless sacrifice- something that occurred on a daily basis for 50
years. This is the first Naruse film I've had the chance to see- but,
based on this one, I fully intend to see more. His characters may exist
in the "grey areas" just this side of the shadows, but they always seem
to be in the ascension. It's satisfying to learn that there were
filmmakers out there who had their cinematic stuff together enough to
do films like this. They should be celebrated.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1718193/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>pottedstu</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Compared to Ozu or Mizoguchi, Mikio Naruse's films are much lighter in
tone, with more humour, and less of the overwhelming sense of pain and
tragedy. Sometimes this works really well, offering stories that are
emotionally involving but not morbidly extreme, but in this film I
think it results in a film that's shapeless and drifts past the viewer
without really going anywhere in particular.The performances are excellent; of course Hideko Takamine is wonderful
in the leading role running a hostess bar, but Reiko Dan is great fun
as a young, flirty, ambitious hostess, and Tatsuya Nakadai as the loyal
young bar manager is like a hero of the French New Wave, quiet, cool,
and intense. Keiko's customers at the bar are to an extent caricatures,
but are nicely drawn.The film offers a full and fair-minded account of the world of hostess
bars, with Naruse's usual interest in financial matters and the
minutiae of life. But despite the occasional sad event, the cumulative
impression is not of a woman in a desperately tragic situation, but
more a case of just one damn thing after another. It lurches from
moments of high drama to silliness to tragedy to the mundane, failing
to achieve a consistent attitude or tone.There are perhaps too many characters, so that while some relationships
are clear and powerful, others pass by with little emotional effect.
Unlike in Iwashigumo (Summer Clouds) the main character of this film
isn't heroic, isn't keeping up any tradition, and doesn't have any
particular claim on our affections. Her defence about needing a fancy
lifestyle and expensive apartment for her job, and her attitude to her
family, don't seem likely to endear her to the viewer either.Overall, it feels like a set of great talents wandering around in an
inadequate storyline. It's not enough to present the facts; a great
film needs to use them to show you something more general about life.
And something more profound than, "Well, every job has its problems."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5449426/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL</from><name>Wallabee_Champ</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
I was just lucky enough to see this at the Gene Siskel theater today,
and I honestly think this is a case of a movie done by a master and it
feeling more special than it truly is due to it's scarcity. It's truly
horrible.The movie has many fatal flaws. The biggest is there's no actual drama,
because the main character doesn't face any adversity. She's just a
whiny woman who's upset with her lot in life, but too unmotivated to
change it, and instead mopes around a lot.The story also has a very odd pacing. The moral dilemmas are sped
through rather quickly while details of irrelevant plans are seen
through each tedious step.There's also very little characterization of the supporting characters,
which makes most of them very tedious and boring. There either should
have been less characters, so they could have been developed more, or
more, so as to avoid the, "oh great, here's this guy to waste our time
again" syndrome.I'm sure some people will think I'm unrefined for not liking this
movie, but I honestly thought it was awful in about every way a movie
can be. If it's someone else's cup of tea, power to them, then.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5449426/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL</from><name>Wallabee_Champ</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
I was just lucky enough to see this at the Gene Siskel theater today,
and I honestly think this is a case of a movie done by a master and it
feeling more special than it truly is due to it's scarcity. It's truly
horrible.The movie has many fatal flaws. The biggest is there's no actual drama,
because the main character doesn't face any adversity. She's just a
whiny woman who's upset with her lot in life, but too unmotivated to
change it, and instead mopes around a lot.The story also has a very odd pacing. The moral dilemmas are sped
through rather quickly while details of irrelevant plans are seen
through each tedious step.There's also very little characterization of the supporting characters,
which makes most of them very tedious and boring. There either should
have been less characters, so they could have been developed more, or
more, so as to avoid the, "oh great, here's this guy to waste our time
again" syndrome.I'm sure some people will think I'm unrefined for not liking this
movie, but I honestly thought it was awful in about every way a movie
can be. If it's someone else's cup of tea, power to them, then.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5449426/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL</from><name>Wallabee_Champ</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/anthony-quinn/</url><url>http://arts.independent.co.uk/film/reviews/article2718312.ece /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643606</url><name>Anthony Quinn</name><from>Independent</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>It's also elegantly shot and scored; all that's missing is a touch of humour.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.totalfilm.com/cinema_reviews/films_out_this_week/when_a_woman_ascends_the_stairs /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643573</url><from>Total Film</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>A heartbreaker.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tom-robey/</url><url>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/arts/main.jhtml?view=DETAILS&amp;grid=&amp;xml=/arts/2007/06/29/nosplit/bfshut129.xml#3 /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643560</url><name>Tom Robey</name><from>Daily Telegraph</from></reviewer><comment>Sprint, don't walk, up those BFI steps to see it.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/peter-bradshaw/</url><url>http://arts.guardian.co.uk/filmandmusic/story/0,,2114211,00.html /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643549</url><name>Peter Bradshaw</name><from>Guardian [UK]</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>The new retrospective of Mikio Naruse at London's BFI Southbank will do much to restore the reputation of a neglected Japanese director, and this 1960 film is a heartbreaking study, to be compared with Mizoguchi's Life of Oharu.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/wendy-ide/</url><url>http://entertainment.timesonline.co.uk/tol/arts_and_entertainment/film/film_reviews/article1994878.ece /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643541</url><name>Wendy Ide</name><from>Times [UK]</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Shot in luminous black and white cinemascope, this is an exquisitely understated study of the plight of a young woman in an unforgiving society.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jamie-russell/</url><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=161956 /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643527</url><name>Jamie Russell</name><from>Film4</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>The money-grubbing realities of late 1950s Tokyo make for riveting viewing in Naruse's naturalistic classic. These are no ordinary memories of a geisha.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/anna-smith/</url><url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/films/2007/06/25/when_a_woman_ascends_the_stairs_2007_review.shtml /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643518</url><name>Anna Smith</name><from>BBC</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Patience will be rewarded.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/trevor-johnston/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/84342/when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs.html /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643512</url><name>Trevor Johnston</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><rating>
5/6
					</rating><comment>A new classic.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-parkinson/</url><url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/ReviewComplete.asp?FID=135047 /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1643430</url><name>David Parkinson</name><from>Empire Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Lustrously photographed in monochrome by Masai Tamai, this is essentially a Tokyo twist on Nights of Cabiria (1957), with Mikio Naruse and Hideko Takamine replacing Fellina and Masina's kooky optimism with a fatalistic humanism.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/whenwomstairs.shtml /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1618009</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>Even a casual viewing of When a Woman Ascends the Stairs shows what a gifted humanist Naruse was.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/whenawomanascendsthestairs.htm /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1525587</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>Naruse creates an affecting scenario of modern Japanese society and the pitfalls a woman in such a patriarchal society must face.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/keith-uhlich/</url><url>http://www.slantmagazine.com/film/film_review.asp?ID=1901 /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1452038</url><name>Keith Uhlich</name><from>Slant Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>The final close-up-featuring Keiko smiling in lieu of tears-might be frozen, framed, and subtitled "Lady Sings the Blues."</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1422969</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/leo-goldsmith/</url><url>http://www.notcoming.com/reviews/whenawomanascendsthestairs/ /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1972459</url><name>Leo Goldsmith</name><from>Not Coming to a Theater Near You</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9F00E5D81731E73BBC4E51DFB0668388679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=1389463</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/9219_WHEN_A_WOMAN_ASCENDS_THE_STAIRS.html /m/onna-ga-kaidan-wo-agaru-toki-when-a-woman-ascends-the-stairs/comments.php?reviewid=28212</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>