<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Rocco e i suoi fratelli</original_title><alt_title>Rocco et ses frères</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Luchino Visconti</director><producer>Titanus</producer><producer>Les Films Marceau</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Sport</genre><synopsis>
The widow Rosaria moves to Milano from Lucania with her 4 sons, one of whom is Rocco. The fifth son...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Alain Delon</actor><actor>Renato Salvatori</actor><actor>Annie Girardot</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0291311/comments</url><from>from NYC</from><name>antonio-21</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Now I understand why Visconti regards this classic as his personal
favorite!!Overwhelmingly Terrific!  The acting, design, music, cinematography, and
especially direction are superb.This epic, grand, personal, and highly dramatic tale of five brothers and
their mother who move from Southern Italy to Milan to change their station
in life is filled with wonderful vignettes and powerful set pieces.The fight between two of the brothers in the slums of the city is one of the
most harrowing and touching scenes ever in cinema history.  This is the kind
of fight which actually means something.  When they hit each other you feel
it down to the core of your being, not just watching mindless brutality like
you would in some brainless movie.The cast is uniformly good with standouts from Katina Paxinou as the long
suffering mother, Annie Girardot as the doomed prostitute who is the
catalyst of the story, and especially Alain Delon who is blessed with a
cinematic beauty which adds poetry to everyone of his close-ups.  The one
actor who really surprised me was Renato Salvatori as the violent brother
Simone. His gradual and completely believable change from sweet young man to
violent brute is incredible to watch.This film satisfies every true movie lovers dream.  To visit a place you
don't know, with characters who fascinate you, and are  framed in a true
CINEMATIC style, that succeeds on every level.GO SEE THIS MOVIE!!  I will add my voice to those who cry out for the DVD
release of this true classic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1265050/comments</url><from>from Richmond, VA</from><name>mido505</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Although the French Nouvelle Vague gets all the press, it is the
Italian neorealist movement that has had the greatest impact on
American cinema. Let's face it, aside from some of Godard's editing
tricks in Breathless, what kind of influence did the Nouvelle Vague
really have? Godard. Truffaut. Chabrol. Rohmer. Rivette. Resnais.
Decent filmmakers all, but, when one looks closely, more interesting
for their influences than for their influence. But the Italians, oh,
the Italians. Bava. Fellini. Rossellini. De Sica. Bertolucci. Visconti.
I think it is safe to say that, without the films of these incredible
innovators, American movies would have rotted away into nothing. It was
the post WWII Italian neorealist movement, and its heady brew of
Marxism and melodrama, that inflamed the imaginations of filmmakers
like Francis Ford Coppola and Martin Scorsese, and led them, especially
in Coppola's case, to use many of the same personnel on their own
productions. Vittorio Storaro. Giuseppe Rotunno. Nino Rota. Ferdinando
Scarfiotti. Danilo Donati. Where would the great American films of the
seventies be without the contributions of these astoundingly talented
artists and technicians?Rocco and His Brothers is a jaw-dropping work, so ferociously brilliant
that it takes your breath away. As a Visconti fan, I have been waiting
to watch it for years. Yet, despite my eagerness, the DVD sat on top of
the television for two weeks before I finally popped it in. Curiously,
I had the same reaction to The Leopard, another Visconti masterwork, a
couple of years ago. As I get older, I find it harder and harder to
abandon myself to a work of art. Great works of art force one to give
oneself over to them completely, suspend judgment, accept them
unconditionally. When one is young and unformed, the process is easy;
as one gets older, and the carapace of personality hardens, the process
becomes more difficult. There is a good reason for this; the effort is
often not worth while; one comes out of the experience diminished,
drained, let down.Rocco and His Brothers holds no such disappointment. It is a vast,
capacious work, complex, generous, passionate, and intensely moving.
The talent on display here defies analysis: Alain Delon is luminous as
the saintly Rocco; Katina Paxinou achieves Shakespearean grandeur as
the Parondi family matriarch; Giuseppe Rotunno's cinematography is
starkly beautiful; and Nino Rota's music is heartbreaking. I do not
want to give too much of this film away, but I must point out that,
contrary to what some reviews on this site have to say, this film is
not just about the corruption that big city life brings to a peasant
family. Rocco may be a saint, but his all-forgiving nature drives much
of the tragedy that unfolds. It is Ciro, the compassionate but just
brother, and successful entrant into Milan's urban proletariat, who
will lead the family into an uncertain but perhaps hopeful future.Let me just finish by pointing out how wonderful it is to see a movie
that ends with a meaningful and distinctive final shot. You don't see
much of that anymore.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0604398/comments</url><from>from new york city</from><name>irajoel (irajoel@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This primo example of Italian neo-realism directed by Luchino Visconti is
one of those films that people either love or hate, there really is no in
between when it comes to this film. I think it magnificent, and I've seen
it
3 or 4 times. The last viewing was last fall at the Film Forum in New
York
City, and once again I was knocked out by it. The plot is simple, a poor
family headed by the mother moves to the big city to try to make a better
life for her and her sons. Katina Paxinou plays the mama mia in a larger
than life performance that at times knocks you out of your seat. The film
is
divided into sections with each one devoted to one of the  brothers, but
the
thrust (and heart) of the narrative concerns two of the brothers, Rocco
played by a never better nor more beautiful Alain Delon &amp; his intense
love-hate relationship with his brother played by Renato Salvatori who
also
gives a superb performance. The other great performance in the film is
from
Annie Girardot as a prostitute with a semi-heart of gold. Girardot first
has
a vivid &amp; difficult relationship with Salvatori who is a brutal &amp; simple
prize fighter, but then she drops him, when she falls in love with Delon.
Needless to say trouble and high operatic drama follows that finally ends
in
tragedy that never fails to leave me in tears. Both soapy &amp; operatic,
this
is one of the great films of the 60's &amp; one of Visconti's best. Also look
for a young Claudia Cardinale in an early film role.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1232518/comments</url><from>from Fords, NJ</from><name>olddiscs</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is a great Italian film directed by Visconti, which somehow escaped me
until  tonite 2/22/02.. I had heard about it and the praise it received at
that time, (1960) but
just never got to see it.  I was seeing Foreign films at that time, I
remember seeing La Dolce Vita, The Virgin Spring, and Hiroshima Mon
Amour
at our local foreign movie theatre in Essex County , The Ormont in East
Orange.. long gone.. but missed this.  Well, thanks to TCM, Ive had another
sleepless night &amp; have just seen a truly great Italian movie/
or
great movie, period!!..What a saga ! what passion, what emotion
!!
The story of a southern Italian peasant family's journey and relocation to
the big city... is just superb film making..The deterioration of
the
brothers relationship is  almost pure GreeK Tragedy (there is a glimmer of
hope with the youngest brother)...superbly acted especially by Renato
Salvatori, as Simon, the most troubled of all the fratelli,
and  young, beautiful, Alain Delon as the younger brother Rocco who
desperately tries to save his brother from destruction; and Annie Giradot,
as Nadia the prostitute who adds to this families woes is
just
sensational in a role that should have won her all kinds of
trophies.
It was no mistake that Visconti used  Greek Oscar winning actress,
Katina
Paxinou, in the role of an Italian mother( instead of say, Anna Magnani ?),
her performance brings to mind all the heroines of Sophocles &amp; Aesculus...
yes tragedy and emotion of epic proportions..played to the nth degree... 
beautiful cast  excellently directed... by Viscont1... thanks to TCM Im
catching up on his great
movies "SENSO" a few months back and now "Rocco"  this is a
treat..
also in cast a very young beautiful Claudia Cardinale as
Ginetta..
This is film making at its best..dont miss it.. to be seen again and
again..
 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0439793/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Frederick</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I was lucky enough to catch this extraordinary film late last night on a
cable channel. It's about a widow from southern Italy who moves to Milan
with her five sons. Gradually they become embroiled in the big city, some
becoming corrupted by its ways, others profiting. Rocco, played by Alain
Delon, is an innocent, looking at his brothers and life in general with
saintly patience. When his beneficent attitude comes under pressure, he
doesn't give in to self-interest, choosing to sacrifice his own
happiness,
and that of the woman he loves, for his family. Family is really what
'Rocco
and his Brothers' is all about. I've never got into Visconti, but seeing
this film has made me want to see more of his work. Also, this move has
one
of the most powerful images I've ever seen, as the maddened Simone
advances
towards the doomed prostitute Nadia. It's an image so remarkable I
actually
shouted aloud when I saw it. I urge you to see this film. It's a
remarkable,
passionate, beautifully photographed drama that will stay with you for a
long time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1809308/comments</url><from>from Oslo, Norway</from><name>Audun Bråten (braugen@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The Italian master Luchino Visconti's 1960 (melo)drama "Rocco e i Suoi
Fratelli" is the best film I've seen in a long, long time, and it deserves
to be up there among European cinema's finest achievements, along with
Visconti's other masterpiece, "Il Gattopardo" (1963).Aristocrat turned communist, Visconti draws a beautiful, but horrible
picture of Milan in the 1960s, when the "immigration" from the South was
at
its peek, and the social problems in Northern Italy exploded. The
differences between north and south in Italy are enormous, and were
perhaps
even greater back when Visconti and his scriptwriting crew decided to make
a
contemporary film about a family moving northwards. Visconti wanted to
make
a film about a mother and her five sons, like the five fingers on her
hand,
like the mother herself exclaimes at the end of the film. This is not an
agitational film, though, just a superbly acted study of a society in
disorder and a portrait of a family trying to make ends meet in a harsh
world they do not know. Like another Italian director, Pier Paolo
Pasolini,
noted, the South of Italy stayed an undeveloped land even after the North
became industrialized, and that didn't happen before after WWII. This is
the
grim truth, and the person who thought this film was depressing should
just
stay on his or her pills and turn his or her eyes towards the real world,
because the world IS a depressing place. You just cannot blame directors
with a social conscience for trying to tell a story which lies close to
their hearts, then you should stay away from film criticism and criticize
the world instead. I am so tired of that.Renato Salvatori makes a performance of a lifetime as the troubled brother
Simone, while Alain Delon stays calm and controlled as Rocco, the
protagonist, if there is one. Boxing is used as a metaphor for the anger
the
young men feel, but when Simone fails, Rocco succeeds by fueling his
fighting with the contempt for his brother's actions. The two brothers are
torn between the beautiful prostitute Nadia, whom they both love
passionately, but she only loves Rocco- and that almost breaks the family.
The other brothers are more supporting characters, and even though the
film
is long it should have been even longer- the second youngest brother,
Ciro,
is an interesting and morally strong character that I would have loved to
see developed further. The pride, ignorance, hatred, loyalty and love of
these people are held together by a perfect script by Visconti and his
four
collaborators, and cinema's finest cinematographer, Guiseppe Rotunno,
moves
his camera magnificently through the streets, houses, and locales of a
growing, but morally decaying Milan.This is cinematic perfection. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0109687/comments</url><from>from Buenos Aires, Argentina</from><name>Bocio</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Visconti at his peak. We are in the fifties, when Italian economy
experiences a post-war boom. A Sicilian family arrives to Milan running
from south's poverty. They dream with a new life at the industrial pole
of the north. But Milan is not precisely a land of opportunities.
Exploitation and xenophobia is the common destiny for those who came
from south of the country. This film is a perfect sequel to "La Terra
Tembla", one of the earliest Visconti's looks on Marxism. The hopes and
lives of this five brother's family sink onto a pit at the same time as
they destroy themselves. "Rocco and ..." is intensely played by the
entire cast, including a young and delicate Alain Delon as the
idealistic Rocco, an exquisite Annie Girardot as a prostitute trying to
survive to her own hell and a terrific Renato Salvatori. But is the
figure of the peasant mother, played superbly by Katina Paxinou, the
most remarkable piece of this operatic story. Claudia Cardinale made
some kind of Italian debut in this film. Nino Rota composes his most
pitiful score and the black and white photography is stunning. The
scene at the rooftop of Milan's Duomo is one of my all-time favorites.
The American version is usually cut so try to find the original or some
DVD restoration. A must see film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1039576/comments</url><from>from Jersey City, NJ</from><name>bernebner</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

  I can't imagine Visconti surpassing this 1960 175-minute masterpiece
(censored when shown in USA originally, now available complete on DVD).
The
triple threat Visconti (producer, co-screenwriter, director) pours all
his
passion in this epic tale of widowed Katina Paxinou leaving her poverty
filled life in Southern Italy with family in tow for the big city life
of
Milan, hoping to better the life of her five sons, Rocco (Alan Delon),
Simone (Renato Salvatori), Ciro (Max Cartier), Moroni (RogerHanin) and
her
youngest boy of 7.  They find dwelling in the basement of a housing
complex
and better themselves eventually when Simone and, later, Rocco enter the
world of boxing.  Both become involved with a former prostitute
definitively
played by Annie Giradot.  Simone turns brutish and attacks Rocco
savagely. 
Rocco is a Christ like figure who forgives all and tries his best to
save
the family, but tragedy is in store when Simone kills Giradot in an
unforgettable waterside scene.  Also in the cast are a very young
Claudia
Cardinale and Suzy Delair.  Paolo Stoppa is brilliant as the boxing
impresario.  Score by Nina Rota (some of which is used later in Fellini
films) and photography by Giuseppe Rotunno are perfection
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0362122/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>daflauta</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
State-of-the-art directing, acting (Katina Paxinou, Alain Delon, Annie
Girardot, Renato Salvatore), photography, superb musical score. A film
to bring any sensitive and open mind to tears near the end. The
destruction of a family order, jealousy, betrayal between brothers and
the saintliness of Rocco, always ready to forgive, thinking more about
his family than himself. All this in black and white! I hope film
directors will never give away this format. By the way, I would like to
know whether the plaque in Rosaria's new apartment (when Rocco's back
from the army) reads "Pafundi" instead of "Parondi" on purpose (why?)
or was it a flaw? I also would like to know which language do some
characters spoke on stage(I think it's french), namely Rocco and
Ginetta. I am watching a Russian edition whose dubbing is disastrous.
Thanks to the ease of DVD players I could choose the Italian soundtrack
and disable subtitles...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12401791/comments</url><from>from Xanadu</from><name>stalker vogler</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The year 1960 was one of the most impressive in cinema history, at
least for Europe. It is the year of The Virgin Spring, L'Aventura and
the Godard debut A Bout de Soufflé. The latter movie signals the
emergence of the French Nouvelle Vague, maybe more so than Resnais'
Hiroshima mon amour or 400 Coupes released a year earlier. All these
movies are different approaches to cinema, different in their
intentions and outlook but similar in quality. We are not dealing here
with art-house movies. Pejorativelly used this term refers to movies
nobody really likes because they're too odd to be understood. This
art-house fever was especially contagious in European cinema. But, for
at least two decades, that is the 50's and 60's, Europe came up with
amazing movies, with interesting plots, great direction and
cinematography and a great number of landmark actors.Rocco e i suoi fratelli stars Alain Delon and Renato Salvatori in a
story that combines drama, romance, and action surrounding a family
that moves from the countryside in southern Italy to Milano where life
is hard and challenging even for the toughest. The story will keep you
glued to the screen in spite of its length of almost three hours.
However I graded the movie only with an eight because I found some of
the acting, and especially the title roles to be somewhat exaggerated.
Maybe Visconti couldn't get the feeling of neorealism the same way as
De Sica and he couldn't push from within it to a different direction as
Fellini or Pasolini did. At the beginning of the 60's the heydays of
neorealism were gone. De Sica's La Ciociara was already beginning to
show signs of fatigue. But the best of this movie lies in the direction
and photography. It is here that Rocco manages to stand among that
year's greatest. L'Aventura received a prize at Venezzia for
cinematography, Nykvist created a truly magic scenery for Bergman's The
Virgin Spring and A Bout de Soufflé was stunning in it's intelligent
mockery of the 40's American noir movies.With Visconti and more generally Italian cinema you are always in good
hands, so there will always be something in these movies even though
the whole may have some problems with the proportion between elements.
The artistic eye of Visconti transforms the dull environment of the
industrialized city into something that it almost becomes odd the
characters don't stop whatever they're doing and enjoy the landscape.The movie also features a great score from Nino Rota, used very
effectively by the director
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12401791/comments</url><from>from Xanadu</from><name>stalker vogler</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The year 1960 was one of the most impressive in cinema history, at
least for Europe. It is the year of The Virgin Spring, L'Aventura and
the Godard debut A Bout de Soufflé. The latter movie signals the
emergence of the French Nouvelle Vague, maybe more so than Resnais'
Hiroshima mon amour or 400 Coupes released a year earlier. All these
movies are different approaches to cinema, different in their
intentions and outlook but similar in quality. We are not dealing here
with art-house movies. Pejorativelly used this term refers to movies
nobody really likes because they're too odd to be understood. This
art-house fever was especially contagious in European cinema. But, for
at least two decades, that is the 50's and 60's, Europe came up with
amazing movies, with interesting plots, great direction and
cinematography and a great number of landmark actors.Rocco e i suoi fratelli stars Alain Delon and Renato Salvatori in a
story that combines drama, romance, and action surrounding a family
that moves from the countryside in southern Italy to Milano where life
is hard and challenging even for the toughest. The story will keep you
glued to the screen in spite of its length of almost three hours.
However I graded the movie only with an eight because I found some of
the acting, and especially the title roles to be somewhat exaggerated.
Maybe Visconti couldn't get the feeling of neorealism the same way as
De Sica and he couldn't push from within it to a different direction as
Fellini or Pasolini did. At the beginning of the 60's the heydays of
neorealism were gone. De Sica's La Ciociara was already beginning to
show signs of fatigue. But the best of this movie lies in the direction
and photography. It is here that Rocco manages to stand among that
year's greatest. L'Aventura received a prize at Venezzia for
cinematography, Nykvist created a truly magic scenery for Bergman's The
Virgin Spring and A Bout de Soufflé was stunning in it's intelligent
mockery of the 40's American noir movies.With Visconti and more generally Italian cinema you are always in good
hands, so there will always be something in these movies even though
the whole may have some problems with the proportion between elements.
The artistic eye of Visconti transforms the dull environment of the
industrialized city into something that it almost becomes odd the
characters don't stop whatever they're doing and enjoy the landscape.The movie also features a great score from Nino Rota, used very
effectively by the director
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12401791/comments</url><from>from Xanadu</from><name>stalker vogler</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>