<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>13 Ghosts</original_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>William Castle</director><producer>William Castle Productions</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
A family inherits what proves to be a haunted house, but a special pair of goggles allows them to see their ghostly tormentors.
</synopsis><actor>Charles Herbert</actor><actor>Jo Morrow</actor><actor>Martin Milner</actor><rt_rating>4.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>31</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3284055/comments</url><from>from San Francisco, California</from><name>John Weybrew</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

William Castle set out to make a fun, spooky, scarey picture for anyone
who
ever believed (or wanted to believe) in ghosts, and the result, 13 GHOSTS,
is a marvelous and memorable little picture, that even after 40-odd years,
still has creeps, scares, thrills and fun galore.If at all possible, see it the way it was meant to be seen- - -with proper
Ghost Viewers-(available with the DVD edition) -so you can experience
Illusiono, by which you can actually see the ghosts in Ectoplasmic Color!The plot, acting and production values may be unsophisticated, but what
matter?- -The important thing is THE GHOSTS- -and they are all there as
promised, including the mysterious thirteenth ghost- -and a wonderfully
familiar witch (who was delighted to play the part)- -This is a great movie for kids (and adults) who love ghosts and spooky
stuff, but are not at all ready (or desirous) of watching a movie full of
gore, putrescent language or non-stop violence.You'll remember the ghosts, the fun and the thrills, for years to
come.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12098478/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>seaview29</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Thirteen Ghosts is one of those great 'classic' horror films,that
relied more on atmosphere and acting, then on 'gory' special f/x. I saw
the re-make' and did not enjoy it at all; being a classic horror film
fan, I was very disappointed. This movie features some pretty good
actings; Donald Woods, Rosemary DeCamp, and Martin Milner of the
classic "Route 66" TV show, Donald Woods as know to classic horror
fans, appeared in the Beast from 20,000 Fathoms, and John VanDreelan in
"The Leech Woman" so it was goods for us old 'classiclovers' to see
them, and lets not forget Miss Margaret Hamilton, the 'Wicked "Witch of
the West" from the great "Wizard of 0z' all in all an entertaining, fun
family film It has its scary moments, but none of the 'gore' so
prevalent in today's films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1325465/comments</url><from>from Pittsburgh, PA</from><name>Hessian499</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

13 Ghosts has stood the test of time well, as have most of Castle's films.
While much is made of the gimmick of seeing the ghosts with 3d glasses, the
movie itself is well made and not just a vehicle to carry the gimmick.
Seeing the movie on television or video without the 3d glasses (but with the
ghosts visible) makes you realize this is a well made film.The scene where the father encounters the ghosts for the first time in the
hidden room is quite spooky, and the special effects are almost hypnotic to
watch. The story behind the ghosts being in the house is developed quite
well, and makes the ghosts themselves more enjoyable. The ghosts range from
almost comical to truly frightening, and it is fun to wait and see what kind
of spirit you will encounter next.The house itself is a rather nice piece of real estate, and I'm sure some
people have driven around Los Angeles trying to find it. Martin Milner plays
the lawyer who facilitates the will giving the family the house, and it is
interesting to see him in his pre-Adam 12 days.13 Ghosts is definitely worth watching, especially around Halloween. While
some may find the plot and idea less than satisfying, I found it to be very
spooky. And you really do get to see all 13 ghosts!
 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1210693/comments</url><from>from midwest</from><name>stargazer24</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The reason I watched this film in the first place was because one of my
favorite actors (Martin Milner) is in it, but now it's one of my favorites.
I don't generally like horror films, but this one is great.  It has
everything: ghosts, spooky little people, screaming women, weird special
affects, and people who are more than they seem.  I actually laid awake that
night listening to noises in my house!  Plus the little boy in this movie is
a pretty good actor.  The one complaint I have is that the ghosts are hard to see.  I'd like to
see this released either on DVD or again on video, but this time with the
special illusion affects William Castle put in it in tact, and special
glasses could come with the DVD/video.  This may look to some like a typical cheesy 50's &amp; early 60's horror film,
but it's one of the best.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I still remember as a kid all the publicity surrounding 13 Ghosts and
how when you went to see the film you were given tinted cardboard
framed plastic glasses. The better to see the ectoplasm on the screen.Sadly my VHS copy doesn't have the ghosts in color. They just appear
very pale on the screen and the film has to carried by the players who
don't look too motivated by the lines they have to utter.Dr. Zorba played by Donald Woods inherits an old haunted house with a
witch housekeeper, Margaret Hamilton, to go with it. Woods moves in his
family which consists of Rosemary DeCamp, Charles Herbert, and Jo
Morrow. The lawyer handling the estate, Martin Milner, takes quite a
shine to Ms. Morrow, but he also has a whole other agenda as well.Of course after they move in, various apparitions start appearing and
it's pretty disconcerting believe me. Action has to be taken and it's
took all right.If you're interested by all means see the film. It's acquired a cult
status over the years. The special effects, impressive back then, don't
quite hold up as well as say DeMille parting the Red Sea in The Ten
Commandments.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0129764/comments</url><from>from Riverside, Ca lifornia, USA</from><name>Richard Hatch (bmscrh@ucrac1.ucr.edu)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I was 8 years old when this movie came out. We saw it as a family at the
Baseline Drive-in. At the time it really scared me and my siblings. I just
saw it recently on video and my impressions now are of course different.
What I remember were the special glasses that you had to use to see or not
to see the ghosts. William Castle at the time was the PT Barnum of horror
movies and this was one of his latest gimmicks. Probably what I remember
the
most was finding for weeks afterward the discarded special glasses in our
families orange grove since we lived about 1 mile from the drive-in and
our
road was on the way home for many people. My dad couldn't stand trash on
our
property and would pay each of us 5 cents for each one we brought to
him.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0909646/comments</url><from>from Hendersonville, TN</from><name>William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

   Ghost movies are among my favorite horror movies even over vampire
pictures because you can't screw up a ghost movie while so many vampire
movies rewrite vampire legends to fit their plots. William Castle knew how
to make really good "haunted house" pictures. "House on Haunted Hill" is a
classic, even with it's so-so remake, but I think "Thirteen Ghosts" deserves
to be counted as Castle's best. In this movie he sets up a family nearing
financial destitution despite the father's white collar job. This family
with its knock-out daughter and flighty son (I shouldn't complain, that boy
acts and talks the same way I was at his age) loses everything except their
private belongings and then discovers a forgotten rich relative has left
them his house and fortune. Wouldn't you want that to happen to you ? Before
you say 'yes,' the house turns out to be haunted by the eccentric relative's
ghost collection (this was years before "Ghostbusters"). The family has to
decide to give up the house which may be hiding the relative's missing
fortune or give it all up. It's a great plot, but the "Illusio" used at the
time to create the ghosts with special glasses doesn't translate well to the
black and white of today's tv screens, not even if you try to substitute 3-D
glasses.Still, for what you see of them, the ghosts are chilling in a
surreal sort of way as they go about their business and scare the family on
the side. Some of the acting is campy, particularly De Camp's reactions to
the ghosts in the kitchen. The boy, Buck, can be particularly chilling in
the way Haley Joel Osment was for "The Sixth Sense." The daughter, Medea,
played by  obscure Jo Morrow, overdoes some of the stern sister's acting,
but the father is played somewhat wooden. "Adam-12's" Martin Milner looks
out of his element as the family lawyer, but he was near the start of his
acting career. Kudos have to go to the casting of Margaret Hamilton from
"The Wizard of Oz" as the housekeeper who may or may not be a witch in this
movie too. Can you imagine what this movie would have been like with Ann B.
Davis ?  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This film by William Castle about a family of four moving into a house
professed to have no fewer than 13 ghosts is a great deal of fun.
Donald Woods is Cyrus Zorba, a paleontologist down on his luck. His
furniture has just been removed from his flat and his wife and two
children, Medea and Buck, seem used to being in continual dire
financial straits. While sitting on the floor for Buck's birthday
party, a creepy message comes telling Cyrus to see a lawyer in the
morning. Cyrus and wife Rosemary Decamp go and discover that Cyrus has
inherited a huge mansion from his Uncle Plato as well as a package
containing some weird type of glasses. It seems that Uncle Plato
collected ghosts. The rest of the story details what life is like in
this house that has these ghosts. I did not have the pair of glasses so
cannot tell you what it looked like in Illusion-O, but I bet it was
even more fun. Castle always seems to do a good job at creating
entertaining, fun films, though none of them ever seem to be much more
than that either. The mystery is not hard to figure out at all. The
acting is good all around with youngster Charles Herbert giving a nice
performance as Buck. Woods is good as the family patriarch and Jo
Morrow is just beautiful as daughter Medea. Martin Milner plays Ben the
lawyer. And as a retainer in the house is Elaine, played by none other
than Margaret Hamilton(always a joy to see her). When Ben first arrives
at the house to see how the Zorbas are doing, Buck says "ring the bell
and you'll see a witch." Of course the witch reference goes throughout
the whole film as Hamilton looks witch-like and this is one marvelous
inside gag about her Wizard of Oz performance. The effects for the film
are pretty tame and very hokey, but this film is just good,
old-fashioned fun. I liked it from beginning to end. If you loved the
new one and decide to go back and see the old one - you will be very
disappointed. Just as I was disappointed having seen the old one and
moving to the new one. They have nothing except some threadbare
incidentals in common and a producer named Castle(though a different
first name for each).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0708885/comments</url><from>from Norfolk, VA</from><name>lthseldy1</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

  Yes, it may be old but I find it better than the "new revised" version
that terribly stunk.  Sure, when we see floating candles and furniture we
can only imagine a small thin piece of string on the tip but hey, at least
they used their imagination and had fun with it.  The part played by the
wicked witch from "The Wizard of Oz" was the best part.  She was perfect in
the film.  As well as the family.  They played their parts better.  The
father didn't act as stupid as the one in the modern version and the rest of
the actors/actresses were better as well.  There were alot of parts in the
film that did not match the ones in the modern version but hey, thats why I
liked it better they didn't have all those boring motives that the modern
version had.  And the ghosts were even scarier even though you could tell
that it was a man in a costume with a reflecting light. 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2339137/comments</url><from>from Iowa, USA</from><name>wind (liathano31@netscape.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Don't confuse this movie with the awful remake.  Thankfully this movie was
shown on one of the old movie channels before the remake came out or I
might
have passed on it.  Maybe I'm biased having grown up watching all kind of
horror movies, but I've always enjoyed the older movies like this one
rather
than the in your face remakes of today.  Subtlety goes a long ways in
telling the story!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2339137/comments</url><from>from Iowa, USA</from><name>wind (liathano31@netscape.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Don't confuse this movie with the awful remake.  Thankfully this movie was
shown on one of the old movie channels before the remake came out or I
might
have passed on it.  Maybe I'm biased having grown up watching all kind of
horror movies, but I've always enjoyed the older movies like this one
rather
than the in your face remakes of today.  Subtlety goes a long ways in
telling the story!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2339137/comments</url><from>from Iowa, USA</from><name>wind (liathano31@netscape.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/13-ghosts-1960-directed-by-william-castle-8/ /m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1992862</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Amateurish and crude, William Castle's film is better known for its aggressive publicity campaign.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/13-ghosts-1960 /m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1926285</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Cheesy -- and gory -- classic; no young'uns.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/13ghosts.shtml /m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1851840</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>It falters just as most of today's movies falter: too much emphasis on effects and not enough on characters.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/13ghosts.htm /m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1680146</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>A dull and crudely made haunted house tale.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/alex-sandell/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1177997</url><name>Alex Sandell</name><from>Juicy Cerebellum</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment>Too bad the ghost goggles didn't blind you from this horrid film.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=788700</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Quaint, creaky, and probably worse than the remake</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=743570</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>eFilmCritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>Dry and dusty; the good bits are doled out slowly and sparingly.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=256553</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Movie Mom at Yahoo! Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>The special effects were low-budget even for their time, but there are a couple of jump-out-at-you moments and plot twists that still work pretty well.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/robin-clifford/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1338595</url><name>Robin Clifford</name><from>Reeling Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rich-cline/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1218552</url><name>Rich Cline</name><from>Shadows on the Wall</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rob-vaux/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=819451</url><name>Rob Vaux</name><from>Flipside Movie Emporium</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-foreman/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=805128</url><name>Jonathan Foreman</name><from>New York Post</from></reviewer><rating>
1.5/4
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cory-cheney/</url><url>/m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=751969</url><name>Cory Cheney</name><from>Urban Tulsa Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9903EFDE133DE333A25755C0A96E9C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/13_ghosts/comments.php?reviewid=1390492</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>