<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Et mourir de plaisir</original_title><imdb_rating>6.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><director>Roger Vadim</director><producer>Documento Film</producer><producer>Films EGE</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
Young Carmilla is jealous of her friend's engagement, and her obsession leads her to the tomb of a female vampire...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Mel Ferrer</actor><actor>Elsa Martinelli</actor><actor>Annette Vadim</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13216814/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>andrabem</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I saw this film a long time ago in the television. I can still remember
the atmosphere and gentle horror that permeate the film. "Et mourir de
plaisir" is based on "Carmilla", an horror tale written by Sheridan Le
Fanu. I had already read the book as a child and had liked it very
much. Later on I saw this film on television and I was deeply impressed
- the atmosphere, the castle and landscape surrounding it, the two
girlfriends running together and laughing (one of them will die because
the other one is in reality a vampire), beautiful flowers ... weave
together a delicate tapestry. Contrary to the Hammer film "The Vampire Lovers" in which the girls
relationship is explored very briefly and superficially, "Et Mourir de
Plaisir" shows in more detail the delicate love story between two girls
lived until death did them part.I don't remember so well the film after such a long time, but some
images remained with me, and those images dictate the words I'm writing
now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1073412/comments</url><from>from Dublin, Ireland</from><name>rockallnight (rockallnight@iolfree.ie)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This article is aimed at people already familiar with the American
version of Roger Vadim's "Blood And Roses". For those who have not seen
the film, it may contain possible "spoilers". Since so few fans appear
to have seen the original "European" version of this film, I shall try
to detail the difference between the two versions. The only video copy
I have is the American version, but have seen the 84 minute
English-dubbed original several times in Irish and U.K. cinemas. The
information given below is drawn from memory. The biggest difference is
the way in which the story is told: in the U.S. version the narrator is
Millarca; in the original, the story is begun and concluded by Dr.
Valeri. Both versions begin with the Caravelle jet taking off, but in
the original this is followed by a scene on board the aircraft in which
Valeri is in conversation with a small group of friends. After a little
encouragement - "Doctor, I've known you a long time; I'll bet you have
a story to tell us", Valeri begins the story of Carmilla, Georgia and
Leopoldo. This is then followed by several scenes that have been cut:
1. Martha, one of the children who has a fascination with the Vampire
legend, is seen exploring the Karnstein cemetery, much to Marie's
trepidation. 2. Signor Lugieri is seen doing a reconnaissance of the
old abbey as a possible location for his firework display. 3. Carmilla
and Georgia are seen sharing a horseback ride. They are greeted at the
villa by Leopoldo, who reminds them that there will be guests for
dinner that evening. 4. Martha and Marie are saying their night-time
prayers. When Martha pleads "Please let me see a Vampire someday" this
leads to a comic altercation between the two, ending in a pillow fight.
The above 4 scenes - which account for about 5 minutes running time -
are introductory, so their absence does not impact too much on the
plot.However, also dropped is a brief scene in which Carmilla, in the
presence of Judge Monteverdi, is seen laughing heartily at an
unspecified joke. This occurs just before the scene with the fox, and
shows another side of Carmilla's character. In two more scenes - the
greenhouse scene and when Dr. Valeri gives his explanation of
Carmilla's behavior to Leopoldo - the dialog has been shortened. Apart
from scenes being cut/shortened and the narrator being changed, there
have also been some additions. These include extra lines spoken
off-camera ("You make it seem too real, Carmilla", "Carmilla, enough;
you're frightening Georgia" etc.), extra sound effects (the
unconvincing screams), and even visuals (the big close-ups of the rose
fading) that Paramount presumably felt were needed to make the story
clearer and the film more "marketable". The difference between the two
versions, therefore, is considerable. My purpose here has been to list
the differences, not evaluate them. However, the use of a Vampire
spirit(!) as a narrator in place of Dr. Valeri destroys the film's
intended ambiguity. In the original, Dr. Valeri's medical/psychological
explanation of Carmilla's behavior is balanced by Giuseppi and the
children Martha and Marie who explain it according to their
superstitious beliefs. The audience is left to decide for themselves.
No such choice for the American viewer: Millarca's over-dubbed voice
tells us that she is taking possession of Carmilla. Giant close-ups of
the fading rose prove it. To my knowledge, "Et Mourir De
Plaisir"/"Blood and Roses" has never been released on VHS or DVD in
Europe. Since it has appeared on VHS in America, it is possible that
Paramount may eventually put out a DVD. However, this would most likely
be the U.S. version. That is unless fans of the film were to bombard
the distributor with requests for the original. But why would fans
request release of a version they have not seen? Maybe this article
will awaken an interest.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0357603/comments</url><from/><name>allusion</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is beautiful and poetic.
If you see this movie on English dialogue, you must see French
version.
English version has terrible narration.
And this movie filmed in TECHNIRAMA, you must see this on letter
box.
If you don't, you have seen nothing yet.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9619568/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL</from><name>Musidora-4</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I'm mad about this film...might just be my favorite vampire film of
all. It's not straight LeFanu, but it has an elegiac air that is. Doing
LeFanu 'straight'--as in VAMPIRE LOVERS-- does not necessarily make for
a better film as Hammer proved.When I first saw B&amp;R 15 years ago, I was disappointed because I wanted
it to be a direct telling of the source material. Later, I saw the
film, again, and it seared in to my consciousness. For no explicable
reason, it suddenly "made sense" and "glammed" me; and, in particular,
Annette Stroyberg's performance suddenly "clicked in." The combination
of her detachment, passivity, out bursts of passion, child-like
felicity, and, of course, beauty recall her literary namesake. Her
profound sorrow and knowledge of being pushed aside from all that she
loves--not just Leopoldo but her whole life, really--is heart-rending. Vadim's Carmilla is always described as "jealous" or "bitter," though I
don't see that. I do see deep disappointment and despair. It's
refreshing, too, to see two women, rivals for one man's affection,
treat each other so civilly, so kindly. Worse, Carmilla is slowly
ostracized from people that she has grown up with and loved all because
of her love of Leopoldo and, then, Georgia. Top that off with being
possessed by a vampire, and I think dismissing her as "jealous" or
"bitter" is a bit heavy-handed and easy.I'm not quite sure why this film is considered "exploitive"--was Vadim
"exploiting" Annette and his divorce from BB? Was LeFanu's "Carmilla"
exploitive? It actually had far more explicit descriptions of
Carmilla's breast-centric vampirism of young woman, but I don't recall
the novella ever being described as "exploitive."There are a couple of jarring moments in the film that don't sit right
with me, for instance, Carmilla and Leopold doing the comic piano duet
about fishing, and some parts of the celebrated "dream sequence"--just
too "art house," even Bergman-esquire, and certainly screaming Cocteau. But, in the end, the film is enchanting, ravishing, and harrowing. As
others have noted, the score is exquisite and sets just the right tone,
and makes me think of "pavane" and "dead princess" at the same time.
Definitely in my top 10.Just hoping that the delay in releasing BLOOD AND ROSES on DVD has to
do with a pains- taking restoration and accumulation of extras on
Paramount's part--this film is long overdue on DVD.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6172354/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>ddx-5</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I was a teenager, that movie was rated +16 and I was 14. I don't
remember why I wanted so much to watch this movie, maybe the poster's
picture, Annette Vadim and Elsa Martinelli kissing :). I borrowed the
ID card of an older friend of mine, then I'd been allowed to go in.That day, I've seen that movie 2 times, and I came back the day after
and I stayed 2 more times watching it, fascinated. Not for the plot,
the plot is cheesy. Not for some nudity, there's none. The beauty of
Annette Vadim, oh yes! The magnificent cinematography? Even if I didn't
know what "cinematography" was, I still remember the fascination I
sensed for the colors and the lighting. And I still remember also the
score of Jean Prodromidès (an underrated genius, his opera "The
Persians" is a masterpiece!) It was almost 50 years ago, thanks to Annette, Claude Renoir, Jean
Prodromidès, Vadim, I was become a movie-goer. By the way, I've never
seen that movie again from that time. I'm afraid to be disappointed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2403537/comments</url><from/><name>callanvass</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This is a beautiful 60's Horror film, with a great story and a wicked
ending!. This really felt like a Hammer film, and for the most part it
was, and it had a beautiful score, plus all the characters were great!.
I found this in the Horror section, and the story looked intriguing so
i picked it up, and i was quite surprised by how good it was, it's a
little dated but the story is very engrossing, and the performances
were all excellent, plus the ending was absolutely wicked!. It's never
boring, and the film surprisingly has a little bit of violence, plus
Annette Vadim is simply gorgeous!. As i said i was really quite
surprised by how much i enjoyed this film, and the set pieces were
fantastic, plus there are a few shocking moments as well!. This is a
beautiful 60's Horror film with a great story and a wicked ending, and
i say it's a must see!. The direction is great!. Roger Vadim does a
great job here, giving it a dreamy look and feel, good camera work,
great set pieces and keeping the film at an engrossing pace!. There i
surprisingly a little bit of violence. We get a bit of blood, bloody
vamp marks and and a gory impaling. The Acting is very good. Mel Ferrer
is excellent here, he was charming, very likable and held his own very
well, i liked him lots. Annette Vadim is stunningly beautiful and is
wonderful here,her character is very unpredictable and she turned me
on, i loved her. Elsa Martinelli is beautiful and does fine with what
she had to do, and had good chemistry with Mel Ferrer. rest of the cast
do fine. Overall a must see!. **** out of 5
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10315844/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>GaultheWarrior</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I saw Vadim's "Blood and Roses" in Germany while stationed there in the
1960's. I was captivated by its ethereal, romantic quality. The
actresses were beautiful and the mixture of romance and vampires was
unusual and hauntingly lovely. In my view, it is a classic. I
particularly loved the musical score, which was outstanding. I cannot
seem to find this musical score other than by ordering the VHS video.I am particularly disappointed that I cannot find this film in DVD
today, since I would like to have it in my library.I thought that Mel Ferrar was perfect for his role since he was
seemingly oblivious as one might expect a country gentleman to be to
what was going on with the girls.The film reveals a poignant story of unrequited love, with a fatalistic
tone. It will be long remembered by those who have seen it. It does not
get the popularity that it deserves.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9316206/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>eagleflyer</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
A school chum and I saw this film only one time - when it was first
released in 1960. During a recent reunion we realized that neither of
us has ever forgotten the spellbinding qualities of the movie as a
whole! I very clearly remember the impression of having walked into a
renaissance-era painting accompanied by a musical score that along with
the visuals, created an almost hypnotic state. Elsa Martinelli was a
familiar face at that time, but the mysteriously beautiful other
actress was not. I now realize she has to have been Annette Vadim. I
clearly remember the undercurrent she portrayed with such seemingly
effortless skill that it almost felt like watching two separate
characters. The other actors and characters seemed to be almost like
props in comparison to these two players in the story. I do hope I can
see it again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5081289/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>matheusmarchetti</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
In a world where films such as "Twilight" are considered great vampire
flicks, a little unknown gem like "Blood and Roses" comes as a
extremely pleasant surprise as it is one of those films that you expect
nothing from and turn out to be real cinematic works of art. Unfairly
underrated director Roger Vadim creates a dark, tragic love story,
filled with beautiful landscapes, terrifying Gothic atmosphere,
surrealistic feel, a lovely soundtrack and a suspenseful build up to a
shocking and heartbreaking finale. Vadim adapts Sheridan La Fanu's
"Carmilla" with a modern twist, whilst keeping the poetry and the
eroticism that so many other, more "faithful" adaptations lack. Making
"Carmilla" a much more human character was a clever choice and makes
you feel sympathy for her character, so therefore you actually feel bad
for both the victims and the killer, which is something that usually
lacks in horror films, at least in such an intelligent way. Annette
Vadim helps bringing the character to life, and is here in one of her
best performances. Mel Ferrer and Elsa Martinelli have a wonderful
chemistry together and are perfect choices for the supporting roles.
Another of the film's highlights is the cinematography, that
unfortunately doesn't show it's full Technicolor glory in the film's
bad VHS print. Hopefully, one day Paramount will release this
masterpiece in DVD or Blu-Ray with it's gorgeous visuals as Vadim
intended. 10/10 - a masterpiece. One of the best vampire movies ever
made.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Joseph Sheridan Le Fanu’s classic horror short story “Carmilla” (which
I own and have read) spearheaded the trend for cinematic tales of
lesbian vampires. This is the second film adaptation of it – the first,
a very loose one, was Carl Theodor Dreyer’s magnificent VAMPYR (1931;
soon to be regaled with two fully-loaded SE DVDs on both sides of the
Atlantic) and it was followed in quick succession by the
Spanish/Italian co-production CRYPT OF THE VAMPIRE (1963; starring
Christopher Lee, a quite good version, of which I foolishly erased a
VHS copy I had recorded off Italian TV – the only edition currently
available is the Retromedia R1 DVD which, unfortunately, presents the
film dubbed in English), the Amicus/Hammer collaboration THE VAMPIRE
LOVERS (1970; starring Ingrid Pitt and Peter Cushing) and Vicente
Aranda’s eerily erotic THE BLOOD-SPATTERED BRIDE (1972).Director Vadim is better-known for having had great tastes in women
(counting Brigitte Bardot, Catherine Deneuve and Jane Fonda among his
discoveries/lovers) than for his film-making talents; I myself have
only been truly impressed by one of his movies – THE GAME IS OVER
(1966) – out of the seven that I’ve watched so far (including this
one). BLOOD AND ROSES could well have been the second…were it not for
the fact that the edited 74-minute version I watched – prepared for
U.S. home video consumption and sporting the Anglicized original title
AND DIE OF PLEASURE – is a bit of a mess (the full-length French
version is 87 minutes long), English-dubbed (naturally),
panned-and-scanned (of course), and preceded by one of the phoniest
credit sequences I’ve ever witnessed (that said, a reasonable photo
gallery was included with the DivX copy I acquired, which starts
automatically soon after the main feature). Needless to say, I’d long
wanted to watch this – but, bearing in mind the state of the edition I
ended up with, in spite of its many pictorial rewards, it wasn’t an
ideal viewing experience…and one can only hope that, given the amicable
relationship between Paramount (who owns the U.S. rights for BLOOD AND
ROSES) and Criterion, the film will turn up someday – in the original
French language and uncut – on a decent official DVD (after all, the
latter’s vast and considerable collection already numbers Vadim’s debut
feature …AND GOD CREATED WOMAN [1956] among its releases).Anyway, the cast is an interesting combination of international movie
stars (Mel Ferrer – who, coincidentally, has just died aged 90 – and
Elsa Martinelli), newcomers (Annette Vadim nee' Stroyberg) and even a
director (Marc Allegret, who had given Vadim an early start when he
engaged him as his assistant). The film makes a fair attempt to update
the LeFanu original to contemporary times – though, rather than make
Carmilla and Millarca one and the same, we get the former being
possessed by the latter: this is quite subtly done (at least in this
reduced form) as Millarca’s personality in Carmilla manifests itself in
her suddenly knowing the steps to an ancient dance and her incongruous
preference for a classical record! As a matter of fact, this medieval
quality permeates the whole film – thanks also to Jean Prodromides’
haunting melancholy score (which is then effectively speeded-up during
the ‘horror’ sequences). Incidentally, the film was clearly intended
for the Art-house crowd (resulting in being fairly talky for the first
two-thirds) – even if it’s not quite in the same league as Georges
Franju’s EYES WITHOUT A FACE (1959), an altogether more accomplished
and successful marriage of the highbrow and the exploitative.That said, it contains any number of striking sequences: the costume
party (with a fireworks display for backdrop) in which Ferrer dons a
bat mask fitted with a pair of wings!; Stroyberg’s wraith-like pursuit
of her first victim (her stilted performance is actually just right for
the character) – despite its being obviously shot day-for-night; the
wilted rose on Carmilla’s white dress turning to a huge blood stain
(incidentally, this vampire registers in a mirror!); Stroyberg’s
seduction of Martinelli on a rainy night inside the Karnstein family
greenhouse (both women also love Ferrer, though he and Stroyberg are
related!); Martinelli’s surreal, erotic and blood-spattered
black-and-white dream sequence towards the end (in which, among other
things, Stroyberg as Millarca operates on her naked self as Carmilla!)
– which is the film’s undeniable tour-de-force; Carmilla’s demise as
she gets staked during an explosion (the location being a cemetery
holding remnant shells from WWII); and the very last image when another
wilted rose betrays the fact to the audience, but not the oblivious
Ferrer, that Martinelli has herself been turned into a vampire (the
latter starts off as an ingénue but slowly, and believably, matures
through her attachment to Carmilla).By the way, some weeks back I happened upon a recent TV interview with
Martinelli; she seemed deservedly proud of her cinematic legacy
(including a successful stint in Hollywood) but, unsurprisingly, this
film – or another good one where she was also involved in lesbianism,
Lucio Fulci’s giallo ONE ON TOP OF THE OTHER aka PERVERSION STORY
(1969) – wasn’t mentioned at all…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Joseph Sheridan Le Fanu’s classic horror short story “Carmilla” (which
I own and have read) spearheaded the trend for cinematic tales of
lesbian vampires. This is the second film adaptation of it – the first,
a very loose one, was Carl Theodor Dreyer’s magnificent VAMPYR (1931;
soon to be regaled with two fully-loaded SE DVDs on both sides of the
Atlantic) and it was followed in quick succession by the
Spanish/Italian co-production CRYPT OF THE VAMPIRE (1963; starring
Christopher Lee, a quite good version, of which I foolishly erased a
VHS copy I had recorded off Italian TV – the only edition currently
available is the Retromedia R1 DVD which, unfortunately, presents the
film dubbed in English), the Amicus/Hammer collaboration THE VAMPIRE
LOVERS (1970; starring Ingrid Pitt and Peter Cushing) and Vicente
Aranda’s eerily erotic THE BLOOD-SPATTERED BRIDE (1972).Director Vadim is better-known for having had great tastes in women
(counting Brigitte Bardot, Catherine Deneuve and Jane Fonda among his
discoveries/lovers) than for his film-making talents; I myself have
only been truly impressed by one of his movies – THE GAME IS OVER
(1966) – out of the seven that I’ve watched so far (including this
one). BLOOD AND ROSES could well have been the second…were it not for
the fact that the edited 74-minute version I watched – prepared for
U.S. home video consumption and sporting the Anglicized original title
AND DIE OF PLEASURE – is a bit of a mess (the full-length French
version is 87 minutes long), English-dubbed (naturally),
panned-and-scanned (of course), and preceded by one of the phoniest
credit sequences I’ve ever witnessed (that said, a reasonable photo
gallery was included with the DivX copy I acquired, which starts
automatically soon after the main feature). Needless to say, I’d long
wanted to watch this – but, bearing in mind the state of the edition I
ended up with, in spite of its many pictorial rewards, it wasn’t an
ideal viewing experience…and one can only hope that, given the amicable
relationship between Paramount (who owns the U.S. rights for BLOOD AND
ROSES) and Criterion, the film will turn up someday – in the original
French language and uncut – on a decent official DVD (after all, the
latter’s vast and considerable collection already numbers Vadim’s debut
feature …AND GOD CREATED WOMAN [1956] among its releases).Anyway, the cast is an interesting combination of international movie
stars (Mel Ferrer – who, coincidentally, has just died aged 90 – and
Elsa Martinelli), newcomers (Annette Vadim nee' Stroyberg) and even a
director (Marc Allegret, who had given Vadim an early start when he
engaged him as his assistant). The film makes a fair attempt to update
the LeFanu original to contemporary times – though, rather than make
Carmilla and Millarca one and the same, we get the former being
possessed by the latter: this is quite subtly done (at least in this
reduced form) as Millarca’s personality in Carmilla manifests itself in
her suddenly knowing the steps to an ancient dance and her incongruous
preference for a classical record! As a matter of fact, this medieval
quality permeates the whole film – thanks also to Jean Prodromides’
haunting melancholy score (which is then effectively speeded-up during
the ‘horror’ sequences). Incidentally, the film was clearly intended
for the Art-house crowd (resulting in being fairly talky for the first
two-thirds) – even if it’s not quite in the same league as Georges
Franju’s EYES WITHOUT A FACE (1959), an altogether more accomplished
and successful marriage of the highbrow and the exploitative.That said, it contains any number of striking sequences: the costume
party (with a fireworks display for backdrop) in which Ferrer dons a
bat mask fitted with a pair of wings!; Stroyberg’s wraith-like pursuit
of her first victim (her stilted performance is actually just right for
the character) – despite its being obviously shot day-for-night; the
wilted rose on Carmilla’s white dress turning to a huge blood stain
(incidentally, this vampire registers in a mirror!); Stroyberg’s
seduction of Martinelli on a rainy night inside the Karnstein family
greenhouse (both women also love Ferrer, though he and Stroyberg are
related!); Martinelli’s surreal, erotic and blood-spattered
black-and-white dream sequence towards the end (in which, among other
things, Stroyberg as Millarca operates on her naked self as Carmilla!)
– which is the film’s undeniable tour-de-force; Carmilla’s demise as
she gets staked during an explosion (the location being a cemetery
holding remnant shells from WWII); and the very last image when another
wilted rose betrays the fact to the audience, but not the oblivious
Ferrer, that Martinelli has herself been turned into a vampire (the
latter starts off as an ingénue but slowly, and believably, matures
through her attachment to Carmilla).By the way, some weeks back I happened upon a recent TV interview with
Martinelli; she seemed deservedly proud of her cinematic legacy
(including a successful stint in Hollywood) but, unsurprisingly, this
film – or another good one where she was also involved in lesbianism,
Lucio Fulci’s giallo ONE ON TOP OF THE OTHER aka PERVERSION STORY
(1969) – wasn’t mentioned at all…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/staci-layne-wilson/</url><url>http://www.horror.com/php/article-3015-1.html /m/blood_and_roses/comments.php?reviewid=1871858</url><name>Staci Layne Wilson</name><from>Horror.com</from></reviewer><comment>Blood &amp; Roses [is] one of the most gorgeous and visually arresting vampire movies I have ever seen.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-szymanski/</url><url>/m/blood_and_roses/comments.php?reviewid=1443514</url><name>Michael Szymanski</name><from>International Press Academy</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/blood_and_roses/comments.php?reviewid=1408030</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/blood_and_roses/comments.php?reviewid=747297</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9903E6D8113DE733A25751C1A9669D946091D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/blood_and_roses/comments.php?reviewid=1390477</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/1162_BLOOD_AND_ROSES.html /m/blood_and_roses/comments.php?reviewid=26824</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>