<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Fuefukigawa</original_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Keisuke Kinoshita</director><producer>Shochiku Ofuna</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis/><actor>Takahiro Tamura</actor><actor>Hideko Takamine</actor><actor>Kôshirô Matsumoto</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1772437/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>zandert33</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I'm not one to usually comment on movies on IMDb, but I think the fact
that the only review that shows up on the site says "Depressing" and
gives it a low mark, I had to resolve that issue.This movie is absolutely amazing. Firstly, the scope of the story is
really quite amazing. We basically have six generations of one family,
and their story. The story itself isn't really complex, but it really
does linger in your mind for a while after watching the movie. The
basic story is the how futile fighting can be. The acting is top notch,
there isn't a bad performance in the lot. I thought the color effects
were a little weird, and I'm not sure I understood the point of them.
It didn't take away from the movie at all though.This is an amazing film. Is it sad? Yes, it is, but that doesn't mean
it shouldn't be watched. This is really a hidden gem of Japanese
cinema, and I'd love to see it get a US release at some point.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9987799/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Michael Neumann</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
There's a rare sense of epic artistry in this unusual and striking
medieval saga, directed by Keisuke Kinoshita as more of an aesthetic
experience than a conventional drama. The film was designed to resemble
a decorative 16th century Japanese scroll, painting spare brushstrokes
of vivid color across each panoramic, wide-screen black and white
image. It can be difficult (and not really worth the effort) to follow
the endless progression of characters, and the manner in which the film
unfolds is often more involving than the story it presents. Each leap
forward in time approximates the turning of another page, usually to
the next in a series of pointless, bloody battles between feudal
warlords, with each conflict properly labeled beforehand, identifying
the date, location, and principals involved. The battle scenes serve as
punctuation, following successive generations of peasant soldiers to
their doom, with the repetition suggesting that war is the only eternal
aspect of the human condition, and passive resistance is futile.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15253413/comments</url><from>from Italy</from><name>signor_rossi-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Don't let the 4 star vote of one of the previous commentators prevent
you from viewing this movie, it conveys much more than only a 'war is
futile' message. Many 'good' war movies could be reduced to only this
message (could, because mostly in reality they are only cheap
propaganda a la 'Waltz with Bashir'), but certainly not this movie. As
another commentator said, it lingers in your mind for a while after
watching it and in this aftermath I really began to realize how
meaningful and elaborate each scene or part of the story of the movie
was. In one judgment sharptongue was right, though, the movie is
depressing, and not only slightly. I don't want to spoil anything so
let me only say that if you liked movies like 'Seven Samurai' this one
is also for you.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0642841/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>sharptongue</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Rating - 4/10The enigmatic title is explained near the end, which more or less
paraphrases "Ol' Man River" - he just keeps rollin' along, regardless of
the
follies of man. The films set in the "turbulent century", and was it ever !
The film's two hours covers about 70 years, and there's a battle nearly
every five minutes. The large cast of characters, principally of one small
family, deal with the age-old problem of the young getting carried away
with
war and the older warning them how futile it all is. There are a number of
deaths which coincide closely with births, and the characters assume they
therefore know where the souls have reincarnated.The war-is-futile message is hammered home without subtlety and, despite
the
downtrodden gaining occasional triumphs, it's all very depressing. The only
character who has a good laugh is killed shortly afterwards, and partly for
that reason !The strange aspect of this film is that it is part-colourized. In many
frames, these are simply large splashes of colour laid-over, and they look
terrible and amateurish. Other frames have more minute and detailed
colorization, which is quite pleasant. But the film would have looked
better
if it had stuck to B&amp;W only.The four points I've awarded this film are mainly for the acting, which is
good to great throughout. The oval-faced beauty Hideko Takamine is very
watchable for the first half at least, but has far less to do than some of
her other roles. The actress (name unknown) who plays the pretend-madwoman
Tatsu is a standout.But it takes more than good acting to make a good pic. I cannot recommend
this pic.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0642841/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>sharptongue</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Rating - 4/10The enigmatic title is explained near the end, which more or less
paraphrases "Ol' Man River" - he just keeps rollin' along, regardless of
the
follies of man. The films set in the "turbulent century", and was it ever !
The film's two hours covers about 70 years, and there's a battle nearly
every five minutes. The large cast of characters, principally of one small
family, deal with the age-old problem of the young getting carried away
with
war and the older warning them how futile it all is. There are a number of
deaths which coincide closely with births, and the characters assume they
therefore know where the souls have reincarnated.The war-is-futile message is hammered home without subtlety and, despite
the
downtrodden gaining occasional triumphs, it's all very depressing. The only
character who has a good laugh is killed shortly afterwards, and partly for
that reason !The strange aspect of this film is that it is part-colourized. In many
frames, these are simply large splashes of colour laid-over, and they look
terrible and amateurish. Other frames have more minute and detailed
colorization, which is quite pleasant. But the film would have looked
better
if it had stuck to B&amp;W only.The four points I've awarded this film are mainly for the acting, which is
good to great throughout. The oval-faced beauty Hideko Takamine is very
watchable for the first half at least, but has far less to do than some of
her other roles. The actress (name unknown) who plays the pretend-madwoman
Tatsu is a standout.But it takes more than good acting to make a good pic. I cannot recommend
this pic.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0642841/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>sharptongue</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>