<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Der schweigende Stern</original_title><alt_title>L'étoile du silence</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>East Germany</country><country>Poland</country><director>Kurt Maetzig</director><producer>Deutsche Film (DEFA)</producer><producer>VEB DEFA-Studio für Spielfilme</producer><producer>Künstlerische Arbeitsgruppe ''Roter Kreis''</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
When an alien artifact discovered on Earth is found to have come from Venus, an international team of astronauts embarks to investigate its origins.
</synopsis><actor>Yoko Tani</actor><actor>Oldrich Lukes</actor><actor>Ignacy Machowski</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0018365/comments</url><from>from Savannah, GA</from><name>Bob-45</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

What's wrong with this picture?  This movie is neither highly regarded by
critics nor IMDB voters.  Yet, it contains some striking visuals;
thoughtful
comments on the "human" condition; an attractive, multiracial, coed
international cast (daring for the time); and a pretty good storyline, to
boot.Excavators at the site of the 1906 mystery explosion in Tunguska, Siberia,
discover evidence that the explosion was the destruction of an alien
spaceship. Evidence includes a "memory spool."  Scientist determine the
alien spaceship came from the planet Venus, and cryptographers and
linguists
begin to translate the memory spool.Before translation can be completed, an international crew is assembled
and
an enormous nuclear powered spaceship constructed (a stunningly beautiful
piece of matte work) for a flight to Venus.  The ship begins its voyage
before the on-board linguist makes a startling announcement.  The memory
spool contains plans for a Venusian invasion of earth!The ship lands on a eerie, vapor-cloaked Venus (Striking art direction;
just
how did they do those strange, microbe-like vapors?).  The crew discovers,
a
burned out, uninhabitable planet.  The Venusians, apparently attempting an
invasion to escape either overcrowding or an impending nuclear war,
have
destroyed themselves, leaving only the shadows of their disintegrated
bodies.
Further exploration discovers a strange, living amoeba-like organism and a
damaged, super-gravity beam weapon aimed toward earth.  Many members of
the
crew are lost, and the ship is eventually deflected back to earth by the
accidental discharge of the gravity beam.The movie IS choppy, without a doubt because the American distributor,
Crown
International, cut the film by over one half hour.  I'd certainly LOVE to
see the excised footage; however, since the film is East German,  I doubt
if
a complete print still exists.  Besides, we Americans are having
enough
trouble finding obscure fifties and sixties from ENGLISH-speaking
countries,
including our own.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3824745/comments</url><from>from Vulcan</from><name>mstomaso</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The amazing imaginative fiction author Stanislaw Lem wrote this
visually stunning East German space exploration film with a dated but
still thoughtful message. The Sets of Der Schweigende Stern are
detailed and beautiful - giving the film an amazingly alien feel. The
cinematography varies from excellent to mediocre, and the visual
effects are cleverly done - relying on actual props and set devices as
opposed to split screen and blue or green screen trick photography.
Lem's plot is poignant and well-paced, but, unfortunately, most of the
acting in this film is a bit difficult to watch. Finally, the overuse
of voice-over narration in the early part of the film detracts from its
otherwise good artistic and technical merit.The story begins with the discovery that, in 1908, an extraterrestrial
space vehicle crash landed on earth. An electronic recording from the
ship is recovered and linguists set about trying to decode its message.
An international team of scientists, astronauts and engineers who are
scheduled to undertake a manned flight to Mars are then diverted to
Venus to make contact with the Venusians. On the way, they decipher the
electronic "cosmic document" and learn that the Venusians were planning
to attack the earth using nuclear warheads. To venture further in the
plot would involve spoilers.This is a film full of mysteries, and a film of its time - near the
height if the cold war. A powerful point concerning the proliferation
of nuclear arms is well made in this film, though it is perhaps the
only truly predictable aspect of the plot. Lem's plot heavy brand of
highly imaginative science fiction is very dense reading and often
carries similar ethical messages, but rarely translates well into
visual media. This is a worthy effort, maintaining the slightly wild
and surreal feel of Lem's aesthetics and yet driving forward the film's
plot at an entertaining pace.Recommended for Lem fans, serious sci-fi film fans, and those
interested in the connection between film and the social history of
ideas. Unfortunately for Der Schweigende Stern, the average movie fan
won't be able to handle this one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0856095/comments</url><from>from Vienna, Austria</from><name>Mort-31</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

Recently shown at the Viennale Filmfestival, this movie (one of only five
East German sci-fi films) was spoken of rather than of a trashy museal
antique stuffed with communist ideology. I had thought it would be about the
quality of Plan 9 from Outer Space, so I was surprised to discover that
First Spaceship on Venus is not at all trashy! A lot of money seems to have
been invested in the design of the mysterious landscape on venus and the
spacecraft. The technical effects look highly professional!As regards ideology, one can't make out more than a slightly pathetic call
for peace in the world (which is perfectly agreeable, really) and a casual
remark on how well Soviet astronomy is developed. The crew of the spaceship,
though, includes an American and a Japanese as well, so it is openly
international.The moment the spacecraft starts, however, the science-fiction story stands
in the foreground. It was written by Stanislaw Lem and is therefore quite
interesting, shocking and full of suspense - another aspect I wouldn't have
expected to get in a film like that. Of course, the acting is stiff,
dialogues are reduced to a necessary minimum and the romantic element in the
plot is too weak to be convincing. Probably, the screenwriters have removed
most of the depth of Lem's original novel. Nevertheless, the whole film
manages to evoke Kubrickesque feelings at times (note that it was made
before 2001: A Space Odyssey!) and serves as an interesting historical
document but also as good sci-fi fun on a Sunday afternoon.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4997726/comments</url><from>from Wavy Wheat, Nebraska</from><name>lemon_magic</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Since this movie was covered fairly early on by the MST3000 crew (along
with "Rocketship XM" and "King Dinosaur"), my initial perception of
this movie was something on the lines of 'Ehhhh, pretty cheesy',
although it was clearly one of the better films they covered.
Undoubtedly I saw the chopped up 93 minute version, instead of the
longer, more coherent original version mentioned by other reviewers. However, I saw a standalone DVD edition on sale at a clearance store
and picked it up for a couple of bucks on some obscure impulse, and one
fine evening I gave it a spin. You know...in spite of the dated message and foreign cultural
references and the problematic dubbing and "Engrish" translations, "1st
Spaceship To Venus" does have a certain quality about it that I've come
to respect. There's a certain gravity and solemnity to the proceedings.
There's a certain wildness and inventiveness to the art direction and
the sound design. And while none of the actors here are going to win
any awards (or even by remembered by American audiences), if you pay
attention you will see humane, approachable performances (undercut by
poor dubbing) that make the film much more watchable than glib junk
like "Rocketship XM" or space flight oriented stuff out of the Roger
Corman sausage factory. When I first saw "1st Spaceship", I had the impression that it
definitely had an East European vibe to it, and the only Slavic
speculative fiction author I was familiar with was Stanislaw Lem (whose
best known work is probably "Solaris", although my favorite piece is
"Non Serviam"). Sure enough, this movie turns out to be based on a Lem
piece from decades back. Lem's dispassionate, Kabbalistic voice and
speech rhythms, and his gift for oddly moving plots and characters
somehow survived the adaptation to film and the tiny budget and the
"Engrish" translation, leaving a dignity and substance to the
proceedings that many contemporary American sci fi flicks can't match. No, this will never be anyone's first choice for a space opera
shoot-em-up, but under the crappy dubbing and hacked-up editing, the
sympathetic eye can see that there is some good work being done here. A
good item to add to the collection of the sci fi completist and
archivist.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1229491/comments</url><from>from Fayetteville, GA</from><name>Bruce Cook (brucemcook@windstream.net)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
An artifact from the planet Venus is found buried on Earth, and
scientists learn that the object is the log of an alien spacecraft
which crashed. After attempts to contact the Venusian civilization are
unsuccessful, a multi-national (and multi-racial) flight to Earth's
sister planet is launched.When the expedition arrives on Venus they find a dead world whose
civilization has been destroyed by some kind catastrophe. The story
contains good ideas, but the plot seems to race along with no regard
for dramatic timing or narrative clarity, undoubtedly because of the
thirty minutes of footage which were removed from the American version.
The obvious dubbing is a major distraction, and the sound effects are
garish and unappealing. For some reason, there are very few shots of
the rocket traveling through space during the voyage. Generally
speaking, the special effects run hot and cold.The spaceship itself, however, is a beauty (both the interior and
exterior), rivaling the best rockets for the 1950s. The little robot is
memorable and well designed (it looks like a miniature tank).The exterior shots of the strange Venusian surface are imaginative,
with superimposed wisps of vapor constantly drifting past. Listen for
several segments of music borrowed from "Destination Moon" and "This
Island Earth".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0468724/comments</url><from>from VEGAS</from><name>jake-179 (jakeb610@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This movie suprised me.  I thought I was going to see a cheesy old science
fiction movie.  But this movie, for its time, is actually really good.  The
special effects are pretty impressive for a film this old, and I love the
design of the spaceship.  I have no idea what kind of budget this movie was
done on, but there are a lot of scenes in this movie that look BIG budget! 
The sets are very impressive, lavish and expansive.  And the enviornment of
Venus is detailed, spooky, and bizarre.  I didn't care for the little
plastic spiders, I thought that was distractingly goofy.  I was very
suprised to see such a forward thinking and racially diversified cast.  For
its time, such diversity was totally unheard of.  Its a little long and
slightly boring, but for good old fashioned sci fi, with cool alien
landscapes and bizarre spaceships, this is a must see.  Thats why I am
rating this movie fairly high, giving it an 8.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0643062/comments</url><from>from Virginia Beach</from><name>tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
In the late 50s Russia changed the world by launching Sputnik. This
really was a shock; modern readers may not appreciate it as of the
magnitude (in the US) of 9-11. In terms of national will, there was a
more universal mobilization and commitment of resources than after
9-11, that's for sure.Both the Russian and American space efforts were at root militarily
motivated, but wrapped in more glorious notions or exploration. And
both depended on "captured" Nazi scientists. At the time, East Germany
was considered the most oppressed of all the communist clients, and the
leaders there tried so very hard to establish itself as the center of
the communist world for technology (which is how Germans see science).East Germany as a region was cut out of the space program proper,
something they wanted to change. So huge government monies went into
this movie, including permissions to use Americanfilm stock and
technology.As it happens, this film proved enormously popular across the communist
world and did have a profound effect on the Soviet space program. See
my comments on "Planeta Bur" for that background.The avowed goal was to show Germany as the leader and catalyst of a
future international collaboration, peace led by a cleansed nation. So
look what we have: a rock from the Gobi desert, a meteor from Siberia,
a team mobilized for a trip — a team from all continents: American,
African, several Asians. And a story from someone widely considered the
father of modern science fiction, a sibling through Warsaw Pact.It really is true that large fortunes, on the order of a trillion
dollars, was swung in part by this film, money that could have
eliminated all hunger and disease everywhere for generations.But it has cinematic history as well. Was it the first one to open
moving through a starfield as 3D points of light (with titles that
recede ahead of us)? A totally fictitious effect that has become
necessary since. Otherwise audiences won't think it "real."The west already had "Forbidden Planet," of course, itself perhaps the
most influential science fiction film in the west. In a way, the travel
technology was incidental there and in fact the design of the rocket
was V2-like. Here, matters of the technology of travel are central.You have some shades of "Forbidden Planet:" a lost, powerful race. You
have some by now staples: lava flows and meteor showers (even in "Star
Wars"). There's an Orrery as a model of and control of the attack plan.
The black man is less racistly portrayed than Americans would have.
That's the point. But he still is the "don't worry, be happy"
personality in the group.They discover a geodesic dome on the planet. In the 60's this was an
architectural icon of modern architecture. Interestingly, there is a
wonderful sequence where the explorers come upon this thing and are
amazed by it. They are talking to the space ship — cut to the interior
of the space ship and what is the ceiling? Yup, a geodesic dome!Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3221986/comments</url><from>from Beltsville, Maryland</from><name>wdbasinger (wdbasinger@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
If I were going to list my favorite 10 science fiction films, this
would be one of them. It is too bad that the original German language
version is not available (as far as I know), but even though the
American release version has some missing footage, the remaining film
still is first-rate.The film features an international cast led by Japanese actress Yoko
Tani (good eye candy) and actors/actresses from Germany, Africa,
Russia, Czechoslovakia, and France. The special effects from the start
of the movie to its end are excellent. The effects as they explore the
surface of Venus are particularly eerie and thought-provoking. But,
best of all, are the philosophical speculations about the role of space
flight in the future of mankind. In addition, the film makes a stern
warning against the misuse of science and technology in the pursuit of
war and aggression and pleads with all men to apply advances in nuclear
and space technology to foster world peace.10/10 Dan BasingerP.S. One of the other critics stated that this was the first German
science fiction film since "Frau I'm Mond" (1929). This may be the
first space film from that country since 1929, but there were other
films from Germany that would be considered science fiction. One of
these was "Gold" (1934) that dealt with atomic power plants in the
transmutation of metals to gold. Some of the footage from "Gold"
appeared in the science fiction film "The Magnetic Monster" (1953).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0943351/comments</url><from>from West Hollywood, CA USA</from><name> (csdietrich@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

FIRST SPACESHIP ON VENUS (aka "The Silent Star") was a collaborative
effort
between film studios in East Germany and Poland and picked up by
Crown-International Pictures for a 1962 US release. Far ahead of its time
FSOV delivers the pacifist message in no uncertain terms. An international
crew lands on the planet Venus to discover that a war has completely
destroyed its inhabitants. Venusian landscapes are surrealistic and
wonderous to behold and the spaceship itself gets my vote as the coolest
cinematic craft of all time. The late Japanese/French actress and model
Yoko
Tani leads the cast and is fetching to look at and enjoy. Englewood
Entertainment once again has delivered a flawless print of this film and
is
available in VHS or on DVD and is letterboxed at proper aspect ratio. The
film is a bit slow even at its 78 minutes (originally it ran at 130
minutes!) This critic would love to see the uncut version someday.
Superior
sci-fi from the Eastern Bloc!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
First Spaceship to Venus is one of those movies that I seem to have
been aware of for what seems like forever. Yet, until the other night,
I had never actually seen the movie. I didn't know anything about it
and just assumed it was another of those goofy sci-fi films Hollywood
was so good at pumping out in the 50s. Well, I was wrong. The most
obvious fault in my thinking was the Hollywood part. First Spaceship to
Venus was made about as far from Southern California as you could get –
Poland and East Germany. Yeah, that's right – First Spaceship to Venus
is a commie sci-fi movie. And while the dialogue may be dubbed,
inappropriate music may have been added, and story elements changed to
fit American sensibilities of the time, a lot of director Kurt
Maetzig's vision gets through. There's a level of intelligence and
seriousness often missing from American sci-fi films of the period. I'm
certainly no astrophysicist (or any kind of physicist for that matter),
but a lot of what the scientists discuss and argue about at least
sounds "good". The special effects are certainly much better than the
cardboard cutouts found in similar American films. The special effects,
especially the Venutian landscape, really help to create a surreal
atmosphere for the film that's more than a little compelling. Finally,
though a little too "stoic" at times, the acting is quite good. The
characters are played with realism. While it may never match something
like Star Wars as an entertaining sci-fi film, First Spaceship to Venus
is at a minimum a nice little curiosity piece that actually provokes
some interesting questions about the role of technology in the world.For my first viewing, I actually watched the MST3K version of First
Spaceship to Venus. And while I'm an unabashed fan of the show, I feel
comfortable in my ability to separate the movie being presented from
the nonsense going on around it. And while I found First Spaceship to
Venus a real revelation, this episode of MST3K is one of the weakest
I've yet seen. The jokes are too inconsistent and lack any sort of
flow. And the running gag concerning Servo's non-stop sarcasm gets old
real quick. Overall, on my MST3K rating scale, I give this episode of
MST3K a 2/5 – find another episode to add to the top of your "to see"
list.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
First Spaceship to Venus is one of those movies that I seem to have
been aware of for what seems like forever. Yet, until the other night,
I had never actually seen the movie. I didn't know anything about it
and just assumed it was another of those goofy sci-fi films Hollywood
was so good at pumping out in the 50s. Well, I was wrong. The most
obvious fault in my thinking was the Hollywood part. First Spaceship to
Venus was made about as far from Southern California as you could get –
Poland and East Germany. Yeah, that's right – First Spaceship to Venus
is a commie sci-fi movie. And while the dialogue may be dubbed,
inappropriate music may have been added, and story elements changed to
fit American sensibilities of the time, a lot of director Kurt
Maetzig's vision gets through. There's a level of intelligence and
seriousness often missing from American sci-fi films of the period. I'm
certainly no astrophysicist (or any kind of physicist for that matter),
but a lot of what the scientists discuss and argue about at least
sounds "good". The special effects are certainly much better than the
cardboard cutouts found in similar American films. The special effects,
especially the Venutian landscape, really help to create a surreal
atmosphere for the film that's more than a little compelling. Finally,
though a little too "stoic" at times, the acting is quite good. The
characters are played with realism. While it may never match something
like Star Wars as an entertaining sci-fi film, First Spaceship to Venus
is at a minimum a nice little curiosity piece that actually provokes
some interesting questions about the role of technology in the world.For my first viewing, I actually watched the MST3K version of First
Spaceship to Venus. And while I'm an unabashed fan of the show, I feel
comfortable in my ability to separate the movie being presented from
the nonsense going on around it. And while I found First Spaceship to
Venus a real revelation, this episode of MST3K is one of the weakest
I've yet seen. The jokes are too inconsistent and lack any sort of
flow. And the running gag concerning Servo's non-stop sarcasm gets old
real quick. Overall, on my MST3K rating scale, I give this episode of
MST3K a 2/5 – find another episode to add to the top of your "to see"
list.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>http://www.dvdtalk.com/reviews/read.php?ID=22269 /m/first_spaceship_on_venus/comments.php?reviewid=1514106</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>DVDTalk.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Non-sensical dub-fest in which a bunch of dry international dolts head out to Venus -- slowly.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/The-Silent-Star /m/first_spaceship_on_venus/comments.php?reviewid=1423387</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Among DEFA's minor treasures, and with a Dr. Strangelove character as Henry Gibson might have played him.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/first_spaceship_on_venus/comments.php?reviewid=838427</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Strangely effective, rather depressing sci-fi flick,</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/first_spaceship_on_venus/comments.php?reviewid=1426299</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/22726_FIRST_SPACESHIP_ON_VENUS_DER_Schweigende_Stern.html /m/first_spaceship_on_venus/comments.php?reviewid=1236864</url><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>