<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Rat Race</original_title><alt_title>Les pièges de Broadway</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Robert Mulligan</director><producer>Perlsea Company</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Tender romantic comedy about an aspiring musician who arrives in New York in search of fame &amp; fortune...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Tony Curtis</actor><actor>Debbie Reynolds</actor><actor>Jack Oakie</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0105696/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>ivan beshkov (ivanbeshkov@msn.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I loved this movie about two struggling young people and the friendship
and
love that grows out of those struggles. You won't find any glamour in this
film, but it manages to be much more beautiful than many a movie oozing
pearls, silk and mahogany. All characters are interesting, likeable and
well-drawn. Rickles is fantastic as an uncouth, vulgar boss, the
personification of a soul destroyed. Everything is just right. As usual,
it
is small movies that reach the greatest heights. I once saw screenwriter
Kanin and his wife Ruth Gordon on "Donahue". I'm sorry I didn't take any
notes. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9090732/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gollytim</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I was 9 years old when I first saw this movie, which was probably too
young. I think it was the "B" movie accompanying "Bells Are Ringing"
with Judy Holliday. To me (at that age), the movie was very grim, but
mesmerizing. Main characters were extremely likable. You could not help
but feel badly for Pete Hammond and Peggy Brown who were good folks but
had to deal with such adversity. Watching the movie, one could not help
but feel so badly for them (Tony Curtis' character for being trusting
and having his musical instruments stolen, and Debbie Reynold's "hard"
character (with a heart) for sacrificing to help Tony's character out
and being abused by Don Rickles' character and his henchman.Norman Fell and Don Rickles were very effective as the "heavies". To
this day, I think of Don Rickles as "Nellie" in this film. I'm a
Rickles fan, but can't make myself like him (smile).Also love the NYC scenes, and film is almost nostalgic (NYC, the way it
was in 1960).Definitely a "must see". Great actors in their environment and in a
past era. I have a VHS tape, but will order a DVD as soon as I log off
:-) Tim
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
DEBBIE REYNOLDS and TONY CURTIS are excellent as two young people in
60's-era New York City facing adversity with street smart skills
developed after abuse from thugs like DON RICKLES (a savage
performance), and other so-called big shots.Curtis takes pity on Reynolds and invites her to share his flat--but
his luck fades when his musical instrument is stolen. True love
blossoms as Reynolds tries to help him with lots of obstacles thrown in
their way by assorted no-gooders.Garson Kanin directed from his play and he keeps the action moving and
the stylish backgrounds show New York City scenes that would make any
New Yorker nostalgic for "the way it was".A downbeat, sometimes bitter dose of comedy/drama that has so much
energy and such appealing performances from Reynolds and Curtis, that
you'll be drawn into it from the start. Well worthwhile.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Why the producers decided to cast New Yorker Tony Curtis in the film, I
just can't understand. Why would they cast him of all people
considering he is supposed to be playing a guy from Milwaukee who gets
lost in the big bad city of New York? With his very strong New York
accent, it just didn't make sense. Listening to him, he sounded like he
should have been perfectly at home in the Bronx or Brooklyn!
Fortunately, the rest of the movie is so good that I really didn't mind
the odd casting. In fact, Tony Curtis and Debbie Reynolds were
excellent in the film--with acting and dialog that seemed pretty
realistic. They both play "starving artists" who come to New York but
find success is somehow always out of sight. I teach at an art school
and would like to show this to my students so they can, perhaps, see
what it usually is like on the slow road to making a living.I also appreciated how the writers didn't allow the film to slide too
far into sentimentality even though this was a romantic-comedy of
sorts. That means when there can be a magical scene where things all
work out perfectly, the writers chose instead to allow for a more
realistic moment where things worked out,...somewhat. My favorite
example was near the end when it appeared that Curtis' musical
instruments unexpectedly re-appeared. This LOOKS like a "happily ever
after moment" but there is a great twist--a twist that reminds us that
in this film, just like in real life, Murphy's Law so often applies. To
me, the real magic in the film is how despite all these setbacks and
problems, the couple STILL manage to find each other and some shred of
happiness. And, if you think about it, this is a great lesson for
everyone.A nice, romantic, funny but occasionally sad and cynical little film
about life and little people.By the way, look for Don Rickles in one of his earliest roles. He plays
a guy who is amazingly creepy and cruel--quite a change from his later
comedic roles. Also, the sweet guy behind the bar is Jack Oakie in one
of his later roles
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1921398/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>sensha</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I am surprised at the reviews thus far posted, as they miss one of the
major novelties of this movie. While Tony Curtis is never going to win
any awards for his musicianship, the little "group" that he tries to
join contains some pretty impressive "ringers", especially for a movie
that isn't all that much about the musical side of things.Any group that contains the likes of Gerry Mulligan AND Sam Butera is
going to raise more than a few musical eyebrows. As mentioned above,
the music used in the film is nothing to get too worked up about, but
these two icons (plus the other sidemen that surround them) are reason
enough to consider this one "special".A musical note or two about Curtis is in order here as well. He also
played a tenor saxophone player in the iconic Some Like It Hot. While
his autobiography is silent as to his actual saxophone playing skills,
some of the fingerings that he used in that film were right for the
music being played (although out of sync with the actual film sound
track). It is mentioned that he has some flute playing skills in the
biography, so his being a sax player is not out of the realm of
possibility.The horns that he is seen playing in this movie all appear to be Selmer
instruments. When his horns get "lifted" by the boys in the band,
Debbie Reynolds goes to bat for him and buys him a set of horns "to get
by" on his cruise ship gig. However, the instruments purchased are
Leblanc horns, recognizable by the distinctive tweed covered cases in
which they came. But, when he is seen performing on the ship, he is
again playing Selmer instruments. Since this was well before product
placement in movies became common, it may be that he was playing his
own horns and the Leblanc cases were used for their visual appeal.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
In watching The Rat Race today, I was struck by the fact that this film
did not lead to any more parts like the one she played here for Debbie
Reynolds. She was quite a revelation as the girl who's been around the
block a few times and just struggling to stay alive in that meat
grinder called New York.By the time The Rat Race came out, Tony Curtis was already being taken
quite seriously as an actor with The Sweet Smell Of Success and The
Defiant Ones behind him. But Reynolds was America's sweetheart, still
basking in the sympathy of the American public when Elizabeth Taylor
stole husband Eddie Fisher. She played good girl roles almost
exclusively, but here she takes on a part that you would have more
readily cast Elizabeth Taylor.Curtis is from the Midwest and an aspiring jazz musician who comes to
New York, but gets quickly victimized by a cruel city. Reynolds is a
woman who is an aspiring model who does what she has to in order to
survive. But that's coming to an end as landlady Kay Medford wants her
money and thug Don Rickles who she's into wants something else and
quick. The two of them decide to move in together without benefit of clergy,
something that was still quite daring with the Code firmly in place.
It's strictly economic at first, but you know these two people living
one step from the gutter would fall for each other.The film was based on a play that Garson Kanin wrote and ran 84
performances in the 1949-50 season on Broadway. It starred Betty Field
and Barry Nelson on stage and repeating his role from the original cast
as a musician con man is jazz great Joe Bushkin. Besides Reynolds the performance to really watch out for is Don Rickles
as murderous hood Nellie. For those of you who think of Rickles as
insult comedian to the stars, his performance will knock your socks
off. He far more than Debbie was the real surprise here. Jack Oakie has
one of his last roles as a philosophical bartender, serving drinks in
the downstairs of Kay Medford's boarding house.I have a sneaking suspicion that Debbie Reynolds might have taken this
part to prove she had every bit the acting chops Elizabeth Taylor did.
She certainly proved it to me and The Rat Race ranks as one of the best
performances by either of the two stars.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Midwestern saxophonist Tony Curtis (as Pete Hammond Jr.) arrives in New
York City, seeking fame and fortune. Instead, he finds himself lost in
"The Rat Race". Mr. Curtis quickly meets disillusioned Debbie Reynolds
(as Peggy Brown). Ms. Reynolds works as a paid dancing partner, for
sailors and other lonely men. The two decide to pool their resources by
sharing an apartment, agreeing to a platonic living arrangement. The
roommates frequent the local watering hole, and hear older, wiser owner
Jackie Oakie (as Mac) and landlady Kay Medford (as Soda) dispense words
of wisdom. Curtis loses his musical instruments. Then, Reynolds loses
her job. Will Curtis and Reynolds gain romance? Robert Mulligan's version of Garson Kanin's play, which starred Barry
Nelson and Betty Field, never really takes off. Curtis and Reynolds
(and the film, generally) look way too sharp to be Mr. Kanin's
desolation row denizens, clawing their way to the top. Don Rickles is a
highlight, as Reynolds' brutal, sadistic boss. Norman Fell is amusing,
as the telephone man. Reynolds is unexpectedly glamorous, almost more
suited for the lead in "Butterfield 8"; and, she looks especially sexy
undressing for the lecherous Mr. Rickles. ***** The Rat Race (7/10/60) Robert Mulligan ~ Tony Curtis, Debbie
Reynolds, Don Rickles
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Not quite innocent,but not really guilty either;that's Miss Debbie
Reynolds in "The Rat Race".Many men are susceptible to a woman with a
slightly bruised aspect to her and Mr Tony Curtis is no exception. It's
a movie where "10 cents a dance" meets "Scrapple from The Apple" as
cool jazz man Curtis shares an apartment with broke and weary taxi
dancer Reynolds who has unwisely accepted a large loan from her boss Mr
Don Rickles who is keen on her repaying him in the traditional showbiz
manner. Daring for its time in its acceptance of the ambivalence of the
character played brilliantly by Miss Reynolds,the movie gives a fairly
bleak view of New York nearly fifty years ago,an era we are frequently
led to believe nowadays was a golden one indeed.Clearly not if you were
struggling in the lower stratum of the entertainment profession. Garson
Kanin's play was 20 years ahead of its time.Less bleak than its
contemporary "The Connection",but quite shocking for mainstream
audiences with its portrayal of the bottom feeders of show business,the
bullies,the pimps,gangsters and the compromises decent young people
were forced to make to follow their chosen paths.Not to mention an
unmarried couple living together. There is some fairly belicose Elmer
Bernstein music diffused by an extract of typical late 1950s West Coast
cool and Mr Curtis is very convincing as the aspirant jazzer with
integrity (i.e.no money) Sedate by today's standards,"The Rat Race"
marked a transition from 1950s movies to 1960s movies in content and
tone.Not until "New York,New York" was there a more impressive
portrayal of an average saxophone player and his showbiz lady,and my
goodness how the movies - and the world - had changed by then.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Tony Curtis, (Pete Hammond Jr.) plays the role as a musician who plays
a saxophone, clarinet and flute and he leaves Milwaukee, Wisconsin and
heads to New York City to start out on his career. Pete has a hard time
trying to find a cheap place to live and winds up sharing an apartment
with a girl named Peggy Brown, (Debbie Reynolds) who is a dancer and
singer and has lived in New York for a few years and is having a hard
time trying to find a job doing what she likes. Peggy does work in a
dance hall where men buy tickets for every dance and the establishment
is owned by Don Rickles who is a very shady character who has a great
interest in Peggy and has loaned her $600.00 and begins to want her to
repay him in more ways than one. This is a great film because Tony
Curtis, Debbie Reynolds and Don Rickles played very dramatic roles and
they all gave outstanding performances. Veteran actor Jack Oakie, (Mac,
Owner of Macs Bar) gave a great supporting role and also some comedy.
If you have not seen this film, you are missing a great 1960 Classic,
so keep an eye out for this film on TV. Enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0487225/comments</url><from>from Seattle WA USA</from><name>j_eyon-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
if you're thinking of Tony Curtis and Debbie Reynolds with their
Hollywood glamor - you're in for quite a surprise - this is grittier
stuff than they usually did - altho - not guttery or depressing - as it
would be in todays milieutry to overlook the residue of Tonys Bronx accent - and enjoy his eager
Midwestern saxophonist arriving in the jazz musicians mecca - Noo Yook
Cityexcept he's not in a typical Hollywood success story - here the
emphasis is on disillusionment - and its actually risqué for its time -
with Tony and struggling dancer Debbie Reynolds sharing an apartment -
both actors are very good - Debbie could have used more such rolesthe script is too talky perhaps - too much like a stage play - the most
memorable thing for me beside the stars is the music - especially the
throbbing theme song played over the opening scenes of Tony's cross
country bus ride - from the plains of the Midwest - to smog shrouded
NYCand i can still hear in my mind the driving version of THAT OLD BLACK
MAGIC played with real life saxophonists Sam Butera and Jerry Mulligan
- and Joe Buskin at the keys - that scene demonstrates how convincing
Curtis was at faking playing a saxophone - notice his red face while
playing the large baritone sax - when i was in the school band - i
could barely get a sound out of one of them
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0487225/comments</url><from>from Seattle WA USA</from><name>j_eyon-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
if you're thinking of Tony Curtis and Debbie Reynolds with their
Hollywood glamor - you're in for quite a surprise - this is grittier
stuff than they usually did - altho - not guttery or depressing - as it
would be in todays milieutry to overlook the residue of Tonys Bronx accent - and enjoy his eager
Midwestern saxophonist arriving in the jazz musicians mecca - Noo Yook
Cityexcept he's not in a typical Hollywood success story - here the
emphasis is on disillusionment - and its actually risqué for its time -
with Tony and struggling dancer Debbie Reynolds sharing an apartment -
both actors are very good - Debbie could have used more such rolesthe script is too talky perhaps - too much like a stage play - the most
memorable thing for me beside the stars is the music - especially the
throbbing theme song played over the opening scenes of Tony's cross
country bus ride - from the plains of the Midwest - to smog shrouded
NYCand i can still hear in my mind the driving version of THAT OLD BLACK
MAGIC played with real life saxophonists Sam Butera and Jerry Mulligan
- and Joe Buskin at the keys - that scene demonstrates how convincing
Curtis was at faking playing a saxophone - notice his red face while
playing the large baritone sax - when i was in the school band - i
could barely get a sound out of one of them
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0487225/comments</url><from>from Seattle WA USA</from><name>j_eyon-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>