<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Die 1000 Augen des Dr. Mabuse</original_title><alt_title>Le diabolique docteur Mabuse</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><country>West Germany</country><director>Fritz Lang</director><producer>CEI Incom</producer><producer>Central Cinema Company Film (CCC)</producer><producer>Critérion Film</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
Wiesbaden. La polizia criminale è in allarme per una serie di delitti misteriosi che hanno come punto in comune l'albergo Luxor...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Dawn Addams</actor><actor>Peter van Eyck</actor><actor>Wolfgang Preiss</actor><rt_rating>6.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>86</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0603620/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Guy_T</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

You don't necessarily need to have seen Lang's earlier Mabuse films to be
able to love this one.  Like in his silent spy film 'Spione', Lang creates
everything that would go on to be a genre cliche - but they all had to be
original once.  Here we have the stolen prototype weapon - a gun that
fires
needle shaped bullets that travel through glass and leave very little
trace
of assassination; and then there's the villain's car, with its revolving
number-plates.  Lang was certainly a few quick steps ahead of the makers
of
the Bond films, and certainly on a level with Hitchcock, Powell et al when
it came to commenting on voyeurism.The plot's labyrinthine, of course, but it rattles along at such a pace
and
with such striking visuals that you hardly have time or the inclination to
stop and worry - and it all comes clear at the end, with one or two
fantastic revelations in addition to the few you expect.If one part doesn't quite please as much as you like, it's the context it
fails to reference properly.  Made at such a crucial time in History by a
man who had seen so much, one only wishes it had more commentary to make.
Lang's career swung like a pendulum between social commentary and serial
escapades - if only he'd been able to pull the two together for his final
film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4756360/comments</url><from>from San Rafael, CA</from><name>El_Rey_De_Movies</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The last film that Lang directed, this was to be his triumphant return
to Germany after having fled the Nazis in the late 1930's.
Unfortunately, it was brutally cut and re-edited when it was released
here, so it never gained the popularity and acclaim that it deserved.
It's the story of an American businessman in Berlin who is drawn into a
secretive world of conspiracies, spies, and murder. Everyone in this
movie is lying to him, with the single exception of the police
inspector, played by a pre-"Goldfinger" Gert Frobe. But it's also the
movie that effectively laid down the basic rules of the modern spy
thriller: the handsome and well-dressed leading man who is equally at
home with a gun, a girl, or a drink in his hand, the megalomaniacal and
shadowy villain with plans for world domination, the gadgetry and
surveillance, the hidden lair, etc. Don't be put off by the fact that
it's a foreign, black and white movie – this is an exciting story told
by a master director who has been unforgivably forgotten.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0199855/comments</url><from>from Saint Clair, Pennsylvania</from><name>Rich Meyer (muzik@ptd.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This is a great little whodunit and an excellent start to the revival of
Fritz Lang's great Dr. Mabuse series.  It is very reminiscent of the earlier
films in the twenties and thirties, particularly Le Testament Du Dr. Mabuse,
from which Lang lifts and modernizes many situations.I said don't read the credits in the title to this review because guessing
who is actually the mastermind Mabuse is half of the fun...there are a lot
of red herrings that don't play out until the last fifteen minutes of the
movie.This was the first movie in the new Mabuse series and I would recommend
anyone delving into the world of Dr. Mabuse use this as a starting point
(especially if none of the silents or early talkies are available in your
area).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239678/comments</url><from>from Bangor ME</from><name>James A. Phillips (unclejappy@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is a 16mm print which I acquired in a batch of films. It is very
well dubbed in English. I assume the film is available on video. This film
reminds me of the serials of the 1930's. Fritz Lang ended his career with
this swansong, a return to a theme of his earlier Dr. Mabuse films. The
master criminal's henchmen have never seen his face, and get their commands
by radio while cruising in a van.
Note the scene in the police commissioner's office. Everyone is smoking
furiously and the room soon becomes filled with smoke. There is an almost
identical scene to this in "M".
Overall and very amusing and enjoyable film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The 1,000 Eyes of Dr. Mabuse represents my first venture into the world
of Dr. Mabuse. Pigeon-holing this movie into a single genre is
difficult. It's one part traditional krimi, one part spy movie, and one
part thriller. Combined, these elements create, at least for me, a one
of a kind experience that I really can't compare with much of anything
I've seen before. I refuse to give the normal plot synopsis. Any plot
details or other information would ruin the many twists and surprises
found in The 1,000 Eyes of Dr. Mabuse. Fortunately for me, I went into
the movie completely blind, knowing very little of what to expect. I
would suggest not even looking over the IMDb page as vital information
is presented on Mabuse's identity. The acting is good from a cast that,
even if I didn't know all of the names, I recognized from years of
watching WWII movies. Actors like Gert Forbe, Werner Peters, and Peter
van Eyck give sold performances. Fritz Lang's direction is as competent
as ever. The 1,000 Eyes of Dr. Mabuse has style to burn. Considering
the movie was made more than 45 years ago, it still feels remarkably
fresh. The mystery of who Dr. Mabuse is and what his fiendish plan is
all about are wonderfully compelling and really pull you into the
movie. The jazzy score is impossible to get out of your mind and fits
well within the film. In short, it's movie like this that keeps me
excited about exploring "new" cinema. If all of my first time viewings
could be this entertaining, I would be very happy indeed.If The 1,000 Eyes of Dr. Mabuse has one weakness, it's the slow pace of
the second act. The pace grinds to a crawl as the police begin their
investigation into the events taking place. While it's fairly
interesting and Gert Forbe is a good enough actor, there's not enough
action in this portion of the film when compared with what came before
and what comes afterward. A little more pep in the middle third of the
film would have made it a real winner with me. It's a minor issue I
have with the film, but it's an issue nonetheless.As I wrote previously, The 1,000 Eyes of Dr. Mabuse is the first Mabuse
movie I've seen. After my wonderful experience with the movie, it won't
be the last.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0804658/comments</url><from>from Marburg</from><name> (amikus2000)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Returning to germany Lang let influence his Hollywood experiences in this
german thriller. The criminal genius Dr. Mabuse (Wolfgang Preiss in his
genious acting; afterwards his career was in international war- and
anti-war movies as a german General) plays tricky with society and police.
Detective Gert Fröbe plays good, some say Preiss plays better, decide for
your own.
This tentious thriller explores, that by little action big disport can be
formed, imagine Lang would have made Face Off (1998) !
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1416505/comments</url><from>from Groningen, The Netherlands</from><name>Boba_Fett1138</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Of course this isn't the most classic or best Fritz Lang movie but it
nevertheless is a more than worthy last one by him. It's not that he
died shortly afterward (he lived till 1976) but he lost his eye sight
and by 1964 he was already nearly blind. It feels right that he ended
his directing career with a Dr. Mabuse movie. His previous 2 directed
Dr. Mabuse movies, "Dr. Mabuse, der Spieler - Ein Bild der Zeit" and
"Das Testament des Dr. Mabuse" are among his best and also best known
works. He obviously had some real passion and respect for the character
of Dr. Mabuse. Why else would he had made 3 movies involving the
character, over the course of 4 decades. The character is of course
also a real intriguing ones. He was one of the first real movie villain
in the 1922 movie "Dr. Mabuse, der Spieler - Ein Bild der Zeit". A
character that manipulates, influences peoples will, all for his own
benefits, with the help of hypnotic and supernatural powers.Just like 7 of the 8 Dr. Mabuse movies made, this movie is shot in
atmospheric black &amp; white. Fritz Lang made a few color movies late in
his career but for this movie he went back to his beloved black &amp;
white. No doubt he did this on intentions to let this movie connect
more and better to the previous 2 Dr. Mabuse movie, made before this
one. After all, the last Dr. Mabuse made before this one dates back
from 1933.Even though this movie is made 27 years later, it's still a direct
sequel to to "Das Testament des Dr. Mabuse". It makes lots of
references to the events which occurred in that movie. However if you
haven't seen the previous 2 movies, I think you'll also still have a
good time watching this movie and understand the events in it. The visual style and style of film-making is also mostly the same when
compared to the 1933 movie. A style Fritz Lang was of course very
experienced in, being one of the best directors of the '20's and '30's.
Nevertheless the movie is still set in its 'present' day 1960. It makes
this a '60's movie in '30's style, which also provides the movie with a
few clumsiness's and at times makes this movie feel, sound and look way
more outdated. It therefor can be argued if this was the right
approach. No doubt it is also part of the reason why this movie isn't
as well known and appreciated as the previous two Dr. Mabuse movies
from 1933 and 1922.The cinematography within this movie is especially great and helps to
give the movie its own unique atmosphere and old fashioned feeling
style.Gert Fröbe was really excellent in this movie. He proofs himself once
more to be one of the best German actors that ever lived. Ir's fun that
many actor appearing in this movie also appeared in the later Dr.
Mabuse sequels, often in completely different roles, including Gert
Fröbe.It's sort of too bad that the whole movie doesn't have the pace and
excitement of the movie its first halve. There is more talking than
real thriller or suspense moments in the second part. Still the whole
mysterious atmosphere and question; 'Who is Dr. Mabuse?', remains
present throughout the entire movie. The movie also ends with a real
blast and gets surprisingly action filled toward its ending.Yet another real recommendable Dr. Mabuse movie!8/10http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0374584/comments</url><from>from Cullman Alabama</from><name>evilskip</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

What a swan song this is! Wild and wooly fun from Fritz Lang. Dr Mabuse is
running his criminal empire from the Hotel Luxor.
His henchmen never see his face as they receive their orders via
radio.Without giving too much away his plans involve the takeover of a rich
man's empire and general blackmail and murder.Gert Frobe plays the inspector
out to nab Mabuse before Mabuse kills him.Funniest scene takes place in the
Inspector's office when everybody starts to fall before a bomb goes
off!
After watching 5 Mabuse movies in a row this is easily the best.It is
available from Sinister Cinema.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3836774/comments</url><from>from Olliergues, France</from><name>Dr Jacques COULARDEAU</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
It is interesting to discover or rediscover Fritz Lang. He was well
known for one film, Metropolis, and then for a few American films,
films he shot in the USA. But the full set of Dr Mabuse's films is
fascinating in a way because it provides a rare vision on the German
cinema from the early 1920s to 1960. The eye looking at the world from
a German point of view that spans over Hitler, Nazism and the Second
World War is Fritz Lang's. We know him for his highly symbolical
Metropolis in which the meaning is built by visual and numerical
symbols. In this Dr Mabuse it is different. There are quite a lot of
symbols but inherited from the silent cinema of the old days, symbols
that are there only to make clear a situation that had been depicted
previously with pictures and no words, or a page of intertitles. Fritz
Lang still uses that technique in his 1960 film, which is a long time
overdue for a silent cinema technique. But that is a style, nothing but
a way of speaking, not a meaning. The meaning is absolutely bizarre. Dr
Mabuse is a highly criminal person but his objective is not to commit
crimes in order to get richer or whatever. It is to control the world
through his criminal activity. The world is seen as basically negative,
leading to chaos and overexploitation, leading to anarchistic crime and
nothing else because the only objective of this modern world is to make
a profit by all means available. Dr Mabuse is a master mind of his time
and for him crime is the only way to destroy that capitalistic world
that he never calls capitalistic or Kapitalismus and to replace it with
pure chaos that should be able to bring a regeneration, a rejuvenating
epiphany, a re-founding experience. We find in his mind what we could
find in some of the most important criminal minds in this world, like
Carlos in France, or Charles Manson in the USA, or those sects that
practice mass suicide in order to liberate the suicidees and to warn
the world about the coming apocalypse. It is the mind and thinking of
those who practice war as a revolutionary activity with a
fundamentalist vision of their religions or politics and the world that
is supposed to reflect that religion. They do not want to build a
different society and when they are in power they are constantly aiming
at antagonizing their own population and the world because they cannot
exist if they do not feel some opposition that they can negate, bring
down, crush, like in Iran, or in Germany with Hitler, though later on
it was not much different under the Communists in East Germany. These
visions need opposition to exist and they provoke that opposition by
aiming at taking the control of the world with violence and imposing
their control with more violence. That's Dr Mabuse, the main brain of a
criminal decomposition and re-composition of society on an absolutely
antagonistic vision of life. But that vision is very common. Just as
common as this phrase "a half full glass is nothing but a half empty
glass". Add antagonism to that dual vision and then you have a struggle
to the death between the half empty glass that wants to be full and the
half full glass that wants to be empty (or full?), one half only
wanting to take what the other half has and impose his half to the
other half to make the world one by the elimination of the other side
of the coin. That dual antagonistic vision is the popular and
shrivelled up approach of the communist catechism of Stalin, inherited
from Marx's French son in law Paul Lafargue, or of course in all
dictatorship that reduces life to a little red book, to one hundred
quotations from the master thinker of the revolution. That's the world
you feel in these films. Fritz Lang embodies this ideology of the
mentally poor in that criminal character of his: kill, rob, steal,
counterfeit. Even if you die when doing so, the world will change and
remember. The master criminal has to die in his activity in order to
regenerate the world. What Fritz Lang introduced in his double main
feature of the early 1920s and in his Testament, is that the master
brain of this vision internalizes this paranoid and psychotic vision of
the world into himself and has to become psychotic himself and it is in
his psychosis that he finds the energy to conquer the world again. In
the third film, Dr Mabuse has been dead for a long time and is
reincarnated by someone who finds his inspiration in the doctor. That
is a far-fetched cinematographic and fictional antic that is necessary
as a reference but brings nothing to the vision itself. A few years
later that ideology was to conquer our imagination in many ways. First
the Berlin Wall became the symbol of that vision the way it was carried
and conveyed to the world by the East-German communists. Then we have
to think of the various revolutionary movements like Der Baader Meinhof
Komplex, Die Rote Armee Fraktion, to take some German examples. But
think of the French Mesrine and the Italian revolutionary urban
guerilla warfare movements and you will have a fair picture of this
psychotic criminal mind copied and pasted into the political field. The
Maoist Red Guard and Cultural Revolution movement was quite typical of
this approach. All that was going to come in 1960 and we must admit
Fritz Lang was seeing ahead of his time, just as he had seen Hitler in
his Testament of Dr Mabuse: a political leader based on hypnosis and
mesmerizing people into blindly following a band of criminals.Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University
Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Créteil, CEGID
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Eccentric characters are drawn to the Luxor Hotel where a panicked and
paranoid pretty lady (Addams) is attempting to kill herself to be rid of
her
fears forever.  Van Eyck saves her, falls in love, but also under the
influence of the nefarious "Dr. Mabuse".  He's the old "prophet" who the
police go to -- or is he?  No, he's the guy pretending to be Dr. Mabuse,
using secret cameras hidden around to Luxor to spy on its guests and set
up
a master plan! -- or is he?This one may sound cheezy, but it's all in good fun and with tongue in
cheeck, and a good final film for Lang.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Eccentric characters are drawn to the Luxor Hotel where a panicked and
paranoid pretty lady (Addams) is attempting to kill herself to be rid of
her
fears forever.  Van Eyck saves her, falls in love, but also under the
influence of the nefarious "Dr. Mabuse".  He's the old "prophet" who the
police go to -- or is he?  No, he's the guy pretending to be Dr. Mabuse,
using secret cameras hidden around to Luxor to spy on its guests and set
up
a master plan! -- or is he?This one may sound cheezy, but it's all in good fun and with tongue in
cheeck, and a good final film for Lang.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/t/1000EyesMabuse.html /m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=1880526</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Lang's late-period masterpiece</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/lang.htm#Eyes /m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=1661254</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Lang's look at the modern world.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/1000eyesofdrmabuse.htm /m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=1336508</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>It's a fun film and a fitting swan song for the legendary filmmaker who made his mark in both Germany and America.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/phil-hall/</url><url>http://www.wired.com/wired/archive/9.01/streetcred.html?pg=10 /m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=248797</url><name>Phil Hall</name><from>Wired</from></reviewer><comment>Fritz Lang's glorious sign-off.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=1418892</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-szymanski/</url><url>/m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=1172516</url><name>Michael Szymanski</name><from>Zap2it.com</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=747631</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/79313.html /m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=1480980</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.bostonphoenix.com/boston/movies/trailers/documents/02245282.htm /m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=739175</url><from>Boston Phoenix</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>/m/1000_eyes_of_dr_mabuse/comments.php?reviewid=237415</url><from>AV Club</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>