<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Warui yatsu hodo yoku nemuru</original_title><alt_title>Les salauds dorment en paix</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Akira Kurosawa</director><producer>Toho Company</producer><producer>Kurosawa Production Co.</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
A vengeful young man marries the daughter of a corrupt industrialist in order to seek justice for his father's suicide.
</synopsis><actor>Toshirô Mifune</actor><actor>Masayuki Mori</actor><actor>Kyôko Kagawa</actor><rt_rating>7.7/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0858615/comments</url><from>from Falls Church, Virginia</from><name>gvb0907</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Akira Kurosawa's "The Bad Sleep Well" is too dense and frankly too slow a
film to qualify as a thriller in the usual sense.  Although the elements
are
there - intrigue, double crosses, revenge, and crimes both naked and
invisible - the pacing is too deliberate and there is little real
suspense.Yes, it's "Hamlet," though in a subtle, understated, Japanese way.  Some
of
the characters are left out, but you'll eventually spot the Prince,
Horatio,
Ophelia, and Claudius.  However, unlike his "Macbeth" ("Throne of Blood"),
this is only a partial transposition and Kurosawa wisely does not carry
the
parallels too far.Although it takes patience, the picture has its rewards.  The performances
are good, especially Masayuki Mori as the reptilian manipulator Iwabuchi,
Kamatari Fujiwara as the hapless accountant Wada, and, as always, Takashi
Shimura as master bureaucrat Moriyama.  The sharp black-and-white
cinematography gives the film a photo-journal aura of authenticity.  And
Masaru Sato's wonderful opening theme, heavy with menace and unease,
certainly sets an appropriate  tone.Toshiro Mifune as Nishi/Hamlet is unusually restrained here, his normal
fire
largely internalized.  He's adequate, but this casting against type
doesn't
really suit him."The Bad Sleep Well" is Kurosawa's attack on Japan's post-war business
corruption that apparently was endemic by 1960 and perhaps still is today.
His critique is harsh and unsparing, though one can't help but get the
feeling that he's shooting at fish in a barrel.Beyond the corruption of the corporate scandal, which the film literally
headlines, is a strong sense of inner decay.   Nearly everyone, regardless
of their position, is uncomfortable.  Even Iwabuchi, for all his power,
must
answer awkwardly to greater, unseen forces.  Only the jackal-journalists
who
cover the opening wedding banquet seem immune to the pervasive uneasiness.Yet all, save Nishi, are prepared to accept this state of affairs in
return
for their security.  Ironically, Nishi himself seems most comfortable in
an
old air raid shelter in the ruins of a munitions plant, his own "castle",
as
it were, where he fights for honor as he understands it.Recommended for Kurosawa fans and anyone interested in Japanese psyche,
culture, or style.  Those expecting a slam-bang 1940s Warner Brothers
treatment will be extremely disappointed and probably won't last an hour.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0369164/comments</url><from>from Rock Forest, Quebec</from><name>Shawn Taber (filmbuffshawn@netscape.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

At the start of this film I didn't know what to expect. I thought it might
be a mediocre Kurosawa film. By the end of the film I realized it was one
of
his best. This film about familial discord and corporate manipulation is
breathtaking. Its filled with irony, double crosses, cynicism, manipulation
and revenge. In short, its endlessly interesting and captivating. Definitly
a must see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2837555/comments</url><from>from in the corrupt Public Corporation</from><name>vikramas1109</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
"The Bad Sleep Well" is a forgotten gem from one of Japan's great
masters, Akira Kurosawa. His other two Shakespeare adaptations, "Throne
of Blood" (Macbeth) and "Ran" (King Lear), are much more famous and
well-regarded, justifiably so if you have seen them ("Ran" is
particular is my favorite of all Kurosawa films). However, this sharp
and caustic adaptation of Hamlet deserves an equal amount of praise and
recognition. It may be the most bleak subject matter that Kurosawa ever
tackled - the corruption in the highest levels of government in
post-war Japan.The film begins with a long but funny wedding sequence that illustrates
Kurosawa's great skill as a director. We (and the camera) are among a
group of reporters discussing the numerous convenient reasons for the
marriage; the bride is lame and the daughter of Iwabuchi, the head of
corporation, and the bridegroom, Nishi, has aspirations to elevate his
status in the business. We see the comedy of manners play out in this
sequence in increasingly humorous situations as the various parties
deny the rumors and reporters continue comment to each other,
culminating in the panicked looks on the faces of the corporate
higher-ups as the wedding cake arrives - in the shape of their office
building, Public Corp., with a red X marking a spot in one of the
windows where one of their former partners committed suicide. It's a
virtuoso sequence that perfectly sets up the tone of the rest of the
film.The newspapers have a field day with this, especially when various
members of Public Corp. are investigated for fraud and embezzlement,
yet they stoically remain silent and the case goes nowhere. Then it
heats up again as a few of them commit suicide; the rumors are that
they were goaded into doing so (n fact, they were). However, without
any substance to press the matter, the case is dropped. And that's when
the real story begins - one of the Public Corp executives, Wada,
survives and is rescued by Nishi and his shadowy accomplice, Itakura.This is followed by a brilliant scene in which Wada is taken to his own
funeral and observes the farce - all the while, Nishi plays him a tape
with Moriyama and Shirai, his former partners, plotting his murder. The
way Kurosawa stages this is masterful; the sublime music emanating from
the funeral is contrasted dramatically with the cold-blooded words of
Public Corp, as Wada listens on. One of the ways Wada contributes is to
scare the living hell out of Shirai - Wada poses as a ghost of himself
in order to freak him out (a clever method of adding in the ghost in
Hamlet). As the plot progresses, Nishi reveals his reasons for saving
Wada and exacting a very personal revenge on Iwabuchi and his cohorts;
and the story's pace becomes more frantic and exciting with a dramatic
but sudden conclusion.Technically, Kurosawa is at his best here. The wedding and the funeral
are both marvels of observational behavior and they contrast each other
perfectly. He uses a lot of intriguing mise-en-scene compositions for
his interiors that serve to highlight his characters' inner thoughts
but very little movement of the camera in order to manipulate his
audience; the dark nature of the story is enough to suck you in. One of
the fascinating observations in "The Bad Sleep Well" is that nearly all
of the characters are morally bankrupt and filled with secrets - even
Nishi, the protagonist. His wife, the Ophelia character, is the only
one that Kurosawa allows us to feel sympathy for, and even then in the
end she is not fully spared her grief. Taken in this context,
Kurosawa's Hamlet becomes a study in the morality and pragmatism of
revenge but also an incisive jab at the fat cats in modern Japan.If there is a flaw in the film, it is that the overall pacing is not
always brisk enough to sustain the long running time (2 1/2 hours). The
wedding, despite being absolutely essential, is protracted; the rest of
the film is much quicker but still drags in parts. Also, Kurosawa seems
unsure about his ending; the film ends quite abruptly but appropriately
in terms of his larger point about the hopelessness of fighting the
rampant corruption, I would argue. However, despite these flaws,
overall "The Bad Sleep Well" is a masterful and dark excursion into the
seedy side of corporate crime, using Shakespeare Hamlet brilliantly but
not completely as it's core. Toshiro Mifune in particular gives one of
his most unique low-key performances; instead of his usual fiery
exterior we get a performance full of internalized anger throughout.
Highly recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
While the Seven Sumarai and Rashomon are wonderful Kurasawa flicks, too
few people are aware that he made other great films that are NOT
samurai films because they are rarely seen in the United States. Only
osscasionally, they are shown on Turner Classic Movies or other
channels and should not be missed.One of the best examples of this is this movie. The Bad Sleep Well is
extremely well-written and acted and keeps your attention from start
(the cake scene) to finish (the final showdown). I love how Kurasawa
does NOT follow the expected path in this and his other pictures.
Anyone wanting something DIFFERENT should give Kurasawa a try. In
addition, I would strongly recommend Kurasawa's Madadayo ("Not Yet") or
Shubun ("Scandal") as among his lesser-known flicks you MUST see. Among
his slightly more famous, try Throne of Blood (a GREAT remake of
MacBeth) or Yojimbo.FYI--this story is a slight re-working of Hamlet, though you might not
notice it unless you are looking.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3063013/comments</url><from>from Ruritania</from><name>Steffi_P</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
For his first film made by his own independent production company,
Kurosawa decided to take advantage of his new creative freedom to make
his most politically daring picture to date. He takes on the corruption
rife in corporate Japan in a film noir of almost epic proportions.This was Kurosawa's most stylised film so far. He takes a nasty, tragic
film noir plot-line (and yes, there are elements of Hamlet, but not
enough to call it an adaptation) but plays it at some times as if it
was a farcical comedy, and at others like it was a horror. The
villainous characters appear slightly ridiculous and even cartoonish.
Only the most senior amongst them, Iwabuchi, is allowed to keep his
dignity. While the others are just puffed-up minions, easily toppled,
Iwabuchi seems truly immovable.The establishing scenes are the film's strongest. It opens, like The
Godfather, with a lengthy wedding scene which serves to introduce all
the principle characters and set the tone. Everything about the way
this scene is put together tells us this is not the happy occasion it
should be – the hall where the ceremony takes place echoes
off-puttingly, a company official about to make a speech cringes as
champagne corks go off behind him like gun shots. Add to this an
interruption from the police, a gang of journalists and photographers
waiting in the wings, and a best man's speech that turns from jokes to
threats, and you can practically taste the corruption and decadence
that is the focus for this story.The wedding scene is followed by a montage of newspaper headlines and
newsreel footage, reminiscent of similar devices used by Frank Capra
and Raoul Walsh. Kurosawa brilliantly choreographs this sequence to
music, a rather eerie little dirge more typical of a Japanese period
piece than a modern thriller. It's the only example of this kind of
montage I know of in Kurosawa's work (it was rare for him to expand the
narrative to the bigger picture), but it's a highly effective one-off.The central plot, of Nishi (Toshiro Mifune) orchestrating spectacular
revenge against the men who killed his father, is full of amazing
set-pieces. There are echoes of Hitchcock in the way Kurosawa shoves
significant objects right up to the camera. The use of music is
dazzling, combining upbeat music with unnerving moments to give a great
sense of irony. Nishi is the last person the villains suspect, and he
often appears innocently in the background with little more
significance than an extra, although of course the audience knows
better. It's a nice touch that Kurosawa has the character wear glasses,
making Mifune almost unrecognisable to us as well.Sadly, the film's pace slows down after the first hour, and rarely gets
back to the same dizzying heights for the rest of its 145 minutes. The
lengthy runtime does however allow Kurosawa to add a depth that is
absent from your average 100-minute Hollywood Film Noir. Kurosawa could
be bleak, but he never forgot the humanity in his films, and this is
really the focus in the second half of the film. He takes time to put
the spotlight on the innocent victims of revenge (Nishi's wife, Wada's
family), and even show the arch-villain in moments of warmth and
tenderness with his family. And this is perhaps where the story's
biggest similarity with Hamlet is – Nishi's revenge falls apart because
he is unable to be totally ruthless and unfeeling.As for the acting, Masayuki Mori is particularly good as Iwabuchi. Just
look at his reaction when the second wedding cake pulls up behind him –
remaining calm, but clearly suppressing concern and annoyance. Kamatari
Fujiwara and Akira Nishimura give great over the top performances as
Wada and Shirai respectively. Unfortunately this is not one of Toshiro
Mifune's great performances. Mifune had an incredible range, but
somehow he doesn't quite work as Nishi. In particular, for me he
doesn't quite get the emoting right when he begins to realise his
feelings for his wife.Kurosawa always liked to be making some kind of point with all his
films, something which sometimes got in the way of decent storytelling.
The Bad Sleep Well is a political soapbox picture if ever there was
one, but luckily in this case that doesn't water it down quality-wise.
True, it is perhaps a little too long, and there are a few dull
stretches, but Kurosawa's direction was still at its peak and this
stands as one of his best contemporary-set pictures.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0276606/comments</url><from>from Skaville, UK</from><name>Hanichi</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

The Bad Sleep Well is a great film, with excellent acting from all the
actors, especially my favorite Japanese actor, Takashi Shimura as
Moriyama.
Kurosawa shows in this film that no one can or will ever top his skill at
doing tableau shots.  The wedding scene in the beginning of the film,
where
the reporters are standing just outside the doors of the reception hall,
commenting on the goings on within, is fantastic.  The ending seems very
abrupt, almost as if they ran out of time while making the film, keeping
this one out of the same league as other Kurosawa classics (7 Samurai,
Stray
Dog, Yojinbo).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5083384/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>M-Petri</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I just watched "The Bad Sleep Well," and finished reading the other
viewers comments. So I will comment on both. "Seven Samurai" is perhaps
my favorite film of all time, and I really like Kurasawa's work. Other
than the brief plot summary, I didn't really know what to expect from
"The Bad Sleep Well." The beginning can be somewhat confusing, as the
reporters throw out lots of Japanese names and the viewer must struggle
to understand what's going on and who is who. But as the film
progressed, I found myself drawn in and completely absorbed by it.
Don't worry if you don't get it at first, all will become clear. I
found this to be an excellent film, and I would recommend it to any
Kurasawa film. Sure, it's not action-packed like his samurai films. And
yes, it is somewhat slow in pace. But I must say that I didn't really
mind that. I found it quite engrossing. There are enough plot twists
and turns to keep the viewer interested. I din't think that Toshiro
Mifune did a bad job either, as some other viewers thought. He's not
wild and crazy like in "Seven Samurai" or "Rashomon" but I didn't think
he was badly cast. Sadly, I am not intimately familiar with "Hamlet,"
so I can't comment too much on the similarities. It seems to be the
general opinion that this "The Bad Sleep Well" is loosely based on
Hamlet, but I also agree that this won't detract from your enjoyment of
the film in any way, and that knowing "Hamlet" doesn't mean that you
will know what happens in this film. I agree with those who say that
this is another underrated Kurarsawa masterpiece, and well worth
seeing. Give it a chance!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12073191/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>RussyPelican</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The Bad Sleep Well is one of the best revenge movies of all time. It
stars the great Toshiro Mifune as a man seeking revenge against the
people who forced his father into committing suicide. Unlike many
revenge movies, The Bad Sleep Well doesn't glamorize its subject.
Instead it shows how in trying to get retribution for a man who is now
dead, Mifune ends up injuring himself and other people he loves who are
still alive. There are a lot of beautiful and haunting images, like
when we see a desperate man struggling to climb a volcano so he can
throw himself in, or a number of scenes that are shot at the bombed out
wreckage of an old WWII munitions plant. The bleak landscape mirrors
the damaged lives of the movie's characters. Powerful and haunting,
this is a movie that will follow you for days.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12355115/comments</url><from>from Varna, Bulgaria</from><name>maurazos</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I am watching Kurosawa's full collection and the more I watch, the more
I love the art of "The Emperor". And unlike many Kurosawa's fans, my
preferred films are those that talk about the time Kurosawa lived, not
about the samurai ages. Again, Kurosawa uses the literature classics
(for this film, Shakespeare's "Hamlet") as a source for his stories,
proving that the subjects they talked about are still modern. Anyway,
the genius of Kurosawa is quite big to make their film be not just a
cinema remake of those texts, but an original, exciting plot. And
again, Kurosawa gives us a film with a clear and worrying social
message, a denounce to a serious problem (company and state corruption
that even today still darkens the image of a "100% legal" Japan). A
film to enjoy and film to learn about Japanese society and life in a
general way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3715200/comments</url><from>from Paris</from><name>Marc Fairbrother</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I have just started watching Kurosawa's film-noirs, and this is the
second one I've seen so far. The first one I saw was Stray Dog which I
believe is slightly better paced than this one which gets a bit too
slow in some parts.The photography is simply magnificent, the depth and the contrasts
really bring the characters to life, Kurosawa's directing is at its
best with many great shots. The acting is also very good, especially
Toshiro Mifune, but not only him, the other characters, both the "bad"
and the "good" are very well portrayed.The plot is quite complex to understand at the beginning. The reporters
in the opening scene of the movie who comment the marriage act like a
classic theatrical chorus, it's quite confusing because they mention
many names and events. But as the story unfolds the pieces start to fit
together and everything starts to appear clearly until the revelation
of Nishi's true identity. From then on the movie turns into a
revenge-story. The ending is so shattering that all that's left to say
is "The Bad Sleep Well".I give this movie an 8/10 because I don't give 10's and as I said it's
slightly too slow at times. The best thing about the film is that it
simply DOES NOT compromise.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3715200/comments</url><from>from Paris</from><name>Marc Fairbrother</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I have just started watching Kurosawa's film-noirs, and this is the
second one I've seen so far. The first one I saw was Stray Dog which I
believe is slightly better paced than this one which gets a bit too
slow in some parts.The photography is simply magnificent, the depth and the contrasts
really bring the characters to life, Kurosawa's directing is at its
best with many great shots. The acting is also very good, especially
Toshiro Mifune, but not only him, the other characters, both the "bad"
and the "good" are very well portrayed.The plot is quite complex to understand at the beginning. The reporters
in the opening scene of the movie who comment the marriage act like a
classic theatrical chorus, it's quite confusing because they mention
many names and events. But as the story unfolds the pieces start to fit
together and everything starts to appear clearly until the revelation
of Nishi's true identity. From then on the movie turns into a
revenge-story. The ending is so shattering that all that's left to say
is "The Bad Sleep Well".I give this movie an 8/10 because I don't give 10's and as I said it's
slightly too slow at times. The best thing about the film is that it
simply DOES NOT compromise.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/louis-proyect/</url><url>http://louisproyect.wordpress.com/2010/04/27/stray-dog-the-bad-sleep-well/ /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1881647</url><name>Louis Proyect</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><comment>A powerful tale of a son seeking to avenge his father in a world of corporate malfeasance with Hamlet-like dimensions.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/armond-white/</url><url>http://www.nypress.com/article-20815-ak-201-kurosawa-to-the-rescue.html /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1865795</url><name>Armond White</name><from>New York Press</from></reviewer><comment>The Bad Sleep Well's ground-breaking concept shows Kurosawa's uncompromised ambition.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/douglas-pratt/</url><url>/m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1735903</url><name>Douglas Pratt</name><from>DVDLaser</from></reviewer><comment>t is almost an anti-thriller, but viewers who are willing to steep themselves in the intricacies of Japanese ceremonies and the banal details of evil will find the experience highly rewarding.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ed-park/</url><url>http://www.villagevoice.com/issues/0230/park2.php /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1735901</url><name>Ed Park</name><from>Village Voice</from></reviewer><comment>Opening with a bravura wedding sequence and ending with a sycophantic bow to a replaced telephone receiver, the film has its longueurs, but Mifune's buttoned-down avenger is a compelling portrait of righteous obsession foundering on unpredictable reality.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/bad-sleep/review/127809 /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1735900</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>One of Kurosawa's finest achievements.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/badsleepwell.htm /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1527331</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>There just seemed to be a missing ingredient to raise this intense psychological drama to the level of a Rashomon.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-kendrick/</url><url>http://www.qnetwork.com/?page=review&amp;id=1597 /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1491131</url><name>James Kendrick</name><from>Q Network Film Desk</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Despite having been made more than 45 years ago and in a postwar Japanese setting, in the age of Enron, it may be more relevant than ever.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tom-milne/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/67296/the_bad_sleep_well.html /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1474004</url><name>Tom Milne</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Kurosawa rather loaded the film on the side of social significance, while neglecting to capitalise on the noir aspects that underlie it. Even so, his use of the 'scope screen is masterly.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nick-schager/</url><url>http://www.slantmagazine.com/film/film_review.asp?ID=2010 /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1470371</url><name>Nick Schager</name><from>Slant Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>A freestyle homage to Hamlet that does away with the costumed faithfulness of Kurosawa's other Shakespeare adaptations.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/peter-canavese/</url><url>/m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1468268</url><name>Peter Canavese</name><from>Groucho Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>A startlingly relevant 'social problem film' (shakai-mono)--of its time and our own--and an existential melodrama by way of Hamlet.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9A05E6DA173CEF3BBC4B51DFB7668388679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1390385</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>This is a powerful and interesting picture that Kurosawa has made -- a bit tedious and mawkish in the last reels, but exciting enough along the way to satisfy audiences that know the subject.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fran-hortop/</url><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=110034 /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1291299</url><name>Fran Hortop</name><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>It's still as visually striking as anything you will see by this director.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/679_BAD_SLEEP_WELL.html /m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1552</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>A well-done thriller with Kurosawa's usual social overtones.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1411545</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=1189699</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/the-warui-yatsu-hodo-yoku-nemuru-the-bad-sleep-well/comments.php?reviewid=747294</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>