<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Tarzan the Magnificent</original_title><alt_title>Tarzan le magnifique</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Robert Day</director><producer>Solar Film Productions</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
Tarzan must escort his prisoner Coy Banton out of the jungle to the authorities. The boat is blown up by Coy's father and brothers...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Gordon Scott</actor><actor>Jock Mahoney</actor><actor>Betta St. John</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
In 1959, producer Sy Weintraub took the series... He decided he had to
get adults (particularly women), interested in Tarzan... So 'out' went
Jane and with her the safaris and the fighting of crocodiles...
Weintraub was convinced of the need of new ideas to improve Tarzan's
image... Tarzan becomes a good shooter and also articulate, speaking,
clearly and distinctly, in complete sentences, displaying few of the
primitive characteristics of the Weismuller version..."Tarzan the Magnificent" chronicles Tarzan's treacherous journey
through the jungle to the authorities with his prisoner, Coy Banton
(Jock Mahoney). They took off on foot when the river boat they were
going to take is blown up by Coy's father, Abel (John Carradine) and
brothers, Martin (Al Mulock), Johnny (Gary Cockrell), and Ethan (Ron
MacDonnell)... Five of the boat's passengers—Tate, a Black engineer
(Earl Cameron), Ames (Lionel Jeffries), his wife Fay (Betta St. John),
Conway (Charles Tingwell), and Laurie (Alexandra Stewart)—all had such
good reasons to go with Tarzan that he couldn't refuse... Thus impeded,
Tarzan set off the Bantons at his heels...As in "Tarzan's Greatest Adventure," Jane is left out and Tarzan had no
romantic involvement... Happily, Cheetah's role is all but eliminated
again...The most rare thing about "Tarzan the Magnificent," is the absence of
the Tarzan famous yell for the first time since sound movies...
Considering the widespread use of the ape-call for laughs—entertainment
as giving in variety shows, the producer acted wisely...Gordon Scott, probably one of the best screen Tarzan, reappeared in
Rome in a couple of Italian spectaculars, "Duel of the Titans," with
Steve Reeves, and "Samson and the 7 Miracles of the World." Many
others, like "Goliath and the Vampires," with Jack Sernas, followed...Becoming quite a sensation in Europe, he made a start on a second
acting career there and was last seen in an Italian Western, "The
Tramplers," with Joseph Cotten as the domineering father...Ironically, villain Jock Mahoney, would take over the lead role from
Scott as the 13th Tarzan in MGM's "Tarzan Goes to India," in 1962...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0382004/comments</url><from>from CARDIFF, WALES</from><name>ALAN MOUNT</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Strange that this movie has such a low rating and stranger still that
no-one
has yet commented on it. Suffice to say,it is the greatest of all Tarzan
movies and a slight rearrangement of the three word title would be an apt
description.Here we have an intelligent jungle thriller,well filmed,well
scripted and above all well acted.Jock Mahoney plays his best screen role
here as the villainous Coy Banton and his unsmiling grimness lent itself
far
better for this sort of portrayal than when he took over the role of the
apeman for the next two in the series.
As Tarzan,Gordon Scott is excellent and he should have stayed in the
role.Although he is not the best Tarzan of all(that honour fell to Ron Ely
in the superb 60's t.v.series)he comes a close second.This is an adult
move
with adult themes and relationships but still has enough action(some of it
brutal)to excite viewers of all ages.Tarzan afficionados would have you
believe that the best Tarzan movie ever made was another Scott thriller
called "TARZAN'S GREATEST ADVENTURE".It isn't;but this is.My best advice
is
watch it and enjoy,then vote and comment.A 4.9 vote does an excellent
movie
a great injustice.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7158952/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>hotknifethrubutter</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is 'real action, adventure' (the way it was meant to be) !!!
Gordon Scott WAS Tarzan (no one has approached his characterization of
this 'mythic figure'). Once again, we see an actor with 'a background'
(i.e. 'life experience'); bringing it to the big screen (see Steve
Mcqueen,Charles Bronson, Lee Marvin, etc...). No 'method acting' here -
just solid performance. A must see for action/adventure fan's !!! Mr.
Scott was a military policeman, judo expert, laborer; among other
things ! This sort of acting is fast disappearing (as more 'emotional'
actors/directors appear). Gordon Scott did not 'leave' this role - the
producers of this 'genre' felt a more 'kinder/gentler' (see
'civilized'), Tarzan was needed (oh, brother !!!). Mr. Scott went to
Europe to make 'sword and sandal' epics (Hercules, Machiste, Goliath,
etc..). What a pity he wasn't given more A-list roles. He was quite the
man !!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1361284/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro - Brazil</from><name>marciodecarvalho</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Along with 'Tarzan's Greatest Adventure', I rate this one as the best
Tarzan
movie of all times. Both of them are quite an improvement over the
black&amp;whites from the 30's and 40's (yes, Johnny Weissmuller was a hell of
a
Tarzan himself, no doubt, and did great movies, but times have changed
quite
a bit).
Tarzan is an adult character now, aiming adult audiences, in these last two
Gordon Scott's appearances. He is articulate, and as straight as he can be.
No Janes, no Boys, no funny chimps around. This is a bloody, violent, dark,
adult movie. This is a violent, dark new Tarzan.
I only regret this wonderful new bias - and the mighty, definitive,
impressive Tarzan Gordon Scott was - had no continuity.  Later on, we were
back to the tired lightweight Tarzans, oh-hum adventures, and here are our
good friends, the chimps, goofing around again.  Pity.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15845202/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mhrabovsky6912</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
After seeing "Tarzan's Greatest Adventure" in 1959 I thought Gordon
Scott had made the best Tarzan film ever.....one year later "Tarzan the
Magnificent" comes along and it is nearly as good, just a tad not as
good as TGA.....Scott, a bulging musclemen and very handsome makes a
great Tarzan, and the old cornshuck scripts and groans were taken out
of his vocabulary again and he is a thinking, intelligent ape man hell
bent on righting the wrongs of the notorious Banton gang....as in
"Tarzan's Greatest Adventure" Scott is after a gang of cuthroats and
killers again and wont settle the score until they are all captured or
killed. Producer Sy Weintraub assembled another top notch cast of
veterans like Jock Mahoney and John Carradine as superb villains and
some other newcomers too......a couple of nice looking women are again
in the mix ala TGA.......This time instead of doing the chasing of
villains as he did in TGA, Tarzan is chased and followed by the
murderous Banton gang, hell bent on getting back their brother (played
by Jock Mahoney) who has been captured by Tarzan and has Tarzan wanting
to give him to the authorities in a settlement a few miles away.
Problem is Tarzan must escort a group of mixed up civilians who do not
know the ways and treacheries of the jungle terrain. Tarzan is
constantly trying to stay ahead of the Banton gang and yet is slowed to
a crawl by his civilian misfits. Then Mahoney creates ultimate friction
by wooing and stealing one of the group's wife.....Tarzan has his hands
full at this point!! In the end Scott must fight the remainder of the
Banton gang and wipe them all out ala TGA.....in the end he delivers
Mahoney to the proper authorities and Scott returns to his jungle
realm. All in all this is another great Weintraub production of an
intelligent Tarzan and Scott rises to the role in superb fashion. He is
definitely the best Tarzan ever in my opinion. Very sadly this was
Scott's last Tarzan film and the thing that has perplexed me is why
Weintraub after the amazing success of TGA and T the Magnificent did
not want Scott to make more of these great Tarzan movies. Very sadly a
skinny, underweight Jock Mahoney became the next Tarzan and he is no
Scott......nowhere near as handsome either. Scott at this point joined
his good friend Steve Reeves and made a slew of the very popular sword
and sandal Hercules type films in Italy during most of the
60s......Scott finished up his film career with a good Italian western
"The Tramplers" made in 1966.....
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0704008/comments</url><from>from Ohio</from><name>observer8</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

For a Tarzan movie, this is about as good as you're going to get.  Gordon
Scott does an excellent job in this film, as he did in the previous
"Tarzan's Greatest Adventure".  Unlike previous Tarzan actors, Scott's
version of the Ape Man speaks good English and is quite intelligent.  The
story in "Tarzan the Magnificent" is well-written and mature.  Again, for
this type of genre, "Tarzan the Magnficicent" and "Tarzan's Greatest
Adventure" are as good as you're going to get.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3662960/comments</url><from>from syracuse</from><name>ewarn-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I'm writing this a few days after Gordon Scott's life has come to an
end, so this review is a tribute to his life and career , especially
his characterization as Tarzan, which many consider the best ever
brought to the screen. Gordon Scott had a great screen presence as well
as underrated acting abilities, and we really need more of his films
released on DVD."Tarzan the Magnificent" is his last Tarzan film, I think, and it was
released in 1960, right after "Tarzan's Greatest Adventure" which I
consider the best Tarzan film ever made. This film is not as good as
that one, though it comes close, therefore coming in as the second best
Tarzan film ever made. In any case, Gordon Scott again does a fantastic
job portraying the ape man. I think he was the only one who convinced
me that physically he could take on lions and crocodiles as well as
Sean Connery.The plot of this movie is basically the same as "Greatest Adventure."
Tarzan pursues and battles a gang of jungle crooks. (What the hell are
backwoods moonshiners doing in Africa anyway?) Here there is a
psychological angle as well as slam bang action. The location
photography is great too. The ending is a little too similar to the
last outing, but hard hitting just the same.Gordon, wherever you are, thanks for the great entertainment!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is probably the best of all Tarzan films to date, and the closest to
the original character created by Burroughs.  Grim, violent, and
threatening, it has Tarzan as the silent and determined hero, just reeking
with machsimo with no silly Jane and Cheetah antics.  This exciting
adventure also boasts one of the greatest on-screen fist-fights ever
filmed
(between Scott and Mahoney, himself a future Tarzan) rivaled only by the
one
between John Wayne and Randolph Scott in "The Spoilers".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4411832/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Ozirah54</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Other reviewers have ably discussed where this movie fits in within the
corpus of Tarzan movies and have pinpointed the epic fistfight battle
of Jock Mahoney and Gordon Scott.Before Scott's Tarzan character tangled with Mahoney as Coy Banton,
however, there is a scene where the youngest of the Banton family
attempts to take on Tarzan and defeat him.The Banton family is a bunch of robbers and killers and, as they follow
Tarzan who is conducting Coy Banton to the authorities, accompanied by
the survivors of a steamboat accident, there are opportunities to
attack this group and rescue Coy.Johnny, supposedly in his early twenties, played by then newcomer Gary
Cockrell, whose career seemingly fizzled out in the 1970s, is making a
daring attempt to go after this group without the support of his father
or older brother and perhaps molest one of the women.Johnny comes across one of the women and chases her to a pool or stream
some distance from the village where they have stopped. Johnny proceeds
to grope and attack her, when Tarzan shows up as a result of her
screams.At first, Johnny goes for his rifle and the two tussle. The rifle is
thrown away and Johnny, his shirt now in shreds, is pushed on to the
ground. He stands and goes for his knife. His muscular, lean, sinewy
chest is revealed and he seems a plausible opponent for Tarzan at the
moment. But the knife fight does not last for long. Johnny wants his
rifle, thinking only that will save him. When he at last spots and
holds it, the fight is maneuvered into the nearby water and the rifle's
barrel is now pointing under Johnny's chin. The rifle goes off in the
scuffle and Johnny is killed. He falls back, the shreds of his shirt
parted on each side so that his chest is fully revealed as he floats
upon the water.Tarzan smashes the rifle, for he knows that Johnny's death will invite
more trouble from the rest of the Banton gang. Johnny's youthful,
daring gamble has failed. The youngest of the Bantons is now dead.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
As the last "Tarzan" movie starring Gordon Scott for producer Sy
Weintraub, British director Robert Day's "Tarzan the Magnificent" with
Jock Mahoney and John Carradine qualifies as one of the better series
entries. Day helmed it after John Guillerman had made what is generally
regarded as the best Tarzan outing, "Tarzan's Great Adventure," which
co-starred a pre-James Bond Sean Connery. Later, Day called the shots
on "Tarzan's Three Challenges" (1963) with Jock Mahoney, and "Tarzan
and the Valley of Gold" (1966) as well as "Tarzan and the Great River"
(1967) both with former football player Mike Henry. In this off-beat,
unusual adventure, Tarzan tangles with bloodthirsty bank robbers who
display few qualms about cold-blooded homicide. You know that you're
watching a different kind of Tarzan tale when the action opens with a
bank robbery and one of the hoods wields a submachine gun. This
"Tarzan" explores dark themes and thrusts the characters into gritty
predicaments. Moreover, Day and co-scenarist Berne Giler eschew the
typical comic relief that earlier "Tarzan" films had featured. Tarzan
entrusts Cheetah in the custody of a friend while he undertakes a
dangerous mission. Not only have those amusing primate antics of
Cheetah been eliminated, but also Tarzan doesn't cut loose with his
distinctive yell. One source contends that Weintraub felt the trademark
holler had been lampooned too often to have any atmospheric value.
Nevertheless, juveniles will enjoy this out-of-doors escapade, but
"Tarzan the Magnificent" is geared more to grown-ups with its
psychological tensions and hardships. Tarzan captures a notorious felon
who has murdered one of his friends. The authorities had posted a $5000
reward on the villain's head when a British policeman named Wyntors
invaded the criminals' campsite and took the treacherous Coy Banton
(Jock Mahoney) at knife point as a hostage. Unfortunately, Coy kills
Wyntors before the policeman can get him out of the jungle. A
resourceful Tarzan intervenes with his bow and arrows, kills one of
Coy's brothers Ethan (Ron MacDonnell), and then decides to escort a
handcuffed Banton through miles of jungle to Kairobi. You see, Tarzan
knew Wyntors and plans to hand over the bounty money to Wyntors' widow.
Meanwhile, Abel Banton (legendary horror icon John Carradine) and his
two remaining sons, Johnny (Gary Cockrell of "Lolita") and Martin (Al
Mulock of "Tarzan's Great Adventure"), threaten to kill anybody who
helps Tarzan. These threats scare everybody off and it puts Tarzan in a
kind of "High Noon" situation. The Bantons make intimidating foes.
Indeed, Johnny shoots a doctor for not furnishing them with information
about Tarzan's plans for Coy. Furthermore, Abel shoots the captain of a
riverboat, force the passengers off and burn the boat. The passengers
walk into town along the river. When they learn that Tarzan is
escorting the villainous Coy, they decide to string along with him
despite the natural hardship that traveling through the jungle means.
This is a good, no-nonsense survival of the fittest epic lensed on
location in Africa. There is far more psychological depth in this
"Tarzan" than you typically see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
As the last "Tarzan" movie starring Gordon Scott for producer Sy
Weintraub, British director Robert Day's "Tarzan the Magnificent" with
Jock Mahoney and John Carradine qualifies as one of the better series
entries. Day helmed it after John Guillerman had made what is generally
regarded as the best Tarzan outing, "Tarzan's Great Adventure," which
co-starred a pre-James Bond Sean Connery. Later, Day called the shots
on "Tarzan's Three Challenges" (1963) with Jock Mahoney, and "Tarzan
and the Valley of Gold" (1966) as well as "Tarzan and the Great River"
(1967) both with former football player Mike Henry. In this off-beat,
unusual adventure, Tarzan tangles with bloodthirsty bank robbers who
display few qualms about cold-blooded homicide. You know that you're
watching a different kind of Tarzan tale when the action opens with a
bank robbery and one of the hoods wields a submachine gun. This
"Tarzan" explores dark themes and thrusts the characters into gritty
predicaments. Moreover, Day and co-scenarist Berne Giler eschew the
typical comic relief that earlier "Tarzan" films had featured. Tarzan
entrusts Cheetah in the custody of a friend while he undertakes a
dangerous mission. Not only have those amusing primate antics of
Cheetah been eliminated, but also Tarzan doesn't cut loose with his
distinctive yell. One source contends that Weintraub felt the trademark
holler had been lampooned too often to have any atmospheric value.
Nevertheless, juveniles will enjoy this out-of-doors escapade, but
"Tarzan the Magnificent" is geared more to grown-ups with its
psychological tensions and hardships. Tarzan captures a notorious felon
who has murdered one of his friends. The authorities had posted a $5000
reward on the villain's head when a British policeman named Wyntors
invaded the criminals' campsite and took the treacherous Coy Banton
(Jock Mahoney) at knife point as a hostage. Unfortunately, Coy kills
Wyntors before the policeman can get him out of the jungle. A
resourceful Tarzan intervenes with his bow and arrows, kills one of
Coy's brothers Ethan (Ron MacDonnell), and then decides to escort a
handcuffed Banton through miles of jungle to Kairobi. You see, Tarzan
knew Wyntors and plans to hand over the bounty money to Wyntors' widow.
Meanwhile, Abel Banton (legendary horror icon John Carradine) and his
two remaining sons, Johnny (Gary Cockrell of "Lolita") and Martin (Al
Mulock of "Tarzan's Great Adventure"), threaten to kill anybody who
helps Tarzan. These threats scare everybody off and it puts Tarzan in a
kind of "High Noon" situation. The Bantons make intimidating foes.
Indeed, Johnny shoots a doctor for not furnishing them with information
about Tarzan's plans for Coy. Furthermore, Abel shoots the captain of a
riverboat, force the passengers off and burn the boat. The passengers
walk into town along the river. When they learn that Tarzan is
escorting the villainous Coy, they decide to string along with him
despite the natural hardship that traveling through the jungle means.
This is a good, no-nonsense survival of the fittest epic lensed on
location in Africa. There is far more psychological depth in this
"Tarzan" than you typically see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>