<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>12 to the Moon</original_title><imdb_rating>2.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>David Bradley</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><producer>Luna Productions Inc.</producer><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
An international team embarks on an expedition to the moon in an uncommonly spacious rocketship. There...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ken Clark</actor><actor>Michi Kobi</actor><actor>Tom Conway</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1633313/comments</url><from>from Chicago IL</from><name>tmpj</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I remember having seen "12 to the Moon" in theatrical release in the
1960's,
the last hurrah of the matinees on Saturdays.
While many of the "gen-X-ers" would not truly understand the times and
feelings of the era, we "baby-boomers" were there, and shared in the fun
and
excitement of the times, and the thrill of going into a theater as a young
person to see even a not-so-good sci-fi flick.
"12 To The Moon" was, as I recall, another one of those "dislocated
dramas". By that I mean--it took place on the Moon, but concentrated more
on
human elements than on actual science. It did not take itself seriously,
and
was un-ashamedly released strictly for entertainment value, as were 95% of
the flicks of that era. The US had not yet conquered space, let alone the
moon, in 1960. It was an era of expectation, anticipation, and
discovery.
The scene that still haunts me from the film is the ill-fated space
voyager
who dies in a form of "lunar-quicksand". The others are virtually helpless
to assist their fellow traveler.
There is a warmth and an empathy present in the sci-fi flicks of that era
that is not present in to-day's "in your face" media and
world.
In those days, "attitude on a stick" was equated with a flawed, or even
evil character, and required redemption on the part of the"attitu-dee"..that is to say, the one who has the attitude.
I don't remember a lot of the film, not having seen it since I was in
third
or fourth grade. But audiences then got a lot from a little, and what was
unspoken or not shown spoke volumes over that which was more
conspicuous.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0291062/comments</url><from>from Minneapolis</from><name>dinky-4</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

Those man's-first-flight-into-space movies from the 1950s often have a
certain charm despite (or perhaps because of) their cheap sets,
black-and-white photography, no-name casts, and scientific ignorance. This
movie, however, has all the Grade-B tackiness without much of the
compensating fun that marks, say, "Cat-Women of the Moon."The plot has an international crew of ten men and two women rocketing to the
moon and encountering the usual meteor showers along the way as they discuss
how small and insignificant the Earth now looks. Upon reaching the moon,
they discover gold, a glowing substance dubbed the "Medusa stone," traces of
air, and evidence of a mysterious, never-seen civilization living below the
surface in a "sealed city." This civilization wants them to leave before
they inflict more damage. The crew of the "Lunar Eagle 1" promptly heads for home but discovers that
North America has been frozen by the civilization on the moon. To thaw it
out, two members of the crew undertake a suicide mission to steer an atomic
bomb into a Mexican volcano. (Don't ask.) The resulting explosion thaws out
the continent and this act of self-sacrifice helps convince the moon-people
that we Earthlings aren't so bad after all.Mixed into this plot are a conflict between two crewmen, (a German and an
Israeli), as well as a scene with a crewman who proves to be a saboteur with
Communist tendencies. Perhaps the movie's "high" point occurs when, mid-way to the moon, the
rocket's American captain -- naked except for a small white towel modestly
looped around his waist -- opens the shower-room door only to discover that
it's currently occupied by the two female members of the crew. The human
race has the expertise to build a rocket to the moon but they can't figure
out how to put a lock on the shower-room door?   Incidentally, the captain is played by Ken Clark and his hairy chest is by
far the best special-effect in the entire movie!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3041573/comments</url><from/><name>jamofrog</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Let me just say first, that it was a very noble idea for the moon to be
explored as a global effort. They had representatives of many nations
and even a black man and two women! (Actually pretty bold ideas at the
time.) And even in the midst of the Red scare, they had a Russian, who,
despite being a jerk, stops another European from sabotaging a mission
to save the U.S. Yes, the movie seems to have been made with noble
intentions towards world peace. That said, this is one big turkey.
First, no one involved with the movie had any idea about what the moon
and space were really like. (They have steam coming out of craters, and
several clusters of meteors just between earth and the moon.) Second,
the SFX are pitiful. (The ship at times has visible strings, and at one
point a stick. The moon also appears to have Stage lights at one
point.) These ingredients makes it a fairly awful movie. My
recommendation? Watch the MST3K version and applaud the good intent but
laugh at how awful everything else is.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4997726/comments</url><from>from Wavy Wheat, Nebraska</from><name>lemon_magic</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
What's fun about this "first men into space" movie is watching how the
movie tries so hard to convince the viewer that it is in fact a serious
dramatic effort displaying the "cutting edge of science" and then
shoots itself in the foot over and over again with laughable special
effects and goofs. I almost fell out my chair laughing when the astronauts climbed into
the control room and it became instantly obvious that the astronauts
were expected to sit in patio lounge chairs to help them endure the
crushing stresses of lift off. And then after going through the motions
of the trip to the moon - blah blah meteor showers blah blah sonic
showers blah blah random lines of dialog meant to convey character and
group dynamics...just before the actual embarkation onto the surface,
one poor actor has to stand in front of the camera all by himself and
babble into his flight log about the 'invisible ray shield' that is
supposed to keep his helmet sealed...instead of, you know, a
transparent visor or a simple bubble helmet. I mean, geez, considering
the quality of the acting in this movie (nothing against the actors -
they just don't have ANYTHING to work with) you wouldn't think they'd
mind if the helmets obscured the actors' faces, would you? Oh, and apparently cocker spaniels, monkeys and house cats are immune
to the forces of lift off, even though it almost kills the oldest
astronaut. The dog just sits on the end of a leash tied to a wall, and
the cats and moneys ride out the whole thing in cages. And then they are ON the surface of the moon, and it's just ludicrous.
It's so obviously a sound-stage made of lathe wood, paper mache and
gray paint that it considers vast viewer effort to suspend disbelief
and not look too hard. I tended to squint at the screen a lot, and that
really helped. And it turns out that the nations of the world spent
millions of dollars to send 12 people to the moon, but they only
supplied the astronauts with 2 hours of oxygen for their space suits. And let's see, blah blah blah quicksand pit, blah blah meteors blah
blah two of the astronauts disappear, blah blah the aliens living in
the moon want the cats, blah blah they take off, blah blah another
meteor shower (or maybe the same one) on the way back, the aliens
decide to freeze the earth, blah blah cooperation and selfless
sacrifice, blah blah, and the special effects budget completely runs
out and you can clearly see the stick holding the model of the
rocket-ship in front of the camera.Then blah blah blah, the selfless sacrifice convinces the aliens, the
moral, and THE END. Frankly, I preferred "Rocket Shop X-M" and "First Spaceship to Venus".
Why didn't someone think to call Issac Asimov, Arthur Clarke, Murray
Leinster or Lester Del Rey, four 'hard science' science fiction writers
of the era who would have been available for cheap? And yet, you can't hate a film like this. The actors were given
cardboard characters to play (which is natural when you've got TWELVE
PEOPLE FIGHTING FOR SCREEN TIME in a two hour movie, unless the
screenwriter and directors are geniuses.) but they really did their
best with the material. And the movie takes a pretty bold step (way
before "Star Trek") by asserting the need for an international crew
(including Russians, Jews, and Blacks) in a time when White Manifest
Destiny was the rule in the movie industry. As lazy as the movie was
with the technical details and the science, it was ABOUT something and
had a message of hope and destiny that you rarely see outside of Disney
films any more. Don't waste your time seeking this one out, but if it falls into your
hands, you might get a kick out of watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1908551/comments</url><from>from Newfoundland, Canada</from><name>Space_Mafune</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

This film remains rather stilted and slow-moving and that's not a good thing
in what is essentially a 1950s style Rocketship B-Movie...it has many of the
trademarks common to those...hurtling meteor storm attacks!, silly and
impossible solutions to every problem usually involving shooting a rocket at
something else and an intergender crew(although this one also has the daring
for its time interracial crew!)...the problem with this film isn't its story
really which could have been fun but the fact we see so little of what we
hear about after the fact..more on screen adventure would have been a
tremendous help..the gay undertones present in this film are also disturbing
and sometimes laughable(although how else could the subject have been
brought up in the time?). Still deserves points for being so
daring.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Speaking for the "International Space Order" of Earth, Francis X.
Bushman announces our planet's "Lunar Eagle 1" mission to the Moon. It
will be Earth's first manned Moon mission, and features a diverse crew
of twelve leading scientists: American Captain and hunk Ken Clark (as
John Anderson), Japanese photographer and pharmacist Michi Kobi (as
Hideko Murata), Russian geologist and mapmaker Tom Conway (as Feodor
Orloff), handsome Brazilian pilot Anthony Dexter (as Luis Vargas),
German spaceship architect John Wengraf (as Erich Heinrich), young
mathematics genius Robert Montgomery Jr. (as Roddy "Rod" Murdock),
British geophysicist Phillip Baird (as William Rochester), Polish-born
Israeli aeronautic engineer Richard Weber (as David Ruskin), Turkish
space medicine expert Muzaffer Tema (as Selim Hamid), French engineer
and technician Roger Til (as Etienne Martel), Nigerian astronomer Cory
Devlin (as Asmara Markonen), and beautiful Swedish physician Anna-Lisa
(as Sigrid Bomark).The filmmakers get Mr. Clark to strip down to a towel, early in the
flight, when he interrupts Ms Kobi taking an "ultrasound shower" (the
towel would be for modesty, since no drying is involved). When the crew
lands on the Moon, and exits the ship, you can clearly see a man on the
moon, walking away from the camera. This is probably a stagehand or
somebody caught on the set in error. Well, the crew claims the Moon as
international territory for the planet Earth; then, they look for air
and signs of life. They find both. And, the Moon inhabitants are
understandably not amused by the appearance of Earthlings on their
world. Let the battle begin! The main story becomes the conflict between the representatives of
Earth and the emotionless Moon beings, and whether or not they will be
able to resolve their differences. There is a well-meaning parallel to
Earth's overcoming of differences, with this "diverse" group presented
as evidence. The sub-plot involving German "Heinrich" and Israeli
"Ruskin" drives the point home. The fate of cats "Mimi" and "Rodolfo"
is never resolved, unfortunately. Relatives to watch include Bob
Montgomery Jr. (son of Robert &amp; brother of Elizabeth Montgomery, in his
best feature film part) and Tom Conway (brother of George Sanders).*** 12 to the Moon (6/60) David Bradley ~ Ken Clark, John Wengraf,
Robert Montgomery Jr.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15856557/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>bobabaya</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
OK, let's get the obvious out of the way. The writers had no clue about
scientific principles, especially space science. Even in 1960, we
already knew about the lifeless moon (it had been years since we
abandoned the notion of little green men from Mars).But the social implications were fascinating to me. The international
crew of the ship was quite impressive, especially in the midst of the
cold war.The inclusion of women, Asians, and even an African American man that
avoided stereotyping was admirable. Talking about racism, the issues of
Israel as a country, and other issues that are just as relevant today
was outstanding.So as a movie, lousy, but the message, outstanding!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1949999/comments</url><from>from Proctorville, Ohio</from><name>Carolyn Paetow</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
Could any space flick be worse than The Angry Red Planet? Yes, it
could. The script for the disaster at hand is so dopey and disjointed
that it could have been scrawled out in crayon by a classroom of
third-graders, each child submitting a short scene that teacher then
patched together, helter-skelter. As for the actors, some of them are
without doubt competent. They've exhibited this in other movies. But,
here, with such dipsticky dialogue, no one could ever know. It makes it
easy to understand why Tom Conway turned to drink and died broke. The
story starts with a big strike against it: twelve characters with
little to distinguish most of them. There are nine white guys, two
women--Swedish and Japanese--and a Nigerian man whose accent never
sounds West African and sometimes slips into Southern American. The
hatch is scarcely secured when the inter-ethnic squabbling and
recriminations start. Didn't these people get acquainted before
blasting off in a rocket? From the amorous behavior of the females with
two of the males, one would think so. But maybe there's something in
the air--or lack of it. There must be some air, even on the moon, since
the spacesuits don't have visors. The ship itself, with its bare-bones
instrumentation and lack of even a beep or buzz, must be of such
advanced technology that it all but runs itself. But, no, that can't be
right. The teen math whiz has to use paper and pen to calculate a path
through a meteor shower. The medical personnel has to struggle with
wrap-around blood pressure cuffs--which they obviously don't know how
to use. The only recorder on board--oh, forget it. There are, in
addition to the dozen humans, two cats and two monkeys in plastic
cases, two parakeets in a traditional cage, and one spaniel on a leash.
The boy genius tells them they've been brought along to see if they'll
mate on the moon. In the doggie's case, the answer is probably no. One
silly circumstance follows another, but maybe the most asinine is that
involving a screen-scrolled message from the Moonmen. Although it's
somehow known that they communicate only telepathically, they have
chosen to relay a series of repetitious, somewhat hieroglyphic-looking
symbols. One crew member decides that the writing looks Chinese (it
doesn't) so the Japanese woman is told to translate. She does, without
a hitch. Now, who but a very young child could make such an assumption?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1681347/comments</url><from>from Coastal Maine</from><name>Michael H</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
12 astronauts of different cultures and races decide the moon would be
a good place to explore, sorry 12 idiots. Sure the movie's heart was in
the right place but poorly cast and directed. Manly Ken Clark is back
after battling leeches (attack of the giant leeches)as the hunky
captain and representative for the USA. He and his well defined area
lead a crew to a sound set that is supposed to be the moon, steam,
exploding urinal cakes and meteor showers (ok how do you have meteor
showers on a world with NO ATMOSPHERE!!) Anyway our crew gets reduced
to 7 or 8 folks and a dog (one or two die and two others make out and
get an invitation by the invisible aliens to live with them) Anyway to
make a way too long story short, our heroes show some humanity to the
aliens and give some hope that all of them can be friends in the
distant future. Silent film actor Francis X Bushman has a small role in
the film as the 800 year old narrator. Great way to end a film career!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16810453/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>zee</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The problem with judging science on the basis of MST riffs is that MST
writers get science wrong every bit as often as the movie makers. The
science in this film is accurate and well considered. To wit, 1) The
"steam" is outgassing (which somehow people believe in the movie Deep
Impact but not in this film, because MST told them to laugh at it, and
they aren't thinking for themselves, alas.) In 1960, it was assumed
that there would be constant, dangerous lunar outgassing. As it ends
up, the outgassing probably was over by 3.5 billion years ago, but in
1960, we knew only a little bit about the phenomenon.2) The dust pits are of regolith, which NASA was very concerned about
when choosing Apollo landing sites. Look it up.3) The moon has an atmosphere. Look it up.4) Walking "slow and stupid" under lesser gravity was also accurate,
and since no one had been on the moon in 1960, they guessed how that
would look, and they guessed pretty well. It's easy to laugh at this in
retrospect, but I never saw even an attempt to get this right in other
moon films of the era.and so on. The movie makers got this all right, which for the date of
the film in startling and admirable. A lot of contemporary s-f films to
this one were ridiculous in comparison. (Yes, they had the typical and
inaccurate meteor shower scene, but you can't have everything.) A lot
of current s-f movies have much worse science. Much! It is also
admirable to see a diverse cast, including, gasp, women. NASA took over
twenty years to catch up with the imagination of these filmmakers, and
Kubrick didn't get that right in 2001, either, filmed ten years later,
so kudos to the filmmakers for that.The movie is a little slow, admittedly. But there is a plot, a heroic
sacrifice, and, my favorite part, the earth people don't win. They
scurry home barely alive, their asses kicked by aliens. That seems more
realistic than all the earth-wins s-f films that posit aliens with
profoundly advanced technologies who bother to visit other planets and
then can't figure out how to beat up an inferior species with gumption,
rain, the magical ability to pilot alien craft, or table salt.Thus, to summarize, the science in this science fiction film is far
better than average, even comparing it to today's films. There is a
plot, but it's a little bit slow. And the acting is not that wonderful.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16810453/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>zee</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The problem with judging science on the basis of MST riffs is that MST
writers get science wrong every bit as often as the movie makers. The
science in this film is accurate and well considered. To wit, 1) The
"steam" is outgassing (which somehow people believe in the movie Deep
Impact but not in this film, because MST told them to laugh at it, and
they aren't thinking for themselves, alas.) In 1960, it was assumed
that there would be constant, dangerous lunar outgassing. As it ends
up, the outgassing probably was over by 3.5 billion years ago, but in
1960, we knew only a little bit about the phenomenon.2) The dust pits are of regolith, which NASA was very concerned about
when choosing Apollo landing sites. Look it up.3) The moon has an atmosphere. Look it up.4) Walking "slow and stupid" under lesser gravity was also accurate,
and since no one had been on the moon in 1960, they guessed how that
would look, and they guessed pretty well. It's easy to laugh at this in
retrospect, but I never saw even an attempt to get this right in other
moon films of the era.and so on. The movie makers got this all right, which for the date of
the film in startling and admirable. A lot of contemporary s-f films to
this one were ridiculous in comparison. (Yes, they had the typical and
inaccurate meteor shower scene, but you can't have everything.) A lot
of current s-f movies have much worse science. Much! It is also
admirable to see a diverse cast, including, gasp, women. NASA took over
twenty years to catch up with the imagination of these filmmakers, and
Kubrick didn't get that right in 2001, either, filmed ten years later,
so kudos to the filmmakers for that.The movie is a little slow, admittedly. But there is a plot, a heroic
sacrifice, and, my favorite part, the earth people don't win. They
scurry home barely alive, their asses kicked by aliens. That seems more
realistic than all the earth-wins s-f films that posit aliens with
profoundly advanced technologies who bother to visit other planets and
then can't figure out how to beat up an inferior species with gumption,
rain, the magical ability to pilot alien craft, or table salt.Thus, to summarize, the science in this science fiction film is far
better than average, even comparing it to today's films. There is a
plot, but it's a little bit slow. And the acting is not that wonderful.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>