<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Time Machine</original_title><alt_title>La machine à explorer le temps</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>George Pal</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><producer>George Pal Productions</producer><producer>Galaxy Films Inc.</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Romance</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
A Victorian Englishman travels to the far future and finds that humanity has divided into two hostile species.
</synopsis><actor>Rod Taylor</actor><actor>Alan Young</actor><actor>Yvette Mimieux</actor><rt_rating>6.9/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>76</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1884226/comments</url><from>from The Pine Barrens of New Jersey</from><name>PRSLRider</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

In the early 1960s my mother used to take my younger sister and me to a
nearby one-screen theater to see Saturday kiddie matinees. It was a great
way to keep us entertained and out of her hair for a few hours,
particularly
after our baby sister was born.One movie I saw during those matinees was the 1960 version of The Time
Machine. It made such an impression on me that, for quite a while
afterward,
I would play Time Machine with my sister and cousin with me as the Time
Traveler.It wasn't until sometime in the 1990s that I was able to see it again when
I
got a VHS copy. It was very much the way I remembered it to be. I have
since
read the book and have found that the movie is quite faithful to the text,
though some scenes involving two stops in the 1900s were added and a few
bright spots appeared that weren't in the book, which is pretty
dark.The special effects look primitive by today's standards, but they did win
the Academy Award for Special Effects in 1961, and rightfully so, though I
have no idea what other films had been nominated.This is still one of my top 10 movies and likely always will be. I haven't
seen the 2002 version, which is probably just as well, since I'm happy
with
the 1960 version and don't want to ruin it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0785249/comments</url><from>from Salem, Oregon</from><name>jhclues</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

	In 1960, filmmaker George Pal brought to fruition a visionary concept for a
film based on a novel by H.G. Wells, about an inventor who builds a machine
that enables him to travel through time, specifically into the future, where
he learns a timeless, universal truth about the machinations of society and
some of the basic tenets of human nature.  `The Time Machine,' which Pal
produced and directed, stars Rod Taylor as George, the inventor/time
traveler/hero, who, born into a time and world that doesn't suit him,
decides to do something about it.  	A week into the 20th Century, four of George's closest friends, Dr. Philip
Hillyer (Sebastian Cabot), Anthony Bridewell (Tom Helmore), Walter Kemp
(Whit Bissell) and his best friend, David Filby (Alan Young), are gathered
at his house for dinner, but George is late; when he finally shows up, he is
disheveled, disoriented and hungry-- and has a story that is beyond belief. 
It's a tale that actually began one week earlier, on New Year's Eve, 1899,
when the five had last been together.  On that evening, George, after a
discussion of the reality of a `Fourth Dimension,' had given them a
demonstration of a model of a `Time Machine,' he had built, a miniature
prototype of the machine he hoped would take him some day into the future. 	His demonstration is met with interest, but skepticism; only Filby, it
seems, is able to keep an open mind, but even he encourages George to accept
the constraints of Time, which to the rational mind are absolute and
immutable.  George, however, views Time as a parameter; a variable whose
value is subject to change.  And on that last night of the 19th Century,
after his friends leave-- gone off to celebrate the arrival of the new
century-- George acts on his theory by stepping into his machine and
beginning a journey that will prove to be the adventure of a lifetime.  A
journey during which he sees a number of wars and changes in the world
around him, and which ultimately transports him some 800,000 years into the
future, where he finds a world ravaged by fate, where humankind has been
divided into two sects:  The gentle Eloi, living on the surface of the
earth, and the Morlocks-- mutants who dwell beneath as the Master Race, and
who prey upon the weak and simple Eloi.	He also discovers the dark secret of the Eloi and the Morlocks, and
determines to address the situation.  But first he returns to his own time,
to tell his friends the story, and to retrieve something he needs.  When his
guests leave, Filby remains behind with words of caution for George; but as
soon as he leaves, George is off to fulfill his destiny, and he has all the
time in the world to do it.	Going into this project, George Pal had a definite vision of what he wanted
to accomplish with this film, from the way the time machine itself looked,
to the way he wanted to present the future of mankind and the world.  And
working from the intelligent, imaginative screenplay by David Duncan, he
succeeded by delivering a film that has since become a classic of the
Science Fiction genre.  The nature of the story demands that the viewer
suspend disbelief, of course, but Pal develops his story in such a
plausible, straightforward manner that it is easy to do just that.  He puts
George on the journey of a lifetime, and he takes his audience along for the
ride.  He does an exquisite job of establishing the Victorian era in which
the story begins, as well as the world of the Eloi and the Morlocks.  The
F/X he employs to convey the sense of George's movement through time-- like
the swift arcing of the Sun and Moon, and the quick, subtle (and sometimes
not-so-subtle) changes George observes-- are entirely effective.  Pal
obviously had a devotion to detail that pays off handsomely here.  A
dedicated filmmaker, he refused to settle for less than what he knew was
right for his picture, and it shows.  The result is a film that is
entertaining, timeless and memorable.	As George, Rod Taylor is perfectly cast and gives a solid performance in
which he embodies the boldness, the imagination and tenacity of his
character.  Most importantly, he makes George believable and his motivations
credible, which enables the viewer to be swept along with the story.  Taylor
has a commanding presence that serves his character well, and he is, in
fact, the veritable personification of the explorer/adventurer, a man
willing to take a chance or face unbelievable odds to accomplish his goal. 
Taylor is a fine actor who has made a number of movies, but of them all,
this is the role for which he will probably be best remembered.	Also perfect in her role is Yvette Mimieux, as one of the Eloi, Weena.  A
talented actress-- now something of a ‘60s icon, in fact-- her fair beauty,
along with the innocent demeanor and vulnerability she manages to convey,
makes her character entirely convincing.  And the way she plays it makes
George's actions more likely, as well.  Granted, her character is well
written to begin with, but Mimieux's the one who sells it in the translation
from page to screen.  	The supporting cast includes Doris Lloyd (Mrs. Watchett), Bob Barran (Eloi
Man), James Skelly (Second Eloi Man) and Paul Frees (Voice of the Talking
Rings).  A transporting flight of fantasy, expertly crafted and
imaginatively presented, `The Time Machine' is captivating entertainment
that will make you believe that time travel is possible.  it paints a bleak
picture of the future, to be sure, but it gives you and leaves you with that
which has kept Man putting one foot in front of the other since Time began: 
Hope.  That's the legacy of H.G. Wells and the promise of George Pal.  And
it's the magic of the movies.  I rate this one 8/10.      	                 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0385776/comments</url><from>from Escondido, California, USA</from><name>LebowskiT1000</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I recently saw the 2002 film "The Time Machine" and liked it a great deal,
so I thought that it was probably in my best interest to see the 1960
version of "The Time Machine".  So, I went ahead and rented it and watched
it.  I knew that this film was made in 1960, so I wasn't expecting anything
spectacular, but I still hoped that it would be good.  I must say that I was
REALLY impressed with the film!  I thought it was great!The story is brilliantly told, smartly done, and quite interesting.  I
noticed a great deal of similarities (and differences) between this film and
the 2002 version.  There was virtually nothing I didn't like about the film,
as far as story goes.  I'm really interested in reading the H.G. Wells story
now, so hopefully in the near future I'll bust out my copy and read
it.I thought the actors in the film did a fantastic job as well!  Sadly, I'd
never even heard of any of the actors in the film.  I thought Rod Taylor,
Alan Young and Yvette Mimieux all did a great job.  The rest of the cast was
good, but these three really struck me as great.  Also, I have to say that
Yvette is one beautiful woman!The special effects in this film were surprisingly good, especially for a
movie made in 1960!  I must admit that I was really impressed with the sets
and the special effects in the film.The only thing that I would complain about, if I had to, is some little
things.  For instance, the classic "monster about to grab the guy, but then
doesn't" sort of thing.  Little things like that kind of bothered me, but I
realize that it was just the style back then, so I can't really complain
about it.  Also, I wasn't too terribly impressed with the mouth and face of
the Morlocks, but again, given that it was made back in 1960, I can let it
slide.Overall, I really enjoyed the film, and would definitely recommend it to
anyone that liked the 2002 version of the film or just enjoys films about
time-travel or science fiction.  I truly hope that you enjoy the film as
much as I do.  Thank you for reading,-Chris
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0324216/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>ROMANVS</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

In isolation, this film is an interesting and rather enjoyable tale.  It
is
only when you appreciate the underlying theme in the original 1895 novel
penned by H.G. Wells that you discovers how the story had been "laundered"
to be "politically correct" for American public release.  In a land where
"socialism" has almost always been a dirty word and at a time when the
McCarthy political witch hunts (that hit Hollywood rather badly) were
still
a fresh memory and when the "Cold War" was at its height, M.G.M. Studios
was
not going to take the risk of preaching a cautionary story about how the
seeds sown by the capitalist system could exact a gruesome nemesis in a
distant future.  Instead, the studio took the story, stripped it of its
ideology and presented it as the adventure of a gifted Victorian
inventor.Throughout his career, Herbert George Wells (1866-1946) placed his
sympathies with the working class.  In 1905, he joined the Fabian Society,
a
socialist think-tank whose ranks included George Bernard Shaw and that
gave
birth to the British Labour Party.  It is not surprising that his ideology
would embed itself in his writing -- and this was certainly true of his
first novel, The Time Machine.  The book tells of an enterprising inventor
who crafts a device that can carry a human passenger forward or backward
through time.  The hero travels 800,000 years into the future and finds a
world in which humans had evolved into two species: an illiterate and
child-like race called the Eloi, devoid of technology but similar in
appearance to modern humans who inhabited the surface of the planet; and
the
more repugnant Morlocks, technologically sophisticated and living in
perpetual darkness in underground caverns.  The hero gradually learns that
it is the Morlocks who supply the Eloi with food, clothing and other basic
necessities of life, but they exact a terrible price.  At periodic
intervals, the Morlocks "harvest" the Eloi for food.(By his own drive, Wells, who lived an impoverished childhood and became
literate only in his teen years, entered university where he studied
biology
under Thomas H. Huxley, the illustrious and outspoken champion of Charles
Darwin.  He was aware of the debates among evolutionary biologists of his
day over the discovery of Neanderthal remains, about how two "distinct"
species of humans -- Neanderthals and our Cro-Magnon ancestors -- existed
in
a prehistoric Europe and whether it was a peaceful co-existence or whether
the two species competed, perhaps violently, for control of resources.
Wells merely extrapolated the concept of two competing human species to a
distant future.)The hero in the novel also discovers how this world came into being.  At
some less remote future time, the industrialists collectively chose to
establish their factories and means of production underground, leaving the
surface of the earth green.  Eventually, the politically powerful classes
decided to banish all workers underground as well, leaving the world of
sunshine and blue skies as a playground for the wealthy and the privileged
-- a paradise that would eventually turn sour when the passage of time
would
adjust the genetic makeup of the two classes in their different
environments
and when a successful "slave revolt" would place the descendants of the
workers in control.Clearly, such a political fable could not be put on screen in the United
States in 1960.  If a cinematic version of the story was going to be made,
another explanation had to be conjured up to account for the evolution of
the two human species -- and it was found in the Cold War itself, a war
that
turns "hot" and forces huge populations underground for survival.  Toady,
however, almost forty years after the movie was released and more than a
hundred hears since the novel first broke onto the world, that M.G.M.
explanation seems horribly dated and it is the original Wells plot that
holds up much better in today's international, political and industrial
climate.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Boy, did a nice DVD transfer of this not only mak me appreciate the
visuals in here more but made the story seem better, too, for some
reason. I only acquired the DVD as a memento, so to speak. I had to
have at least one movie which had the woman I had a crush on back in
the early '60s: Yvettte Mimieux. She still looks great, too. The main
thing, however, is how I now viewed this story and how much more I
wound up liking it than in the past. This was my fourth look at this
movie over a 45-year span and I enjoyed it the most this last time. Since time travel stories always fascinate me, my favorite part of the
film is when "George" (Rod Taylor) is actually in his time machine and
experiments with it, slowing it down here and then and then stopping it
a couple of times to observe World War I and then WWII. Then, he stops
in 1966 when supposedly there was a nuclear attack. (Apparently,
scare-mongers back in '60 thought that was a short-term likelihood.)Anyway, when "George" (H.G. Wells, the author of this story) finally
stops, in the year 200,000-something, the story loses some of its
momentum. However, it's a fairly interesting study of a group of
ultra-passive people being dominated by others who live underground and
then literally eat the good people. Taylor is astounded that mankind
has not progressed as he had figured but seemed to have regressed.The message I got on this last look is that man is still man, meaning
sinful and capable of anything bad as well as good, and to put one's
faith totally in man is a mistake. It's only going to lead to
disappointments as "George" found out on each of his stops. (Notice he
never stopped during a peaceful, progressive period.) Yet, "George" is
still an optimist and wants to be one to help initiate change for the
better. There's always hope for a better world and people like George,
with his idealism put to action, can make a difference.Overall, an entertaining and thought-provoking film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5296618/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name> (andy.cippico@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
OK, so some people are intent on pointing out factual or historical
inaccuracies. Some people ridicule the costumes and accents, but what's
important is the spirit of the film. I sincerely doubt anyone made the
same kind of comments back in 1960. It was a seminal film and must have
inspired a generation of film makers. You don't need CGI to make a good
film. It's all about the story and the ingenuity of having to make do
with the things you've got to hand. This film exemplifies that
attitude.I first saw The Time Machine as a 10 year old in 1970 and was utterly
captivated. The stop-motion photography was spell-binding to me;
particularly when George kills one of the attacking Morlocks. The gory
footage of the body decomposing will abide with me forever. More
importantly, and for the first time in my life, I was completely swept
away with the concept of time travel. This film was unlike anything I
had ever seen before and sowed seeds of profound thought for many years
after.This film may not be for everyone, but it was for a certain 10 year-old
boy all those years ago. How I wish I could go back and recapture those
moments...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0313186/comments</url><from>from Auburn, Me</from><name>yenlo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

One of those Sci-Fi films that's made just right to be watched over and over
again and never gets old. The special effects were ahead of their time but
the film is not bogged down with them and the actors are allowed to ply
their trade. Rod Taylor puts in a solid performance as George the time
traveler. George Pal did a great job with this picture. A remake would
probably be flashier with the FX but would be hard to beat this classic.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I first saw The Time Machine when I was young and is one of my
favourite sci-fi movies.An inventor, George develops a machine that can travel through time and
he shows the model version of this to his friends to prove it. Despite
it disappearing, they don't believe him. He then starts time travelling
and first stops off during World War One, then briefly World War Two
and then arrives in 1966 and discovers a nuclear war in progress (which
never happened of cause). After the nuclear bombs have dropped, causing
a volcanic eruption, he travels to the far future where he ends up in
the world of the Eloi and the Morlocks, cannibalistic mutations. After
meeting Weena and falling in love with her, George helps to defeat the
Morlocks and then returns to his own time. After saying goodbye to his
friends, he returns to the far future.This has great special effects and a good music score.The excellent cast includes Rod Taylor (The Birds), Yvette Mimieux as
Weena, Alan Young, Sebastian Cabot, Tom Helmore, sci-fi regular Whit
Bissell (Creature From the Black Lagoon, I Was A Teenage Frankenstein)
and Doris Lloyd as housekeeper Mrs Watchett. Taylor and Mimieux were to
be reunited in 1968's Dark of the Sun.The Time Machine is a must see movie for all movie fans. Fantastic.Rating: 5 stars out of 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0583640/comments</url><from>from Tucson  AZ</from><name>Robert Reynolds (minniemato@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This is a very well-done adaptation of the H. G. Wells novella, with an
Oscar for the special effects that are still impressive more than 40
years
later.  Good performances by an ensemble cast and a good script also
help.
One interesting side note: character actor Whit Bissell was in both the
1960
version here and the version done for television in 1978, playing
essentially the same part with two different character names!
Recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

The original film version of THE TIME MACHINE is almost certainly the best
adaption of any of H G Wells work and deserves its status as a classic SF
film. That`s not to say it`s without flaws , it starts very slowly and I
found Filby`s obviously false Scottish accent very irritating ( Notice when
a Scotsman appears in a SF film or series his accent is poor ? Scottie from
STAR TREK , Jamie Mcrimmon from DOCTOR WHO etc ) , but once the hero goes
off into the future it`s entertainment all the way.Special mention should go to the very intelligent script, it does simplify
much of Wells subtext but also adds an anti war theme , you can actually
believe the hero`s thought processes came out of the mouth of Wells , and
during the nuclear war the Earth show`s its anger at mankind with a series
of devastating volcanic eruptions. Is this the first time that " the Gia
Theory " has appeared on film ? Perhaps the greatest compliment I can pay this film is that it reminded me
of the early DOCTOR WHO stories . Praise indeed 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

The original film version of THE TIME MACHINE is almost certainly the best
adaption of any of H G Wells work and deserves its status as a classic SF
film. That`s not to say it`s without flaws , it starts very slowly and I
found Filby`s obviously false Scottish accent very irritating ( Notice when
a Scotsman appears in a SF film or series his accent is poor ? Scottie from
STAR TREK , Jamie Mcrimmon from DOCTOR WHO etc ) , but once the hero goes
off into the future it`s entertainment all the way.Special mention should go to the very intelligent script, it does simplify
much of Wells subtext but also adds an anti war theme , you can actually
believe the hero`s thought processes came out of the mouth of Wells , and
during the nuclear war the Earth show`s its anger at mankind with a series
of devastating volcanic eruptions. Is this the first time that " the Gia
Theory " has appeared on film ? Perhaps the greatest compliment I can pay this film is that it reminded me
of the early DOCTOR WHO stories . Praise indeed 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-biodrowski/</url><url>http://cinefantastiqueonline.com/2010/07/the-time-machine-a-50th-anniversary-review/ /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1918911</url><name>Steve Biodrowski</name><from>Cinefantastique</from></reviewer><comment>Seen today, The Time Machine remains a reasonably elaborate affair, with impressive production values and fine special effects (even if these are somewhat dated,</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/timemachine1960.htm /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1760908</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>A colorful special effects film.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/time-machine/review/120662 /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1637188</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>This smashing science-fiction adaptation of H.G. Wells's famous novel has more creativity in every frame than most latter-day rip-offs have in their entirety.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/8385_TIME_MACHINE /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1637187</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>Parts of it are colorful and imaginative, but the film flattens out toward the end.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-bourne/</url><url>http://www.dvdjournal.com/reviews/t/timemachine60.shtml /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1497353</url><name>Mark Bourne</name><from>DVDJournal.com</from></reviewer><comment>Pal's movie is a brightly colored sweetmeat with all the indicting political ideology of a buttered scone.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/79447/the_time_machine.html /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1480096</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>The quaint time machine and Oscar-winning special effects hold one's interest initially, but the overall effect is one of glossy emptiness.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9E07E6D71E3EEF3ABC4052DFBE66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1388782</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>The drama, for all its invention, is creaky and a bit passé.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/luke-y-thompson/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1282875</url><name>Luke Y. Thompson</name><from>New Times</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Somewhat dated, and not quite up to the source material, but still some good retro fun.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rob-vaux/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1275021</url><name>Rob Vaux</name><from>Flipside Movie Emporium</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>A unmistakable product of its time, but lovingly rendered and always respectful of its source.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/kevin-a-ranson/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1257439</url><name>Kevin A. Ranson</name><from>MovieCrypt.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Still the best.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/widgett-walls/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1254241</url><name>Widgett Walls</name><from>Needcoffee.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>As an adaptation? Sure, not so good. But as a classic sci-fi flick? Yeah, sure, it's harmless.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=1225217</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Quaint sci-fi that's still engaging without being convincing.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pablo-villaca/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=827988</url><name>Pablo Villaca</name><from>Cinema em Cena</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Um clássico que, como seu protagonista, sobreviveu ao tempo.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-sanford/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=792673</url><name>James Sanford</name><from>Kalamazoo Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Pure delight, a sci-fi fantasy you will never forget</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/gerry-shamray/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=778237</url><name>Gerry Shamray</name><from>Sun Newspapers of Cleveland</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>The granddaddy of all time travel movies. Grand fun.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-oehley/</url><url>http://www.scifimoviepage.com/timemachine.html /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=322617</url><name>James O'Ehley</name><from>Sci-Fi Movie Page</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>If you're a serious SF fan then you'll no doubt enjoy The Time Machine and agree that it is deservedly the classic that it is held out to be.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jon-popick/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/articles/293025/anyone_who_digs_those_incredibly_cheesy_and_wonderfully_campy_50s_sci-fihorror_films_wont_want_to_miss_out_on_this_one/ /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=293025</url><name>Jon Popick</name><from>Planet Sick-Boy</from></reviewer><comment>Anyone who digs those incredibly cheesy and wonderfully campy '50s sci-fi/horror films won't want to miss out on this one.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/The-Time-Machine-(1960) /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=19689</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>Probably edgy and thrilling in its day, The Time Machine hasn't aged so well.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>/m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=208162</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
6/10
					</rating><comment>...the filmmakers managed to mislay most of Mr. Wells' eloquent language and philosophical questions in favor of a simplified Classics Illustrated approach.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dragan-antulov/</url><url>http://reviews.imdb.com/Reviews/168/16856 /m/1021500-time_machine/comments.php?reviewid=767488</url><name>Dragan Antulov</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
7/10
					</rating><comment>Through the years, [it's] become genre classic of its own.</comment></review></movie>