<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Inherit the Wind</original_title><alt_title>Procès de singe</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Stanley Kramer</director><producer>Stanley Kramer Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Based on a real-life case in 1925, two great lawyers argue the case for and against a science teacher accused of the crime of teaching evolution.
</synopsis><actor>Spencer Tracy</actor><actor>Fredric March</actor><actor>Gene Kelly</actor><rt_rating>7.8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>91</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Like Elmer Gantry I first saw Inherit the Wind in the theater in
Brooklyn when I was 13 years old. Both of those films dealt with issues
arising from the Roaring Twenties out of religion. At the time I
thought both were great dramatic pieces dealing with issues of the
past. I thought how much we'd grown up as a country from 1925 to 1960.If you had told me that 46 years later we'd be fighting these same
battles and that preachers had as much political power as they do I and
many others would have said you were nuts. Yet here we are today in an
age when Pat Robertson is taken as a serious political figure. Inherit the Wind is a dramatization of the famous Scopes Monkey Trial
of 1925 when a biology teacher was arrested and challenged a law passed
by the Tennessee State legislature making it a crime to teach anything
other than the account of creation as set down in the Book of Genesis.
Dick York is the biology teacher here, renamed Bertram Cates for the
play and the film version of that play.In fact all the names of the dramatis personae of the Scopes Trial have
been changed to allow some creativity by the authors Jerome Lawrence
and Robert Lee. Spencer Tracy and Fredric March play fictionalizations
of Clarence Darrow and William Jennings Bryan named Henry Drummond and
Matthew Harrison Brady respectively.Of course that is what Inherit the Wind is primarily known for, a duel
of double Academy Award winners. In fact Spencer Tracy received another
Academy Award nomination for this film, but lost to Burt Lancaster for
Elmer Gantry. That's ironic to me because I thought March captured the
essence of William Jennings Bryan better. Bryan is a man whose time has
passed him by. But he's still a hero to the folks of small town rural
America in the south and middle west. One thing to remember is that
while Bryan was a great orator and advocate, he had not practiced law
in over 30 years when he stepped into the courtroom for the trial. If
he had been a better lawyer, he might not have fallen into the one big
trap Tracy set for him and the trial and the attending publicity might
have been better for his side.As good as Tracy is, the year before in Compulsion I think that Orson
Welles captured the real Clarence Darrow in his character of Jonathan
Wilk. No one in Hollywood could do long take speeches quite like
Spencer Tracy though. I'm sure that's why Director Stanley Kramer hired
him and they developed quite the screen partnership with Tracy doing
four of his last five screen roles for Kramer. Stanley Kramer made some impeccable casting choices filling out the
minor roles of the various townspeople of Hillsboro, Tennessee. There
are two that I would single out. Claude Akins who usually played tough
guys in various action films was astounding as the town preacher, the
Reverend Jeremiah Brown. Sad to say there are still many like him out
there. Akins's offbeat casting worked wonders, it turned out to be the
high point of his screen career. On the opposite end of the spectrum was Noah Beery, Jr. who is a farmer
and who's son was drowned some time before the events of the film.
Beery is the town non-conformist, he refused to allow his son to be
baptized and Akins has said the adolescent is in hell because of it.In a key scene when Tracy draws the ire of Judge Harry Morgan who
sentences him to jail for contempt of court, Beery offers to put up his
farm for collateral for Tracy's bail. Tracy's about to quit the case,
but that simple gesture gives him hope, in the ultimate decency and
clearheadedness of ordinary people. It's my favorite scene in Inherit
the Wind.Stanley Kramer lived long enough to see this film become so relevant
for today's times. I wonder what he must have thought.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3645069/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>stanford-4</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
We have been blessed with many, many wonderful films over the decades,
and we have also been blessed with seeing many, many fine actors and
actresses. Here you have a film, with a host of stars; brilliantly
portraying characters from a true story, with acting that is sublime.
The dialogue is sharp, witty, and each performance is gripping. Small
town America, religious bigotry are all handled in a sympathetic manner
by the use of powerful acting. I gave this film a 10 purely because it
is one of those rare gems that stay in the mind forever. It is truly
memorable, and one can watch it time and time again to marvel at the
superb portrayals. There is a saying that they don't make 'em like they
use to. No sir, they certainly don't!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0305877/comments</url><from>from Ephrata, WA</from><name>Jim Corkrum (jcorkrum@corkrum.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

After recently watching each remake of this film, one can easily
appreciate
what an incredible film the 1960 version is.  It is the perfectly made
film
and should be held up to all as the pinnacle of film making.  It has the
perfect director and the perfect actors.  It probably has the best
behind-the-scenes crew ever assembled including the perfect film editor.
The
choice of black and white is also perfect.  This is one of those few gems
where every element of film making came together to make the perfect
movie.The story is very thought provoking from both points of view, the
evolutionist and the fundamental Christian.  While I am not even close to
being a Christian of any kind, I am haunted by the speech given by Matthew
Harrison Brady that says how our children will turn into a godless mob
with
no direction without the teachings of the Bible (paraphrasing).  But,
isn't
that what has happened some 80+ years after the story takes place?  The
actors effortlessly sell each character's point of view.There is very little that can be said about Spencer Tracy, Frederick March
and Gene Kelly that hasn't already been said.  When you see the new
version
of this film, you can really understand why these actors are held in such
high esteem.  These guys are actors!In short, this is one of the finest films ever made and should be seen by
everyone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1206462/comments</url><from>from ontario canada</from><name>pcfalconi</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This movie is well acted both March and Tracy perform remarkably.  The story
line depicts how ignorance and blind faith can generate a mob mentality. It
beautifully reflects the social values of the time and depicts very well the
attitudes of the time in which the movie was set. Like 12 angry men, it has
simple sets and gives hope to the notion that not only can movies be
educational and entertaining, there are producers that care about making a
meaningful statement using a plot and acting to entertain.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4019986/comments</url><from>from U.K.</from><name>paulsp2 (pclewis2000@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I have recently seen this movie on t.v. and was highly impressed with
direction, photography and of course the acting! Spencer Tracy is one
of my all time greats along with Frederic March so imagine seeing them
together! Some may thing March a little over the top but personally I
find his performance one of the most riviting and engaging I have ever
come across in film, he should have received an Oscar for this. Somehow
although acting styles have become more naturalistic over the years the
spark and energy given by the greats of the past is simply missing in
the vast majority of modern performances. That God they are preserved
on film.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1582207/comments</url><from/><name>Registered_User</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
People like to comment on this film's "overacting". Try watching any of
Joan Crawford's movies from this period and then get back to me.
Inherit the Wind is a totally compelling story of the traditional
school of thought versus a new scientific one. It centers on a small
southern town coming to terms with Darwinism and its implications on
Christianity. Spencer Tracy is an eloquent defense lawyer fighting to
let evolution stay in the public schools. The script is quite good. The
court room exchanges are thought provoking and moving especially when
one knows about the real people and events behind the story. It's very
difficult to come up with a criticism here. Not a weak performance to
be seen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3192976/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, USA</from><name>marcosaguado</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The pleasure! Spencer Tracy and Frederic March going at each other.
Masterfully spot on. As in most works of art, the passing of time adds
to its relevance. Very much true in this case. Fanaticism without
reason, such an everyday occurrence in our daily 2007 lives. There is
nobody more deaf than the one who doesn't want to hear.Spencer Tracy
personifies the truth, everything he utters is immediately believable.
The cross examination of Frederic March is a classic on his own. The
only discording notes are: the presence of Gene Kelly - very
distracting indeed -and Claude Aikens in a way over the top
performance. The way the trial is shot reminded me of the brilliant
blocking of another Stanley Kramer film with Acting Giants And Relevant
Themes "Judgement At Neuremberg" If you haven' seen "Inherit The Wind"
do so, if you have, see it again and share the experience with your
kids. I highly recommend it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This movie is made by the performances. The material is very good, but at
time its a bit melodramatic and obvious, which is the way the play is. Were
it not for the collision of Spencer Tracy and Frederick March this would be
just an excellent Hollywood film instead of the classic that it
is.I would be tempted to say that all you need is a basic knowledge of the plot
and the ability to jump straight to the court room scenes, but that would be
unfair. Watch the movie once  and then after that you can simply watch the
fireworks.What can I say about the battle between Tracy and March? Nothing. Words fail
me. This is one of the great battles on screen in any film. It should be
seen by anyone who wants to see how "easy" acting should appear. All the
more important is the fact that this is a battle of ideas that still matter
today as much as then. If only all of the world's problem could be debated
this perfectly we'd live in a happier place.See this movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0867063/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>FilmFlaneur</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
It's a rare American film that takes the grand clash of ideas as almost
its entire central subject matter, and Inherit The Wind has for that
reason alone for long been a personal favourite. It's also a film that
features some outstanding, larger than life acting, notably from the
leads, whether it is Tracy, playing the crusty liberal for whom "an
idea is more important than a monument" or the superb March, his
performance full of facial tics and movement, and whose fundamentalist
character does "not think about what I do not think about." Director
Kramer clearly places his sympathies in the former camp, although he
does not bludgeon the audience with preconceptions. In fact as a
filmmaker he had a reputation for making movies that held opinions and
took stands, with a particular weakness for courtroom scenarios.
Inherit The Wind came after the post-apocalyptic On The Beach, and just
before the sombre Judgement At Nuremberg (also with Tracy). In the
mid-1970s the director also made three 'judgement' films for TV based
on other real trials.Whilst On The Beach offers a verdict of its own on humanity's military
foolishness, and Judgement At Nuremberg is a just as sombre account of
another judicial milestone of different significance, arguably Inherit
The Wind falls neatly between the two in ways other than just the order
of production. Like On The Beach, it makes its judgement too: not on a
worldwide disaster visited by man upon himself, but on the perils of
stifling free thought. And, as in Judgement At Nuremberg, it's a trial
of ideas here too. But whereas the evil ideology of the Nazis
ultimately brought millions to their deaths and stands condemned with
its architects, it is enough in Hillsboro that "That if you take a law
like evolution and you make it a crime to teach it... tomorrow you may
make it a crime to read about it. And soon you may ban books... because
fanaticism and ignorance is forever busy, and needs feeding." In fact
Tracy and March, with Kelly's able help, hold the centre stage for so
much of the time that despite their best efforts the supporting cast
seem a little enervated. The romantic subplot between Cates and his
girlfriend (ostracised by her father for straying into the wrong camp)
is occasionally a little cloying and, upon reflection is too much of a
reflection from the main event. More damagingly, the character of the
Rev. Jeremiah Brown, as portrayed by a miscast Claude Akins, is so
fervent and cold hearted in the cause of the righteous that it
occasionally wonders too close to self parody. An improvement to
historical events is made by the introduction of a, for the most part,
even-handed trial Judge Mel. It is he who provides an anchor for the
audience in court as the two heavy weights slug it over points of order
and procedural objections. Judge Mel also provides one of the trials
more memorable, quiet moments when, just as it did in the real case, he
finds the increasingly frustrated Drummond in contempt of court - only
to see the fine which he levies paid for by the parents of a drowned
child condemned by the fundamentalist lobby.In the light of today's religious debates in the US, Inherit The Wind
seems braver than ever, and Tracy's character is allowed several hard
hitting outbursts which, one wonders, would remain as so powerfully
expressed if rewritten for a modern retelling. When he says, "I don't
swear for the hell of it. Language is a poor enough means of
communication. We've got to use all the words we've got. Besides, there
are damn few words anybody understands" we all know what he means. And
when he campaigns for a man to have the same right to think "as a
sponge" it's a moment that remains starkly memorable. Curiously, a less
emotional Darrow variant was essayed a year earlier by Orson Welles in
Compulsion (1959), a version of another famous criminal trial. Inherit
The Wind has been remade thrice more to good, but ultimately less
memorable, effect (including once with Kirk Douglas) but the Kramer
version remains ahead.Dramatic variances aside, inevitably any presentation of the Scopes
trial, and such controversial material as it contains, will never
please everyone. The source play upon which Kramer's film is based
simplifies matters a little too readily and other criticisms can be
made: for instance the original textbook from which the schoolteacher
was convicted of teaching illegally evidently contained an advocacy of
racist policies and eugenics unacceptable today while it also accepted
the notorious Piltdown forgery as genuine proof of a 'missing link' and
so on. Again, the relationship between Bryan and Darrow was more
complicated in real life than the film has time or care to show -
although ultimately one is so caught up in the fairground of judicial
combat as the case progresses that one forgives such accommodations
with the truth.Inherit The Wind stands badly in need of a decent special edition, a
golden opportunity perhaps being offered by the widely followed 2005
debate that took place in Pennsylvania. The current disc offers little
more than the film, although the widescreen presentation does justice
to the splendid black-and-white cinematography of Ernest Laszlo, which
effectively conveys the sweaty claustrophobia of small town, Bible-belt
America. Whether or not the hesitation in bringing out such a
potentially controversial, expanded package is a matter of intelligent
design or just random selection, the public will have to judge for
itself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2138545/comments</url><from/><name>middleburg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

To see brilliant acting at by well-seasoned professionals at their very
peak,  rent 
or buy this great American film classic.  Timing that is impeccable, nuance
as 
subtle as could be, bravura declamations that are almost stunning in their
power 
and intensity--this film has it all.  It should be studied and analyzed by
any 
serious actor in the profession.  (It should also be studied and analyzed by
any 
trial attorney as well!)  Who'da thought that Fredric March's raging bullpersonality could at times be so touching and tragic--or that Spencer
Tracy's 
character should show such emotional and heartfelt depth when he is simplygrilling witnesses on the stand.  The trial is the very heart of the
movie--and yet it 
is supported by a wealth of early 20th century Americana--the
fire-and-
brimstone preacher, the look and feel of that hot Tennessee Summer, theboistrous singing of "Gimme that Ole Time Religion" that makes the audiencewant to join right in, these are all terrific details that add to the keen
enjoyment of 
this film.  But the trial's the thing.  And it is riveting!  

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2138545/comments</url><from/><name>middleburg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

To see brilliant acting at by well-seasoned professionals at their very
peak,  rent 
or buy this great American film classic.  Timing that is impeccable, nuance
as 
subtle as could be, bravura declamations that are almost stunning in their
power 
and intensity--this film has it all.  It should be studied and analyzed by
any 
serious actor in the profession.  (It should also be studied and analyzed by
any 
trial attorney as well!)  Who'da thought that Fredric March's raging bullpersonality could at times be so touching and tragic--or that Spencer
Tracy's 
character should show such emotional and heartfelt depth when he is simplygrilling witnesses on the stand.  The trial is the very heart of the
movie--and yet it 
is supported by a wealth of early 20th century Americana--the
fire-and-
brimstone preacher, the look and feel of that hot Tennessee Summer, theboistrous singing of "Gimme that Ole Time Religion" that makes the audiencewant to join right in, these are all terrific details that add to the keen
enjoyment of 
this film.  But the trial's the thing.  And it is riveting!  

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2138545/comments</url><from/><name>middleburg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ellen-mackay/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/Inherit-Wind-1960.html  /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1950422</url><name>Ellen MacKay</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Knock-out courtroom drama has deft comic touches.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/article.php?articleID=6283 /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1716052</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Director Stanley Kramer can't overcome the trepidations of a verbose courtroom drama, so he lets his two actors, Spencer Tracy and Fredric March dominate and go at each other, pretending it's a deep play of ideas.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1711120</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Stagey yes, but powerful Tracy and March acting + subject matter make this a must see.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/inherit-wind/review/102085 /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1662336</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>Absorbing, if long-winded courtroom drama bolstered by two fine central performances from Tracy and March.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/4545_INHERIT_THE_WIND /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1662335</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>Spencer Tracy does his cuddly curmudgeon turn as Clarence Darrow; it's a lazy, vague performance, but its wit provides the only crack of light in the film's somber, gray overcast.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lori-hoffman/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1616205</url><name>Lori Hoffman</name><from>Atlantic City Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>An all time classic</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/inheritthewind.htm /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1611071</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Tracy and March turn in superlative performances, each trying to upstage the other.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/76002/inherit_the_wind.html /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1480195</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Tolerably gripping in its old-fashioned way, thanks chiefly to old pro performances from Tracy and March as the rival lawyers and ideologists.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jake-euker/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1257963</url><name>Jake Euker</name><from>F5 (Wichita, KS)</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment>Director Kramer at his most unbearably high-minded and ostentatious</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1124540</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Movie Mom at Yahoo! Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Extraordinarly vivid, rich, and wise about the core questions of how we know and who we are.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/brian-webster/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=3806 /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=285978</url><name>Brian Webster</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
78/100
					</rating><comment>A most worthwhile film, if for no other reason, because it provides a great opportunity to watch Tracy and March go at it in a most entertaining fashion.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-kendrick/</url><url>http://www.qnetwork.com/?page=review&amp;id=419 /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=276372</url><name>James Kendrick</name><from>Q Network Film Desk</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>Producer-director Stanley Kramer ably handles the incendiary material visually, making good use of deep focus and careful compositions</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Inherit-the-Wind /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=267649</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Inherit the Wind is well crafted and can entertain even the most jaded of modern audiences.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tim-dirks/</url><url>http://www.filmsite.org/inhe.html /m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=9915</url><name>Tim Dirks</name><from>Tim Dirks' The Greatest Films</from></reviewer><comment>Inherit the Wind (1960) portrays the famous and dramatic courtroom "Monkey Trial" battle (in the summer of 1925 in Dayton, Tennessee)</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tony-medley/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1345985</url><name>Tony Medley</name><from>tonymedley.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/robin-clifford/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1339352</url><name>Robin Clifford</name><from>Reeling Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1266686</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/edward-havens/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=1169086</url><name>Edward Havens</name><from>FilmJerk.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/robert-roten/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=848087</url><name>Robert Roten</name><from>Laramie Movie Scope</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/brian-j-arthurs/</url><url>/m/1010555-inherit_the_wind/comments.php?reviewid=805617</url><name>Brian J. Arthurs</name><from>Beach Reporter (Southern California)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>