<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Tell-Tale Heart</original_title><imdb_rating>5.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Ernest Morris</director><producer>Danziger Productions Ltd.</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
When Edgar sees his girlfriend Betty getting up close and personal with his best friend Carl, he murders Carl in a jealous rage and hides the corpse under the floor of his piano room...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Laurence Payne</actor><actor>Adrienne Corri</actor><actor>Dermot Walsh</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1808709/comments</url><from/><name>Bub_the_zombie</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Definitely one of the better takes on the classic Poe story. The acting
in this version is simply fantastic. A moody little piece with some
risqué' scenes to be of such an early caliber. A very interesting
rarity.The quality of the print isn't great, but has still held up well
throughout time, considering... It's a wonder that someone still had
the negative.. I was really surprised,as a lot of times, films like
these can really be tedious, but not this one.A welcomed attempt is what this is. One gets the sense that even tho it
had been done to death (even previously from 1960) the filmmakers took
their approach seriously, with an end result that is creepy and risky.I'm surprised that more people haven't seen this film, given the fact
that it's pretty readily available on a one buck DVD alongside Chiller.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0814168/comments</url><from>from New Orleans, Louisiana</from><name>pmsusana</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

One critic described this film as "A real bore"; I vigorously disagree.  It
has its flaws - modern audiences would probably find it slow to start, and
that blaring backround music detracts from a few scenes - but it does build
slowly to some wonderfully creepy and horrific scenes during the second
half
which are well worth hanging on for.  I was also impressed with the
sincerely tormented performance of Laurence Payne in the central
role.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1439650/comments</url><from>from Newcastle upon Tyne, England</from><name>Geisterzug</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I completely agree with the first reviewer.A little gem - co-written by Brian Clemens (who went on to create THE
AVENGERS, THE PROFESSIONALS etc.)A surprising 'sexuality' about the proceedings. Utterly passe now, but it
must have been a little intense and 'naughty' at the time. The slow-burn
attraction between Walsh and Adrienne Corri is quite good. And given that
the Danzigers' track record for British B movies is not brilliant - this
one
certainly tries to deliver the goods. The murder scene, and the gore
content, is quite graphic for its time. 1961, remember? (I suspect there
would have been British censor trouble then, had the movie been filmed in
colour).Trivia: Co-star Dermot Walsh was married at the time to Hazel Court (of
Hammer/Roger Corman movie fame.) Walsh then went on to star in the
Danzigers' TV series: RICHARD THE LIONHEART. I can still sing the title
song
on request. Sad, eh? And how Dermot maintains that high quiff-hairstyle is
an astonishment. Laurence Payne (who I've always liked and was co-star in
THE TROLLENBERG TERROR/THE CRAWLING EYE),lost an eye in the early sixties
during a fencing scene in his British TV series SEXTON BLAKE. Great
casting
for that part, I always thought. He was always good.)Bar tender Frank
Thornton, who has two brief scenes, went on to great success as a comedy
character actor in theatre, and British TV (eg ARE YOU BEING
SERVED?)Geisterzug
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0517466/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Zombie_CPA</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This was $1 well spent at Wal-Mart yesterday. The acting is this film
was very solid. Adrienne Corri was sexy and perfect for the role of
Betty. You could tell of her disinterest in poor Edgar by her head and
body language. Laurence Payne did a fantastic job as Edgar too. You
really believed that he was going mad.This is a nice slow-burn horror movie that comes to a great climax
after slowly building suspense. It is available in a $1 DVD with
Chiller. I purchased it for Chiller, but decided to watch Tell-Tale
Heart first. This movie was a great surprise. The movie also has great
atmosphere and a solid story. Tell-Tale is my favorite Poe short story
and it was brought to life wonderfully is this 1960's gem.Go to Wal-Mart and buy it today.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12564380/comments</url><from>from Kentucky</from><name>trinityann8423-1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I actually enjoyed this movie.I am a huge horror fan. I read scary
books and love scary movies, Edgar Allen Poe is one of the authors I've
enjoyed since I was a child. I received this movie as a gift from work
for Halloween.I found out that it had only been a dollar plus it had
the movie "Chiller" on it. It was a lot better than I thought it would
be. A lot of movie adaptations of classic stories aren't nearly as good
as the stories but I believe this one was a well done adaptation. It
kept my attention from the beginning until the end.The only flaw I
guess was that the main female character was too obvious most of the
time while the main character, Edgar, seemed pretty oblivious at the
beginning.Other than that, very good acting, I was pretty impressed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14283277/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>dseast</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The original murder of an old man is not seen in this movie, but a more
interesting and prolonged plot involving love and betrayal. The main
character, named Edgar Poe, seems a bit unstable from the very
beginning, if not just plain creepy. The theme and feel of the original
work is alive in this picture as our main character slowly progresses
into psychological deterioration. Good climax and plenty of classic
gore for a black and white film.I think Poe would have liked this one.I too bought this as part of a double feature for $1 at Wal-Mart, and
tax free in New Hampshire no less. Great find if you happen upon it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13401764/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>kai ringler</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This story is one of the all time favorites of mine, whether on film,
or in the book, you can't help but be drawn to it. Always have been a
big fan of Edgar Allen Poe , going all the way back to childhood. This
particular movie i think does the book a lot of justice, although the
female lead character is kinda a little over the top obvious , but
other than that, hey the movie really works for me, it doesn't really
drag, you feel so sorry for Edgar plodding along in the movie after
that girl, i kept telling him Edgar don't tell her about you're best
friend, why would you do that, guess he doesn't have to much brains
with woman at the time. the plot in the movie was great. although a bit
worn, but the music, omg was excellent, very creepy, well done, really
there ain't nothing hardly wrong with the movie, if you can overlook
the female lead's obvious obnoxiousness then you got it made.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3199297/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Skragg</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Like a few of you, I found this on an inconspicuous DVD along with
"Chiller," and I just saw it a few hours ago. This film is as good at
"stretching out" a short Poe story as the AIP movies (and I'm VERY
attached to those). I'm not familiar with Lawrence Payne, but he was
great in the part, as were the Dermot Walsh and Adrienne Corri. But I
didn't realize Frank Thornton was the barman till I read it here - I'll
have to watch for him next time. As for the ending - which I won't give
away here - some people might see it as a "cop-out" ending, but I think
it works perfectly well. As some of you say, the "risque" side of this
film was slightly surprising for a film of 1960 - I kept thinking I was
seeing a Hammer film (minus the cleavage!).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9938570/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Scarecrow-88</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
A pitiable, terribly timid librarian, Edgar Marsh(Lawrence Payne, who
is superb), falls head over heels for a new neighbor, a flower
sales-girl who lives across the street. This lovely creature is Betty
Clare(Adrienne Corri)and she agrees to date Edgar out of sympathy for
his pathetic nature, but soon is attractively drawn to his best friend,
playboy Carl Loomis(Dermot Walsh), a ladies' man with quite a
reputation around the place. Carl, at first, resists Betty who clearly
displays arousing affection for him, but soon accepts a sexual
invitation for which a gullible Edgar sees from his window(..he often
watches her undress, the voyeur that he is). Edgar, who had spent a
considerable amount of money and time on Betty, reacts hostilely to
Carl's betrayal by attacking him with a fireplace poker, burying the
body under a floor board. This act of violence, haunts him as he hears
the loud pounding of Carl's heart beat, which rarely ceases, plaguing
him night after night. Succumbing to drink and madness, it's only a
matter of time before he cracks. Meanwhile, Betty pursues the answer as
to why Carl hasn't returned to her, suspicious since he proclaimed
their future betrothal after he broke the news of their engagement and
love affair to Edgar.I think this was a really nice surprise. Director Ernest Morris builds
the torment existing within Edgar's soul slowly, over time, using the
movement of objects, simple but effectively spooky tricks anchored by
Payne's pitch-perfect portrayal of a rather feeble man whose guilty
conscience starts to erode his psyche, and his already fragile mental
state slowly crumbles..and Morris uses images and sounds such as a
water faucet dripping, a clock ticking, a chess piece rolling on a
board back and forth(..wonderful symbolism, to boot, since Edgar and
Carl played chess all the time), and a rug moving up and down
symbolizing the supposed beat of a heart. Corri is ideally cast as the
lustful object of Edgar's affections, and she's incredibly sexy which
provides an understanding as to the infatuation of the film's
protagonist and why he'd constantly obsess over her, to the point that
he'd kill his best friend as a result. Great use of
silence(..accompanied by the variety of sounds I mentioned above), as
well, pointing out Edgar's isolation as the heart beats and he can not
escape it, eventually cutting it from Carl's chest, looking at it
thump, finally burying it. I think the filmmakers(..and, especially
Payne) effectively convey this poor loser's slow descent into hysteria.
Bravura job for all concerned..a real sleeper, see it of you get the
chance. A word of warning, though..this is a slow burner, a film that
takes it's time, allowing all the elements to take shape.MAJOR SPOILER: Maybe, the twist at the end is a bit of a drag(..the
whole "it's all a dream" aspect), but Edgar is quite a whimpering chap,
so he deserves some sympathy, which may be why he's spared.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The Tell-Tale Heart is one of the best known of Edgar Allen Poe's
works; and I was surprised that I had not seen a film based on it. The
original story is just a short story, and while there have been many
versions of this tale committed to screen; most of them are only shorts
themselves; thus making this film one of the few feature length
editions of the story. Well...after having seen it, I have to admit
that I'm not surprised there aren't more feature length versions
because really there isn't enough plot to stretch to such a long
running time. Thus, most of the story of this film has no relation to
Poe's original story. We focus on a man named Edgar (a bit of a
ham-fisted reference if you ask me); a quiet man that lacks experience
with women. When he notices a young lady named Betty in a house across
the street; he resolves to romance her and asks his close friend Carl
for advice on how to speak to women. He and Betty are getting on well;
until he discovers that Carl and Betty are also getting on well, and so
Carl is murdered.The film is shot in black and white and looks really cheap throughout.
Director Ernest Morris appears not to have the resolve to elevate the
film above the mundane and also fails to get a good performance out of
his any of his (relatively) unknown cast; which renders the whole
production rather bland. Of course, the whole film is just build up to
the inevitable situation whereby the murderous central character is
haunted by the echoes of the beating heart from the man he has killed,
and this leaves most of it feeling rather pointless. To the film's
credit, however, it does handle Poe's actual story well and things do
become much more interesting once we reach the main part of the film.
This version of The Tell-Tale Heart never really gets into the
psychological side of Poe's original story; and the reason for that
really just goes back to the characters, which aren't interesting
enough. Overall, this is really a lacklustre effort and I wouldn't
recommend tracking it down; this story is more suited to a short film
anyway, and I'm sure that at least one of the many short film versions
is superior to this effort.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The Tell-Tale Heart is one of the best known of Edgar Allen Poe's
works; and I was surprised that I had not seen a film based on it. The
original story is just a short story, and while there have been many
versions of this tale committed to screen; most of them are only shorts
themselves; thus making this film one of the few feature length
editions of the story. Well...after having seen it, I have to admit
that I'm not surprised there aren't more feature length versions
because really there isn't enough plot to stretch to such a long
running time. Thus, most of the story of this film has no relation to
Poe's original story. We focus on a man named Edgar (a bit of a
ham-fisted reference if you ask me); a quiet man that lacks experience
with women. When he notices a young lady named Betty in a house across
the street; he resolves to romance her and asks his close friend Carl
for advice on how to speak to women. He and Betty are getting on well;
until he discovers that Carl and Betty are also getting on well, and so
Carl is murdered.The film is shot in black and white and looks really cheap throughout.
Director Ernest Morris appears not to have the resolve to elevate the
film above the mundane and also fails to get a good performance out of
his any of his (relatively) unknown cast; which renders the whole
production rather bland. Of course, the whole film is just build up to
the inevitable situation whereby the murderous central character is
haunted by the echoes of the beating heart from the man he has killed,
and this leaves most of it feeling rather pointless. To the film's
credit, however, it does handle Poe's actual story well and things do
become much more interesting once we reach the main part of the film.
This version of The Tell-Tale Heart never really gets into the
psychological side of Poe's original story; and the reason for that
really just goes back to the characters, which aren't interesting
enough. Overall, this is really a lacklustre effort and I wouldn't
recommend tracking it down; this story is more suited to a short film
anyway, and I'm sure that at least one of the many short film versions
is superior to this effort.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>