<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>La vendetta di Ercole</original_title><alt_title>La vengeance d'Hercule</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Vittorio Cottafavi</director><producer>Achille Piazzi Produzioni Cinematografica</producer><producer>Comptoir Français du Film Production (CFFP)</producer><producer>Produzione Gianni Fuchs</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis>
A warrior returning home to his country must battle giant bats, three-headed dogs and a vicious dragon to save his wife, and his people, from the machinations of an evil ruler.
</synopsis><actor>Mark Forest</actor><actor>Broderick Crawford</actor><actor>Gaby André</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3630708/comments</url><from>from Berkeley, CA, USA</from><name>steven-222</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw the Alpha Video DVD of GOLIATH AND THE DRAGON, which is from a
well-preserved widescreen print, and it's dazzling to look at! To be
sure, the color balance goes a bit wonky in a few outdoor scenes, but
the aquamarine trees and purple skies almost seem intentional, given
the strangeness of director Vittorio Cottafavi's vision. If all the old
sword and sandal epics were in this good a shape, the genre would
attract many more fans.The movie itself is a delirious muscleman fantasy from start to finish.
A bearded Mark Forest shows off the biggest pecs and widest lats of his
generation, and melts everyone with his smile (except scar-faced
Broderick Crawford as the cranky villain). The costumes are beautiful,
the sets are extravagant, the exterior landscapes are a lush paradise,
the monsters are huge puppets, and just when you think the story can't
become more bizarre...it does! An absurdly majestic music score by Les
Baxter strives to match the melodrama of a hero who dares to revolt
against the gods themselves.Cottafavi will try just about anything to dazzle and disorient the
viewer. In one scene, as our hero approaches, looms above, and then
passes over the camera, the point of view turns completely upside-down;
the effect is so audacious I had to laugh out loud! This is fearless
(and yes, perhaps sometimes mindless) film-making, and the result is
truly dreamlike, if not downright mythic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1199344/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>PrincessAnanka</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Mark Forest, aka Lou Degni from the Bronx, made his movie debut in this
colorful swords and sandals saga and became an overnight sensation. No
one had ever seen muscles that big--or beautiful--with a body and a
sensually beautiful face to go along with it. No, not even Steve Reeves
could match Forest in this department. His torso is incredible. With
the biggest pectorals and lats in the business and a justly famed
ridged stomach. Although born in the Bronx, he became the most sought
after physique model of the 50s and later won Mr. America and Mr.
Universe. Everyone agreed it wasn't just his stupendous physique that
made him a sensation. He had a smile and charisma to burn. This is
captured in this film and he went on to make a string of highly
successful muscle men features, the best of them, "Kindar the
Invulnerable" and "Hercules versus the Mongols" and "Hercules versus
the Barbarians." Forest left Italy at the peak of his career to return
to America to study opera and performed all over Europe. Today, he
still teaches voice and sings and works--surprise--as a personal
trainer to a handful of lucky stars in Los Angeles.. Reeves may have
been the king of Italy's muscle movies during the 60s but his prince
was Mark Forest--perhaps the biggest and most fabulous of them all.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1570951/comments</url><from>from Philadelphia, PA</from><name>Erzebet von Tepes de Neirhazi (luciemanet@netzero.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Broderick Crawford plays his role of a corrupt would-be emperor like
he
were still playing a 20th century gangster.  Watch him bark orders to
soldiers like he were plotting a gangland rubout.  Meanwhile Mark Forest
is
the hero called "Emilius" who is nicknamed Goliath because he is so strong
and (apparently) immortal.  He also has a younger brother is is neither
superstrong nor immortal and a mortal wife who is not bothered by the fact
that she will eventually grow old and die but he won't.  Go
figure.
Most of us watch these movies for the monsters and oft-times the
cheesier the better.  After a mechanical 3 headed fire breathing dog
(ahem,
that is NOT Cerberus!), a man in suit giant bat and a centaur (which had
to
have been the most uncomfortable costume in the bunch) seeing a dragon
that
is partially stop motion animated was a real treat.  Oh yeah, in closeups
it
is a giant rubber prop but those few moments of animation make it
worthwhile.
There is enough plot here for 2 movies and it does not always make
perfect sense but the action will keep your attention.  Oh and look
closely
at that dragon.  David Hewitt borrowed some of the stop-motion scenes for
his no budget thriller THE MIGHTY GORGA.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1546152/comments</url><from>from Colorado Springs, CO</from><name>TheVid</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Broderick Crawford is a slimy politician in a toga and Mark Forest
(bodybuilder Lou Degni) is muscleman Goliath in this kitsch epic from
Italy,
exploited to the max in the U.S. by American International pictures during
the drive-in heydays of the late 50's and early 60's.
This one's quite a potboiler, with a various assortment of cheesy monster
creations (including some very brief stop-motion footage by Jim Danforth),
the usual buxom babes with big Roman hairdos and, of course, the solid and
stiff muscleman hero performing various feats of strength
(like wrestling a bear suit and, rather impressively, genuinely warding off
a real elephant!).  It's all a lot of nostalgic fun and the new DVD release
is a revelation in quality, bringing back the bright color and widescreen
TotalScope ratio of the original theatrical presentation.  The DVD is also
packed with campy tributes to the whole muscleman, sword-and-sandal genre,
including a gallery of trailers, shorts and even an entire second strongman
feature, the truly ridiculous CONQUERER OF ATLANTIS!  Get ready for a great
late-night schlockfest with this package!  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4166957/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>horrorfilmx</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I saw the poster for GOLIATH AND THE DRAGON outside a theater when I
was a kid and was dying to see it. Unfortunately I had to wait over
thirty years until just the other day when I found a cheap VHS copy in
a video store. Was it worth the wait? Absolutely --- but not for the
reasons I'd expected. In addition to the cool poster what intrigued me
about the film were the Jim Danforth stop motion sequences added for
the American release. Pictures of the dragon made it look pretty good.
Unfortunately the model is poorly used in the film itself, and nowhere
is it shown off to such good advantage as in the publicity stills.
Animation-wise the film was a major disappointment.And other-wise? Well, you gotta give this movie a big A for Ambition.
Hercules (excuse me, GOLIATH) doesn't just duke it out with soldiers,
he battles a three headed dog, a bat monster, a centaur, a bear, and at
one point even wrestles an elephant to the ground! Unfortunately none
of these conflicts is handled with anything like the skill needed to
really bring them off, but you've gotta love them for trying. And the
movie, goofy and slipshod as it is, never bores. Peplum fans should
check it out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
"King Eurystheus rules the land with cruelty and terror, using his
monsters to keep the people under his control. Goliath returns home to
find his wife and the people in peril from the monsters and vows to
defeat the creatures and overthrow the wicked king. Our hero is faced
with the task of fighting a three-headed fire-breathing dog, a giant
bat, a centaur, and finally a dragon before he can confront King
Eurystheus for the fate of the kingdom," according to the DVD sleeve's
synopsis.Re-titled "Goliath and the Dragon" for American International Pictures
release, this Italian film arrived as the Herculean "sword and sandal"
genre was gaining steam. There are some good locations and sets; but,
the overall production is nothing special. As mini-skirted Mark Forest
(as Hercules aka Goliath) goes through the regular routine, the plot
interest is on brother Sandro Moretti (as Illo aka Illus) and lover
Federica Ranchi (as Thea), who is forcibly betrothed to... Broderick
Crawford!*** La vendetta di Ercole (8/12/60) Vittorio Cottafavi ~ Mark Forest,
Broderick Crawford, Sandro Moretti, Leonora Ruffo
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3902771/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>thinker1691</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
In the 1960's as a child I and dozens of theater goers were watching
this interesting Movie called " Goliath and the Dragon " when a small
fire in the building sent everyone racing out in a panic. Although, I
got the price of admission back, (15 cents) I never did get to finish
the film. Due to the fact, I was very young, I was most impressed with
the parts of the movie I did get to see. It is years later and I
finally got to see the entire movie completely. I am surprised to sit
through the entire film without yawning. The scenes which intrigued and
captivated me as a child, were laughable as an adult. However, I am
impressed with the story of how Goliath or Hercules was able to
mesmerize young impressible audiences with such a small budget and
hokey special effects. Still, as a grown-up I would quickly recommend
this film to young members of the audience as they have not lost their
imagination or have forgotten what it means to be inspired by
flickering images. During the Sword and Sandal era, these movies are
the very inspiration we received when it was needed most. How else
could Gods, Goddesses, Monsters, Centars and heroic deeds have
impressed us so much? Recommended! *****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
For a sword and sandal movie, Goliath and the Dragon has about the most
convoluted and ridiculously hard to follow plot that I can remember. It
was kind of like watching two or more different movies at the same time
where the pieces just never seem to fit into a cohesive whole. Based on
what I did get out of it, King Eurystheus (Broderick Crawford) has it
out for Goliath. He kidnaps Goliath's brother Illus and, when that
doesn't work, he kidnaps Goliath's wife. King Eurystheus also has the
hots for a babe about a third his age who just happens to be in love
with Illus. To win her over, King Eurystheus takes the reasoned
approach of having her imprisoned as well. In the meantime, Goliath is
off doing battle with a three-headed dog, a giant flying bat creature,
a wife-snatching centaur, and a dragon that can't seem to decide
whether it's a stop-motion creature or a big, goofy looking puppet. In
the end, Goliath literally brings down the walls of King Eurystheus'
fortress and, with the help of an army from Thebes, saves the day.Overall, Goliath and the Dragon is a real mixed bag – hence my very
average 5/10 rating. There's a lot about the movie I enjoyed. The
beyond cheesy fight scenes with the various creatures I mentioned is an
obvious place to start. These scenes are just plain old fun. I also
enjoyed the scenes of prisoners being crushed by a trained elephant.
You don't see stuff like that everyday. Watching Goliath tackle the
elephant was a hoot. But when Goliath and the Dragon is bad, it's real
bad. Some of the acting is painful. Mark Forest, the requisite body in
this sword and sandal epic, is about as wooden as you'll find in one of
these movies. He moves in a very unnatural manner that looked odd to me
for lack of a better word. And what's Broderick Crawford doing in this
movie? He's so out of place I often felt embarrassed for him. Another
big negative for me is how deathly dull much of the movie is. When
Goliath's not fighting some creature, the movie can be terribly sleep
inducing. Too many unnecessarily confusing plot points, too many
characters I didn't know or care about, and too many scenes with
nothing going on – not the sign of a what I'd call a good movie. Like I
said, Goliath and the Dragon is a real mixed bag.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Mark Forest as Goliath in a more spectacular than usual sword and
sandal production. The film co stars Broderick Crawford as the villain
trying to take over Goliath's kingdom while he is out battling monsters
in order to complete a task for favored goddess.The film and the plot are typical for the genre, however the film has a
larger than normal number of supernatural creatures including gods,
multi-headed dogs, winged monsters, and a dragon. The film also has
some large scale action set pieces that make it clear they spent a
couple of bucks on the film. In no way serious or deep, its the sort of
mindless spectacle that you can let wash over you on a Sunday
afternoon. I've seen most of the films in the swords and sandal cycle
and this is one of the most enjoyable and best made. Worth a
look-especially if you can get one of the great looking letterboxed
editions floating around.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0863093/comments</url><from>from Seattle, WA</from><name>Steve O.</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Mark Forest looks incredibly handsome and acts very competently in his
first peplum outing. His physique is awesome and he handles the fights
and action sequences with aplomb, even battling silly rubber monsters
with passion and conviction.The two things that make so many peplum movies boring -- talky court
intrigue and confusing, interminable battle scenes -- are kept to a
minimum here, which make this faster-moving and more entertaining than
most.The film serves up of a lot of what most of us watch peplum for: crazy
monsters and imaginative, surreal action scenes like the one where
Forest demolishes a palace by knocking down the stalactites in the cave
beneath it.Definitely recommended for fans of the genre. One thing I don't
understand, though. Goliath's wife dies near the end, but in the final
shot we see her alive again, smooching with her husband. Was this
contrived "happy ending" created by moving a shot from early in the
film to the end? I haven't seen anyone else comment on this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0863093/comments</url><from>from Seattle, WA</from><name>Steve O.</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Mark Forest looks incredibly handsome and acts very competently in his
first peplum outing. His physique is awesome and he handles the fights
and action sequences with aplomb, even battling silly rubber monsters
with passion and conviction.The two things that make so many peplum movies boring -- talky court
intrigue and confusing, interminable battle scenes -- are kept to a
minimum here, which make this faster-moving and more entertaining than
most.The film serves up of a lot of what most of us watch peplum for: crazy
monsters and imaginative, surreal action scenes like the one where
Forest demolishes a palace by knocking down the stalactites in the cave
beneath it.Definitely recommended for fans of the genre. One thing I don't
understand, though. Goliath's wife dies near the end, but in the final
shot we see her alive again, smooching with her husband. Was this
contrived "happy ending" created by moving a shot from early in the
film to the end? I haven't seen anyone else comment on this.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/loves_of_hercules/comments.php?reviewid=1426549</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>