<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Krzyzacy</original_title><alt_title>Les chevaliers teutoniques</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Poland</country><director>Aleksander Ford</director><producer>Zespol Filmowy "Studio"</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>
A tale of a young impoverished nobleman, who with his uncle returns from a war against the order of the Teutonic Knights in Lithuania...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Urszula Modrzynska</actor><actor>Grazyna Staniszewska</actor><actor>Andrzej Szalawski</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3630708/comments</url><from>from Berkeley, CA, USA</from><name>steven-222</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
KNIGHTS OF THE TEUTONIC ORDER, based on the novel by Nobel winner
Henryk Sienkiewicz, is full of intensely melodramatic conflicts and
nonstop action; Sienkiewicz's fiction was more in the mold of THE THREE
MUSKETEERS and IVANHOE than WAR AND PEACE, and the source material
makes for a highly entertaining movie. The epic scope is quite
impressive (fully comparable to Hollywood epics of the same era, like
QUO VADIS or SPARTACUS). The setting will be unfamiliar to many
audiences (Poland and Prussia in the middle ages), but the plight of
the Polish knight Jurand as he and his family are tormented by the
dastardly Teutonic Knights is emotionally involving. I saw this in 2005
on a not-so-good video from Polart (washed-out color, poor subtitles),
but I've recently seen a DVD on offer, which I hope will have higher
quality; it's a handsomely made film that deserves restoration and a
wider audience.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0973098/comments</url><from>from Krakow, Poland</from><name>nergal18 (nergal18@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The best historical movie ever set in Middle Ages. After 40 years it is
still unbeatable. There is no single minute without action and no chance of
getting bored. The film, based on the novel by Henryk Sienkiewicz, was seen
by over 30 million Poles and is a must for historical movie fan. Many
scenes
hit a viewer with power and skill but nothing beats the battle of Grunwald
sequence, which lasts almost 20 minutes. Every Hollywood film lacks such
sequence. No detail is bit of absurd as it sometimes happens in American
movies. Actors are at their peak, especially Andrzej Szalawski(Jurand) who
plays his best role. Absolutely worth of seeing.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1966202/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>muellerroth</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I saw the German dubbed version of this movie over 20 years ago, when I
was
maybe 7 or 8 years old.  Nonetheless, I have most vivid memories of this
movie. This is a rare masterpiece, that sparks every little boys
imagination, simply spectacular. I would love to see this movie again but
so
far no luck finding it on video.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0162275/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>Mick898 (mick898@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I have seen this movie many years ago. This movie to my knowledge is one
of
the best Knights movies that ever been made. The plot is fantastic and the
ending is a very sad one. This movie shows to what extreme some people
would
go to avenge even if they are in the wrong. A great movie and not enough
acclaimed to my satisfaction.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11215533/comments</url><from>from Russian Federation</from><name>denis888</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Polish cinema is always good at adapting heroic war films like Potop or
Ogniem I Mieczem. This one, based upon the book of the Noble Prize
winner, Henryk Sienkiewycz, is a real hit. The directors managed to
adapt this large and serious historical novel to a screen version. The
plot tells about the wars between Poland and the Knights who were
called the Crerss Bearers and lived in old Prussia nearby. The
thrilling story tells about two brave and valiant Polish knights, Macko
and Zbyszek. This story has everything - love story, tragedy of the
Polish people being oppressed by the knights of Prussia, the heroic
struggle, and on top of it all, the Grunwald Battle, that was the
deafening defeat of the Prussian knights and lead to the changes in
their history after that. Music, operators' work, actors' play,
especially the parts of Henryk Borowski and Mieczyslaw Voit are
impeccable. This is a fine example of the classic Polish battle movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1802666/comments</url><from>from California</from><name>ania2001</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Good acting.
Great plot.
This is a very sad movie, but it presents the true facts in
history.
It should be released on DVD.
One of the best Polish movies.
I recommend this movie to everyone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12394050/comments</url><from>from Poland</from><name>mizb</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The movie is based on a Sienkiewicz's novel written in 1910 (500th
anniversary of Tannenberg battle) and during the time of top German
power in Europe. The content describes the life of medieval Polish
gentry on the background of historical events (conflicts between the
German Teutonic Orden and Kingdoms of Poland and Lithuania). Shows, how
crude and cruel the life was that time. The movie has been made about
1960 on order of communist and para-nationalist propaganda to
illustrate the role of alliance between Poles and "eastern nations" in
stopping the German expansionism (a cold war ran that time, Poland had
no diplomatic links with FR of Germany, which was putting Poland's
western borders into questioning). The final Tannenberg battle scene is
probably the best one battle movie in the history of cinematography.
However, some propaganda accents have been put, i.e. German knights
shooting "Heil!" at the beginning of the battle. The main tune of the
film is to present Poles as a fit and sound nation.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3034018/comments</url><from>from Vancouver Canada</from><name>pkolasa (pkolasa@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is movie made in 1960. It features REAL extras numbering at least
35 000 people. How many American movies have that many extras to start
with??? 2 people DIED in making of this movie, because the battle is so
realistic. It has excellent plot, begging for a remake by Spielberg,
Soderberg or Petersen! Or Mel Gibson :)It's based on a novel by NOBEL prize winning writer Sienkiewicz. He is
only matched by Robert Graves of "I, Claudius". The costumes are
realistic. The locations are accurate. This was about one of 10 battles
defining the destiny of the world, yet because, it's in Eastern Europe
it's downplayed by the West, which is arrogant and proud of its
ignorance, lol. As if it was something to brag about ;)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0962765/comments</url><from>from FINLAND</from><name>Oslo Jargo (osloj@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Watching this was a chore. It is, for the entire length of the film,
nothing but anti-German Propaganda. The Teutonic Knights are played by
steel eyed doofuses. The battle scenes are terrible; repetitive
editing, horse riders jumping off horses for no reason, and no one is
ever hit by a weapon it seems. Plus, there's not enough extras to fill
in the gaps for the battle so it looks like a small fight between inept
idiots.The Polish are played by good natured nobles and there's an annoying
quote to "god" about every 20 seconds. I can't recommend this since
it's so tepid and dull.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5564095/comments</url><from>from Poland</from><name>gabajelenska</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
It is a good film and - as some reviews pointed out - of quite a big
importance (and sentimental value!) to Poles. As every nation, Poles
delight in productions illuminating the splendor years or turning
points in their history, so the film has a guaranteed place in the
pantheon of Polish films. It is begging for a remake though. If it is
to be equally enjoyable for younger generations technical anachronisms
and especially lengthy scenes need to be taken care of. The plot is
great, so it definitely deserves a lifting. Apart from the
extraordinary number of horses and extras, and Guiness record long
battle scenes the film is famous for 2 amazing goofs: 1. In one of the
battles, far beyond the herd of knights, you can see a crew car happily
passing on the horizon 2. During the main battle of Grunwald scene
(1410!) an electric watch can be seen on the actor's wrist as the
Polish king zestfully waves his sword fighting his opponents.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5564095/comments</url><from>from Poland</from><name>gabajelenska</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
It is a good film and - as some reviews pointed out - of quite a big
importance (and sentimental value!) to Poles. As every nation, Poles
delight in productions illuminating the splendor years or turning
points in their history, so the film has a guaranteed place in the
pantheon of Polish films. It is begging for a remake though. If it is
to be equally enjoyable for younger generations technical anachronisms
and especially lengthy scenes need to be taken care of. The plot is
great, so it definitely deserves a lifting. Apart from the
extraordinary number of horses and extras, and Guiness record long
battle scenes the film is famous for 2 amazing goofs: 1. In one of the
battles, far beyond the herd of knights, you can see a crew car happily
passing on the horizon 2. During the main battle of Grunwald scene
(1410!) an electric watch can be seen on the actor's wrist as the
Polish king zestfully waves his sword fighting his opponents.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5564095/comments</url><from>from Poland</from><name>gabajelenska</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>