<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hell Is a City</original_title><alt_title>Un homme pour le bagne</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Val Guest</director><producer>Hammer Film Productions</producer><producer>Associated British Picture Corporation (ABPC)</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Committed but seen-it-all police inspector Martineau rightly guesses that after a violent jailbreak a local criminal will head home to Manchester to pick up the spoils from his last job...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Stanley Baker</actor><actor>John Crawford</actor><actor>Donald Pleasence</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I had been postponing my purchase of this and another Stanley Baker
crime drama, Joseph Losey's THE CRIMINAL (1960; see below), ever since
their DVD release back in 2002; ironically, what eventually pushed me
into ordering them was the recent death of this film's director Val
Guest - at the venerable age of 94! Well, all I can say is that I was
foolish to have deprived myself of it for so long; this is surely one
of the best British crime films ever and, being an atypical release for
Hammer, is also one of their finest non-horror efforts! During the excellent Audio Commentary included on the splendid Anchor
Bay DVD edition, Guest admitted that one of his major influences (and
not only on this particular film) had been Jules Dassin's innovative
THE NAKED CITY (1948) and, curiously enough, one has to go back to
Dassin's own NIGHT AND THE CITY (1950) to find an equally hard-hitting
British noir!; then again, the film was ahead of its time since it
would be years before a similarly truthful depiction of a policeman's
domestic life would emerge in the U.S. (THE DETECTIVE and MADIGAN {both
1968}, for instance). The film is a veritable class act in every
department: Guest's direction never puts a foot wrong and his
screenplay (adapted from a novel by Maurice Proctor and deservedly
nominated for a BAFTA award) is truly exceptional; Arthur Grant's
chiaroscuro camera-work (mostly shot in real Manchester locations) is
stunning; while Stanley Black's jazzy score lends the fast-paced if
rather involved proceedings the requisite urgency.Stanley Baker has one of his best leading roles as the tough cop who
tries to make several ends meet - catch a dangerous criminal (American
actor John Crawford, very effective) who's basically his alter ego,
save his childless marriage with selfish Maxine Audley, and escape the
daily temptation of a fling with the carnal (despite being middle-aged)
but genuinely concerned barmaid Vanda Godsell (who also happens to be
Crawford's old flame). Donald Pleasence has an important,
scene-stealing supporting role as a bookmaker marked for robbery by
Crawford - who had also been intimate with Pleasence's sluttish young
wife (Billie Whitelaw who, despite this being her 12th feature film,
was impressive enough to be up for the "Most Promising Newcomer" BAFTA
award - and is even featured in a brief but startling nude scene which
was promptly snipped for the U.S. version!). The rest of the cast is
filled with familiar character actors, many of them members of Guest's
own stock company.Among the film's best scenes are the swift alleyway heist towards the
beginning (which ends in murder), the wonderful "tossing school" (an
illegal form of gambling) scene which takes place on the moors, several
grueling interrogation scenes (with Baker often reduced to blackmailing
his hard-as-nails 'customers') and the remarkably violent rooftop
climax. By the way, I wasn't as displeased as Guest was with the
alternate ending included as an extra (and which he had never seen
before!) - inverting a couple of scenes and adding a brief hopeful coda
(not filmed by Guest) with Baker and Audley - but I totally respect the
director's decision to stick with his uncompromising original vision.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4547709/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>mb014f2908</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I watched Hell is a City on DVD again the other day and was struck by
how fresh and undated the story and acting still appears. It was a
breakout Brit film for 1959/60- with its semi-documentary approach to
police procedure,meshed with a tough on women approach and attempt to
show relationships that don't have happy endings. On the DVD there is
an alternate ending shown, which the director Val Guest claims to have
no knowledge of at all! It's much weaker i think than Guest's own
choice of ending. Stanley Baker is excellent; successfully showing all
dimensions to an Inspector's working/personal life; Billie Whitelaw got
nominated that year with the BAA for in the Newcomer category and
deservedly so. All the support cast flesh out their characters' quirks
very well. Actual location shooting (in this case-Manchester) was still
quite unusual and there is a world of difference between this and a
studio based crime thriller of maybe 10 years before.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3192075/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>jeremyehowell</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a wonderful example of how worldly some british films can seem,
while maintaining their local flavor. I believe that this film is very
appropriately set in Manchester, anyone having been to Manchester will
tell
you its quite a tough place.50s British entertainment was heavily influenced by Hollywood and
continued
to be influenced especially on TV until the late 70s, when things all
started to get a bit colorless. This movie was made in a time when
entertainment came first and the needs of the audience and hence a box
office return, came before the politically correct requirements of the
day.
Having said that I have to say I'm VERY glad that you don't see many
characters quite as sorry as Martineau's repressed housebound wife these
days!For those who are not familiar with director Val Guest - check out his
other
movies. He was a director who knew exactly what he was
doing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1162550/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>movieman_kev</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Inspector Martineau knows in his gut that a recently escaped criminal
will come back to the scene of the crime to recover the goods that he's
stolen. It's up to him to piece together the new assignment that he's
given and trace it back to the guilty party. Stanley Baker shines as
Martineau (one year later Baker would be in one of the greatest war
films ever with "The Guns of Navarone") in this taunt, gripping little
crime thriller by Val Guest. All the minor characters are equally good.
This is one film that I wouldn't mind revisiting. Another great film to
come out of the sadly defunct Hammer studios.My Grade:B+ DVD Extras: Commentary by Val Guest and Journalist Ted Newsom;
Alternate Ending; Talent Bios for Val Guest and Stanley Baker; and
Theatrical Trailer Eye Candy:a blink and you'll miss it Billy Whitelaw topless scene
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0538451/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Popey-6</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

No other film of this period gives such a clear indication of the attempt of
British crime thrillers to become more exciting.The introduction of John Crawford as the American bad guy and one time buddy
of Stanley Baker is enthralling to watch and can seem slightly odd and out
of place. The opening sequences are reminiscent of British TV show 'Z Cars'
and were later spoofed in Naked Gun (though not as a direct result of this).Donald Pleasance is very reliable as the Jewellry Shop owner who has much to
reveal, while Baker himself plays another tough cop as he did in Blind Date
(1959) and Violent Playground (1958) - the latter was also directed by Val
Guest.Look out for the climactic sequences - gripping stuff and still ever so
British.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Inspector Harry Martineau is a hard-edged police man in gritty Manchester.
When a major criminal, Don Stirling, escapes from jail by killing a guard
Martineau makes it his person responsibility to hunt him down. Stirling gets
his old gang together to steal £4000 from wealthy businessman Gus. However
the theft goes wrong and a young girl is killed and the money begins to
leave behind a trail that will lead to the gang.This desperately wants to be an English 1950's American style film noir. It
has the gritty urban title, it has a moody lead actor with an iffy moral
code, a pumping jazz soundtrack and is surprisingly tough. It isn't
completely successful because of one main problem - it's in England. In
Manchester. It's tough even for someone who lives here to take it as
seriously as the Bogart-esque equivalents. It's an unfair criticism perhaps
but it is off-putting to hear the thick Yorkshire accents in the setting of
an urban crime drama.There is quite a lot to like here. The plot is interesting with gritty
levels, the whole idea of the money being dyed and staining hands is a good
concept and only seems stretched occasionally and is actually a very
effective way of leaving a money trail. The jazz score does give the film a
real feel of a urban crime zone, but at times it feels a bit out of place
with some of the scenes.The 2 lead performances are mixed in their roles. Stanley Baker is good as
Martineau mixing the role with a bad guy edge by being distant from his wife
etc, but he isn't as convincing as his American equivalents. You never are
totally convinced that he is anything but a good guy, with his only real
faults being his commitment to work over his wife. John Crawford is better
as Stirling who benefits from not having an English accent. He plays the
violent, cruel criminal well and is totally convincing. It's also good to
see Donald Pleasance in a small role as Gus, but his accent is frighteningly
thick.The film is surprisingly tough. I assumed that this would be a lesser film
because it's British but this has quite strong language (although not by
today's standards) and is very violent considering when it was made. There
is quite a bit of violence towards women all of which gives the film a much
more believable very tough edge that adds to it's credentials as a crime
thriller.Overall a strong attempt to make a British film noir. It loses something
with Baker being too clean-cut in his role and the Manchester setting and
accents are hard to line up mentally with the action. But hey - it's pretty
good.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Hammer studios are, of course, best known for their horror films; but
early on in the studio's history, there were a number of noir style
films produced; and while this is one of the later efforts, it's surely
one of the best! The film is clearly intended to mimic the American
film noir being produced en mass during the fifties; although the film
does retain an aura of Britishness which is achieved through the
locations and strong accents of most of the lead characters. The film
is suitably dark, though not as dark as many of its American
counterparts. The plot focuses on a criminal that has escaped from jail
after committing a robbery that went wrong. Inspector Harry Martineau,
who happened to have gone to school with the criminal, guesses that he
will return home to Manchester in order to pick up his share from the
job. The criminal does return to Manchester and ends up with the
inspector on his tail as he moves through the underworld, trying to
find a place to hide.Writer-director Val Guest (who previously directed a handful of
Hammer's earliest horror films) spins an interesting story that remains
intriguing throughout. The dialogue is surprisingly witty at times, and
the characters are 'cool' enough to rival the films that this one is
trying to imitate. There's more to the plot than just what is
immediately going on, and the inspector's personal life is one of the
main sub-plots. This thread is somewhat well expanded; although it has
to be said that some other areas of the plot do not go as far as they
could; although at only ninety minutes, there was obviously only so
much that could be squeezed in. The film moves forward well, although
at times it is a little silly; a plot that hinges on the idea of nobody
looking at their hands is somewhat far fetched. The cast is strong,
with Stanley Baker and John Crawford taking the lead roles and doing
well with them; there's also a small appearance for the great Donald
Pleasance. Overall, Hell is a City is an excellent British noir, and
well worth a look.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8239592/comments</url><from>from The Last New Jersey Drive-In on the Left</from><name>Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Cunning, lethal, ruthless criminal Don Starling (excellently played by
John Crawford) escapes from jail and returns to Manchester to perform a
robbery. Rugged, no-nonsense, hot-tempered Inspector Harry Martineau (a
superbly hard-boiled performance by Stanley Baker) is bound and
determined to nab Starling. Things get sticky when Starling kills a
19-year-old girl during the heist and the manhunt becomes a much more
deadly pursuit. Writer/director Val Guest keeps the pace rattling along
at a brisk clip, maintains an uncompromisingly tough-edged tone
throughout, and does an expert job of creating a seedy urban
atmosphere. Stanley Black's rousing, swinging jazz score really hits
the spot. Arthur Grant's crisp, handsome, agile black-and-white
cinematography likewise impresses. The occasional outbursts of raw
violence are shockingly brutal. The climactic rooftop chase between
Starling and Martineau is genuinely tense and exciting. Baker and
Crawford excel in the leads; they receive fine support from Donald
Pleasence as irritable book maker Gus Hawkins, Maxine Audley as
Martineau's fed-up, neglected, long-suffering wife Julia, Billie
Whitelaw as Gus' trampy wife Chloe (she's also Starling's frightened
former old flame), Vanda Godsell as sassy bar maid Lucretia "Lucky"
Luske, Joseph Tomelty as feisty old duffer Furnisher Steele, and George
A. Cooper as petty gambler Doug Savage. A highly atypical Hammer
Studios production, this rough and hard-hitting crime thriller winner
makes for completely absorbing and satisfying viewing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6870994/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>BJJManchester</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
A surprisingly tough,no-nonsense crime thriller for it's time,HELL IS A
CITY (set in my hometown Manchester) has a fairly routine plot but has
compensations with fast-moving direction by Val Guest,a decent script,a
fine jazz score by Stanley Black,and most of all,first-class
photography on actual Mancunian locations.This was something of a first
for British crime thrillers for this period,which were mostly shot in
dingy studio sets,but director Guest's decision to film many scenes
outdoors,and in a provincial city as well(virtually all of this film's
contemporaries were set in London,particularly Soho),is
refreshing,fairly innovative and gives a sense of realism that is
unusual but welcome,especially in this era(the late 50's -early 60's)
of UK film-making.Unfortunately,there are some compromises that mitigate against the
film;one is the casting of American John Crawford(who appeared in
several other British thrillers around this period)as the murderous
villain which strains credibility somewhat;Crawford makes no attempt to
hide his American accent,which makes his role as a native(as the script
makes clear) hard to take;there are rather obvious domestic scenes of
strife with Inspector Stanley Baker and spouse that drag the pace down
somewhat(it would have been better simply to concentrate on the basic
story)and seem irrelevant,and Guest falters when he makes some obvious
attempts to imitate Hollywood film-noirs;he is better when he sticks to
straightforward,semi-documentary realism.The film features very few Mancunian actors (only John Comer,and Doris
Speed,who very soon after began her stint as TV's most famous
barmaid,Annie Walker,in CORONATION STREET);they are mostly from
Yorkshire or Southern England,and Welshman Baker occasionally struggles
with his Northern English accent. Never afraid to play
unsympathetic,dislikable heroes,Baker is still good in the lead role,in
his familiar virile,aggressive and uncompromising persona.This style of
acting led the way out of the rather stuffy,RADA-accented manner that
had held back British cinema for years into more a working-class,gritty
and realistic era,and somewhat better films.HELL IS A CITY has it's faults,but is valuable today as an unexpected
social document of Manchester of the time,and has much more than a
touch of class than other contemporary routine crime dramas,thanks to
the reasons stated above.Rating:6 and a half out of 10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
"Life on Mars"?This is more like life on Pluto.Mr Stanley Baker plays
the type of cop who feels compelled to try it on with any female with a
pulse. He can't walk past an open pub door and threatens to rape his
wife in order to impregnate her against her will.Just another day at
the office for one of Manchester's finest. "Hell is a city" is an over
- rated pseudo Don Siegel opus.Possibly seeing itself as a herald of a
new hard - hitting school of Britcop movies,it has a sub - sub Elmer
Bernstein/Leith Stevens/Shorty Rogers soundtrack of generic Britjazz
cobbled together by that clever musical chameleon Mr Stanley Black that
places it exactly in its era. It borrows that hoary old Western plot
about childhood companions turned deadly adversaries that ends with one
of them dangling on the end of a rope.Full of British actors assuming
the all - encompassing "Northern" accent that is both inaccurate and
insulting to its Manchester setting, it deals the English language a
further blow by having an American play a Manc villain,a piece of
casting of breathtaking audacity and indifference to the audience's
intelligence. Cardboard character follows cardboard character muttering
"eee by gum" imprecations,Yorkshire and Lancashire dialects being
freely mixed.Stanley Baker's Inspector Martineau is a despicable woman
- hating psychopath.Novelist Maurice Procter who wrote the novel on
which the movie was based was said to be "delighted" with the result.It
all seems a bit rum to me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
"Life on Mars"?This is more like life on Pluto.Mr Stanley Baker plays
the type of cop who feels compelled to try it on with any female with a
pulse. He can't walk past an open pub door and threatens to rape his
wife in order to impregnate her against her will.Just another day at
the office for one of Manchester's finest. "Hell is a city" is an over
- rated pseudo Don Siegel opus.Possibly seeing itself as a herald of a
new hard - hitting school of Britcop movies,it has a sub - sub Elmer
Bernstein/Leith Stevens/Shorty Rogers soundtrack of generic Britjazz
cobbled together by that clever musical chameleon Mr Stanley Black that
places it exactly in its era. It borrows that hoary old Western plot
about childhood companions turned deadly adversaries that ends with one
of them dangling on the end of a rope.Full of British actors assuming
the all - encompassing "Northern" accent that is both inaccurate and
insulting to its Manchester setting, it deals the English language a
further blow by having an American play a Manc villain,a piece of
casting of breathtaking audacity and indifference to the audience's
intelligence. Cardboard character follows cardboard character muttering
"eee by gum" imprecations,Yorkshire and Lancashire dialects being
freely mixed.Stanley Baker's Inspector Martineau is a despicable woman
- hating psychopath.Novelist Maurice Procter who wrote the novel on
which the movie was based was said to be "delighted" with the result.It
all seems a bit rum to me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/chris-cabin/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Hell-Is-a-City /m/hell_is_a_city/comments.php?reviewid=1837119</url><name>Chris Cabin</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/5
					</rating><comment>harkens back to the pulp serials where noir was birthed</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/hellisacity.htm /m/hell_is_a_city/comments.php?reviewid=841654</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>It's a gritty Hammer story.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/hell_is_a_city/comments.php?reviewid=1445990</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117791586.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/hell_is_a_city/comments.php?reviewid=1805605</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/71912/hell_is_a_city.html /m/hell_is_a_city/comments.php?reviewid=1517711</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9502E5DB1739EE32A2575AC1A9679C946091D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/hell_is_a_city/comments.php?reviewid=1389468</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>