<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Man on a String</original_title><alt_title>Contre-espionnage</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>André De Toth</director><producer>RD-DR Productions</producer><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>A spy story that's tense, tough and true.</synopsis><actor>Ernest Borgnine</actor><actor>Kerwin Mathews</actor><actor>Colleen Dewhurst</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Based on the real life story of Boris Morros who was a musician instead
of a film producer, Man on a String comes at the tale end of the Cold
War espionage thrillers where there was absolutely no doubt as to who
the good guys and bad guys were on the screen.I can understand the reason for renaming the lead character that Ernest
Borgnine plays Boris Mitrov and changing his occupation even, for
dramatic purposes to give the character more scope. But for the life of
me was anyone fooled when the agency he worked for was renamed the
Central Bureau of Intelligence? Borris Morros has his own page on IMDb and you can see the rather
astonishing list of film credits he had, working on the scoring of a
whole lot of films, some of them classics like Stagecoach. His own life
gives a lie to the notion that there were no Communists in Hollywood.
The blunderbuss approach taken by the House Un-American Activities
Committee is another issue altogether.The Mitrov character we see here isn't exactly stealing the atomic
secrets, in fact he's not really doing any spying at all so to speak.
As the Russian agent says, all they're doing with him is buying his
good name to gain entrée into other places.Our own CIA knows that and turns him into a double agent where he does
perform useful work in identifying Soviet agents here. In real life it
wasn't quite as dramatic as shown in Man on a String.One thing that is of interest is that Man on a String, made as it was
in 1960 in the wake of Nikita Khruschev's boast about how he would bury
America. That is their attitude, that victory for them was inevitable
because Marx said that's how history was flowing. It's interesting to
watch this film now in the light of the fall of the Soviet Union. And
it fell because it's economy couldn't keep spending militarily and
provide its citizens with basic necessities.Man on a String is a Cold War relic, but interesting viewing
nonetheless.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
These sort of espionage stories are not favorites of mine unless done
with a storyline that is not too convoluted, as is sometimes the case
in these kind of spy thrillers. But if they're taut and suspenseful
throughout, I can forgive too many complications. Fortunately, the
cat-and-mouse game played here is understandable enough and crackles
with suspense and tension.MAN ON A STRING is a spy thriller based on the true-life adventures of
a real counter-spy Boris Morros (dubbed Boris Mitrov here), played by
ERNEST BORGNINE. While the plotting is far from simple, it's easy
enough to enjoy the air of menace and danger that permeates the entire
story without getting bogged down into the details of entrapment that
always accompany these spy stories.It moves at a brisk pace under the direction of Andre deToth (for
awhile, he was a husband of Veronica Lake in the '40s), and all of it
is filmed on locations in East and West Germany. KERWIN MATTHEWS is
Borgnine's fellow spy assigned to guide him through the various
activities, COLLEEN DEWHURST does well in her second film after a
couple of TV roles, and GLENN CORBETT is excellent as a government
agent.It's rather talky for the first hour and then builds to a tense climax
among the deserted buildings of East Germany when Mitrov's activities
become known to the Russians, which leads to a shootout scene that caps
the ending in a satisfying and suspenseful way.Borgnine gives a solid performance and the film itself is well worth
watching.There's a narration that gives it an almost documentary approach,
somewhat like another film produced by Louis De Rochemont, THE HOUSE ON
92nd STREET.Summing up: Crisp, exciting spy thriller.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This is a decent Cold War film about a Russian film director working in
the United States. While he is not a Communist, his "friends" are and
while he tells himself he isn't working for them, he has accepted
favors and naively thinks it will all somehow work out. However, when
he is confronted by the CBI(?) (a fictional US government agency), he
realizes he's become a Communist stooge and agrees to help the US in a
counter-espionage mission behind the Iron Curtain.While the film is a decent enough time-passer and the last 1/3 of the
film is pretty exciting, it has one giant problem and a few small ones.
Oddly, they decided to cast Ernest Borgnine as the Russian Director yet
he never even sounds the least bit Russian and you can STILL detect his
New York accent. This makes the entire film seem rather cheesy and very
tough to believe. Had they recast the film and perhaps punched up the
first 1/3, it could have been an exciting spy yarn. Oddly, just a few
years later, Borgnine was cast as a Russian in ICE STATION ZEBRA and he
was able to do a decent Russian accent! Additionally, when Borgnine's
character went to Moscow, it looked like a bad travelogue with all the
stock footage inserted rather haphazzardly into the movie. As it is,
it's just passable entertainment and a mildly interesting curio of the
Cold War.By the way, don't get the idea I hate Cold War films--I am a history
teacher and naturally love a good espionage film and could recommend
several good ones such as I MARRIED A COMMUNIST and ASSIGNMENT Paris.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Perhaps Borgnine is not the very first name that would come to mind
when casting a film about a Russian spy who is coerced into working as
a double agent, yet here he is, enjoying his brief tenure as a leading
man in the wake of his Oscar win for "Marty". He plays a Russian-born
Hollywood film producer (inspired somewhat by a real life man who was
in the music end of the film business) who has been goaded into passing
on secrets to the Communists in order to save the lives of his father
and brothers who remain in the USSR. He is discovered by young agent
Corbett (here referred to as working for the CBI, but clearly meant to
be the FBI) and is convinced to work both sides in order to avoid being
executed for his crimes. This involves his flying to West Berlin and
commuting between the free world and the Iron Curtain in an effort to
uncover the latest Communist plot against the US. Meanwhile, his
American cohort Matthews tries to ensure his safety and fellow red
spies Prentiss and Dewhurst work on exposing him in order to save their
own necks. The sometimes-pedestrian plot is amped up near the end by a
tense arrest and escape attempt filmed amid the ruins of the Berlin
border. Borgnine tries hard to convey his character's torment and
untenable situation, but the fact remains that he is miscast. Matthews
is nice-looking and gives a decent performance, but is fairly
colorless. It's quite a shock to see slim, youngish Dewhurst, who is
very different from the woman most people recognize from her later TV,
stage and film work. She does well here, yet hadn't completely
accumulated the throaty tones in her voice, which would later make her
voice so distinctive. Joloff, who plays a Soviet leader, has his voice
very obviously dubbed by Paul Frees. There's also a very annoying
narrator who feels the need to dryly state the obvious. He is relieved
occasionally by Borgnine, who should have been permitted to provide
whatever narration was deemed necessary by the producers. The
ridiculous spy training academy pictured in the film almost takes this
into parody with obviously American people playing Russians trained to
behave like Americans. (This idea was ripped off by "Mission:
Impossible" in its first season.) Check out the VERY abbreviated
swimwear on the German men in some of the stock footage used. Some
dancing girls also appear in a nightclub and they seem to have on
bottoms about a size or two too big and aren't exactly the most
coordinated Terpsichoreans ever seen. There are a few decent sets and a
couple of well-handled location shots, but the budget does appear to be
low for this one. It winds up being a capable, but unremarkable,
programmer with precious little to distinguish it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Had no idea if I was going to enjoy this film from 1960, but I had a
good idea that Ernest Borgniine, ( Boris Mitrov) would put his heart
and soul into his role and he did just that through out the entire
film. This was a true story concerning a man who was called Borris
Morras, and in this picture was called Boris Mitrov a double agent
between the United States and Russia during the Cold War Era. Boris
Mitrov is a successful Hollywood producer who was born in Russia and
got himself involved with Russian Spys who were willing to bring his
father and brothers back from Russia to his home in Los Angeles.
However, Boris Mitrov is being watched by our Government Agents and
they decided to enlist Boris to become a double agent for the United
States in order to be cleared of the charges for espionage against the
U.S. There is plenty of suspense and this story takes many twists and
turns.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2706684/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY USA</from><name>sol</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
***SPOILERS*** Somewhat far fetched Cold War drama with Earnest
Borgnine playing the very reluctant Hollywood film producer and double
agent Boris Mitrov who's manipulated by both sides The USA and Soviet
Union to do their dirty work. Boris had been suckered into helping his
native country the Soviet Union by Col. Vadja Kubelov, Alexander
Scourby, the first secretary to the Soviet Embassy in Washington D.C in
the promise that it would help him have his father Papa Mitrov,
Vladimar Sokoloff, and brothers giving free passage to the United
States.During Boris' involvement with Kubelov &amp; Co. he's been watched by the
CIB or CIA who've been following his every move. The CIB needing to get
someone inside the Soviet Union to infiltrate it's spying apparatus
sees in Boris the perfect pasty who with his dealing with the Soviet
here at home can only go along with them or else face life imprisonment
or worse. Meanwhile Boris' Soviet handler Col. Kubelov want's him, as
repayment for having his father released from a Soviet work camp, to
sell out his film production company to millionaire and undercover
communist Adrian Benson, Ed Prentiss, in order to have him secretly
make subversive and pro Soviet movies to brainwash the American public.Things start to get very complicated when Boris, who was ordered by his
now CIB controllers, goes to West Berlin to make a documentary and use
it as cover to get himself into the Soviet Union to work for it's KGB
as a spy against the United States. Taken in by the Moscow KGB chief
Gen. Chapayen, Friedrick Joloff, as one of his newest and brightest
discoveries Boris in no time at all memorizes every Soviet agent in the
United States, which numbers in the thousands. Boris' cover is soon
blown when Benson finds out that his house had been bugged by the CIB
and together with his wife Helen, Colleen Dewhurst, makes a run for it
across the US/Mexican border.Benson who was allowed to escape by the CIB, so his arrest wouldn't
blow Boris's cover in the USSR, get's to Moscow via East Berlin and
desperately tries to get in touch with Gen. Chapayen to alert him that
Boris is rally a double agent. Boris who was informed by friend and CIB
agent Avery, Kerwin Mathews, that the jig was up and told to check out
of the country and take a plane to East Berlin and then make it to the
US controlled west before he's caught and shot on the spot by the KBG
as a US spy.Just when you, and Boris, think that it's all over it's then when the
action really starts with Boris on the run all over the communist
controlled city trying to make it back to West Berlin and both safety
and freedom. Doing a James Bond bit three years before James Bond was
ever introduced to the movie going public Boris gets away from an East
Berlin policeman shooting him dead with a secret cyanide dart gun and
then crosses back into West Berlin only to find out that the East
Berlin secret police are there waiting for him.The ending was just too much to take with Boris running around
handcuffed being chased by communist agents in the middle of US
controlled West Berlin with not a single US, as well as West German,
soldier or police official coming to his aid. Unbelievable and
outlandish shoot-out, again with on one in the city coming to their
aid, at the CIB headquarters with Boris taking matters into his own
hand by cold cocking the chief communist agent with his handcuffs; this
after Avery and his fellow CIB agents ended up getting shot and killed
by the communist agents.Boris by getting the names and addresses, that he kept only in his
head, of thousands of Soviet agents all over the United States wrecks
the entire Soviet spying network that it's so painfully nurtured over
the last fifteen years. In the end Boris get a commendation for his
services from the US congress and his involvement with the Soviet Union
is forgotten about since he did it to help his family members not the
Soviets. As for Boris' bothers back in the USSR it's fond out, from pop
Mitrov himself, that they actually died in a Siberian prison camp and
were being used, in Boris being told that they were alive, by
Col.Kubelov to keep Boris in line and under the KGB's and Soviets
control.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1118564/comments</url><from>from offenbach/rodenbach</from><name> (luckysilien@t-online.de)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

Ernest Borgnine, now almost 90 years of age and still acting for
Hollywood,
went in 1960 to Berlin to play the main character called Boris Mitrov in
an
east - west drama of  director André de Thoth called Man On The String. He
is the man on the (black and white) run for cover through east Berlin
before
the great Wall was built and Kennedy named himself a Berliner. Borgnine
has
learned in Moscow the names of American spies in the states; he memorizes
them and is picked up by a friendly helper next to the American sector and
is taken in a nice Mercedes sedan car back to Uncle Sams sector where he
spills the beans.
Not much later Billy Wilder went to Berlin as well an made a great comedy
about Coca Cola and the rest of the world. De Thoth picture isn't funny at
all and actually the time before and after the making of the big Wall was
not to laugh at. So director de Thoth  decided to play the semi
documentary
card and one must say he succeeded in giving an impression of the area
around the Brandenburg Gate and the nowhere land that is today called
again
Pariser Platz. So the artwork he took straight from the streets and ruins
of
cause of the western sectors. 15 years after the war quite some parts of
West Berlin  still looked pretty far from nowadays and were well to use as
action areas suggesting  the Hollywood staff had permission to film beyond
the American sector right in the middle of East Berlin.Borgnine is an unusual type of spy and he decorates the scenes in the
Moscow
offices of the soviet secret service fairly well. Of cause he is not Paul
Newman who is also a spy memorizing a secret formula in the Torn Curtain
of
Mr. Hitchcock  a little later but not a bad alternative.The area next to the reborn American embassy and also not far from the
Russian embassy was in the meantime nicely swept and one would need
skilled
optical and digital works to bring back an image of the invisible iron
curtain of 1960.
Spy games of the old fashion type are presently not fashionable, spy games
star no more Borgnine but Redford and Pitt and are placed in the near east
in colour and scope. I am beginning to like Borgnine in his black suit
tumbling over the ruins of Berlin and showing his life long gap between
teeth.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Ernest Borgnine is the "Man on a String" spy who is persuaded to work
for the Central Bureau of Intelligence (which is supposed to be the
CIA, of course). He is a movie producer, and is relocated to Berlin, to
be close to the Communist enemies. The actors read their lines like
they're bored to death. Mr. Borgnine sets the tone - his dialog is
mostly, monotone, soft-spoken, and emotionless. Maybe this is how you
are supposed to play a Russian spy? A narration relentlessly punctuates
the drama with a mostly, monotone, soft-spoken, and emotionless
off-screen explanation of the unfolding on-screen events. It also makes sure we viewers know Communists are very bad people.Kerwin Mathews plays the friend and partner spy. He has more
expression, and tries to liven Borgnine and the others up; but they
doggedly resist. Mr. Mathews' performance is not bad, and I wondered,
in his scenes with Borgnine, if Mathews was wondering: what happened to
the great actor from "Marty" and "From Here to Eternity"? *** Man on a String (1960) Andre De Toth ~ Ernest Borgnine, Kerwin
Mathews, Colleen Dewhurst
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Ernest Borgnine is the "Man on a String" spy who is persuaded to work
for the Central Bureau of Intelligence (which is supposed to be the
CIA, of course). He is a movie producer, and is relocated to Berlin, to
be close to the Communist enemies. The actors read their lines like
they're bored to death. Mr. Borgnine sets the tone - his dialog is
mostly, monotone, soft-spoken, and emotionless. Maybe this is how you
are supposed to play a Russian spy? A narration relentlessly punctuates
the drama with a mostly, monotone, soft-spoken, and emotionless
off-screen explanation of the unfolding on-screen events. It also makes sure we viewers know Communists are very bad people.Kerwin Mathews plays the friend and partner spy. He has more
expression, and tries to liven Borgnine and the others up; but they
doggedly resist. Mr. Mathews' performance is not bad, and I wondered,
in his scenes with Borgnine, if Mathews was wondering: what happened to
the great actor from "Marty" and "From Here to Eternity"? *** Man on a String (1960) Andre De Toth ~ Ernest Borgnine, Kerwin
Mathews, Colleen Dewhurst
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/manonastring.htm /m/man_on_a_string-1960/comments.php?reviewid=1666517</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Flat, dated and unbelievable anti-communist propaganda film.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9A02EFD91331EF3ABC4951DFB366838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/man_on_a_string-1960/comments.php?reviewid=1667894</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>