<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Robin Hood e i pirati</original_title><alt_title>Robin des Bois et les pirates</alt_title><imdb_rating>3.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Giorgio Simonelli</director><producer>Finanziaria Cinematografica Italiana (FICIT)</producer><genre>Action</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
On his way to (or from) the Crusades, Robin Hood is shipwrecked but saved by pirates who plan to return him home in order to ransom him to his father...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Lex Barker</actor><actor>Jocelyn Lane</actor><actor>Rossana Rory</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1060482/comments</url><from>from Bronx, NY</from><name>Brian Camp</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
ROBIN HOOD AND THE PIRATES (1960) is an enjoyable Italian costume
adventure with a particularly fanciful rendition of the Robin Hood
tale, set entirely in a Mediterranean 'Sherwood,' with the pirates of
the title, standing in for the Merry Men, camping out in a 'forest'
that looks suspiciously like a beach. (The waves hitting the sand are a
dead giveaway.) Interestingly, the place marker for Sherwood reads
'Conten di Sherwood.'Lex Barker, a former Tarzan (1949-53), cuts a striking figure in a
traditional Robin Hood outfit and wields a mean sword and bow and arrow
as he battles the usurper, Lord Brooks, who killed his father and took
over Sherwood. Robin's aligned with a group of shipwrecked pirates who
offer some half-hearted help at various times and includes a
multi-racial group of 'Saracen' women, led by a hefty black woman named
Bambola, who prefers to be called 'Sweetpea' and is played by American
singer Edith Peters. She speaks with an American southern accent,
despite the fact that the American South was still hundreds of years in
the future at the time this film is set. However, she sings a song in
Italian at one point and develops a yen for the equally hefty white
pirate captain, 'One-Eye' (played by American actor Walter Barnes).
Peters had performed in the U.S. in the 1940s with her sisters in a
trio called, appropriately enough, the Peters Sisters. The Vienna-born Jackie Lane plays Robin's impassioned love interest,
Karin Blain. Lord Brooks keeps trying to marry her and Robin Hood keeps
rescuing her, until the final melee involving all the townsfolk,
pirates and the Lord's knights. Lord Brooks's daughter, Lisbeth (played
by Rossana Rory), complicates things by desiring Robin herself. The
stunning Miss Lane appeared in a wide range of films in England and
Europe in the 1950s and early '60s and was also known as Jocelyn Lane
during a lengthy Hollywood stint in the mid-to-late '60s, which
included playing opposite Elvis Presley in TICKLE ME (1965). Her first
film happened to be an earlier Robin Hood film, MEN OF SHERWOOD FOREST
(1954).The film is nicely photographed on location at a genuine castle
situated atop a seaside cliff. The tone of the film is lighthearted in
the manner of some of the old Hollywood swashbucklers, with the pirates
and Bambola providing comedy relief, while filled with sufficient
swordfighting, horse-riding and castle wall-climbing action to keep
even the genre's most jaded fans happy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A nasty traitor has deprived Robin Hood of his desirable fortress and
his valuable properties when he was away in the crusades .This time,he
has pirates with him (and their exotic mates).Strange that we find the
forest of Sherwood on the seaside :I naively thought it was near
Nottingham.There's no sheriff,no Prince John and Lady Marianne has
become Lady Kareen (?).Kareen has been in love with Robin since
childhood,but alas ,the villain wants to marry her and to make matters
worse,his own daughter,Lisbeth,is in love with the hero .Robin is so busy recovering his possessions and coming to Kareen's
rescue that he does not find any time to steal from the rich and give
to the poor.A disappointment for the whole family.Lex Barker is
credible as a hero but no match for Errol Flynn.The screenplay,which
looks like an eleven-year-old 's essay ,is nothing but a series of
clichés.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
"Robin Hood and the Pirates" is without doubt the saddest entry yet in
a trail of tawdry films set in Sherwood. The coastal Mediterranean
locale in this one resembles England about as much as its inhabitants
resemble Britons. Lex Barker, usually a stalwart performer in the
historic adventure drama here can do little to rise above the banal
script which leaves no cliché unplayed. Mario Scaccio as the evil Lord
Brooks makes a pitiful adversary, so outmatched by big, blond and bland
Barker that this Robin Hood and his crew look like the bullies in
comparison to such scrawny and lackluster villains. After the
magnificent 1938 Flynn version there had been a steady stream of
inferior sequels,most of which do not merit much notice. To further
enjoy the Robin Hood character's exploits, one would do better to seek
out the 1952 Richard Todd version or the equally good 1954 Don Taylor
version, both of which are leagues ahead of this Robin Hood pirate
venture which sinks in its own tedium.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
"Robin Hood and the Pirates" is without doubt the saddest entry yet in
a trail of tawdry films set in Sherwood. The coastal Mediterranean
locale in this one resembles England about as much as its inhabitants
resemble Britons. Lex Barker, usually a stalwart performer in the
historic adventure drama here can do little to rise above the banal
script which leaves no cliché unplayed. Mario Scaccio as the evil Lord
Brooks makes a pitiful adversary, so outmatched by big, blond and bland
Barker that this Robin Hood and his crew look like the bullies in
comparison to such scrawny and lackluster villains. After the
magnificent 1938 Flynn version there had been a steady stream of
inferior sequels,most of which do not merit much notice. To further
enjoy the Robin Hood character's exploits, one would do better to seek
out the 1952 Richard Todd version or the equally good 1954 Don Taylor
version, both of which are leagues ahead of this Robin Hood pirate
venture which sinks in its own tedium.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1585316/comments</url><from>from Fairfax, VA</from><name>ccmiller1492 (ccmiller1492@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>