<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Because They're Young</original_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Paul Wendkos</director><producer>Drexel Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
New high school teacher tries to help troubled students and falls in love with the principal's secretary.
</synopsis><actor>Dick Clark</actor><actor>Victoria Shaw</actor><actor>Michael Callan</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0484304/comments</url><from>from Stroudsburg, PA</from><name>fordraff (fordraff@ptd.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I first saw this film on April 29, 1960, during its original release (I
kept
movie notes even then), not because I was a fan of Dick Clark's but because
I'd read and liked very much Harrison High, the novel from which the film
was taken.  In 1960, I was very disappointed in the film because the film
made the novel's adolescent characters supporting characters and focused
instead on Neil Hendry (Clark), a teacher and minor character in the novel.
This transformation was a result of Dick Clark's involvement in the
development of this film and because, in 1960, Clark's name was the biggest
one in the cast.There were two major things that caught my attention when I saw the film
this time, more than forty years after my original viewing of
it.First was the lighting.The film starts out well lit, but grows darker as it goes along.  Perhaps
this was director Paul Wendkos' way of indicating the dark nature of the
events that occurred as the film progressed.  In essence, "Because They're
Young" ends up with classic noir lighting.The entire scene of the robbery at the warehouse, which involves Chris,
Patcher and Griff, is filmed in classic low-key noir lighting, which is
appropriate to the action that is occurring.During the film's climax, there is a scene where Patcher is searching for
Griff in one of the school's science labs.  All of the blinds in the
classroom are closed, though some bars of light do come through the closed
blinds, and these bars of light are shown against Griff in the opening part
of the scene.  Then Patcher enters the room, searching for Griff.  He
passes
by each of the classroom's windows, opening the blinds to admit more light,
thereby throwing unto the opposite wall the classic noir image of light
slashed into lines by the blinds.  When he finally gets all of the blinds
open, Patcher turns to see Griff Rimer against the opposite wall, standing
as if imprisoned by the bars of light.Other details of noir exist but limitations of space prevent my detailing
them.  I'm surprised that someone hasn't called "Because They're Young" the
first teenage noir film, what with critics' eagerness today to use the term
noir.The second thing that riveted my attention was the butcher Chris, who is
clearly homosexual and something of a sadist as well.  For most teenagers
in
1960, this homosexual subtext would have passed them by.  It obviously
passed over the heads of The Production Code censors.  But there certainly
would have been a group of male teens who would have known from their own
experience what was going on between Chris and his boys.Chris is a butcher in the grocery store where Griff (Michael Callan) works
after school.  In a scene where a detective enters the store and asks for
the manager, Chris suspects he may be after Griff, who has been stealing
cartons of cigarettes, so Chris deflects the detective to another boy who
has been stealing six packs of beer.After that moment, Chris and Griff are alone together in a back room behind
the butcher counter.  Griff thinks he's safe now from the detective and is
pretty light and airy with Chris.  Suddenly, Chris slaps Griff a stinging
blow in the face and tells him he knows that Griff is stealing cigarettes,
too, but that he decided to spare Griff while giving the detective the
other
boy.  This slap is a sobering moment for Griff--and an eye-opener for the
audience--who knows better than to deny his theft.Having quickly tamed Griff, Chris takes a friendlier attitude toward him.
And this involves his touching Griff.  Indeed, Chris can't keep his hands
off this hot hunk for the rest of the film.  He tells Griff that he can
even
borrow his car, if he wants to.  Just drop by my apartment and I'll give
you
the keys.  But throughout this scene, Chris is wielding a dangerous meat
cleaver, which he viciously embeds in a meat carcass at the end of the
scene.  Chris's unpredicted slap to Griff and that meat cleaver give this
scene an eerie sense of suspense and tension.In a later scene when Griff goes to Chris's apartment, he sees that Patcher
is there concluding some business with Chris.  What kind of business?
Well,
it's not specified, but Chris gives Patcher money, and Patcher asks some
questions about when the next time will be.  One doesn't have to be
depraved
to interpret this scene as one following a possible sexual liaison between
Chris and Patcher, tho later events make clear Patcher is Chris's partner
in
crime.Chris is in his later 40s, but his bachelor "pad" is a 50's adolescent's
fantasy.  The main feature is a well-stocked bar and an expensive hi-fi
set,
playing a jazz record.  There are pictures of women on the wall near the
bar, the nearest the film could come back then to Playboy-type centerfolds.
The entire apartment is a den into which Chris can lure his boys, give them
booze, and heat up their libidos with the photos of the women.  When
they're
hot, there's Chris willing to---do what?Throughout all of the scenes between Griff and Chris, Chris's hands are
busy
all over Griff.  He's patting his back, rubbing his hand along the side of
Griff's chest, outlining Griff's chin with his forefinger, cupping Griff's
head in his hands, reaching out and pulling Griff close to him, so close in
one scene their cheeks touch--the nearest this film can bring them to a
kiss.I'm sure Paul Wendkos directed actor Rudy Bond to play Chris this way.
What
was Wendkos thinking of, subverting a Dick Clark film like this?  Love
it!Limitations of space prevent me from going into more detail about the noir
ambiance and the homosexual subtext and many other items of interest about
other plot events and the actors.  I've written a long article about this
film and would be happy to e-mail it to anyone who's interested.Certainly not an innocuous teen flick!  Have a look with your eyes open
this
time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0249396/comments</url><from>from Marietta, GA, USA</from><name>Hermit C-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

On his first teaching assignment, Dick Clark has a problem: He cares too
much. That's not what we want, says his stern principle. Just teach your
classes and send all the discipline problems to me. Not surprisingly, Clark
can't stay uninvolved. Who would want it any other way?Clark is no seasoned pro in this film, but he's basically playing himself,
or his public image, anyway, and he can do that well enough. He's there to
try to straighten out all types of kids including the insecure newcomer
(Warren Berlinger) and the incipient juvenile delinquent (Michael Callen.)
This movie doesn't have anything close to the grit of 'Blackboard Jungle' or
the lurid laughability of 'High School Confidential' but a big fan of the
movies will likely find it worth the time. Admirers of Tuesday Weld will
want to check her out, too. Victoria Shaw plays a school secretary who
serves as a love interest for Clark.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0320474/comments</url><from>from Willow Grove, PA</from><name>Denny Keyes (statie68@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Yes- I was a teenager when this movie came out. Actually, I was lucky enough
to have danced on Dick Clark's American Bandstand on and off in 1962 at WFIL
TV studios in Philadelphia. Seeing this movie really helps "take me back" to
those carefree days of youth. Of course, the movie shows some problems among
a few of the kids,  but my enjoyment of it lies in identifying with the
happy-go-lucky majority. These are the kids seen dancing, laughing and just
enjoying themselves in being a teenager in 1960. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2029693/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, California</from><name>Dejael</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Another movie I'd love to see released on video/DVD that's been too
long neglected is "BECAUSE THEY'RE YOUNG" (Columbia, 1960) starring
Dick Clark of American Bandstand with Duane Eddy and his Rockin'
Rebels, and Bobby Rydell on the soundtrack. Oh yes, that cool blonde
hottie Tuesday Weld was in there too. Too bad it was in black &amp; white,
but they were doing a retake on "BLACKBOARD JUNGLE" (MGM, 1955) so it
had to be, and look like a B-movie. I know I'm dating myself, but I did
see this movie in the theaters when it was released in May-June 1960.
It was the coolest, man. I mean like I really dug it the most, at age
13. I was into Edd 'Kookie' Byrnes' jive talk, rock'n'roll, and hip
beatnik jazz so Maynard G. Krebs was my buddy on TV. And DIck Clark was
a swingin' hipster on American Bandstand, WFIL-TV in Philly, broadcast
on ABC-TV network nationwide. I watched it every afternoon after coming
home from school, along with reruns of "Adventures of SUPERMAN",
"Topper", and "Ramar of the Jungle"! Dick Clark really clicked for
teens and kids in this movie, I remember everyone thought he did a
great job with his first acting role. In retrospect, not having seen
this movie since the early '70s when it was shown on TV one Saturday
afternoon, I can't really judge it as an adult, but I fondly remember
it being kind of a dark, melodramatic sort of "American Graffiti" movie
experience. I would love to see it again after all these years! Please,
Sony Pictures, put this one on your DVD-to-do list!!! I'd love to see
an interview with Dick Clark about this movie. I wonder if he's up to
that challenge now?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Because They're Young marked Dick Clark's dramatic big screen debut and
while it didn't electrify the cinema world, he doesn't turn in a bad
screen performance as the high school history teacher involved with his
kids and with school secretary Victoria Shaw.The plot of the film centers around a high school triangle with jock
Warren Berlinger, cheerleader Tuesday Weld, and troubled youth and
James Dean knockoff Michael Callan. Hints of the less than Ozzie and
Harriet background of the three of them can be seen it brief vignettes
of their troubled homes.Clark's also having issues with principal William Genge who wants him
to stick to teaching and leave the social work alone. Before Joe Clark
was ever heard of, this principal has a once strike and you're out
policy in the school. Dick Clark takes more of the Father Flannagan
approach.Two of the supporting cast, Doug McClure and Roberta Shore, would later
be together on The Virginian television series. But that wouldn't be
for another five years.Look for a good performance also by Rudy Bond who's got a Fagin like
role as the leader and fence of a juvenile heist gang in which Callan
is a member. Music by Duane Eddy, James Darren, and Bobby Rydell place the film
firmly in 1960, the year of its release. The first two make guest
appearances at a school dance. I know we didn't have names of that
caliber at anything my high school ever ran back in those days.It's not a bad film given the obviously low budget for it. It does have
some nice noir touches and sincere performances by its cast.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Dick Clark strays too far from the Bandstand in this misguided youth
flick, which is one-half benign high school opus and the other half a
"Rebel Without a Cause"-type drama. Based on John Farris' novel
"Harrison High", the plot has been reworked in schoolteacher Clark's
favor, turning the teenagers of the piece into 'problems' this
sensitive adult can solve. The newest teacher at a high school
primarily home to the wealthier teen set gets involved with the
principal's secretary while straightening out entangled young lives.
Worse off seems to be Michael Callan as a working-class boy who doesn't
fit in; his love-hate relationship with a touchy-feely butcher who
wields a mean cleaver has to be seen to be believed! Tuesday Weld,
suffering under the thumb of her harping, bed-ridden mother, is anxious
to shed her trampy reputation, crossing paths with bad-boy Callan for
the second time. Clark has problems of his own, nursing a wounded ego
after a car accident has left him unable to play football--oh, and the
wreck killed his brother and sister-in-law, too! The stilted dialogue
throughout, courtesy screenwriter James Gunn, renders the teen
conversations utterly false, while the only animated thing about Dick
Clark is his eyebrows (and when he jiggles them around, his forehead
becomes lined with curious criss-cross wrinkles). The film's third act
becomes intentionally mired in juvenile delinquent melodramatics, with
moody lighting and mad bongos on the soundtrack; however, since none of
the characters have managed to elicit our sympathies, one is inclined
not to care who makes out all right and who doesn't. *1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Dick Clark strays too far from the Bandstand in this misguided youth
flick, which is one-half benign high school opus and the other half a
"Rebel Without a Cause"-type drama. Based on John Farris' novel
"Harrison High", the plot has been reworked in schoolteacher Clark's
favor, turning the teenagers of the piece into 'problems' this
sensitive adult can solve. The newest teacher at a high school
primarily home to the wealthier teen set gets involved with the
principal's secretary while straightening out entangled young lives.
Worse off seems to be Michael Callan as a working-class boy who doesn't
fit in; his love-hate relationship with a touchy-feely butcher who
wields a mean cleaver has to be seen to be believed! Tuesday Weld,
suffering under the thumb of her harping, bed-ridden mother, is anxious
to shed her trampy reputation, crossing paths with bad-boy Callan for
the second time. Clark has problems of his own, nursing a wounded ego
after a car accident has left him unable to play football--oh, and the
wreck killed his brother and sister-in-law, too! The stilted dialogue
throughout, courtesy screenwriter James Gunn, renders the teen
conversations utterly false, while the only animated thing about Dick
Clark is his eyebrows (and when he jiggles them around, his forehead
becomes lined with curious criss-cross wrinkles). The film's third act
becomes intentionally mired in juvenile delinquent melodramatics, with
moody lighting and mad bongos on the soundtrack; however, since none of
the characters have managed to elicit our sympathies, one is inclined
not to care who makes out all right and who doesn't. *1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>