<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Moderato cantabile</original_title><imdb_rating>6.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Peter Brook</director><producer>Documento Film</producer><producer>Iéna Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A wealthy and bored woman (Moreau) is witness of a murder in affection and meets another witness (Belmondo). She asks him about the history of the victim and falls in love with him.
</synopsis><actor>Jeanne Moreau</actor><actor>Jean-Paul Belmondo</actor><actor>Pascale de Boysson</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7033348/comments</url><from>from Out There in the Dark</from><name>mackjay2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Peter Brook's MODERATO CANTABILE was praised in its day, but has nearly
been forgotten. Not a crowd pleaser, this is a film that will probably
appeal to a limited audience. The screenplay is based on the Marguerite
Duras novel of the same name. Duras deliberately avoided dramatic
incident for the main characters and wanted to only observe their
interior states. In the film, Brooks tries to find an equivalent for
this approach and he succeeds. From the opening scene, we can see we
are in for an unusual type of film experience. A young boy is in the
middle of a piano lesson. We see his teacher react with impatience to
the boy's distracted dreaminess. The boy's mother, Anne (Jeanne
Moreau), tries to keep him on track, but little is accomplished. Then,
a woman's scream is heard from outside the window. Boy, mother and
teacher look out to see a great deal of commotion and police presence
in front of a café next door. When the woman goes down to look, she
sees a female corpse in the café and a man being led away by police.
Surreptitiously watching Anne is Chauvin (Jean-Paul Belmondo). For the
first third of the film, he will follow the mother and son around the
town (Blaye, near Bordeaux). Idly rich and bored, the pair have little
to do but wander in the woods and ride the ferry across the dull, gray
Gironde river. Chauvin has little to do himself and one day he
approaches Anne. After a short time, they begin a romance. The romance
is presented in a very muted, unprovocative way. What is interesting
about it is the way that Anne insists on Chauvin narrating his
rendition of the story behind the shot woman and the man in the café.
It's clear that an analogy is being made between that couple and the
film's protagonists. The drama in this story happens to other people,
not to the main characters. Clandestine meetings continue and at one
point Chauvin decides he has had enough of Anne's need to live a
vicarious tragedy. He puts her off and refuses to continue. The film goes to great length to express the isolation of these
characters: a bored, lonely rich man's wife in an enormous estate and a
solitary factory worker (we are only told he works there, we don't see
it). Brooks and his cinematographer Armand Thirard do a fine job of
establishing the overwhelming melancholy of this story. Locations are
used to express the characters' emotional states in much the same way
that Antonioni uses locations in his films. This film seems to be
saying that some are trapped in their lives and there is only
temporary, perhaps imagined, escape from the dull greyness of it all. A
piano sonatina by Diabelli is the only music used for the soundtrack
and its Mozartean prettiness seems at odds with the somber tale,
perhaps a small touch of irony. Or perhaps an expression of the way
small amounts of sunlight can be let into a gray world, singing, but
with moderation.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Peter Brooks' film of Marguerite Duras' Moderato Cantabile is one of
those good ideas that should make for a better film, but in its
determinedly artistic distance and relentless melancholy it never draws
you into its characters lives enough to make you care about the
inevitable outcome. Jeanne Moreau's dissatisfied wife of the local
steel mill owner finds herself increasingly fascinated with a crime of
passion after overhearing the victim's scream and seeing her
lover/killer taken away by the police and is drawn repeatedly back to
the scene of the crime. Equally fascinated by her, Jean Paul Belmondo's
steelworker starts inventing details about the doomed lovers to get
closer to her. Even though she knows he's lying, his version starts to
fill a void in her soul and a need for a vicarious romantic tragedy of
her own but from the monotonous gloom of their surroundings and the
desperate emptiness of their meetings, it's obvious a happy ending
isn't on the cards...It perfectly captures the dull grey feel of a small dead end coastal
town and Armand Tirard's crisp black and white CinemaScope photography
(beautifully preserved on the Australian DVD) is easily the best thing
about the film, but the film is as drained of real passion as the
characters and the minimalism and predictability of every plot and
emotional development of its determinedly internal narrative (you just
know you're going to hear that less than convincing scream again) makes
it all seem rather superficial and uninvolving. There may well be more
nuance and meaning in Duras' original story, but Brook never really
finds a cinematic equivalent with the result that there's less than
meets the eye to the film. Still, if it were made today the plot would
suddenly make a U-turn into woman-in-peril territory as Belmondo turned
out to be the real killer and Moreau his next intended victim, so for
sparing us that cliché at least it probably deserves an extra point.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3001058/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>Bob Taylor (bob998@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This has to be one of the dullest films of the early Sixties. Remember
that Godard, Malle, Truffaut and company had been challenging the
traditions of story telling; the world seemed young again, and full of
possibilities. Moderato cantabile has nothing of this spirit. It might
have been made by an old-guard director like Clément or Delannoy (if
they had decided to take a chance on a Duras script).There isn't much energy or interest in this story: what happens in the
first ten minutes is endlessly rehashed throughout the remainder.
Belmondo is ill at ease here, or at least seems that way to me--there
is no chance for any extroversion, exuberance or even anger from the
character. Jeanne Moreau is used decoratively (Brook must have seen
what Resnais was able to do with Delphine Seyrig in Last Year In
Marienbad) and always looks elegant, if never really desperate or
anguished. You know something's wrong when the piano teacher provides
much of the dramatic interest: she's bullying the child into giving her
a Diabelli sonata "moderately, with a singing feeling".Note: I have just remembered that Clément did do a Duras script
(Barrage contre le Pacifique) in 1958.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16858462/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>carvalheiro</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Moderato cantabile" (1960) directed by Peter Brook was a movie with a
certain spleen of its weather, like a love story in a foggy atmosphere
near or not too much far away in Gascogne Gulf from the quite distant
channel between England and France. The couple had met in a coffee
break at the place of the port and both were seeing each other
concerning a criminal environment from the daily journey, nowhere
outside with the police searching for somebody helping to solve the
killing of someone there. Director Peter Brook so happy with his career, that he forgot perhaps
in making more movies like this one, even though this one it was not so
easy in finishing it, but that unfinished touch is not evanescent. This
kind of appearance from the main characters, a woman with a child and a
man, both young and the message it was there like that. A stylish look
for both main characters that knowing something else about an event
have an approach to a soft sentimental adventure and forgotten the
reality of their acquaintance created a link of friendship without any
presumption for after tomorrow. Because it seems if did you understood that, something is always
possible when things are confused for the minds and the first is
breathing well and expelled oxygenate air, making steam by night :
reconciliation brought her for another stand of high society from the
time. It seems also that the screenplay came from someone who had much
pleasure to bring any confusion in the mind of the characters with her
- because is a she - deconstruction in her obsessive purpose, that life
is not so important around if a kiss save your honor and butterfly.
This is the strength of Marguerite Duras story adapted anyway by Peter
Brook with a kind of innovative and quite prejudice against savagery of
the time, during persecutions in France, because colonial defeat at the
time mixed with resistance from Gironde tradition where the story came
from.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16858462/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>carvalheiro</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Moderato cantabile" (1960) directed by Peter Brook was a movie with a
certain spleen of its weather, like a love story in a foggy atmosphere
near or not too much far away in Gascogne Gulf from the quite distant
channel between England and France. The couple had met in a coffee
break at the place of the port and both were seeing each other
concerning a criminal environment from the daily journey, nowhere
outside with the police searching for somebody helping to solve the
killing of someone there. Director Peter Brook so happy with his career, that he forgot perhaps
in making more movies like this one, even though this one it was not so
easy in finishing it, but that unfinished touch is not evanescent. This
kind of appearance from the main characters, a woman with a child and a
man, both young and the message it was there like that. A stylish look
for both main characters that knowing something else about an event
have an approach to a soft sentimental adventure and forgotten the
reality of their acquaintance created a link of friendship without any
presumption for after tomorrow. Because it seems if did you understood that, something is always
possible when things are confused for the minds and the first is
breathing well and expelled oxygenate air, making steam by night :
reconciliation brought her for another stand of high society from the
time. It seems also that the screenplay came from someone who had much
pleasure to bring any confusion in the mind of the characters with her
- because is a she - deconstruction in her obsessive purpose, that life
is not so important around if a kiss save your honor and butterfly.
This is the strength of Marguerite Duras story adapted anyway by Peter
Brook with a kind of innovative and quite prejudice against savagery of
the time, during persecutions in France, because colonial defeat at the
time mixed with resistance from Gironde tradition where the story came
from.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16858462/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>carvalheiro</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9506E7D91338E13ABC4F53DFB766838F679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/moderato_cantabile/comments.php?reviewid=1389167</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chireader.com/MovieCaps/M/MO/12973_MODERATO_CANTABILE.html /m/moderato_cantabile/comments.php?reviewid=127904</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>