<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Tormented</original_title><imdb_rating>3.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Bert I. Gordon</director><producer>Cheviot Productions</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
A man lets a former flame fall to her death rather than let her interfere with his new relationship, but her ghost returns to disrupt his impending nuptials.
</synopsis><actor>Richard Carlson</actor><actor>Susan Gordon</actor><actor>Lugene Sanders</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0463200/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Tom Stewart (Richard Carlson) is about to marry sweet Meg Hubbard
(Legene Sanders). So, a week before the wedding he decides to break it
off with big-breasted girlfriend Vi (Juli Reding). A WEEK BEFORE the
wedding??!!!??? Hey, why so soon Tom? Why not do it on your honeymoon?
She threatens to blackmail him with love letters. She tells him this
while they're on top of a deserted lighthouse on a remote island. Great
timing Vi. She falls to her death--Tom could have saved her, but
doesn't.Next thing you know her ghost is tormenting him--parts of her body
appear to him (but no one else), he hears her voice, sees her in
pictures and begins going crazy. But is she really come back from the
dead or is he out of his mind?Silly, but I enjoyed it. I was never really bored and the story throws
every ghost story cliché at you with blaring music and amusing special
effects. There were even a few very creepy moments in there.Even the crappy video transfer I saw didn't hurt--it was also 5 minutes
shorter than it's reported running time and there were obvious bits
missing and scratches all throughout the print. Purportedly, Something
Weird Video said this was a new transfer. Oh really? I find that hard
to believe.Still, it's a cheesy, fun, little horror film. Take it for what it
is--don't go in expecting some classic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Bert I. Gordon – cleverly shortened as B.I.G - is a notorious
director/producer/writer whose films are too often automatically
categorized as 'awful' and textbook material for spoof-shows as MST3K.
Even 'Tormented' featured in the legendary show and I, for one, think
this was really unjustified. Underneath all the cheapness and inferior
production values of this project homes a modestly grim and slick
thriller. The plot handles about a successful piano player (Tom) who
lives on a remote island community. He's all set to wed a rich high
society girl but first he has to get rid of his Marilyn Monroe-like
mistress Vi. Things seem to turn out fine when she falls off the
lighthouse but Vi comes back to haunt Tom…body part by body part. This
thriller with obvious Freudian influences is quite atmospheric and
features interesting sub-plots and a few genuine frights. It only
suffers from too many scenes in which the protagonist (Richard Carlson)
wanders around the beach talking to himself. It's not a bad film at all
and most people probably just refer to it as a turkey because Gordon
directed it…whether his films feature giant fake mutated animals
(Empire of the Ants, Food of the Gods) or not, they all get labeled the
same way. Cinema is a hypocrite industry, my friends…it's up to you to
give this 'Tormented' a look and realize it should be rated slightly
higher.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0650226/comments</url><from>from Universal City, TX</from><name> (michael.e.barrett@worldnet.att.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The first thing to notice is the photography of Ernest Laszlo, a veteran of
film noir who shot the classic "D.O.A.", "Kiss Me Deadly" and Fritz Lang's
"While the City Sleeps." (And the same year "Tormented" came out, he did
"Inherit the Wind"!) He elevates this little ghost tale no end, with nice
compositions such as the shots through broken lighthouse windows.Classical ghost stories usually don't have very far to go, and that's
probably why there aren't too many of them in American cinema. Someone's
haunted, that's it. Such tales are atmosphere-heavy instead of plot-heavy,
since motive and outcome are usually obvious. In this case, the atmosphere
is a combination of spookiness (with some clumsy effects, and some smooth
ones, like the pan shot across the room to reveal the missing LP which has
somehow moved to the record player) and the neurotic paranoia of the hero,
who reveals himself as trapped a sap as many a noir fool who blames his
troubles on a dame. The plot delays and prolongs, but the last act juggles
several nice twists. By the end, this cynical little flick has shown more
style and imagination than several recent special-effects ghost
movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0861465/comments</url><from>from Queens, NY</from><name>InzyWimzy</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

That Bert I. Gordon made some wacky flicks!This film definitely has a dark, somber mood and rightly so.  Is it really
happening too Tom or is guilty conscience and insanity taking over?  Despite
the hindering of special effects at the time, the apparition scenes are
pretty funny.  Sandy really did grow up a lot during this movie.  Was it a
message of how the best laid plans end up crumbling like dust in the wind? 
Hey, can you blame Tom for falling for Vi?  Oh, was there unintended humor
when Tom asks the blind housekeeper if she saw something, and when she
reminds him of her handicap, he says, "Sorry, I forgot.?"  I always crack up
at that one scene and anytime the beatnik shows up."No habla beatnik!"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Alright, so "Tormented" isn't a masterpiece, or even a cult classic for
that matter. However, its far from the turkey its often reputed to be.
Sure, its obviously cheap, but what do you expect with these kinds of
things? For all its impoverishment and limitations, "Tormented" manages
to tell a reasonably creepy ghost story. Its probably the most
well-made film from Bert I. Gordon, a director often looked upon as a
hack. Its only second to "The Magic Sword" as my personal favorite from
him.Sure, the film isn't perfect. With the exception of Richard Carlson,
the acting is pretty lousy (especially the annoying little girl) and
the pacing is rather poor (to be expected from Gordon). Still, the film
has atmosphere to spare. The shots of the shoreline in the dark can be
quite eerie (if a bit clichéd). Its campy at moments, but surprisingly
effective in others. What makes this work more than it should however
is Carlson. As the tormented jazz pianist, he gives an oddly
sympathetic character. You hope the best for him even when he commits
murder. Plus, Juli Reding is absolutely gorgeous.This brings me to my main problem with the film. It would've been far
more effective if the makers had made the audience wonder if Carlson is
really being haunted or if its just all in his head (the films of
Jacques Tourneur do this). Still, "Tormented" is creepier than it has
any right to be. (6/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Tormented is quite a scary ghost story from Mr Big. No giant insects in
it though.On a remote island,a musician's former lover falls to her death from a
lighthouse even though he could have stopped her. He then tries to
carry on with his life and prepare for his forthcoming wedding but she
comes back to haunt him. This leads to many strange and creepy
happenings including a record player playing on its own accord, the
supposedly disused lighthouse working, footprints in the sand and the
flowers wilting at his wedding. She also causes him to murder a young
man. He then returns to the lighthouse to confront the ghost...Despite reading bad reviews about this movie, I found it quite
enjoyable and certainly scary at times.The cast includes sci-fi/horror regular Richard Carlson (It Came From
Outer Space, Creature From the Black Lagoon), Mr Big's daughter Susan
Gorden, Lugene Sanders, Juli Reding, Joe Turkel and Gene Roth (Earth vs
the Spider).Catch this if you get the chance. Excellent despite the low budget.Rating: 3 stars out of 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1203819/comments</url><from>from Jacksonville, FL</from><name>Jeff (Inthegoodlife@Aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The idea of a man allowing the death of a lover so as not to get caught by
his future wife is a nice concept.  His subsequent guilt and the paranoia it
causes is also an interesting idea.  Then why is this movie not that great? 
A few reasons, the biggest being the reliance on hokey special effects that
are laughable.  Vi's head talking to Tom Stewart while sitting on a shelf
can't be looked at with a straight face.  Her redundant accusations while
wrapped in a sack is even more hilarious.  The movie is also very dull and
the dramatic moments aren't executed very well.  They also deteriorate into
laughter.  Some of the dead air does work well with Tom's inner voices and
the acting isn't really that bad.  The cast has some talent and is led by
Carlson of Creature from the Black Lagoon fame.  This movie could be a big
time fright fest with a better script.  This attempt doesn't deliver on a
good idea.  4.2/10       
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12371785/comments</url><from>from Durham NC</from><name>mlraymond</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie on television in the late Sixties, knowing nothing
about it, and was literally scared to the point of having nightmares
for the next two months. It's a hokey, campy, overdone film that still
manages to be genuinely eerie. There are some truly creepy scenes that
will unnerve any viewer, no matter how silly the movie gets at times.
WARNING;SPOILERS AHEAD: the scene in which the blind woman is lured up
into the abandoned lighthouse is really effective. The best remembered
scene has to be the confrontation between Richard Carlson as the guilty
man and the floating, disembodied head of the ghost, as he holds her by
her long blonde hair and tries to stuff her into a bag, while the head
shrieks out " Tom Stewart killed me! Tom Stewart killed me!" As foolish
as that sounds, it's a really scary scene. The great scene in which the
unseen ghost disrupts the wedding by crashing into the church and
causing the flowers to wilt, just at the point where the minister is
reading from the wedding ceremony, " if there be anyone present who
knows just cause why these two may not be lawfully joined together, let
him now speak or forever hold his peace" is a real tour de force. The
film has moments of total absurdity, which run up against truly macabre
moments that will absolutely chill you. The overall effect is a taut,
atmospheric little ghost story that works pretty well. Worth seeing at
least once.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8743363/comments</url><from>from Toronto</from><name>worldsofdarkblue</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Of course, I was ten years old in 1960 and back then disembodied
talking heads, mysterious winds that attack weddings and kill all the
flowers, and a white-ish, translucent ghost woman who swoops directly
at you was pretty decent entertainment. Us kids ate this stuff up
during the matinée; then, all the teens and adults arrived in the
evening and I was captured by that delicious shared experience of
shouted-out banter, witticisms and wise-cracks to appreciative audience
laughter. Now and again a scene was intense enough to elicit some girl
screams and the whole place would crack up.See, this is the problem with writing 'dated' b-horror commentary.
We're talking about the olden days here. Ya kinda had to be there. Just
try recommending this to the average young adult of today! I can
imagine how he'd be looking at you if he actually watched it - I'm
laughing my ass off already. Yep, most of the people in this world are
gonna rate this melodramatic dinosaur pretty darn low.......and yet,
recently viewed, the final scene - the final 'movement' of the scorned
woman was still chilling to me. Okay, so I'm a total melvin.Anyway, if you've got the right eyes, this is a kitschy, 'modern'
haunting in glorious black and white, complete with the very middest
level of late fifties' special effs. If that encourages you to watch
it, you are a kindred spirit, no matter your age
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0597572/comments</url><from>from Montreal</from><name>michael.will (michael.will@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A taste for Bert I. Gordon is as personal a thing as the approach he takes
to his modest little movies, and this his contribution to the early 60s
supernatural craze is gourmet stuff. No subtlety, and who expects it, in
this 19th century style tale of ghostly revenge as a modern day jazz
musician is hounded to insanity by the ghost of a scorned lover whose death
he deliberately failed to prevent. How this angry barfly manifests herself
is alternately hilarious (the floating head) and downright creepy (the
footprints in the sand, the wilting wedding bouquets) but, in the
climax-focused tradition of Mr. B.I.G.'s best size meditations, especially
the first COLOSSAL with its javelin-syringe, these moments imprint
themselves on the viewer's memory and meet the standards of pure cinema,
however unassumingly. There's a certain period loveliness to the lazy
California beach town locale (many of the sets reused in the charming but
perverse BOY AND THE PIRATES) and the pace has a leisureliness to match,
but
what grips one is the sheer moral ambiguity of the not quite anti-hero
Richard Carlson. He's really not such a bad guy but who knows what extremes
he'll be driven to, especially concerning the little girl who finds herself
in the middle of things. A lot of Gordon flicks, in fact, have this
melancholiac uncurrent of the aggressor's turmoil between human decency and
the urge, circumstance-driven, to destroy. I'll leave analysis of this to
the academically inclined, but I do wish true lovers of B-films would get
past that "Mystery-Science" whatever nerd-need to express one's imagined
sophistication with shrieking assaults on another era's conventions and
technical primitiveness, and simply go with the flow and reap the rewards
that films like TORMENTED offer. The finale, involving sea weed and the
mind's eye, is really quite brilliant. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0597572/comments</url><from>from Montreal</from><name>michael.will (michael.will@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A taste for Bert I. Gordon is as personal a thing as the approach he takes
to his modest little movies, and this his contribution to the early 60s
supernatural craze is gourmet stuff. No subtlety, and who expects it, in
this 19th century style tale of ghostly revenge as a modern day jazz
musician is hounded to insanity by the ghost of a scorned lover whose death
he deliberately failed to prevent. How this angry barfly manifests herself
is alternately hilarious (the floating head) and downright creepy (the
footprints in the sand, the wilting wedding bouquets) but, in the
climax-focused tradition of Mr. B.I.G.'s best size meditations, especially
the first COLOSSAL with its javelin-syringe, these moments imprint
themselves on the viewer's memory and meet the standards of pure cinema,
however unassumingly. There's a certain period loveliness to the lazy
California beach town locale (many of the sets reused in the charming but
perverse BOY AND THE PIRATES) and the pace has a leisureliness to match,
but
what grips one is the sheer moral ambiguity of the not quite anti-hero
Richard Carlson. He's really not such a bad guy but who knows what extremes
he'll be driven to, especially concerning the little girl who finds herself
in the middle of things. A lot of Gordon flicks, in fact, have this
melancholiac uncurrent of the aggressor's turmoil between human decency and
the urge, circumstance-driven, to destroy. I'll leave analysis of this to
the academically inclined, but I do wish true lovers of B-films would get
past that "Mystery-Science" whatever nerd-need to express one's imagined
sophistication with shrieking assaults on another era's conventions and
technical primitiveness, and simply go with the flow and reap the rewards
that films like TORMENTED offer. The finale, involving sea weed and the
mind's eye, is really quite brilliant. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0597572/comments</url><from>from Montreal</from><name>michael.will (michael.will@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-biodrowski/</url><url>http://cinefantastiqueonline.com/2010/08/tormented-1960-on-mystery-science-theater-3000-a-50th-anniversary-review/ /m/tormented/comments.php?reviewid=1924418</url><name>Steve Biodrowski</name><from>ESplatter</from></reviewer><comment>Bert I. Gordon is most well known for his low-budget 1950s sci-fi pics, but this little seen relic of 1960 is actually one of his better efforts. It is also one of the more entertaining installments of the always enjoyable Mystery Science Theater 3000. </comment></review></movie>