<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Das Spukschloß im Spessart</original_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>West Germany</country><director>Kurt Hoffmann</director><producer>Georg Witt-Film</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><genre>Musical</genre><synopsis>
From her father Charlotte inherits a dilapidated castle near the small German town Bonn. The castle is encumbered with debt...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Liselotte Pulver</actor><actor>Heinz Baumann</actor><actor>Georg Thomalla</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4848961/comments</url><from>from Germany</from><name>flocgn</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
basically a sequel to "Das Wirtshaus I'm Spessart" based on the popular
German fairy tale/legend, which came to the big screen 2 years earlier,
this movie stars nearly all of Germany's comedians of that time. At
first a mixture of comedy and musical, it is also pretty political and
aims mostly for post-war short-comings after the German
"Wirtschaftswunder", like pensions still paid to former
"Wehrmacht"-Officers, but makes fun also of celebrities of that time
like the liaison of Onassis and Maria Callas, just to name one. The story is about the ghosts of the robbers from "Wirtshaus I'm
Spessart" and how they redeem themselves. As a punishment for their
crimes they were locked up in the basement of the "Wirtshaus" (pub) to
starve to death, accompanied by a curse that they should rot there as
long the walls would be standing. The wall falls when the old pub has to make room for a gas-station and
a new motel next to the brand new freeway and the souls of the robbers
are freed. Now ghosts they come to the conclusion that they have to do
something good, so be released. So they decide to search for the Castle
of the Comte, they blackmailed in the first Movie and who resided over
the Woods they were thieving in.They find it to be inherited by the last Comtess, played by Lieselotte
Pulver, who has no money at all, because her late father lost all the
family fortune.(to be continued)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1581642/comments</url><from>from Wales, UK</from><name>PlanecrazyIkarus</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This sequel takes place several hundred years after the original movie
"Wirthaus im Spessart". The robbers have long been caught and sentenced to
death and killed, now their ghosts have returned to the castle of the
contessa who once befriended their leader. There, they find her
grand-grand-grand..... daughter, and decide to help her out to pay for
their
sins in their lives.Once again it is a romantic comedy, this time with a few ghost sidekicks
thrown in, and lots of slapstick humour that kids like. My favourite part
has to be the musical number "Woll'n wir doch mal sehn ob's nicht
Gespenster
gibt in Bonn" - hillarious!However, I'm not sure how much it would appeal to adults.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1581642/comments</url><from>from Wales, UK</from><name>PlanecrazyIkarus</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This sequel takes place several hundred years after the original movie
"Wirthaus im Spessart". The robbers have long been caught and sentenced to
death and killed, now their ghosts have returned to the castle of the
contessa who once befriended their leader. There, they find her
grand-grand-grand..... daughter, and decide to help her out to pay for
their
sins in their lives.Once again it is a romantic comedy, this time with a few ghost sidekicks
thrown in, and lots of slapstick humour that kids like. My favourite part
has to be the musical number "Woll'n wir doch mal sehn ob's nicht
Gespenster
gibt in Bonn" - hillarious!However, I'm not sure how much it would appeal to adults.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1581642/comments</url><from>from Wales, UK</from><name>PlanecrazyIkarus</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>