<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ocean's Eleven</original_title><alt_title>L'inconnu de Las Vegas</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Lewis Milestone</director><producer>Dorchester</producer><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Music</genre><synopsis>
Eleven friends who know each other from World War II service plan to rob five of the biggest casinos in Las Vegas in one night...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Frank Sinatra</actor><actor>Dean Martin</actor><actor>Sammy Davis Jr.</actor><rt_rating>5.2/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>46</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The only real pleasure in "Ocean's Eleven" is being let into the Rat
Pack circle for a couple of hours... The film stops all too frequently
for guest spots and in-jokes, with a slow first hour... Compared to
Jules Dassin's 'Rififi,' or to Phil Karlson's 'Five Against the House,'
it pales considerably... 'Ocean's Eleven' is a weak heist film with the emphasis firmly on light
humor, and few diverting escapades, but nobody cares because the cast
includes the biggest stars of the day (Frankie, Dino, Sammy etc...),
burning the motion picture into the collective memory of the public as
the first to showcase Hollywood's notorious Rat Pack...'Ocean's Eleven' is a buddy movie made with real buddies, and it's
fun... It in't supposed to be very good... It is supposed to be cool...
A playground for legendary entertainers, these guys knew how to get the
job done, to pause only to knock back innumerable Whisky sodas, wear
their tuxedo, hang out in bars, talk the talk, belt out a couple of
classy little numbers, and have a great sense of fun together on
screen... And this fun filtered off the silver screen and into the
audience like a tasty appetizer before the main course...Old Blue Eyes is the mastermind of the heist... He is carrying out a
plan originated by racketeer Spyros Acebos where five gambling casinos
(Sahara, Riviera, Desert Inn, The Sand and The Flamingo) will be robbed
simultaneously at midnight on New Year's celebration...During the week before Christmas, the 'special combat team' (all
experts in one thing and another) arrive in Las Vegas, for the
job-of-a-lifetime... The scheme of the robbery is ingenious, requiring
military precision and perfect timing... An electrical tower will be
blown up to black out the whole town... The swag will be deposited in
garbage cans outside the casinos, and the cans will be collected by a
disposal truck... On New Year's Eve, the hold-up goes off beautifully, exactly as
planned... Only one of the men has a heart attack on the street and
collapses... The gang cannot get the multi-million loot out of Las
Vegas but they manage to hide it in some place, unknown to them,
however, that 'someone' was preparing for them all a nice wry
outcome... Dean Martin, the eternal essence of cool, is the entertainer who sings
"Ain't That a Kick in the Head,' and Sammy Davis Jr. is the perennial
icon of cool who sings "EEO-Eleven.'Peter Lawford is the playboy with one objective and one mission: To hit
Las Vegas, Nevada!Angie Dickinson is the understanding wife, discreet, feminine and
chic... Unfortunately the camera does not especially flatter her
looks...Richard Conte is the master electrician dying of cancer, who needs to
leave some cash for his kid's college...Cesar Romero is coldly menacing and very amusing: 'They shouldn't have
done it while I was in town. It's embarrassing!'George Raft is the mob with the best deal to get the money back...Akim Tamiroff is hilariously neurotic as the master planner...Buddy Lester wants to get his wife out of stripping...Shirley MacLaine is the drunk gal in urge for a little kiss in a
critical moment...Red Skelton is the unlucky player, arguing with the casino cashier how
to raise his gambling limit..."Ocean's Eleven" could never be made again... The new 'Ocean's Eleven,'
2001 is considerably different in the details.. After all, there was
only 'one' Rat Pack, and if the Ocean's Eleven of 1960 is anything, it
is certainly a Rat Pack movie... So if you still have a strange
fascination with this gang of friends, and like to watch essentially a
these guys playing around on screen, and to watch Las Vegas as it
looked in 1960, well... check out this nostalgic trip back... You'll
never see its like again...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0187171/comments</url><from>from California</from><name>BB-15</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

Ocean's 11 never tries to be brilliant and is only sometimes good. The thin
plot is a set up for the "boys" to look sharp (and they sometimes do), sing
songs (which they do well) and to show off 1960 Las Vegas (which by today's
standards looks pretty shabby).                           
This is a second rate heist story with a few gangsters thrown in. But after
all, we have Sinatra and company. You can see that the excellent film, The
Rat Pack, was very right on. Sinatra is his arrogant self. Martin is
relaxed, Lawford is suave and the singing by Sammy Davis Jr. is great.Ocean's 11 is a snap shot of what was "cool" in the ultimate era of
coolness. It's all here, the clubs, the Marilyn Monroe look a likes, the
flashy clothes and lots of money. It's better than imitations such as
Swingers since Ocean's 11 is the source. Of course it includes the legendary
bad treatment of women and African Americans. The actresses are either
add-ons or pathetic martyrs (Angie Dickinson). As for Sammy, he puts up with
the garbage man part, a racial slur (all in good fun of course!) and the
self centeredness of these guys. I just admire him because he had to do it,
so he could perform.Back to the "fun". The boys get to be clever, then there's a surprise ending
and finally we see them shuffle hung over in front of a casino. Every few
years I check out Ocean's 11 not just to watch this silly movie but also to
see the rats (or brats?) and chuckle (and wince) at an amazing time in the
USA, baby.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I remember back in the day when the commercials were out for Ocean's
Eleven it was described as the heist of all time. It wasn't exactly
that, but there is a spirit of camaraderie that is present through out
the film. Frank Sinatra had signed a picture deal with Warner Brothers and was
beginning a long term commitment to the Sands in Las Vegas. What better
way than to combine everything at once. A film on location in Las
Vegas. So Frank got his pallies together and they filmed Ocean's Eleven in
between shows at the Sands. They also managed to get into another film,
several of the principal players in Ocean's Eleven did guest shots in
Pepe while at the Sands.Ocean's Eleven has a lighthearted insouciance about it, a group of
former Airborne Rangers get together in Las Vegas for a heist of the
big casinos carried on with military precision. Why waste all that good
airborne training now that they're civilians.Sinatra doesn't sing in this, I can't imagine why he didn't give
himself a song here, but Dean Martin and Sammy Davis, Jr. did sing two
numbers suited to their talents. Ocean's Eleven marked the first time that Richard Conte worked in a
Sinatra film. He became a Sinatra retainer in his later years,
appearing in several Sinatra films. They parted when Conte appeared in
The Godfather against Frank's wishes. After Ocean's Eleven came Sergeants Three with the main cast members
appearing again. After that the Rat Pack broke up with these guys going
their own way, though many of them did have joint projects together
over the years. The quality of the films went down hill, except for
Robin and the Seven Hoods. That was a musical and not something to be
done in your spare time.The remake of Ocean's Eleven that George Clooney, Brad Pitt, Matt Damon
and several other name players of today did was a far more serious
film. Good in its own way, but just not the same.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0826090/comments</url><from>from Boston, MA</from><name>caspian1978</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The original Ocean's 11 will always remain a classic because of the Rat
Pack. It is unfair to compare both Ocean 11's movie because of the
different cast, different stories, and completely different endings.
Still, looking at both films, you can make a case for both why each is
better than the other. Frankie, Dean, Sammy, Peter and Tony are all
gone now, making the cast of the original legendary. The remake is more
realistic as it answers many if not all the questions that the original
failed to answer. Even for a Rat Pack movie, the original turns out to
be more campy that the remake. The ending alone is worth discussion. In
1960, how wrong is it to have the criminals get away clean? For 2000,
it is not only welcomed but rewarded if the "little guy" can out do or
cheat the big system. For 1960, the ending of Ocean's 11 advertises
that crime does not pay.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5258677/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>NF09</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Two years ago, when I was twelve years old, I watched a video called On
the Town.Uneducated little dunce that I was, before that I'd known only
vaguely of Francis Albert Sinatra. And after spending half the movie
trying to figure out which of the three sailors WAS the Sinatra of whom
I had heard vaguely, I finally decided correctly on the adorable,
skinny one with blue eyes. And promptly after that, I announced to
several uninterested audiences that I was a fan. I am now fourteen. I
have read 60 or 70 biographies on him and his contemporaries, have seen
approximately 25 of his sixty movies, have heard and memorized a
sizable amount of his complete discography, have written quite a few
essays and reviews, and would be more than happy to recite to you a
detailed account of his career, life, and the tremendous gossip and
legends that followed it about.I think those uninterested parties are starting to believe me.In any case, I am a definitive Sinatra adorer writing a review for one
of his movies, so I'll warn you before hand: it may be a little bit
biased, but I'm going to be as honest as I can. All right. You've been
warned. Carry on then.The main problem I've read about in these ''instructive criticism
reviews,'' is that this movie moves much too slowly, meaning that for
the first hour or so the picture is about Frank and company, not about
eleven guys holding up a couple of casinos. I readily admit that, and
so much the better. If you expected to see the latter when you saw the
posters proclaiming FRANK SINATRA!! DEAN MARTIN! SAMMY DAVIS JR.!!, you
are extremely dense and certainly deserve your disappointment. Yes,
believe it or not, this is a RAT PACK movie, and as such it happens, by
a strange twist of fate, to be about the Rat Pack. Elementary, my dear
Watson.Another complaint involves severe lack of plot.(See above inscription.)Yet another of the whiners has pouted that none of the cast appears to
have much interest in what they're doing. I would like to mention here
that, like they themselves modestly pointed out in a gag used
frequently on various Vegas stages, they could do this kind of stuff
anytime they wanted to. At this moment in time Frank Sinatra was the #1
singer in the country, the #1 box office attraction in the country, one
of the highest paid individuals who ever won an Oscar or a Grammy, the
biggest draw in Las Vegas, or anywhere else for that matter, had more
power than all the Harry Cohns and Louis B.Mayers put together, and was
on his way to Camelot with Senator John Fitzgerald Kennedy. The Rat
Pack playing at the Sands was such a gigantic draw they were having to
turn down thousands of reservations, and when Ocean's 11 was released
it immediately made the list for the biggest box office smashes of all
time.In other words,even if the whiner's complaint is true, (and I don't
think it is) it's laughable to imagine that the Clan's not especially
caring whether or not they won Academy Awards would stop either the
success of the movie or (ha) their careers.Anyway, if they are blasé in the picture, they are the coolest
not-caring actors in show business. There is also a much more serious accusation that many people actually
believe. And I honestly believe that this accusation is not true. This
rumor involves the color conscious sixties, some allegedly racist
jokes, and Sammy Davis Jr.Yeah, the Rat Pack told some jokes about Sammy. On the Copa Room stagemany an audience would roar at stupid gags like ''Keep smilin' Smoky,
so everyone knows where you are" and '' Nat King Cole was a merry old
soul.A merry old soul was Nat King Cole.... A merry old COLORED soul,''
and ''Have you noticed how much better it sounds when he does his own
people rather than our people?'' And, of course there were the times
when Dean would scoop little Sammy up in his arms, waltz forward, and
say ''I'd like to thank the NAACP for this trophy.''Sam, for his own part, would come on after Dean sang ,''Did you ever
see a Jew - jitsu? Well, I did.'' and complain on cue ''How would you
like it if I said,' Did you ever see a wop-SICLE!!!''It didn't mean a thing. It wasn't cruel. It was corny, hilarious
chatter between three grown-up boys who treated each other - and kidded
each other- like brothers. It's only since then that the situation has
been contorted into a racial injustice by idiots who are looking for a
fight. That's all.I guess that about sums up the Defence's case, unless the Prosecution
has anything it wishes to add. No? All right then.I love this movie. I'll admit that. I know there is probably a grand
total of 3 critics out there who agree with me, but I'm not a critic.
I'm a fan. I'll never tire of watching Sam dancing on garbage cans as
he sings Ee-o-eleven, or be bored watching Dean, with his nonchalant
cool, croon about you-know-what being a kick in the head, and I can't
watch that last scene enough where Frank Sinatra, Dean Martin, and
Sammy Davis Jr. stroll past The Sands' sign that advertises.... I'd
better not give it away. Watch it yourself.There are plenty of better movies out there- but there was only one Rat
Pack.And, no matter what anyone say's- They were magic. This is magic.Ring-a-ding ding.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2556340/comments</url><from/><name>misslv80</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Ocean's Eleven is the definitive Rat Pack film. I have not seen the remake,
but it's hard to imagine a new crew who could pull off a Las Vegas heist
like old Frank, Sammy, Dean, and all the rest. Ocean's 11 represents a
period of time when the Rat Pack were at the top of their game. I really
liked the simplicity of the film, that snappy and campy Rat Pack humor. The
film has a great score by Nelson Riddle and the intro/opening credits of the
movie were very imaginative for its day. Watching this movie, I was almost
rooting for the guys to pull off the heist and get away with it. The movie
also features Angie Dickinson, who plays Sinatra's long-suffering wife,
Cesar Romero as a shady character who is engaged to Peter Lawford's mother,
and Norman Fell (who went on to play Mr. Roper in Three's Company) as one of
the Eleven. Shirley Maclaine also has an uncredited cameo. It's definitely a
must for any Rat Pack fan! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0137908/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>didi-5</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This version of 'Ocean's 11' hardly needed a plot, did it?  Just an extended
ad for the Rat Pack's Vegas shows and the enormous ego of Frank Sinatra,
here strutting his stuff as Danny Ocean, leading his war chums in a plan to
rob numerous casinos in one night.So we get Sinatra, Dean Martin, Sammy Davis, Peter Lawford, and Joey Bishop
(did they play characters in this?  can anybody remember who?) and a fun
romp to the pay off - still getting referenced in films being made today. 
George Clooney's remake was nowhere near as much fun.  There's music in this
movie, of course (with that cast you'd be disappointed if not), plus
appearances from Angie Dickinson, Shirley MacLaine (uncredited but
noticeable), Cesar Romero, and Errol Flynn's widow Patrice
Wymore.This really is a lightweight lark if you're in the mood.  Is it a good film?
 Probably not.  Is it good entertainment?  Absolutely.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0191275/comments</url><from>from Annandale, VA</from><name>bobc-5</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
While other movies try to induce the willing suspension of disbelief,
this movie goes the entire opposite direction and never lets us forget
that these are entertainers putting on a performance. In case you
weren't entirely sure, the closing shot leaves no doubt. As one
reviewer perfectly describes it, "The blurred boundaries between
showbiz and private life seem to have vanished for good." That's quite
an accomplishment!The stars aren't acting, they're partying down in an elaborate
role-playing game and inviting you the viewer to play along with them.
Join the party and for 2 hours you too can be a swinging, sophisticated
member of the rat pack who can simultaneously handle a martini and
cigarette in one hand and doesn't have to pause for even a second when
somebody asks "what's your drink?". "Ocean's Eleven" is the "Pulp
Fiction" of the Kennedy era - a movie that makes you feel hip just to
watch it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1455067/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>discogoth</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I haven't seen the new remake of this movie yet, but they have some pretty
big shoes to fill. Technically Ocean's Eleven may not be a great film, but
whatever minor plot shortcomings that exist are made up for in spades by
immeasurable style.I'm not going to explain the plot, as I'm sure that 50 other people already
have. It's been a while since I've watched an older movie, so I found the
loose-yet-confident chemistry and acting of the brat pack members to be
very
refreshing. They seemed so natural around each other, which is no surprise
considering that they were buddies in real life. Sammy Davis Jr. was his
usual charismatic self (why didn't he take off with the money??), Dean
Martin seemed to be playing himself, a bit tipsy and sweaty with a drink in
one hand and a smoke in the other, as he does in most of his films, and
Frank Sinatra was also good as the understated womanizing organizer.
However, I thought that Cesar Romero (known for his manic portayal of the
Joker in the 60's Batman tv series) really stole the show right out from
under the overly confident brat pack...I found his performance to be very
commanding and impressive. A nice surprise to see comedian Red Skelton and
Norm Fell (Three's Company's Mr. Roper!) in there as well!A few things hilariously go unexplained, like how they all managed to get
casino jobs virtually overnnight, but it hardly seemed to matter. You know
this movie is basically just a vehicle for the brat pack, and it's pure
entertainment to just watch all these legends hamming it up, especially
during the couple of musical interludes where you get to hear Dean Martin
and Sammy Davis Jr. croon a few really catchy songs, like E-O Eleven!At the same time it's also a window into another era, a time of larger than
life Hollywood stars. Another thing that really jumped out at me was how
unabashedly politically incorrect this movie is, showcasing a dramatically
different mentality than what we see in movies today. Ocean's Eleven is a
pure guy flick, where all the women are no more than window dressing and
are
treated as such by the male characters. As dated as the macho attitude of
the film may seem nowadays (and even already by late 60's standards), I
found it to be a fascinating glimpse into the past when guys were guys and
women were umm, dames! As ironic as it is, I found seeing this old movie
without the typical modern day contrived politically correct preaching to
be
very refreshing, and somehow strangely rebellious!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5501912/comments</url><from/><name>silverscreen888</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Please, forget whatever you have heard about this film. It is a very
interesting adventure-comedy, very-well directed, decently-acted and
intelligently presented. The "Rat PacK' whom singer Frank Sinatra had
gathered about him in the late 1950s and early 1960s included singers
Sammy Davis Jr. and Dean Martin, comic Buddy Lester and Joey Bishop and
actor Peter Lawford. This is the best film this group of friends ever
made together, one absolutely filled with interesting character
revelations, old Sinatra songs used as background and fine co-stars
including Ilka Chase, Cesar Romero, Angie Dickinson, Akim Tamiroff,
Richard Conte, Henry Silva, Patrice Wymore, Norman Fell, Richard
Benedict, Jean Willes, Clem Harvey and George Raft. This effort has
very good dialogue, many interesting confrontations between characters
and the best portrait of Las Vegas 1960 available anywhere. It also has
that rare achievement, style,, and a fascinating plot-theme. Danny
Ocean's old outfit from WWII have been home 15 years-- and they are
finding there is no place in a corporate-government bureaucratized
United States for independent minds--they are all facing a "system"
that wants no part of men who think for themselves or want justice and
are willing to work to get it. Enter Tamiroff, who plays an idea
man--Acevos--who with the help of Sinatra and Lawford concocts a daring
plan to rob several Las Vegas casinos on New Year's Eve of millions of
dollars. The plan requires commando-like precision and skills--so Ocean
recruits his hungry war buddies, ranging from Conte with a serious
heart condition who wants to do something for his son, to Lawford who
just wants to recapture the wartime sense of purpose, to bright,
talented Sammy Davis, stuck on a garbage truck. The plan is initiated
and set into motion step-by-interesting step; but even when it comes
off flawlessly, the outfit is not home free. Chase's fiancée, Romero as
Duke Santos, a man who plays the percentages and has gone legit is
hired by the casinos' owners to find the money for a finder's fee; and
he puts two and two together--and comes up with eleven. The surprise
climax, as the money, secreted for out-of-town delivery in the coffin
of a dead Richard Conte, ends up being burned in a cremation ceremony
as the group are present for the funeral is a classic of its sort. Of
course, this disaster robs Ocean's team of their proceeds, but keeps
Santos from profiting and makes sure they do not go to jail. At the
end, the eleven wander into the sunlight, to ponder perhaps another
scheme to get the justice that seems to be nowhere for them. The film
has a very-special look. with Nelson Riddle's music, Lewis Milestone's
veteran direction and a good script as its main underproppings. This is
a storyline so strong it can be a mission film, an adventure and a
satirical comedy at the same time. its authors can digress, make a joke
at their own expense and deliver a telling one-liner with powerful
effect. It has characters, warmth, and much more. An unpolished gem.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5501912/comments</url><from/><name>silverscreen888</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Please, forget whatever you have heard about this film. It is a very
interesting adventure-comedy, very-well directed, decently-acted and
intelligently presented. The "Rat PacK' whom singer Frank Sinatra had
gathered about him in the late 1950s and early 1960s included singers
Sammy Davis Jr. and Dean Martin, comic Buddy Lester and Joey Bishop and
actor Peter Lawford. This is the best film this group of friends ever
made together, one absolutely filled with interesting character
revelations, old Sinatra songs used as background and fine co-stars
including Ilka Chase, Cesar Romero, Angie Dickinson, Akim Tamiroff,
Richard Conte, Henry Silva, Patrice Wymore, Norman Fell, Richard
Benedict, Jean Willes, Clem Harvey and George Raft. This effort has
very good dialogue, many interesting confrontations between characters
and the best portrait of Las Vegas 1960 available anywhere. It also has
that rare achievement, style,, and a fascinating plot-theme. Danny
Ocean's old outfit from WWII have been home 15 years-- and they are
finding there is no place in a corporate-government bureaucratized
United States for independent minds--they are all facing a "system"
that wants no part of men who think for themselves or want justice and
are willing to work to get it. Enter Tamiroff, who plays an idea
man--Acevos--who with the help of Sinatra and Lawford concocts a daring
plan to rob several Las Vegas casinos on New Year's Eve of millions of
dollars. The plan requires commando-like precision and skills--so Ocean
recruits his hungry war buddies, ranging from Conte with a serious
heart condition who wants to do something for his son, to Lawford who
just wants to recapture the wartime sense of purpose, to bright,
talented Sammy Davis, stuck on a garbage truck. The plan is initiated
and set into motion step-by-interesting step; but even when it comes
off flawlessly, the outfit is not home free. Chase's fiancée, Romero as
Duke Santos, a man who plays the percentages and has gone legit is
hired by the casinos' owners to find the money for a finder's fee; and
he puts two and two together--and comes up with eleven. The surprise
climax, as the money, secreted for out-of-town delivery in the coffin
of a dead Richard Conte, ends up being burned in a cremation ceremony
as the group are present for the funeral is a classic of its sort. Of
course, this disaster robs Ocean's team of their proceeds, but keeps
Santos from profiting and makes sure they do not go to jail. At the
end, the eleven wander into the sunlight, to ponder perhaps another
scheme to get the justice that seems to be nowhere for them. The film
has a very-special look. with Nelson Riddle's music, Lewis Milestone's
veteran direction and a good script as its main underproppings. This is
a storyline so strong it can be a mission film, an adventure and a
satirical comedy at the same time. its authors can digress, make a joke
at their own expense and deliver a telling one-liner with powerful
effect. It has characters, warmth, and much more. An unpolished gem.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/charles-cassady/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/oceans-eleven-1960  /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1946149</url><name>Charles Cassady</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Chummy caper comedy, mainly for Rat Pack fanciers.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/colin-kennedy/</url><url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/reviewcomplete.asp?FID=131241 /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1825871</url><name>Colin Kennedy</name><from>Empire Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>There are many incidental pleasures to be had.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=106651&amp;section=review /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1825870</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>Considering the iconic status of all involved, the result is disappointing.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies.tvguide.com/oceans/review/107921 /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1825869</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/4
					</rating><comment>Sinatra, Davis, and Martin performed their club acts at night and worked on this Las Vegas-set film during the day, and the good time they were having fairly jumps off the screen.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117793637.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1825868</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>Laboring under the handicaps of a contrived script, an uncertain approach and personalities in essence playing themselves, the production never quite makes its point, but romps along merrily unconcerned that it doesn't.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/13300_OCEANS_ELEVEN_MILESTONE /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1825866</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>Terminally boring.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/65899/oceans_11.html /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1518460</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>The heist itself, though, is a superb piece of movie-making.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/oceans11.shtml /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1509460</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/4
					</rating><comment>One suspects that the most memorable moments occurred off-camera.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9F06E6D7113EEF3ABC4952DFBE66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1389685</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>Young people are likely to find this more appropriate and bewitching than do their elders. The latter are likely to feel less gleeful in the presence of heroes who rob and steal.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jon-niccum/</url><url>/m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1130166</url><name>Jon Niccum</name><from>Lawrence Journal-World</from></reviewer><rating>
1/5
					</rating><comment>Sluggishly paced, shoddily staged, and featuring a plot full of inconsistencies</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/alex-sandell/</url><url>/m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1121994</url><name>Alex Sandell</name><from>Juicy Cerebellum</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>At least as entertaining as the remake. Probably better.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/edward-johnson-ott/</url><url>/m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=851459</url><name>Edward Johnson-Ott</name><from>NUVO Newsweekly</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Tepid. The idea is so much better than the execution.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/brian-webster/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=3866 /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=284276</url><name>Brian Webster</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
75/100
					</rating><comment>A heist flick that counts on its coolness -- and a remarkably downbeat ending -- for its success.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>http://www.dvdtown.com/review/oceans-11/blu-ray/8488 /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=282965</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/10
					</rating><comment>Think of it as an ancient-history lesson in the social evolution of long-extinct male dinosaurs.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/karen-croft/</url><url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2001/12/11/oceans_rant /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=273536</url><name>Karen Croft</name><from>Salon.com</from></reviewer><comment>The original Ocean's is fun, fun, fun.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tom-coates/</url><url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/films/2001/06/06/oceans_eleven_1960_review.shtml /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=264786</url><name>Tom Coates</name><from>BBC</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>There are just too many main characters for any of them to develop any depth, too many shots of casino signs sparkling in the night, and too little pace and plot to pull the whole thing together.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Oceans-Eleven-(1960) /m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=13838</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Implausible yet wholly unforgettable</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>/m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1680457</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1408358</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/greg-maki/</url><url>/m/1015373-oceans_eleven/comments.php?reviewid=1372586</url><name>Greg Maki</name><from>Star-Democrat (Easton, MD)</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>