<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Kanoon</original_title><imdb_rating>7.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>B.R. Chopra</director><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><synopsis>
A lawyer holds the eyewitness evidence to catch a killer, but the identified criminal is the lawyer's own mentor, prospective father-in-law, and also the judge who presides over the case.
</synopsis><actor>Rajendra Kumar</actor><actor>Ashok Kumar</actor><actor>Nanda</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16522302/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>Peter Young</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
B.R. Chopra's Kanoon is a damn good movie of its time. It is a murder
mystery cum courtroom drama and is generally full of suspense which
makes for a very effective and interesting watch. The concept is very
well brought out on screen. Kanoon questions the righteousness of
India's judicial system and shows the two faces of justice and law.
There's a saying which says, "It is easier to commit murder than to
justify it". This film only strengthens it. It is well scripted and
narrated, and Chopra's direction is excellent. He pays attention to
details and makes the viewer a silent and curious witness of the
often-confusing proceedings. The film is often cited as the first Hindi
film which has absolutely no songs. That was quite a refreshing change.
It moves at a steady pace and is consistently tense and intriguing. The
courtroom scenes are fascinating. That said, Kanoon is not flawless and
it certainly could have been better. As I expected from Chopra, the
ending is a bit sugarcoated, and the long speech in court did not make
much sense to me. The cast, however, is roundly good. Ashok Kumar, who
is according to me one of the finest actors to have ever appeared in
Hindi cinema, is unsurprisingly excellent. He is at par with the best
actors from Hollywood's golden era: classy, controlled, likable and
restrained, always delivering nuanced, impressive and convincing
performances. Rajendra Kumar is also very good though he is a bit
over-the-top at times. Mehmood introduces another comic character which
does not really go well with the proceedings, and this is another flaw.
Nanda and Manmohan Krishna are both effective. But, the one who
completely steals the show, and I think many would agree with me, is
Nana Palsikar, in a performance that is heartfelt and moving. His
character was the one I felt for the most, and due credit for this goes
to the actor himself. He brilliantly captures his character's essence,
which proves once again that poverty is the mother of all crimes. All
said and done, Kanoon is a Hindi classic which is worth watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22238372/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>jmathur_swayamprabha</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is an excellent suspense-thriller of 1960 which is an all time
classic from the black and white era. Can you imagine a bollywood
entertainer from the fifties and the sixties which is sans the regular
ingredients of songs, romance and comedy ? No ? Please do see Kanoon
which is devoid of songs, romance and comedy and yet it keeps you glued
to the screen for two and a half hours. Its suspenseful drama is so
impactful that the audience does not feel any need for any other
bollywood formulae in the narrative.It discusses the relevance of the DEATH PELANTY or the CAPITAL
PUNISHMENT too. The verdict of the moviemaker is that the death penalty
should be done away with in toto. My own view is that let it be in the
books of law, only to be awarded in the rarest of rare cases. It has
its importance but considering the fact that once awarded, it cannot be
reverted even if it is known later that the verdict of the case was a
faulty one; it should be awarded only selectively when the crime is
quite heinous and there is little doubt in the accused's being guilty.Judge Badri Prasad (Ashok Kumar) strongly opines that the capital
punishment should be deleted from the book of Indian Penal Code because
it is cruel and moreoever it does not leave any scope to correct the
faulty judgment in any case which is always likely because judgments
are given on the basis of evidences and witnesses which might be
misleading. The twist in the tale comes when a moneylender, Dhaniram
(Om Prakash) who is after his borrower son, Vijay (Mahmood) is
murdered. The interesting thing is that the judge's would be
son-in-law, Kailash (Rajender Kumar) is the eye-witness to this murder
and he is shocked to see that the murderer is the judge himself. Now
when an innocent person is arrested and put under trial for this murder
in the court of the same judge with Kailash being the defense lawyer,
the mutual relations of the judge, Kailash and the judge's daughter,
Meena (Nanda) become tense and uneasy. After a memorable court-room
drama, Kailash accuses his would-be father-in-law to be the murderer
and gets him arrested and put under trial for the murder. The truth is
revealed in the end with the reiteration that death penalty should be
considered redundant and deleted from the legal books.This suspense-thriller is so intriguing that it engrosses the viewer
from the beginning to the end without any boredom. The viewer just
forgets that there are no songs, no romance and no comedy served to
him. He only keeps on watching, holding his breath and waiting for the
suspense to be revealed. Legendary producer-director B.R. Chopra has
directed this movie with such finesse that it is considered a twinkling
diamond in the highly decorated crown worn by him.The performances are great. Ashok Kumar and Rajender Kumar have
delivered great performances in a neck-to-neck contest of excellence.
Nanda, Jeevan, Mahmood, Manmohan Krishna, Shashikala, Nana Palsikar
(won the award for the best supporting actor for this movie) and Om
Prakash, all have done admirably.As already said, there are no songs. However the background score is
impressive. Technically this black and white movie is perfect without
any deficiencies.On the flip side, the narrative loses its charm in the end after
revelation of the suspense and the five minutes long lecture of Ashok
Kumar on the relevance of the capital punishment bores. Anyway, this is
not a big minus point because the movie is just about to end.Some three decades back, a session judge, Justice Sanwar Mal Agarwal
had awarded capital punishment in a dowry-murder case and became quite
famous due to this verdict. I had read his interview given to the
popular Hindi magazine - Sarita in which he had referred to this movie
(seen in his youth when he was studying law) and asserted that the
difference between reel courts and real courts is even bigger than the
reel life and real life. He's right. The high-voltage drama shown in
the court in this movie is impossible to be witnessed in real courts.
We can ignore this unreal portrayal of courts for the sake of the
liberty taken by the narrator for the sake of entertaining the
audience, i.e., us.Summing up, Kanoon is an edge-of-the-seat classic suspense-thriller
with a gripping court-room drama. No movie buff should miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16566113/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mehtarohit87</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The word's on the street that director B.R. Chopra, commercially
successful after his early sensations like Naya Daur and Dhool ka
Phool, was once in Germany attending a film festival. He took it as a
challenge when told that 'Indian films have nothing but songs', hence,
giving birth to Kanoon (1960), India's first songless Hindi film.I always believe that when taking a critical decision, people either
choose between right and wrong OR between friends and strangers.
Irrespective of the fact that its someone from your family who sinned,
you'd choose between right and wrong. Rajendra Kumar falls under a
similar dilemma in this 150 min courtroom drama.The film revolves around a judge, played by the superstar of that era,
Ashok Kumar. Kumar had faith in this unconventional story about a judge
who starts to find flaws in the Indian Judicial System after a failed
decision from the past comes haunting his court. Played by Jeevan, a
man who went to prison for ten years for a crime he did not commit is
released. Ironically, he commits the exact crime he went to prison for,
just to prove a point. Although, he suffers from a stroke during the
proceedings, successfully brings out some serious flaws in the system.The story takes its natural course with another murder. The film is
about the proceedings of this case in Kumar's court, defended by
Rajendra Kumar who is also the soon to become son-in-law of the judge.The film starts with promise, drags at times and picks up again. This
happens not once or twice but at several occasions. The lack of
expertise in the genre is visible as the grip at the mystery looses
right in the beginning.As a viewer, you are a part of all the secrets. Or that is what you
think. As most of the characters are one dimensional, there is nothing
much left to fathom. For one who is an ardent follower of mysteries,
this is a below average feature. From the Indian point of view, this
rebellious film was an instant classic. Nothing like the usual Indian
films, Kanoon casts a strong impression on the Indian minds. Although,
at a couple of instances some brief music pieces are inserted as a part
of the story, these do not let the story digress from its main course;
just slows the pace a bit.The acting, to my disappointment, was equally over-the-top as the other
Indian movies, especially the ones of those times. Ashok Kumar, being
the senior most actor, is content. On the other hand, Nanda, playing
his daughter, is heavily artificial and Rajendra Kumar walks in and out
of his zone of comfort. Others are just forgettable. But the one that
bothers the most, is Mehmood. Though Mehmood grew out to become the
greatest comedian alive in India, this was one of his early films and
probably one of his worst performances. His bizarre style of delivering
dialogs break the rhythm of the film that could have been much better
without his idiotic mannerisms.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16566113/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mehtarohit87</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The word's on the street that director B.R. Chopra, commercially
successful after his early sensations like Naya Daur and Dhool ka
Phool, was once in Germany attending a film festival. He took it as a
challenge when told that 'Indian films have nothing but songs', hence,
giving birth to Kanoon (1960), India's first songless Hindi film.I always believe that when taking a critical decision, people either
choose between right and wrong OR between friends and strangers.
Irrespective of the fact that its someone from your family who sinned,
you'd choose between right and wrong. Rajendra Kumar falls under a
similar dilemma in this 150 min courtroom drama.The film revolves around a judge, played by the superstar of that era,
Ashok Kumar. Kumar had faith in this unconventional story about a judge
who starts to find flaws in the Indian Judicial System after a failed
decision from the past comes haunting his court. Played by Jeevan, a
man who went to prison for ten years for a crime he did not commit is
released. Ironically, he commits the exact crime he went to prison for,
just to prove a point. Although, he suffers from a stroke during the
proceedings, successfully brings out some serious flaws in the system.The story takes its natural course with another murder. The film is
about the proceedings of this case in Kumar's court, defended by
Rajendra Kumar who is also the soon to become son-in-law of the judge.The film starts with promise, drags at times and picks up again. This
happens not once or twice but at several occasions. The lack of
expertise in the genre is visible as the grip at the mystery looses
right in the beginning.As a viewer, you are a part of all the secrets. Or that is what you
think. As most of the characters are one dimensional, there is nothing
much left to fathom. For one who is an ardent follower of mysteries,
this is a below average feature. From the Indian point of view, this
rebellious film was an instant classic. Nothing like the usual Indian
films, Kanoon casts a strong impression on the Indian minds. Although,
at a couple of instances some brief music pieces are inserted as a part
of the story, these do not let the story digress from its main course;
just slows the pace a bit.The acting, to my disappointment, was equally over-the-top as the other
Indian movies, especially the ones of those times. Ashok Kumar, being
the senior most actor, is content. On the other hand, Nanda, playing
his daughter, is heavily artificial and Rajendra Kumar walks in and out
of his zone of comfort. Others are just forgettable. But the one that
bothers the most, is Mehmood. Though Mehmood grew out to become the
greatest comedian alive in India, this was one of his early films and
probably one of his worst performances. His bizarre style of delivering
dialogs break the rhythm of the film that could have been much better
without his idiotic mannerisms.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>