<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Mountain Road</original_title><alt_title>Le commando de destruction</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Daniel Mann</director><producer>William Goetz Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>THE REAL EPIC OF THE SCORCHED EARTH...when hate and heroism, danger and disaster blocked escape on...THE MOUNTAIN ROAD</synopsis><actor>James Stewart</actor><actor>Lisa Lu</actor><actor>Glenn Corbett</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0410081/comments</url><from>from Columbus, GA</from><name>Michael J. Horn</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

This film portrays the lives of a US Army engineer squad in China during
WW
II.  Their mission is to delay the advance of the Japanese Army.  They
must
blow up bridges and ammo dumps along a long mountain road while dealing
with
a never ending line of Chinese refugees.  James Stewart finds love with a
beautiful Chinese widow.  He must deal with his personal feelings toward a
woman, a foreign people and the challenges of command.  Not one of your
best
Jimmy Stewart movies but well worth a look. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This film can really be subtitled, "Why did We Bother to Get
Involved?". It is the kind of World War II film that Hollywood would
never have shot in the 1940s. For the purpose of wartime propaganda is
to attack one enemy at a time. In 1941 - 1945 the Japanese were the
enemy, and our allies were the brave Chinese people. Only a handful of
specialists on China knew the complexity of relationships in Chinese
politics. One was Lieutenant General Joseph ("Vinigar Joe") Stillwell,
who had been in China since the 1930s. He knew the main enemy was
Japan, but he had little trust for the Kuomintang government of General
Chang Kai Shek, which he knew was corrupt. China since the teens had
been suffering from a large number of civil wars between generals with
armies called "War-Lords". When Sun Yat Sen founded the Kuomingtang he
hoped to get the assistance of the west to build up it's arms and
defeat the war-lords. Unfortunately the Japanese prevented this kind of
period of consolidation to occur, so Chang found he was supporting the
representatives of a constitutional government, and was opposed by the
Japanese and the War-Lords. Then a third foe arose: the Communists
under Mao Tse Tung. In such a complex quilt pattern like country, we
could not know who were our friends or foes. Washington, D.C. decided
our ally was Chang, and Stillwell was frustrated on the support we
wasted on him and his cohorts.THE MOUNTAIN ROAD is a simple film about a set of Americans, led by
Jimmy Stewart, who are ordered to slow down a Japanese advance into
Western China by the Japanese. The interesting thing of the movie is
that we never seen any Japanese soldiers. No we see only Americans and
Chinese. We see how they mingle and interrelate, but also how they may
end up fighting. Americans being hurt by one of the brave allied people
we try to help - how familiar that sounds nowadays.Stewart initially tries to get permission from the local Kuomintgang
Colonel to blow up a bridge. He does get it, although he finds the
customs of the Colonel too showy (he has to eat some lunch with the
Colonel). He is given the use of a Colonel Kwan (Henry Silva) as a
translator, and he has to escort a well educated woman, a General's
widow (Lisa Lu) to the town that is their destination. Stewart has
always wanted to have a command, so he had agreed to this one. He has
Harry Morgan as his chief sergeant, James Best and Mike Kellin as two
of his troops, and Glenn Corbett as Collins, his right hand man and
translator.The film really follows how the Americans deal with their erstwhile
allies, and the results are somewhat discouraging. As time passes
Steward's patience with the Chinese begins to crack. In particular two
tragedies destroy it: the death of Collins while trying to do an act of
kindness to the starving villagers they are among; and the roadside
murder and robbery of two of the men (one a sick man) by Chinese
soldiers turned into bandits. Stewart and Lu had slowly developed a
love affair but the two tragedies, and Stewart's reaction to the second
destroy what chances the bi-racial love affair might have had. In the
end they part, and Stewart realizes he was to blame for it.Or was he? Lu makes several realistic assessments of what her China
requires to survive, and it is right that unity is needed. But she is
unwilling to admit that her people do not have the right to kill people
for personal gain. She keeps hiding behind the fact that they don't
know better. Yet the scene when Stewart catches the thief and murderers
drinking in a bar in a town, they realize what he is there about and
start arming themselves for the upcoming fight. Stewart tries to
explain his seeking punishment of the guilty was do to the headiness of
having the power of life and death in the form of his getting an active
command on the field. That may be true, but the two incidents involving
his men and the locals hardly paint them as innocents types protecting
themselves against wicked Americans. In the end the two points of view
just cannot meet at a particular point. So the romance cannot last. But
the audience wonders if friendship between the two countries is worth
it in the end.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4873814/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>stevegoode1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The Mountain Road is the story of an American Enginers destroying
military stockpile ahead of a Japanese advance in late World War II.
The corrupted Chinese Warlords refused to equip their men for the fight
against the Japaneses and wanted to hoard so they could profit from the
sale of gasoline and military supplies. One of the themes of the movie
is the cultural clash between Americans and Chineses. One of the major
difference between the two was the value of human life. I wish that
this movie was available on DVD or VHS tape as I would like to have it
for my collection. It is well worth while seeing to see one aspect of
World War II in China.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0208117/comments</url><from>from Ny, NY</from><name>Holly (aromatic@ivillage.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Intriguing wartime character studies. Outstanding characters abound. 
Stewart's romance with the Asian female lead is very poignant. Harry Morgan
and Mike Kellin give outstanding character support - in fact the whole cast
does, including a young James Best, looking hunky, well before his Dukes of
Hazzard days.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The only film that World War II veteran James Stewart made during his
career was one far away from his wartime experience flying missions
over Germany in the European Theater. In fact it's the Chinese mainland
theater which few have ever written about.One of those who did was Theodore H. White who in the year before his
first Making of the President books came out wrote the novel on which
The Mountain Road is based. White was a correspondent during World War
II and he covered this forgotten theater of the war where more time was
spent in the quarrels with American commander Joseph Stilwell and
Generalissimo Chiang Kai-Shek of the Kuomintang Nationalist Chinese
forces than in actually fighting the Japanese.The year is 1944 and the Japanese army is once again on the offensive
and the Chinese are retreating deeper into their interior. Stewart
heads an eight man army demolition team and he's destroying a whole lot
of things useful to the advancing Japanese, scorching the Chinese earth
for the invaders.But he's in a country that the only things Americans know about it come
from missionary tales, Pearl Buck novels, and Charlie Chan movies.
Which would make Stewart's character no different than most of the rest
of his countrymen. One of the people in his team is the Chinese
speaking Glenn Corbett who's studied the language and culture.In this war movie, we never see the Japanese. Stewart's big problems
come from the mass of refugees heading west to escape the advancing
Japanese. He's also dealing with conflicting orders, with Chinese
commanders looking to evade responsibility, and some outright bandits
who really don't care who wins the war.Four of the team are killed and the reprisals Stewart takes cost him
the affection of Lisa Lu, widow of a Chinese general who chose wrong
politically and paid for it. Actually the performance I liked best in the movie is that of Frank
Silvera as a Chinese Kuomintang commander who actually does understand
and sympathize with Stewart, but who also knows his people.My guess is that James Stewart took this film because it's not a
typical war film with no great combat scenes. It's about the
responsibility of command in a war where you can't tell whom you should
fear.Still The Mountain Road drags in spots and comes to no real
satisfactory conclusion. It's different, but because of that remains
one of James Stewart's least known and viewed films.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0376331/comments</url><from>from concord, ca</from><name>mike-859</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Watching this film with jimmy stewart as a driven military man was
interesting. I have always thought of stewart in the role in Harvey or its
a
wonderful life.Stewarts characters struggle with power and his obsession to accomplish
his
objective was fun to watch. This film is worth the time spent and includes
some great character actors of this period. I think it deserves its 6.6
overall rating.Watching this movie develop reminded me of recent events in europe and
made
the film seem timely despite its age.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3285083/comments</url><from>from Japan</from><name>matchettja</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Major Baldwin (Stewart) has his first command in East China when he is
put in charge of a demolition squad with orders to evacuate once a base
has been destroyed to prevent its capture by the advancing Japanese.
Along the way he discovers the power associated with command and the
abuse temptation offers along with such power. He also encounters some
unexpected romance when the widow of a Chinese general in need of
evacuation joins his squad.Unfortunately, as the group never comes into contact with the Japanese
and is never in serious danger, we don't feel a lot of tension.
Whatever threat there is comes from the Chinese themselves, from mobs
of starving peasants to bands of wayward deserting marauders.The most interesting feature of the film deals with the difference of
customs. The pomp and ceremony important to Chinese is alien to the
Americans just wanting to get down to the business at hand. Looking
from different points of view, each side views the other as somewhat
barbarous and inhumane and as a result never quite reach the level of
friendship each would have.Although Jerome Morass provides a spirited music score, it doesn't
quite fit in with the action, or rather the lack of it. With an
exception or two, the events on the screen just never generate much
pathos, resulting in a not so poignant anti-war film.Stewart, as always, is worth watching, Lisa Lu has charm, and Harry
Morgan gives a preview of what would become his Colonel Potter M*A*S*H*
character.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0278527/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Hitchcoc</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I am a huge Jimmy Stewart fan. Yet this film left me cold. I think that
the director and the screenplay conspire to not let him develop as a
character. One time he is doing some poignant scene, where one thinks
he has turned a corner in his short-sighted racist view of the larger
world, and in moment, he goes right back to where he was. There's no
carry-over. This film takes place in 1944 as the U. S. forces are in
Chine, looking out for a tenuous ally. This particular group is a
demolitions team whose purpose is to blow up roads and bridges and move
on. The Japanese are very formidable and have decimated the Chinese
people. Stewart expects the Chinese to act like Americans (Sound
familiar?) but can't get them to follow his lead. Starvation and pain
have a way of doing that. His relationship with a Chinese woman is the
most interesting. I'm sure the cowardly film boards kept anything from
happening. Once that factor in the film is thrown out, there is a
skeleton left and it's not a very interesting one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17409002/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gerdeen-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Legendary American reporter Theodore H. White covered China in the
1940s, and he wrote the novel on which this unusual James Stewart
feature is based. It's not quite anti-war, but it's a very long way
from the flag-waving military movies that Stewart made in the 1950s.Stewart's character is a U.S. military engineer working with a small
team trying to slow a Japanese advance in China. Though there's plenty
of action (especially explosions), the emphasis is on the Americans'
interaction with their Chinese allies -- which is fraught with
problems. Stewart's character has a local love interest, played by Lisa
Lu, but their relationship is nothing like a conventional GI romance."The Mountain Road" was obviously meant to be a thought-provoking look
back at World War II, and to audiences in the early 1960s it probably
was. The climax may have been almost shocking. In today's more jaded
world, the movie is likely to strike many viewers as dull, with an
ending that resolves very little. But it you still have a rose-colored
view of the "Greatest War," and think it was less morally messy than
our current conflicts, this could be enlightening.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Enjoyed this film which was shown on TCM and I was very surprised to
see that James Stewart, (Major Baldwin) starred in this film which is
about a unit of American Engineers who were a demolition crew out to
destroy a Chinese stockpile of weapons. These men had to travel on one
mountain road which had plenty of these stockpiles to destroy in order
to make certain the Japanese did not obtain any of these weapons. Major
Baldwin runs into all kinds of problems, like a young Chinese woman
named, Madame Sue-Mei Hung, (Lisa Lu) who was the wife of a Chinese
General and he wanted her to travel with these American soldiers in
order to secure her safety. Men get sick and there are many Chinese
people who do not want the Americans blowing up this stockpile of
weapons, as they can use them as a bargaining tool in order to secure
food and shelter. There is even some romance going on between Madame
Sue and Major Baldwin as he finds out her general husband was killed.
Harry Morgan, (Sgt. Michaelson) gave a great supporting role along with
Lisa Lu as the only woman in the picture. This film clearly points out
the difficult problems that existed between American and Chinese
relations during World War II. Great film to view, it is rather long
and draw out, but we have to consider this film is from 1960.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Enjoyed this film which was shown on TCM and I was very surprised to
see that James Stewart, (Major Baldwin) starred in this film which is
about a unit of American Engineers who were a demolition crew out to
destroy a Chinese stockpile of weapons. These men had to travel on one
mountain road which had plenty of these stockpiles to destroy in order
to make certain the Japanese did not obtain any of these weapons. Major
Baldwin runs into all kinds of problems, like a young Chinese woman
named, Madame Sue-Mei Hung, (Lisa Lu) who was the wife of a Chinese
General and he wanted her to travel with these American soldiers in
order to secure her safety. Men get sick and there are many Chinese
people who do not want the Americans blowing up this stockpile of
weapons, as they can use them as a bargaining tool in order to secure
food and shelter. There is even some romance going on between Madame
Sue and Major Baldwin as he finds out her general husband was killed.
Harry Morgan, (Sgt. Michaelson) gave a great supporting role along with
Lisa Lu as the only woman in the picture. This film clearly points out
the difficult problems that existed between American and Chinese
relations during World War II. Great film to view, it is rather long
and draw out, but we have to consider this film is from 1960.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/mountainroad.htm /m/mountain_road/comments.php?reviewid=1738785</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Glum WW II drama that takes special care in showing the sensitive relations between the Chinese and American allies fighting the Japanese.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=106166 /m/mountain_road/comments.php?reviewid=1766034</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9502E5D81638EF32A25753C3A9609C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/mountain_road/comments.php?reviewid=1741408</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>