<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Flaming Star</original_title><alt_title>Les rôdeurs de la plaine</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Don Siegel</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
Sam Burton's second wife Neddy is Indian, their son Pacer a half-breed. As struggle starts between the whites and the Kiowas...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Elvis Presley</actor><actor>Barbara Eden</actor><actor>Steve Forrest</actor><rt_rating>7.3/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>90</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0529079/comments</url><from>from LA</from><name>dubricus</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Basically, Elvis does not sing much in this one. It is a dramatic role
in which he plays a half-breed youth, raised in his father's white
world, but now caught in the midst of an Indian war.This film is a sad statement of what might have been. Here we glimpse
the natural dramatic talent that was never allowed to blossom. There
would be no "From Here to Eternity" for Elvis as there was for Sinatra.
Contracts later forced him in to the musical-comedy roles that he grew
to hate. He was told you will do these movies with this starlet or that
starlet, sing this bad music with ducks or cows in the background, play
the race car driver, the speed boat driver, the motorcycle racer, or
you won't work at all.The truly sad thing is that if this part of Elvis' talent had been
cultivated, if his musical career had been kept separate from a
dramatic acting career, perhaps his life would have traveled a very
different road. It is a horrible thing to know that you have talent &amp;
to want to be able to use that talent, but be forced to waste it. IMHO,
it was something that gnawed at him and played no small part in his own
self-destruction.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0447031/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gazzo-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is definitely one of the King's best flix, his best performance surely.
It was nice to see him play a taciturn guy but be believable, the
surrounding cast-from LQ Jones to Jeanie there to Del Rio to John
McIntire-were all pros, plus Don Seigel's record(Dirty Harry, Invasion of
the Body Snatchers, etc.) speaks for itself.Elvis, in Walter Matthau's opinion(co-starred with Elvis in 'King
Creole')had some talent and could have become a decent actor if he'd stuck
to things like this.By all means, give it a look, its worth watching-Elvis gives it his best and
it's a solid flick all around.*** outta ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from>from Santander Spain</from><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The film tells about Burton family formed by the father (John
MacIntire), his second Indian wife (Dolores del Rio) and two sons , one
(Steve Forrest) of the first wife and another (Elvis Presley) results
to be a half-breed . The latter will have to choose sides when the
battle between white men and Kiowas (Rodolfo Acosta) go on the warpath
. Burton family splits loyalties, the confrontation will be violent and
lethal. It's an interesting western with exceptional interpretation by Elvis
Presley who only sings two songs at the beginning of the film . He's a
mestizo who along with his mother will be excluded for both races . The
picture is considered Presley's best western and with ¨King Creole¨
(directed by Michael Curtiz) and ¨Jailhouse rock¨ (by Richard Thorpe)
his greatest movies . Steve Forrest (Dana Andrews's brother) as his
kind brother is very fine . Dolores del Rio as his affectionate mum and
Rodolfo Acosta as Kiowa chief , repeat well their usual Indians roles .
Barbara Eden as wonderful youngster who helps protagonists is enjoyable
and enticing . Besides , in the secondary cast appears Richard Jaeckel
(Dirty dozen) , L.Q.Jones( Peckimpah's habitual) and Karl Swenson.
Glittering and shimmer cinematography is perfectly reflected on
spectacular outdoors and colorful interiors by cameraman Charles Clarke
. Lively and atmospheric musical score by Cryl Mockridge . The motion
picture is accurately directed by Donal Siegel (Dirty Harry) . The
flick specially will appeal to Elvis Presley fans and Western genre
enthusiasts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0737873/comments</url><from>from Menifee, California</from><name>Samoan Bob</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Elvis stars as a half-Indian in this exciting Don Siegel-helmed Western
with
a ton of action and a meanstreak. Elvis's character is surprisingly tough
and hard-assed, plus the songs are kept to a minimum (he sings the title
song and does a little hoe-down at the beginning...that's it). Anyway,
Indians are massacring farmers in an attempt to take back their land, and
Elvis is torn between the Indians and the racist white folk. Elvis gives a
great, understated performance...he seems aware that this is a Siegel
film,
not an Elvis film. All in all it's the King's best foray into filmland.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A lot of highbrows will dismiss that as another Elvis lousy movie.But
just have a look at the name of the director:it's not Norman
Taurog,it's Don "Body Snatchers" Siegel!And every Siegel movie is worth
a watch at least or more with such gems as "invasion of the body
snatchers" and "beguiled".The screenplay is close to John Huston's "the unforgiven",Hepburn and
here Presley are half-breed people and thus generate violence.But what
seems fascinating here is Presley's part and his tragedy ,both in the
movie,and in real life:the loss of his owwn mother.His performance is
by far his most moving not only because he 's directed by a director
with a genuine talent,but also because he probably searched his
memories to give such a harrowing rendition.The old mom,an Indian
herself ,who tries to go back to the mountain to die there is the
moment which climaxes the movie.This obsession with the mother's loss will continue in "wild in the
country" ,Elvis's next movie,before he sank in an ocean of schmaltz.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0455701/comments</url><from>from rancho santa fe, california</from><name>rsfgerry</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Clair Huffaker was a master story teller. His westerns are still read by
true western aficionados. "Flaming Star" was Elvis's opportunity to act
and
to prove to the world that he could. Unfortunately the Colonel didn't want
the world to know.  This is one of Hollywood's best kept secrets. Maybe
the
fact that Elvis knew that he had actual talent for acting broke his heart,
and those stupid Hall Wallis "sillies" must have driven Elvis crazy!
Huffaker writes a good story of an interracial family harassed by
prejudice
and bigotry of the small western town. It is the struggle of two brothers
in
love with the same woman.
It shows the love of a husband to his Indian wife. This film has enduring
story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2573293/comments</url><from>from Calgary AB Canada</from><name>skoyles</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I have been humming and singing the theme song from this motion picture
since I first heard it on CKLW radio in Windsor Ontario in 1960 as a
dewy-eyed grade ten student. It is a superb song, evocative and
obviously memorable. Somehow I never saw the movie whence it came and
was never a fan of Elvis Presley motion pictures, having been turned
off by previews of his other movies. So finally - after a couple of
lifetimes - I bought the DVD and watched Flaming Star, the only Elvis
Presley movie I have ever seen or am likely to see. First, what is
wrong with Flaming Star? The incidental music is pedestrian, and the
trailer (included on the DVD) makes it look like an entirely different
movie. Presley is excellent; Forrest is superb; John McIntyre has never
been better. In fact, the whole cast, with the possible exception of
Barbara Eden, have never been better. Delores Del Rio plays Pacer's
Mother with a wonderful and believable dignity. I do not know the
Kiowas but I do know the Blackfoot and Ms Del Rio could well be
Blackfoot lady. Let us imagine this movie without Elvis: a very well
written, well-directed, racially sensitive, surprising, solid Western
tragedy introduced in a counterpoint by a party with songs. If Flaming
Star had starred Paul Newman or Marlon Brando it would be revered with
such films as The Magnificent Seven and The Wild Bunch. I highly
recommend this thinking-man's sad Western.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0906794/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>shank6</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I had never seen the entire edition of Flaming Star, but I've got to say
Elvis did a pretty good job!. I caught the very beginning with the song
session in the house and I thought, just another Elvis singing
vehicle.The real surprise came for me with the plot and the action sequences.
Wow!.
If Elvis could have chosen some better parts, I think he could have
transitioned himself into a decent actor.Too bad this type of performance is far and few between.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2573153/comments</url><from>from Iceland</from><name>Bjorn (jbjorns)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

One of Elvis's best films.  
Legendary film director Don Siegel (Invasion of the Body Snatchers, Dirty
Harry) gets the most out of Elvis and the King proves here that when he had
something of substance to work from, he was more than capable. This film not only has a gripping and tragic storyline, it looks and feels
authentic enough in dealing with an important chapter in American history. 
The film is packed with emotional moments and action and an all round good
cast.  
If Elvis had gotten more film roles like this one, he could have become one
of the great movie stars.
8 out of 10.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1725119/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas, NV</from><name>Shane Paterson</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Spoilers...Two years in the Army and a lightweight, family-oriented musical -- "GI
Blues" -- intervened before Elvis again got to show his natural acting
talent in "Flaming Star,"  a film originally slated for Marlon Brando.
Elvis acquitted himself well in the role of Pacer Burton, half Caucasian
and
half Kiowa, in 1878 Texas.  Pacer is a young man trapped between two
cultures and races, in a situation in which either of two available choices
spelled tragedy.  The same is true of the other members of his family,
including an older, white brother (Steve Forrest), and his parents (Dolores
Del Rio and John McIntire) -- all perfect in their roles.  This is really a
film about hate, and just as much about love, loyalty, and family.  It's
also probably a more-than-oblique commentary on the state of race relations
within the US at the time, during the rise of the Civil Rights movement.
Apartheidmongers in South Africa banned this film because Elvis played a
'colored' person.  On the other hand, Elvis was inducted into the Los
Angeles Indian Tribal Council for his positive portrayal of Pacer
Burton.Elvis is thoroughly convincing as the 'half breed' Pacer and the film
showcases his considerable nonverbal communication skills.  He convincingly
portrays a very conflicted character (the same was true to some extent of
"King Creole") and runs the full gamut of emotion through the film.
Pacer's
basically a bit of a hothead, but he's also possessed of a fairly chilling
cool, and both aspects of the character are played well by Elvis (who,
himself, shared the same dichotomy).  The scene in which Pacer and Clint,
his 100%-white brother, scuffle is pretty intense.Elvis could appear quite menacing and in this film he is pure menace at
several instances.  He'd have made a great bad guy in a movie and I really
do believe that he could have acquitted himself well in Marlon Brando's
role in "Apocalypse Now" had it been shot circa 1974, particularly if
circumstances had conspired to have Elvis make more films like "Flaming
Star" than "Clambake" during the '60s.  Is this the best scripted Elvis
Presley film?  Well, most'd point to "King Creole," and this film is so
un-Elvis that it's really NOT an 'Elvis Presley film.'  It's a powerful
film, with a strong and intelligent point to make that also ensures that it
is not just another horse-opera, in which Elvis happens to have a key role.
Also, the film does not focus exclusively on him and his co-stars are
essential to the film and all turn in excellent performances.  Still, I
think that it's perhaps in this film that he turned in his best acting
performance.The rest of the supporting cast does a more-than-competent job, and among
their number are Barbara Eden, Richard Jaeckel, and Rodolfo Acosta.
Interestingly, LQ Jones -- who plays the clueless redneck who says that Mrs
Burton's cooking was indistinguishable from any white mother's -- showed up
again in Elvis' 1968 "Stay Away, Joe," the other movie in which Elvis
played
a native American (Jones later played Three-Finger Jack in "The Mask Of
Zorro").The film was directed by Don Siegel, who'd earlier been behind "Invasion Of
The Body Snatchers" and who later went on to do the "Dirty Harry" films
among many others.   It's a pretty violent piece, especially for one shot
in
1960.  The Kiowa attack near the film's start is quite graphic for the time
and the implied violence within and around that scene is even more
disturbing.  "Flaming Star" includes axes to the head, spears in the thigh,
arrows in various parts of the anatomy, and fatal knife attacks, as well as
shootings and assorted fisticuffs.  Elvis wades into the violence with
relish, particularly during his one-man war against the Kiowa warriors
toward the film's end.  The thrashing that he administers to two unsavory
trappers is also realistic and pretty savage, beginning with a rifle butt
snapped into one trapper's chin.  Elvis, five months after his black-belt
grading, must have loved the physicality of his role.  He's in good shape
for it, too."Flaming Star" and Fox's follow-up, the contemporary drama "Wild In The
Country," basically didn't make as much money as "GI Blues."  That fact
determined what was pretty much the formula for most of the '60s.  It's a
pity, because Elvis' career path during the '60s could have taken an
entirely different path:  appearances in high-quality movies (including the
odd musically-oriented one) and occasional , big-event concert performances
at home and abroad.  What might have been...The ending never fails to sadden me immensely.  As in his debut film, this
film ends with the death of Elvis' character.  I guess the obvious thing is
that Pacer's off to die and, in a way, being a man between peoples, he's
got
no other place to go.  It says something about Elvis' characterization of
Pacer, I think, that we'd even care.  The same is true of the deaths of
Pacer's mother and father.  More to the point, though, I always think of
Elvis seeing his own Flaming Star of Death 17 years later.  For that
matter,
10 out of 10 people die, as do 10 out of 10 pets, and we all face our own
mortality and that of our loved ones.  I must admit that, figuratively,
Elvis has yet to die -- as I write he's in an amazing third week at #1 on
the UK singles charts, with #1 rankings in several other countries courtesy
of a remixed, relatively obscure 1968 movie song. I went to high school and
university with a kid (Robert Trueman, good friend of my best friend) who
died, rapidly, of leukemia -- ironically enough, a few years before he'd
told me that he wasn't really into Elvis but that he loved the song
"Flaming
Star."  It's indeed a great song, but one forever touched by an additional
aura of sadness the result of Robert's passing too soon.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1725119/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas, NV</from><name>Shane Paterson</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Spoilers...Two years in the Army and a lightweight, family-oriented musical -- "GI
Blues" -- intervened before Elvis again got to show his natural acting
talent in "Flaming Star,"  a film originally slated for Marlon Brando.
Elvis acquitted himself well in the role of Pacer Burton, half Caucasian
and
half Kiowa, in 1878 Texas.  Pacer is a young man trapped between two
cultures and races, in a situation in which either of two available choices
spelled tragedy.  The same is true of the other members of his family,
including an older, white brother (Steve Forrest), and his parents (Dolores
Del Rio and John McIntire) -- all perfect in their roles.  This is really a
film about hate, and just as much about love, loyalty, and family.  It's
also probably a more-than-oblique commentary on the state of race relations
within the US at the time, during the rise of the Civil Rights movement.
Apartheidmongers in South Africa banned this film because Elvis played a
'colored' person.  On the other hand, Elvis was inducted into the Los
Angeles Indian Tribal Council for his positive portrayal of Pacer
Burton.Elvis is thoroughly convincing as the 'half breed' Pacer and the film
showcases his considerable nonverbal communication skills.  He convincingly
portrays a very conflicted character (the same was true to some extent of
"King Creole") and runs the full gamut of emotion through the film.
Pacer's
basically a bit of a hothead, but he's also possessed of a fairly chilling
cool, and both aspects of the character are played well by Elvis (who,
himself, shared the same dichotomy).  The scene in which Pacer and Clint,
his 100%-white brother, scuffle is pretty intense.Elvis could appear quite menacing and in this film he is pure menace at
several instances.  He'd have made a great bad guy in a movie and I really
do believe that he could have acquitted himself well in Marlon Brando's
role in "Apocalypse Now" had it been shot circa 1974, particularly if
circumstances had conspired to have Elvis make more films like "Flaming
Star" than "Clambake" during the '60s.  Is this the best scripted Elvis
Presley film?  Well, most'd point to "King Creole," and this film is so
un-Elvis that it's really NOT an 'Elvis Presley film.'  It's a powerful
film, with a strong and intelligent point to make that also ensures that it
is not just another horse-opera, in which Elvis happens to have a key role.
Also, the film does not focus exclusively on him and his co-stars are
essential to the film and all turn in excellent performances.  Still, I
think that it's perhaps in this film that he turned in his best acting
performance.The rest of the supporting cast does a more-than-competent job, and among
their number are Barbara Eden, Richard Jaeckel, and Rodolfo Acosta.
Interestingly, LQ Jones -- who plays the clueless redneck who says that Mrs
Burton's cooking was indistinguishable from any white mother's -- showed up
again in Elvis' 1968 "Stay Away, Joe," the other movie in which Elvis
played
a native American (Jones later played Three-Finger Jack in "The Mask Of
Zorro").The film was directed by Don Siegel, who'd earlier been behind "Invasion Of
The Body Snatchers" and who later went on to do the "Dirty Harry" films
among many others.   It's a pretty violent piece, especially for one shot
in
1960.  The Kiowa attack near the film's start is quite graphic for the time
and the implied violence within and around that scene is even more
disturbing.  "Flaming Star" includes axes to the head, spears in the thigh,
arrows in various parts of the anatomy, and fatal knife attacks, as well as
shootings and assorted fisticuffs.  Elvis wades into the violence with
relish, particularly during his one-man war against the Kiowa warriors
toward the film's end.  The thrashing that he administers to two unsavory
trappers is also realistic and pretty savage, beginning with a rifle butt
snapped into one trapper's chin.  Elvis, five months after his black-belt
grading, must have loved the physicality of his role.  He's in good shape
for it, too."Flaming Star" and Fox's follow-up, the contemporary drama "Wild In The
Country," basically didn't make as much money as "GI Blues."  That fact
determined what was pretty much the formula for most of the '60s.  It's a
pity, because Elvis' career path during the '60s could have taken an
entirely different path:  appearances in high-quality movies (including the
odd musically-oriented one) and occasional , big-event concert performances
at home and abroad.  What might have been...The ending never fails to sadden me immensely.  As in his debut film, this
film ends with the death of Elvis' character.  I guess the obvious thing is
that Pacer's off to die and, in a way, being a man between peoples, he's
got
no other place to go.  It says something about Elvis' characterization of
Pacer, I think, that we'd even care.  The same is true of the deaths of
Pacer's mother and father.  More to the point, though, I always think of
Elvis seeing his own Flaming Star of Death 17 years later.  For that
matter,
10 out of 10 people die, as do 10 out of 10 pets, and we all face our own
mortality and that of our loved ones.  I must admit that, figuratively,
Elvis has yet to die -- as I write he's in an amazing third week at #1 on
the UK singles charts, with #1 rankings in several other countries courtesy
of a remixed, relatively obscure 1968 movie song. I went to high school and
university with a kid (Robert Trueman, good friend of my best friend) who
died, rapidly, of leukemia -- ironically enough, a few years before he'd
told me that he wasn't really into Elvis but that he loved the song
"Flaming
Star."  It's indeed a great song, but one forever touched by an additional
aura of sadness the result of Robert's passing too soon.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bill-chambers/</url><url>http://filmfreakcentral.net/dvdreviews/elvises.htm#star /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1922015</url><name>Bill Chambers</name><from>Film Freak Central</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>The filmmaking may be a little ramshackle, but it's sensitive, and the performances are soulful.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/blake-french/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Elvis-Lives!-(at-least-he-does-on-DVD) /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1835584</url><name>Blake French</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/5
					</rating><comment>...proves that Elvis didn't just get lucky with his first performance; the boy could actually act.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/flamstar.shtml /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1780572</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>Famed action director Don Siegel saw an element of raw danger in Elvis and gave him his very best role in this excellent quasi-Western.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sean-axmaker/</url><url>http://music.msn.com/music/artistofthemonth/elvis /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1662620</url><name>Sean Axmaker</name><from>MSN.com</from></reviewer><comment>Less an "Elvis film" than a western starring young Presley in a surprisingly well cast role, this lean frontier drama... offers one of his most impressive performances.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1467121</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Elvis' best performance, in a solid Don Siegel Western</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/flamingstar.htm /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1418229</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>An emotionally charged liberal themed Western that keeps things rocking.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1399332</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Among the best Presley features; directed by Don Siegel.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/rachel-sanders/</url><url>http://www.apolloguide.com/mov_fullrev.asp?CID=4386 /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1149995</url><name>Rachel Sanders</name><from>Apollo Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
60/100
					</rating><comment>Although the sight of a shirtless Elvis wrestling a native warrior is fascinating enough, there are few surprises in the sequence of events.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bob-bloom/</url><url>/m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=808335</url><name>Bob Bloom</name><from>Journal and Courier (Lafayette, IN)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Pretty good Elvis vehicle; the young man could act.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1422119</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117790958.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1806265</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/66778/flaming_star.html /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1475596</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ah-weiler/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9803E5DA103FE63ABC4F52DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/flaming_star/comments.php?reviewid=1390519</url><name>A.H. Weiler</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>