<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Savage Innocents</original_title><alt_title>Les dents du diable</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><country>Italy</country><country>UK</country><director>Nicholas Ray</director><producer>Gray Film-Pathé</producer><producer>Joseph Janni/Appia Films</producer><producer>Magic Film</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
An Eskimo who has had little contact with white men goes to a trading post where he accidentally kills a missionary and finds himself being pursued by the police.
</synopsis><actor>Anthony Quinn</actor><actor>Yoko Tani</actor><actor>Carlo Giustini</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2116813/comments</url><from>from oakland, CA</from><name>wild-plum</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

In the late sixties, bob dylan was asked how he came to write the song
"Quinn the Eskimo". He replied that he'd seen this movie in which Tony
Quinn
played an Eskimo. The Savage Innocents is that movie. (In a much later
book
about his lyrics, Dylan says he doesn't remember how the song came about-
like many of us, ol' bob's memory ain't what it used to
be.)This is the most accurate portrayal of Eskimo customs ever to come out of
Hollywierd. It contrasts the cultural practices of Inuit and North
American
societies at a time when many Inuit people had not yet encountered the
white
man and his ways. The movie asks the question "who is savage and who is
innocent?" The movie is full of memorable performances and  "sound bites".
You'll come away with a new appreciation for traditional Eskimo culture
and
more than a few new quotable quotes.When Quinn the Eskimo gets here, everybody's gonna jump for
joy!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0902607/comments</url><from>from Sacramento, CA</from><name>artzau</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This is a memorable film in many regards.  Quinn plays an Inuit who
inadvertently kills a priest who declines his offer of sexual hospitality
with his wife. O'Toole, in his first film, plays a policeman who captures
Quinn who later saves his life.  O'Toole eventually lets Quinn go because he
realizes that he will likely be convicted of murder because a Western jury
won't understand he accidently killed the priest because he wouldn't sleep
with his wife.  There are some wonderful scenes of Inuit igloo life,
including the daughter (Quinn's wife, Yoko Tani) chewing food for her mother
(Marie Yang) because the mother's teeth are worn out from chewing skins. 
The film is full of surprises with little moments that delight an
anthropologist familiar with Inuit traditions and lifestyles.  No video, no
DVD listed, so watch for it on the late show and enjoy seeing the exciting
young Peter O'Toole in days before the good life got to him. 

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7373129/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>wedraughon</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I saw and heard Anthony Quinn in a television interview about his
autobiography which had just been published. He said that there were
only three films out of the many that he had made in his life that he
was truly proud of. The Savage Innocents was one of the three. (Guess
what the other two were. Right! Zorba and La Strada.) This estimation
puts this movie in with some very select company. And this film
deserves it.It is NOT a documentary. There is a story here, an exciting story, at
times edge of your seat--or maybe I should say, a number of stories,
all interesting, all moving. The photography, sound, scenery, acting,
all were excellent.What struck me most, out of a long list, was the way the point of view
of these Inuit people was gotten across. For instance, the missionary
butts his head into the igloo and says, "God be with you." Quinn looks
puzzled, glances at his wife and says, "No, there's nobody here but
us." When the missionary goes on preaching at them, trying to convert
them to the "true" faith, Quinn whispers to his wife, "I think he needs
to laugh with a woman. Make yourself beautiful." In other words, the
guy needs to get laid. The Freudian insight implied by these simple
remarks is staggering. And this is only a small sample.Perhaps the fate of this movie had a lot to do with the advertising.
The picture at the top of this page suggests that this is a "savage"
movie. It isn't. The title itself is unfortunate.Yes, when oh when will we get to see this movie again? When will the
savage and not-so-innocent moguls deign to put this beautiful film onto
DVD?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0488634/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>drrap</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This film is not without its merits. The second unit shot some really
quite beautiful location footage in the Arctic, and the cinematography
throughout is impressive. Anthony Quinn brings tremendous verve to the
role, and there are several memorable turns by the supporting cast,
particularly Peter O'Toole.But it's depressing to see how many people regard this as an accurate
portrayal of Inuit culture. One hardly knows where to begin! The Inuit
customs regarding "wife-sharing" are distorted (the idea that it would
be a terrible insult not to accept such an offer is groundless), and
the use of "laughter" as a euphemism for sex is merely an old Hollywood
notion. Inuit mothers are not left until their mother's death to be
told of common matters such as the importance of cutting a child's
umbilical cord, and a grandmother, however infirm, would never be left
out in the open to be eaten by a polar bear (a special igloo would
instead be prepared, with important personal items, and then sealed up,
after which the village would be moved). Most insulting of all is the
notion that somehow Inuit would be unaware that babies are born without
visible teeth!The inaccuracies are not merely cultural, but historical as well. There
is simply no period of time when the Inuit (or other Arctic groups such
as the Inighuit, Inupiat, or Yupik) would have been unfamiliar with
firearms and yet exposed to 1960s-style rock music -- these events are
anywhere from 75 to 100 years apart, depending on the region. Inuit who
went to trading posts would never be mocked by other Inuit, or by
traders, at a trading post -- trading was serious business -- and would
never be sold a gun with zero ammunition. This is not to say that
traders were always totally fair; the guns were often of inferior
quality, and the addiction to a source of powder and shot, along with
the switch to fur-bearing animals as a sort of cash crop, were indeed
problems.The saddest thing of all is that, 27 years before "Savage Innocents," a
far more accurate account of the disparities, tensions, and injustices
between Inuit and traders and police was released by a major Hollywood
studio -- this was 1933's "Eskimo," starring Ray Mala, a half- Inupiat
Alaskan actor.Having nearly no Inuit in the cast at all is, despite comments to the
contrary, a problem as well. Hollywood had cast Inuit as Inuit as early
as 1911, and "Eskimo" enjoyed an almost all- Inuit cast. The fact that
all of the principal photography was done on a sound stage decorated by
people with no knowledge whatever of either Inuit or northern homes is
a further issue.There's no question that "Savage Innocents" works hard to elicit
sympathy with an "alien" culture -- the only problem is that this
culture is almost entirely a fantasy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2867855/comments</url><from>from St. LOUIS, MO</from><name>pembroke3004</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is a very powerful and moving study of the decisions faced by law
enforcement when there is clearly a situation not forseen by lawmakers
and
how a police officer might conclude that the "right" thing to do is not
always to follow proper procedure. To me, one of the most moving  scenes
in
the movie is the final scene in which the wife's mother appears. Also,
the
scene where Anthony Quinn has his chance to escape is a very revealing
instance of character. I would very much like to see this movie available
on
video or DVD.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1578142/comments</url><from>from Houston, Texas</from><name> (jerphayes)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Anthony Quinn at his usual best giving a masterful performance of a native
Alaskan Inuit and his daily struggles and challenges. A docu-drama that
shows the challenges and struggles when two cultures collide. Great
cinematography of the Alaska wilderness its makes you feel as if your
right
there in the igloo with Inuk and his wife Asiak as they eat whale blubber
and hunt seal and birth babies. Gives a feel of life in the Alaskan
wilderness from a unique Alaskan native vantage point.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3167858/comments</url><from>from Arkansas, U.S.</from><name>Kimberley Lee (kimberleylee2004@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I have to say that this is one of mine and my husbands favorite movies.
My
husband recorded it on VHS in the early 80's and that copy is now caputz.
I
was able to get a copy off of ebay and then converted it over to DVD.  We
watch is all the time.It is a fantastic example of what we could be.  The Inuit of the Alaskan
Region are always pictured with huge smiles.  Especially those who remain
nomadic.  Perhaps the joy of waking each morning is enough to make them
happy.Yoko Tani and Anthony Quinn are fantastic in their portrayals.  I love
that
this movie reminds me of the very first documentary titled Nanook of the
North.  I love it love it love it.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4036034/comments</url><from/><name>norma-19</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I cant remember which year I saw this film but it was a very long time
ago. It did however make quite an impression on me, i enjoyed the
glimpse into the lives and traditions of the Eskimo's. and certain
events have stayed in my mind all this time. For instance when the aged
decided the time was right, they would just sit out on the ice one
night, never to be seen again. Awesome. But it was such a long time ago
I was thinking i must have imagined it for i have never heard of it
since. The title stayed in my head though. Then i decided to look it up
on the internet and am very glad to know that I wasn't alone in my
regard.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4202108/comments</url><from>from Chicago</from><name>luganrn77</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I haven't seen this film for years.......but would love to again. I
remember this film as an accurate description of Inuit culture and
mores of the time. It is an educational journey into innocent tundra
social structure (if any) intermingling occasionally with modern (at
the time) Western culture. Anthony Quinn was brilliant in this
role...and probably created for it. And..., oh my God,....that was
Peter O'Toole in his very first role??? No wonder I loved him
afterwards......even being dubbed (why??) he showed sensitivity in
dealing with both the savage(?)Inuit lifestyle, the current legal
structure of Western society of the day, and his own personal feelings
in the interactions with these primitive peoples. Hey! Where else can a
man offer gourmet larvae to his esteemed guests, then offer his wife
for any man to "laugh" with, and then take his mother-in-law miles away
with a dogsled to go die on the ice with her approval?? Way to go!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655556/comments</url><from>from Austin, TX</from><name>NeverLift</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie in its original release, ca. 1960, while living in
Canada. We didn't see it so much a drama as an exposition of Eskimo
(now Inuit) culture, behavior, and mores that used the story line as a
vehicle to help in that process. And, of course, it is visually
stunning.A story I heard at that time claimed the reason the secondary roles are
not played by Eskimos was that they didn't have the concept of lying in
their culture, and acting -- pretending to be another person, as
opposed to taking on the role of, say, a seal in a story-telling
activity at a communal gathering -- requires that one, essentially,
lie. That is, the claim was that the casting staff could not find an
Eskimo that could act.There are episodes in the portrayal that seem over-acted, but that
opinion may be a result of my not having personal experience with how
Eskimos would actually behave in the activity being portrayed in those
scenes. But the scene of death and survival after the sled breaks
through the ice is, to coin a phrase, chilling. Asked for help to save
the soaked Mountie, Quinn, in the lead Eskimo role, responds, "That man
is dead." And then you watch the Mountie freeze to death in under two
minutes. Very powerful.Highly recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655556/comments</url><from>from Austin, TX</from><name>NeverLift</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie in its original release, ca. 1960, while living in
Canada. We didn't see it so much a drama as an exposition of Eskimo
(now Inuit) culture, behavior, and mores that used the story line as a
vehicle to help in that process. And, of course, it is visually
stunning.A story I heard at that time claimed the reason the secondary roles are
not played by Eskimos was that they didn't have the concept of lying in
their culture, and acting -- pretending to be another person, as
opposed to taking on the role of, say, a seal in a story-telling
activity at a communal gathering -- requires that one, essentially,
lie. That is, the claim was that the casting staff could not find an
Eskimo that could act.There are episodes in the portrayal that seem over-acted, but that
opinion may be a result of my not having personal experience with how
Eskimos would actually behave in the activity being portrayed in those
scenes. But the scene of death and survival after the sled breaks
through the ice is, to coin a phrase, chilling. Asked for help to save
the soaked Mountie, Quinn, in the lead Eskimo role, responds, "That man
is dead." And then you watch the Mountie freeze to death in under two
minutes. Very powerful.Highly recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>