<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Djävulens öga</original_title><alt_title>L'oeil du diable</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Sweden</country><director>Ingmar Bergman</director><producer>Svensk Filmindustri (SF)</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis>
The devil has a stye in his eye, caused by the purity of a vicar's daughter. To get rid of it,...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jarl Kulle</actor><actor>Bibi Andersson</actor><actor>Stig Järrel</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3638742/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>Patrik_Lemberg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A clever comedy; Satan permits Don Juan a leave of absence from hell to
cure a sty in the Devil's eye which is caused by the virginity of a
young earthly woman. It's a very funny movie - without being
intentionally "stupid." It has a very theatrical feel, but tastefully
so, and brings everything needed from Jarl Kulle as Don Juan. Nils
Poppe (known best as "Jof" from "The Seventh Seal") and Bibi Andersson
also contribute with an additional display of their usually skillful
performances. The plot is light, but brilliant, and will probably shock
regular Bergman fans. For some reason "Smiles of a Summer Night" is
talked about as Bergman's "best" or even "only" comedy, but although I
really like that film too, and have watched over forty of his movies,
and must say that this is the funniest by a long shot. A highly
enjoyable, but sadly underrated (possibly misunderstood) movie. At the
time of my writing this, Djävulens Öga is not yet a DVD item in the US
or the UK.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1355003/comments</url><from>from Perth, Australia</from><name>sol-</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The screenplay is the most interesting element of this film: it
presents an original tale with some bits of humour along the way. It is
a bit too verbose and talkative now and again, which is very
distracting from what is happening on screen, but it very amusing
whenever it is amusing. The movie is filmed in a play-like fashion,
separated into three acts, and narrated in part. This makes the film
feel more like a play, and it does limit Bergman to how much skill he
can show as a director. There are still nevertheless some well set up
shots, in particular in relation to framing, lightness and darkness.
The ending is a tad weak, but the bulk of the film is oddly engaging -
atypical and yet still admirable Bergman.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I liked this movie a lot--more than many of the dreadfully serious
Bergman films.The movie is staged like a play--complete with a narrator and acts. The
story begins in Hell. It seems the devil is in a funk, as he's got a
sty. Why? Apparently, there is a virginal woman whose decency is
causing the devil great agony, so he sends his favorite Lothario, Don
Juan, to despoil this virgin and this make the sty go away! Really
weird stuff, huh?! Well, the tongue in cheek style makes this a pretty
funny comedy. Not GREAT comedy, but very good AND so weird and unusual,
it's worth a look.By the way, isn't Don Juan's sidekick about the most devilish character
you've ever seen? Watch it, turn off your brain and have fun.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453068/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Jack Gattanella (whiplashfilm@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
It's funny, so to speak, that Bergman's most touted dark drama has its
wealth of light and even comedic moments, and vice-versa in the case of
Devil's Eye. For the much-touted movie I mean The Seventh Seal, where
we get much ado about the existence of God or lack thereof and Death
looming large, but it's also got its share of laughs and unintentional
witty dialog. It's a major work and without much argument the
quintessential work of the filmmaker.On the other hand, we get The Devil's Eye, which is more of a minor
work, done by Bergman, admittedly, as a work-for-hire project in order
to direct the Virgin Spring that same year. It's a comedy, as we're
told right from the get-go by the 'narrator' of the story Gunnar
Bjornstrand about the old 'sty in the eye' proverb where Satan will
deflower a virgin to get rid of it (in this case he sends Don Juan,
whose been spending 300 years in a loop of the same failed courtship in
hell with his compadre Pablo, to do it for him on a Nordic girl about
to get married). And yet this comedy of sorts, which is filled with sly
moments and turns of performances that are uncharacteristically campy
for a Bergman film, also has some dark connotations about infidelity
and desire and love in the face of evil. It might be a minor work, but
it's probably one of the director's strongest and most underrated.In fact, I'd wager that Bergman put more work into this than he'd even
care to cop to: the design of hell itself is ingenious, akin to the No
Exit set with Satan in a suit and cool but firm demeanor played by Stig
Jarrel, and a constant flame burning behind his quaint book-room
setting, and his servants being prissy-looking chaps out of some French
royal palace. Bergman also casts this really wonderfully, with Don Juan
played by Daniel Craig-look-alike Jarl Kulle with his suave demeanor
but sad interior coming out some of the time, and Nils Poppe (who also
played the cheery Virgin-Mary hallucinator Jof in Seventh Seal) as the
aloof Parson whose daughter is to marry/possibly be seduced.Bergman also gets some laughs and some surprisingly tender scenes
between the Parson's wife Renata and Pablo and the Demon put on
assignment by Satan to keep watch on Pablo only to end up in 'Satan's
Closet' that the Parson has set up for just such an occasion. It's
clever on top of this that the intended goals are reversed in the scope
of Britt-Marie (Bibi Andersson) and his mother Renata in terms of their
seductions and falling from graces. There's a lot of devilish (some pun
intended) fun to be had I wouldn't want to reveal, but suffice to say
that Bergman has his cake and eats it too: he crafts a pleasurably
stylish picture loaded with his intriguing and occasionally deep
conversations about love and the nature of Heaven and Hell and Satan
and God. It may be 'light' material, but in its own limitations it's a
more satisfying effort than the good but overrated Wild Strawberries.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5876717/comments</url><from/><name>kosmasp</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Or don't. It is up to you. And up to the characters in this Bergman
movie. While it could be quite heavy (and it has some weight in its
dialog) it is pretty light and has quite some comedic moments. Which is
a really good contrast to the story that is being told. Of course this
is not a comedy. Anything but that, considering the themes it is
portraying, but it plays with the heavy stuff.I did watch quite a few Bergman movies at the Berlin Internationl Film
Festival this year and I can say that some movies are quite hard to
get. But I think this is one of Bergmans more accessible movies. Still
not your usual stuff, but worth your time. One of his most underrated
movies/comedies I guess. But then again, people(fans) might have
expected something different
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1124558/comments</url><from>from sweden</from><name>anton-6</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

A woman's chastity gives the Devil sty in his eye, so he sends Don Juan
back
to Earth from Hell to seduce her, but the modern-day woman finds his
old-fashioned charm amusing rather than irresistible.No masterpiece but
funny and Nils Poppe has some really funny scenes.Rating:4/5
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2488512/comments</url><from>from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</from><name>Claudio Carvalho</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
In order to get cured from a sty in his eye, the devil (Stiq Järrel)
sends Don Juan (Jarl Kulle), his servant Pablo (Sture Lagerwall) and
his worst devil to earth to seduce Britt-Marie (Bibi Andersson), the
virgin daughter of a vicar (Nils Poppe) and makes she loses her
chastity. This unusual Ingmar Bergman's movie is a slow and very
theatrical comedy spoken in English, divided in three acts and with use
of many chords in harpsichord. Bibi Andersson is very beautiful as the
twenty-two years old woman who caused the sty in the devil's eye. The
story is ironic and funny, with great direction and performance of the
cast, an Ingmar Bergman's trademark. My vote is seven.Title (Brazil): 'O Olho do Diabo' ('The Devil's Eye')Obs: On 06 March 2005, I received the following remark from an IMDb
User: "Please note that the original language for the movie "Djävulens
öga" is Swedish and not English as you say in your comment. I realise
that you saw a dubbed version, but the casual reader will think that
it's in English when they read your comment. "
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2436779/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>marymorrissey</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
this film gets off to a very slow start and some aspects of the
production are pretty cheesy... the period costumes and some of the
sets and the manner of conveying that we are in "hell" when we are
there, are not exactly stunning.... also Bibi's husband to be is said
to be 25 and he looks about 40.but do stick with it because it does become really really funny and
there are a lot of great lines I have to have at least 10 lines in my
comment so I'll praise Bibi's acting... also the other woman, who plays
her mother... and I"ll say the film is also very sweet.Bergman fans will not be disappointed in the lightness cause there is
plenty of heaviness too in the scenes between the maiden and DJAfter thinking about this film awhile it hit me a lot harder what's
seems to be being said. In a sense some people seem to have grace such
that even sin can't touch them, even sinning can't touch them, because
of how they do it, somehow skirting the devil, while they don't by any
means have to become angels themselves. wow!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0094322/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Steve Sturdevant</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

An old theme, the devil plotting against people , but also funny in that
things don't always turn out the way it seems they should.  Also very funny,
for a Swedish movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0094322/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Steve Sturdevant</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

An old theme, the devil plotting against people , but also funny in that
things don't always turn out the way it seems they should.  Also very funny,
for a Swedish movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0094322/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Steve Sturdevant</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>