<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Two Faces of Dr. Jekyll</original_title><alt_title>Les deux visages du Dr Jekyll</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Terence Fisher</director><producer>Hammer Film Productions</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Romance</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
Dr. Henry Jekyll experiments with scientific means of revealing the hidden, dark side of man and releases a murderer from within himself.
</synopsis><actor>Paul Massie</actor><actor>Dawn Addams</actor><actor>Christopher Lee</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6385373/comments</url><from>from www.martsander.com</from><name>Mart Sander</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Very nice and quite original adaptation of this often (ab)used
material. This is probably the only version where Hyde is actually more
handsome, social and sexy - even in a sort of school-boyish way to
begin with - than Jekyll, who is a total wet blanket. There is indeed
one of the sexiest performances by Christopher Lee in the film. I'm
very happy he isn't in the lead role - I suggest he would have been
directed to be his usual grim and menacing self again. Instead of that
we get a smiling, easy-going Lee, dripping with wicked charm and
sexuality. There aren't many available films to see him still under 40,
so if you are a fan of his, I suggest you check this one out. Sure, it
tends to be a bit melodramatic, but fortunately everyone around the
poor, misunderstood Jekyll is so delightfully evil - his
double-crossing wife, and double double-crossing friend - that the
dramatic outbursts are nicely suppressed. Also, you get a very intimate
close up at the holiest of holies of a scantily dressed snake charmer,
and we get the "b"-word loud and clear - rather nice for 1960. Nice
sets, nice Victorian frolics, very good looking cast, and generally a
more fun version of the book than we usually get. I only have a strange
looking pan and scan bootleg version of this film, which obviously was
shot in widescreen. Typical vibrant colours of the period, good score
and expert direction plus mostly proper British accent from everyone in
the cast. I'm very glad I stumbled upon this film, and should I ever
see a legitimate widescreen version released, I'd snatch it without a
second thought. I'm rich, you see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1234929/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gavin6942</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Dr. Henry Jekyll (Paul Massie) is working on a serum that brings out
the animal instincts of man. After testing it on a monkey (who goes
berserk), he turns to himself. As his alternate self, Edward Hyde, he
stumbles upon his friend's treachery and his wife's sordid affair.
Hyde, the animal that he is, is ready to go on his own little excursion
into debauchery and hedonism.I was really blown away by this film. The Jekyll/Hyde story has been
told again and again and the main character has been portrayed by
countless actors. Yet, this may be the great version out there --
definitely the best one I've seen yet. The Canadian actor playing both
roles was a new face for me, but is pretty amazing and I couldn't see
the two personas as the same actor no matter how hard I tried. It was
quite impressive.Christopher Lee, ever-present in the Hammer films (did he ever have a
day off?), plays friend Paul Allen. Wow. I've praised Lee in "Scream of
Fear", but he should be praised no less in this, where he's a
convincingly sleazy gambler and womanizer. Not the way I picture Lee to
be, but it seems so natural here. The more I see this man in action,
the more I see what the generation before me saw. I had always been a
Peter Cushing fan, but maybe it's time for me to switch sides? I
enjoyed the philosophical questions raised by this film. There's the
portrayal of Hyde as younger, more handsome and more charming... not
the monster he's usually shown to be. I think this fit well... he still
had the spontaneous violence, but not unlike the devil himself, knew
his way to get to people with savoir faire. Early on, Jekyll also talks
of the man "beyond good and evil", the "higher man", evoking the words
of philosopher Friedrich Nietzsche, though certainly not in the way
Nietzsche would have endorsed. Both Nietzsche's and Jekyll's higher man
use their wills to gain what they most desire, but Hyde is something of
an unhinged creature, not the refined and academic man Nietzsche
preferred.Nietzsche also spoke of "beyond good and evil" as a transcendence of
morality, moving beyond our traditional concepts and accepting that
there is good and bad, but no overarching divine good or evil. In this
regard, Hyde may be comparable. He certainly has no care for his "evil"
actions... though one suspects that not even Nietzsche would support
these "bad" actions destroying those around him.You must pick up this film (preferably in the four-disc set of Hammer
films also containing "The Gordon" and "Scream of Fear"). You don't
need to be as analytical or philosophical as I am when digesting it,
but you'll love the film for its great characters and hedonistic
wickedness... drunken, licentious men in 1870s London? Let the
depravity begin.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0440176/comments</url><from>from dea. hts. mi.  u.s.a.</from><name>davey-30</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A good Hammer Film.  The plot is  keeping with in the Jekyll-Hyde story. 
Christopher Lee is in it, and so is sexy Dawn Adams.  The snake dancer in
the night club  is one of the best I have ever watched!  I was watching a
documentary on the history of Hammer Films, and one of the producers said
this film was not well recieved, for a B- Horror Movie I strongley
dissagree. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0084347/comments</url><from>from West Point, MS</from><name>newfunk-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Having long been a serious Hammer fan, this film somehow escaped me for
years.  I recently viewed it for the first time, and was very impressed.
Christopher Lee rarely had such a delicious part, as the pompous and sleazy
Paul Allen.  Director Terence Fisher and composer Monty Norman are in top
form as well.  Of course, the story itself is familiar but thoroughly
engaging.One thing troubles me, the tape I saw  had a few obvious dialog cuts.  If
you've never seen The Two Faces of Dr. Jeckyll, AND you like the horror
cinema of this period, I strongly urge you to see this one.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1605950/comments</url><from>from usa</from><name>ctomvelu</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I remember seeing this in the movies on on early TV, and it has stuck with
me all these years later. Probably as good a version of the RLS story as
any
except for the 1931 Frederic March version. Hammer really outdid itself,
in
one of its earliest horror outings. See it if you can. It puts many more
recent, larger budgeted versions to shame.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2945144/comments</url><from>from Kirkkonummi, Finland</from><name>kriitikko</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
In the 1870's London, the middle-aged Dr. Henry Jekyll lives a
reclusive life with his young wife Kitty. Jekyll has given up lecturing
in Universities and dedicates his time for charity works and his
personal research in his private lab. He completely neglects his wife
Kitty, who has started an affair with Jekyll's friend Paul Allen, who
also spends Jekyll's money on his gambling debts. One night, Jekyll
tests a drug he has invented to separate the good and evil in man, on
himself. As a result he becomes young and handsome Edward Hyde, who
soon begins his mission of not only to destroy Kitty and Paul, but
Jekyll as well. Terence Fisher's film "The Two Faces of Dr. Jekyll" is one of the most
original and underrated adaptations of Robert Louis Stevenson's classic
"The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde". Since the three most
well known movie versions of Jekyll &amp; Hyde before this (1920 silent
film with John Barrymore, 1931 classic with Frederic March and 1941
remake with Spencer Tracy) all repeated similar plot pattern, the
Hammer Films wanted to give something different. Like with Hammer's other adaptations of classic horror stories, the
film only keeps the essential backbone of the original story and
changes all else. Unlike in the three previous movies where Jekyll was
presented as a young handsome and likable man and Hyde as evil looking
ugly monster, here Jekyll is middle-aged bearded and very cold and
harsh towards others. Hyde on the other hand is smooth, handsome player
who gets everyone to like him like that. However, he is no less evil
then other versions of Hyde. This time Hyde doesn't use Jekyll as a
hiding place to escape to, but he puts the blame of his crimes on
Jekyll. Nasty piece of work. The film has been much underrated because it doesn't have the same kind
of Hammer horror feel to it. But Fisher and others are not even trying
to make this same kind of shocking horror film as their previous works
"The Curse of Frankenstein", "Horror of Dracula" and "The Mummy" are.
Instead Fisher and screenwriter Wolf Mankowitz are telling a tragedy of
how one man's quest for knowledge ultimately destroys everything and
everyone around him. The makers are more interested in showing the
duality of Victorian era, where people were respectable during the day
and transformed during the night. Jekyll in the movie is just the only
one who does it literally. The role of Jekyll/Hyde was originally meant for Christopher Lee, but
not wanting to be type casted as the monster, since he had already
played Frankenstein's creature, Count Dracula and the Mummy, Lee was
casted as Paul Allen instead. Obviously glad to play different kind of
part, Lee delivers one of his best Hammer performances as the suave and
unreliable gambler. Lee played Jekyll and Hyde later in a movie called
"I, Monster" from 1971, which follows Stevenson's book more faithfully
than this one. In the role of Jekyll/Hyde, Paul Massie is really underrated. Sure, I
could name half a dozen other actors who have played the part better.
But Massie is one of the few actors, along with Frederic March and Jack
Palance, who managed to make both Henry Jekyll and Edward Hyde
interesting characters. Most actors I've found are rather boring when
playing Jekyll, only coming to life when changing to Hyde. In the role
of Jekyll's cheating wife Kitty, Dawn Addams is not just a candy to the
eyes, she really fits the part perfectly and is one of the few Hammer
leading ladies with some other talent than just their looks. In minor
roles you can see Norma Marla and her very erotic snake dance, as well
as young Oliver Reed in one of his earliest movie roles. All in all, "The Two Faces of Dr. Jekyll" is a forgotten gem, an
enjoyable film from Hammer's highlight era, as long as you keep open
mind and not expect gallons of blood.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8239592/comments</url><from>from The Last New Jersey Drive-In on the Left</from><name>Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
1874, London. Obsessive and reclusive weakling Dr. Jekyll (superbly
played by Paul Massie) creates a formula that causes him to transform
into his evil and impulsive id run amok alter ego Mr. Edward Hyde, who
stirs up much trouble and eventually tries to take over Jekyll's meek
personality altogether. Director Terence Fisher and writer Wolf
Mankowitz offer a sound, absorbing and surprisingly elegant
psychological take on the often told tale along with a flavorsome
evocation of the Victorian era. This film further benefits from
splendid acting from a top-notch cast: Massie delivers an impressively
anguished portrayal of a tormented split personality in the demanding
lead role, Dawn Adams brings real class and poise as Jekyll's fed-up
faithless wife Kitty, the always great Christopher Lee positively oozes
smarm as Kitty's shameless ne'er-do-well gambler lover Paul Allen,
ravishing brunette beauty Norma Marla burns up the screen as fiery,
sultry dancer Maria (her introductory snake dance set piece is
memorably sexy), and David Kossoff does well as Jekyll's wise,
concerned colleague Dr. Ernest Littauer. Better still, this movie rates
as pretty bold stuff for the decade it was made in: we've got opium
smoking, adultery, implied nudity, mild profanity, and even (offscreen)
rape. Having the wimpy and homely, but humane and pleasant Jekyll turn
into the suave and handsome, yet foul and caddish Hyde is a very nice
touch, thereby suggesting it's what's on the inside that makes a man
either good or bad. Look fast for Oliver Reed as a nightclub bouncer.
Both Jack Asher's vibrant color cinematography and the jaunty, dramatic
orchestral score by David Heneker and Monty Norman are up to snuff.
Well worth a watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2076319/comments</url><from>from Cleburne, TX</from><name>Justin Stokes</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Ostracized by the scientific community, Dr. Jekyll is doing some rather
pointless sounding experiments while his wife is cheating on him with
his gambler friend. Unhappy with their relationship, he turns his
experiments on himself and becomes the suave Mr. Hyde.Another take on the Jekyll and Hyde story, this one has some
interesting ideas, but it never does much with them. Ultimately, the
film is quite dull. Too much focus is placed on Jekyll's poor marriage
and the affair his wife is having. It might not have been so bad if his
wife were actually desirable, but she's an annoying shrew. Jekyll
should just rid himself of her and consider his life all the better for
it. Christopher Lee plays the friend with whom she's having the affair.
He's playing against type here and is actually sort of the protagonist,
but it's hard feeling sympathy for a philanderer. Paul Massie plays
Jekyll and Hyde. He's actually not that great as either. His line
delivery just sounds unnatural, especially when he's playing Jekyll.There are some interesting twists towards the end, but it's too little,
too late. This isn't one of the better films from Hammer.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16161013/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>JohnRouseMerriottChard</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Dr. Henry Jekyll (Paul Massie) has no life anymore, chained to his work
and stuck in a loveless marriage to Kitty (Dawn Addams), he busy's
himself working on a character altering potion. Firstly testing it on
primates, Jekyll ignores the warnings from his friend Dr. Ernst
Littauer (David Kossoff) and experiments on himself. The result brings
out Jekyll's alter ego, Mr. Edward Hyde, a debonair gentlemen who holds
within a sadistic dangerous streak. Hyde spells danger for anyone who
gets too close to him, particularly Kitty, Jekyll's morally bankrupt
friend Paul Allen (Christopher Lee) and more worryingly, Jekyll
himself.The Two Faces of Dr. Jekyll is by Hammer Film Productions. It's
directed by Terence Fisher and is adapted by Wolf Mankowitz from the
famous story of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde by Robert Louis Stevenson. Tho
very much a middle tier offering from the house of Hammer, this version
of the often told tale puts a different slant on things to make it
unique and always interesting. Jekyll here is a bland and reclusive
person, the people closest to him cheat on him and he is powerless to
stop it. Contrast with Hyde, handsome and charming and able to take
what he wants either by cunning or brute force. This was a deliberate
shift from the normal by Fisher and Mankowitz, they didn't want Hyde as
some furry half man beast frothing at the mouth, they sided with evil
lurking behind a charming facade. It's also notable for its ending too.
Where they had the courage of their convictions to stay with a
differing formula.The problems come if one is searching for a horror film in the Hammer
tradition. For although Hammer traits such as a smouldering sexiness
hang over proceedings, the film is in truth lacking in terror.
Something which is sure to annoy the horror purists. But if you can
accept this as a more restrained psychological horror piece, one that
deals in the duality of man, the pursuit of something more and the
often treacherous nature of the human being, the rewards are there to
be enjoyed. The cast are fine, Massie is competent without the ham, and
Lee is elegantly vile to fit seamlessly into character. But the bonus
is with a flame headed Dawn Addams who comes up with something more
than the usual heaving bosom Hammer leading lady. The cast also
features an early appearance from none other than Oliver Reed, suitably
playing a night club pimp type bit of muscle. Shot in Megascope and
Technicolor the film thankfully looks gorgeous and has transfered
excellently on to DVD. With the sultry red lipped Addams and Jekyll's
garden particularly benefiting from the pinging colours.A dam good story with wit and cautionary observations of the human
condition, this isn't one for the blood and gore brigade. But it has
many other qualities just waiting to be discovered by the more literary
minded horror fan. 7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12371785/comments</url><from>from Durham NC</from><name>mlraymond</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I recently acquired the two disc set that includes this movie, and was
finally able to see it uncut, and uninterrupted by commercials, having
last viewed it in the early Seventies on network television.I found it a genuinely unnerving movie, with a very depressing
atmosphere that lingers in the mind for days afterward. This is
surprising, given how well known the story is, and how many film
adaptations there have been over the years.Part I think is due to the screenplay, which depicts Dr. Jekyll as less
benign and more of an egotist than he's usually shown. Mr. Hyde in this
context seems more like a logical extension of the repressed and
frustrated Dr. Jekyll's id run amok, than the more conventional " evil"
half of his personality. One could say that Mr. Hyde is more truly the
man Jekyll wishes he was.The other aspect is the convincing portrayal by actor Paul Massie of
two completely different men. His Mr. Hyde is almost cute and charming
at times, with an oddly naive quality that is unexpected. Hyde becomes
more vicious and cunning as the story unfolds, but there's no getting
around the fact that Hyde is overall more appealing than Jekyll, who
almost seems more like the bad guy, in this version.To say more would be to risk spoiling the movie, which has its share of
surprises. It's an uncomfortably absorbing film, that nearly overwhelms
the viewer with its sordid atmosphere. Seldom have Victorians seemed so
decadent and unlikable on screen.One other thing must be mentioned. The portrayal of suave womanizer
Paul Allen by Christopher Lee is unlike anything else Lee ever did. His
charm, wit and lighthearted personality are miles from the usual somber
Lee presence and manner. It's truly amazing to see Lee smiling and
joking, and even getting drunk, with self indulgent glee. The movie is
probably worth seeing just for Lee by himself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12371785/comments</url><from>from Durham NC</from><name>mlraymond</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I recently acquired the two disc set that includes this movie, and was
finally able to see it uncut, and uninterrupted by commercials, having
last viewed it in the early Seventies on network television.I found it a genuinely unnerving movie, with a very depressing
atmosphere that lingers in the mind for days afterward. This is
surprising, given how well known the story is, and how many film
adaptations there have been over the years.Part I think is due to the screenplay, which depicts Dr. Jekyll as less
benign and more of an egotist than he's usually shown. Mr. Hyde in this
context seems more like a logical extension of the repressed and
frustrated Dr. Jekyll's id run amok, than the more conventional " evil"
half of his personality. One could say that Mr. Hyde is more truly the
man Jekyll wishes he was.The other aspect is the convincing portrayal by actor Paul Massie of
two completely different men. His Mr. Hyde is almost cute and charming
at times, with an oddly naive quality that is unexpected. Hyde becomes
more vicious and cunning as the story unfolds, but there's no getting
around the fact that Hyde is overall more appealing than Jekyll, who
almost seems more like the bad guy, in this version.To say more would be to risk spoiling the movie, which has its share of
surprises. It's an uncomfortably absorbing film, that nearly overwhelms
the viewer with its sordid atmosphere. Seldom have Victorians seemed so
decadent and unlikable on screen.One other thing must be mentioned. The portrayal of suave womanizer
Paul Allen by Christopher Lee is unlike anything else Lee ever did. His
charm, wit and lighthearted personality are miles from the usual somber
Lee presence and manner. It's truly amazing to see Lee smiling and
joking, and even getting drunk, with self indulgent glee. The movie is
probably worth seeing just for Lee by himself.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>