<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Never Let Go</original_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>John Guillermin</director><producer>Julian Wintle/Leslie Parkyn Productions</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A cosmetic salesman sets out to prove to himself and his wife that he is not a failure.
</synopsis><actor>Richard Todd</actor><actor>Peter Sellers</actor><actor>Elizabeth Sellars</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0417726/comments</url><from>from Ann Arbor, MI</from><name>Kevin G. Helfenbein (kgh@umich.edu)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Never Let Go, a movie rarely shown in the U.S. (and perhaps elsewhere), is
well worth your time, especially if you are a Peter Sellers fan. The plot
is
reminiscent of The Bicycle
Thief, though this movie will not be confused with Italian Neo-Realism.
Under John Guillermin's direction, this drama moves from a nervy look at
the
underworld to a climax comparable to a western's showdown on a deserted
dirt
street.  Richard Todd plays a cosmetics salesman barely doing well enough
to
make a living, in part due to his milquetoast-type personality.  When his
car is stolen, his life takes a serious downturn--he cannot work without
it.
His quest to get his car back drives the plot till the movie's end.
Unlike
The Bicycle Thief, however, much of the focus scene-by-scene is on the
thief, played here by the late, great Peter Sellers.Sellers's performance is overwhelming, completely over the top. The best
comparison I can make is to Dennis Hopper's memorable performance in
Lynch's
Blue Velvet.  As the movie progresses, his manic behavior becomes
infectious: there was a palpable sense of the hysteric in the theater where
I saw this movie, the audience just waiting to explode with laughter or
shock with each move that Sellers made. This can be see as a distraction,
and for a moment here or there it is, but by the end, the performance works
very well, making the Todd character's growing determination to reclaim his
car a point of tension--it will lead to direct confrontation with a maniac.
Inexplicably, there is a sugary last scene tacked on to the end of this
film, but it is easily forgiven.  Ask your local art film house if it can
show this movie--if so, it will be a memorable experience.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0446634/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>Silasss</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Of course, it's Peter Sellers' name which has attracted attention to this
little-known film, made at a time when he was trying out some serious
acting
work in addition to his renowned comedy talent.  It must be said that he
does pull off a remarkable performance.  As the gangster, Meadows, he
does a
lot more than put on a tough voice and bash a few heads in.  He perfectly
portrays an outward smoothie, concerned for appearances, a man who
doesn't
like getting his hands dirty - but underneath is a barely-repressed
streak
of sadism verging on psychopathic tendencies.  There is a remarkably
daring
scene (for the time) which distinctly adds a sexual dimension to his
dominant personality.  As he tells Carol White to take her top off, the
sound of his breathing and the look in his eyes verge on the shocking,
and
the fact that it is Peter Sellers performing this, adds to the shock
value.However, Sellers does not upstage the film from Richard Todd who is also
cast considerably against type.  In films of this period Todd always
played
the handsome debonair hero, but in a complete reversal Todd here plays
what
the Americans refer to as a "milquetoast".  But again,
multidimensionality
in the character is beautifully brought out, as Cummings starts to show
the
obsessive side of his personality.  The expository scene in which his
wife
tells him, as gently as she can, that he has always been a failure, and
that
getting the car back would not, as he claims, solve all their problems,
is
beautifully handled by Todd and Elizabeth Sellars as his long-suffering
wife.This film, an X-Certificate upon release (equivalent to 18 or NC-17
certificates today) doesn't shirk from showing the execution and effects
of
violence.  One scene, in which Todd gets badly beaten up by David Lodge
(of
all people), must have represented a very early usage of amplifying the
sound of a fist hitting a torso for the purposes of magnifying the
horror.
This scene remains effective over forty years later.  As a result of
this,
the film acquires a beautiful sense of unpredictability.  There's clearly
going to be a showdown between Cummings and Meadows, but the film very
effectively adds to the suspense by a long sequence in which Cummings in
a
cafe and Meadows in his penthouse flat are both shown waiting for it -
without any clue tipped to the audience as to what finally will happen.
John Barry's score is very effective, if a trifle old fashioned, in
heightening the tension - Barry's trademark chord progressions are still
a
way off in the future.De Sarigny and Guillermin put together a brilliant script, two
wonderfully
talented actors and superlative direction to create a great British noir
movie which should be more widely known.Incidentally, for young Harry Potter fans who think the car in "The
Chamber
of Secrets" was made up, here is the proof that the Ford Anglia really
did
exist, all the way back to 1959 (although sadly it doesn't fly) - here an
example of one is the cause of all the trouble.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0864985/comments</url><from>from Brisbane, Australia</from><name>Steve Pyott (spyott)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I've now seen this film a few times when it gets shown late at night on
ABC
TV here in
Australia and it is still compelling viewing.  It is a classic example of
the gritty working class
social reality/suspense genre in a post Angry Young Men gloomy London
setting with a
superb cast all giving stellar performances, particularly Peter Sellers as
the petty vicious
crook (one of his best roles), Elizabeth Sellars as the long suffering
wife,
Carol White, Mervyn
Johns and Adam Faith.  The casting of Richard Todd in the lead role of the
down-trodden but
defiant cosmetics salesman who wants to show everyone he can succeed is
superb, inspired
and brilliant, particularly given that he was normally cast as heroic and
successful types, such
as officers.It is impossible not to identify with the personal struggle against the
injustice of the very
difficult situation in which Todd's character has found himself and that
was
not of his own
making.  Although the film has the typical feel of the late 50s/early 60s
era in British urban
society (which I love, by the way!), I found his work situation, which is
at
the heart of the
story, and the way he tried to deal with it achingly convincing and
clearly
reminiscent of more
modern eras, particularly with the constant threat of up and coming
younger,
brighter and
sharper sales staff being used by the management as an unsubtle threat to
his position if he
does not improve his sales figures.  I am sure anyone who has ever been
paid
on a sales
commissions basis in a competitive product or service field would be able
to
identify easily
with that situation.His persistent determination to deal with the unsavoury types he thinks
are
responsible for
the theft of his car in the face of police indifference and try to get
back
everything that he
has lost, while everyone is telling him to just give up, is portrayed very
convincingly and the
final ending and resolution with the fight scene in the garage is utterly
convincing and
satisfying.  I strongly recommend this film and I have always found it
difficult to understand
why Richard Todd never became the huge star I believe he deserved to
be.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3051873/comments</url><from>from Switzerland</from><name>michelerealini</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
As I'm a Peter Sellers fan I discovered this film by chance on DVD... I
was totally amazed by the story and the acting. All the cast is TOP,
but I was mostly surprised by Peter Sellers -here he's not comical or
funny at all, here he's a villain, a gangster. He's so good in the
performance that you hate him -as a character, of course!A salesman is victim of a theft. His car is stolen by a disbanded young
who works for a car seller, a criminal who soups up engines for selling
them again.Not only Peter Sellers is excellent, the other great actor is Richard
Todd. He's moving in the part of the salesman, obsessed by the search
for his car and the will to show his wife (Elizabeth Sellars) he's not
a loser. Adam Faith (one of the first rock singers in Britain before
the Beatles and the Stones...) is the young thief.The film has rhythm and is very realistic -for its time it's strong,
fight scenes are quite violent. The film is in the wave of "Look back
in anger", "Saturday night and Sunday morning". There's rage and a
touch of "Free cinema", even if director John Guillermin has a more
commercial style and later went to Hollywood for directing blockbusters
like "The Blue Max", "The towering Inferno" and "King Kong".A great classic, by the way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5330240/comments</url><from>from Germany</from><name>gvit-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is not as great a film as the comments lead me to believe.
However, it is a well done piece of work and obviously done on a very
modest budget. The story is a bit heavy-handed in places, and the scene
where the wife tells her husband that he's a loser is very hard to
believe. That all being said, it is a dreary, gritty slice of England
in the early sixties and is a showcase for the dramatic talents of
Peter Sellers. While some of the supporting roles are well done,
Sellers shines like a bright diamond with his intense and convincing
portrayal of a carjacker, free of any moral pretense. If this film had
been widely seen, I am convinced that many directors would have tried
to get Sellers into more serious roles. His ability to leave all traces
of the Goon comedy figure behind is truly astounding. If you are
interested in post-war English cinema, this is an interesting film. If
you are a fan of Peter Sellers, it's a must see.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0382004/comments</url><from>from CARDIFF, WALES.</from><name>ALAN MOUNT</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

How many movies conclude with a no holds barred one on one fight between a
disgruntled toiletries salesman and an evil garage owner? Not many I
bet,"NEVER LET GO" does and it serves as a prime example of a tough
British
crime thriller of the late 50s and early 60s.It was made at a time when
the
British cinema chose to make films on subjects other than homosexuality
which is rarely the case nowadays and tells a strong,gripping story of a
ordinary,decent working man forced to stand up for himself against
injustice
even if it costs him his job and his family.Richard Todd eschews his usual
"stiff upper lip" roles to portray an everyman, John Cummings,whose car is
stolen by the underlings of a thoroughly nasty used car salesman and mini
crime boss portrayed with real menace by Peter Sellers.Cummings' efforts
to
retrieve his motor bring his marriage to breaking point and his latent
heroism to the surface.Todd is excellent as is every member of the
supporting cast and its London locations are used sparingly but
effectively.The music is by John Barry and is very jazz oriented and a bit
raucous and over-used in places but this was often the case in this
era.Watch this hard to find movie and you will remember it as an example
of
a long gone time when the British knew how to make movies that would
appeal
to more than just an effete elite.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4877471/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>keithtrumbo</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Saw this movie in the UK in the early 60's. Sellers was a major comedic
hero of mine who I first discovered in The Goon Show. What made "Never
Let Go" so important was that as far as I can remember this was the
only time he played a vicious character. The scene where he is crushing
Adam Faith's hands in a drawer stayed with me forever not only because
Faith was a major pop star at that time but that it was shocking to see
Sellers play this cruel roll. Now some 40+ years later I wish Sellers
had pursued this other side of his character in more films as I think
he could have become a real 'bastard' London character that have become
so popular. Yes I prefer his comedy as it was so important to Britain's
comedic release from it's stiff upper lip but he might have become one
of the few actors that span both comedy &amp; drama. Imagine Sellers with a
touch of Bob Hoskins &amp; Michael Caine (Long Goodbye mixed with
Ipcress/Alfie). Definitely worth seeing. As an aside Adam Faith was a
huge pop singer who did some acting and later became a very successful
business man. Look out for his music.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is a nice little picture, kind of a commentary on crime, which
features Richard Todd as a perfume salesman who doesn't take kindly to
having his new Impalia stolen by a gang lead by Peter Sellers. Although
there may be elements of dark comedy, this is basically a
straightforward crime drama and all the principals are very effective,
particularly Sellers.You could basically see this film as a modern urban variation on "High
Noon." The police and the man's wife eventually decide that going after
Sellers is far too dangerous, but as the title implies this man will
just not let go of his precious car. He goes so far as to bring danger
down upon his own household, when Sellers tracks him there and pushes
his wife around. Finally he has to have a man-to-man showdown with the
villainous Sellers, and the men beat each other nearly to death.I've never really seen Sellers quite as evil as he was in this film. He
pushes women around, he robs from innocent people with no remorse, and
he brutally punishes his underlings when they disappoint him. He
attacks the role with great relish, like a man who enjoys doing bad
things. This was Sellers' least mannered performance to date, among the
films I have seen. In contrast to some of his later films where his
excellent performances stand out like a sore thumb compared to the rest
of the film, this one serves the story and the film before all else.It's an interesting comment on materialism in our society, although I
don't know if it plays out today exactly as it was intended. I found
myself becoming quite aggravated with the good guy and wishing that
Sellers could get away with it, because I was almost as infuriated with
him as the bad guy. There's also a juvenile delinquent couple that just
seems thrown in to give the story "modern relevance." But all in all
this is a very memorable movie and I'm surprised that it's not
discussed more often.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1090243/comments</url><from>from Lancaster - UK</from><name>Mark Rasmussen</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

In a sea of monotonous black and white 50's - 60's films it was great to
see
a master of roles playing an classic villain - Sellers.  Peter Sellers
role
in this film was quite superb as said above a classic villain for this
master of character acting to sink his teeth into.  Adam Faith and
Richard
Todd turn in an uneventful performance - in fact Todd's role was very
wooden.  In support of the masterly Sellers was David Lodge and Nigel
Stock
who in their turn have supported the best over the years and in my
opinion
both gave small but convincing performances as Seller's side
kicks.An excellent film to see if only to watch the performance by Peter
Sellers
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
While the star of this film technically is Richard Todd, Peter Sellers'
supporting performance dominates the film and it's no surprise that the
DVD features Sellers on the cover, not Todd. It's one of the better
performances of his career--and, interestingly, it's not at all comedic
but a VERY gritty and serious role.The film begins with a working man (Todd) leaving work--only to
discover that his car's been stolen. He goes to the police but after a
couple days there doesn't appear to be any chance he'll get it
back--and it's not insured. Todd is a very mild-mannered man and not
the sort you'd expect to do anything about the crime, but his car is
needed for his job and he won't let it rest. So, he starts trying to
find leads on his own--and repeatedly he nearly gets himself killed.
Yet, for once this mild-mannered man is NOT going to just back down--he
will follow this as far as he can and the consequences be damned.
Through the course of Todd's investigations, the trail leads to a truly
horrible man (Sellers). On the surface, Sellers seems sophisticated and
mild-mannered himself. However, he is a very violent bully--and this
comes out with the least provocation. What's to happen next? Tune in to
this excellent film to see for yourself--just be forewarned...it's
amazingly brutal for 1960--so brutal the Brits gave it what is
equivalent to a restricted rating!As I said, Sellers is at his best here. Wearing bulky clothes (and
perhaps lifts to make him look taller), he looks beefier and plays a
great heavy. His violent and sadistic routine is mesmerizing--and it
was hard to believe this is the same guy who made a career out of
making people laugh. Here, he's malevolent and cruel--and very
effective. Now all this does NOT mean Todd isn't quite good as well--he
is. But even in turning in a dandy performance himself, he is
overshadowed by the malevolent Sellers. The sum effect of both of them
is quite compelling--making a simple and inexpensive film much better
than you'd ever expect. If you like to see excellent acting and
characters, then see this one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
While the star of this film technically is Richard Todd, Peter Sellers'
supporting performance dominates the film and it's no surprise that the
DVD features Sellers on the cover, not Todd. It's one of the better
performances of his career--and, interestingly, it's not at all comedic
but a VERY gritty and serious role.The film begins with a working man (Todd) leaving work--only to
discover that his car's been stolen. He goes to the police but after a
couple days there doesn't appear to be any chance he'll get it
back--and it's not insured. Todd is a very mild-mannered man and not
the sort you'd expect to do anything about the crime, but his car is
needed for his job and he won't let it rest. So, he starts trying to
find leads on his own--and repeatedly he nearly gets himself killed.
Yet, for once this mild-mannered man is NOT going to just back down--he
will follow this as far as he can and the consequences be damned.
Through the course of Todd's investigations, the trail leads to a truly
horrible man (Sellers). On the surface, Sellers seems sophisticated and
mild-mannered himself. However, he is a very violent bully--and this
comes out with the least provocation. What's to happen next? Tune in to
this excellent film to see for yourself--just be forewarned...it's
amazingly brutal for 1960--so brutal the Brits gave it what is
equivalent to a restricted rating!As I said, Sellers is at his best here. Wearing bulky clothes (and
perhaps lifts to make him look taller), he looks beefier and plays a
great heavy. His violent and sadistic routine is mesmerizing--and it
was hard to believe this is the same guy who made a career out of
making people laugh. Here, he's malevolent and cruel--and very
effective. Now all this does NOT mean Todd isn't quite good as well--he
is. But even in turning in a dandy performance himself, he is
overshadowed by the malevolent Sellers. The sum effect of both of them
is quite compelling--making a simple and inexpensive film much better
than you'd ever expect. If you like to see excellent acting and
characters, then see this one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>