<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>It Started in Naples</original_title><alt_title>C'est arrivé à Naples</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Melville Shavelson</director><producer>Capri Productions</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Mike Hamilton, a Philadelphia lawyer, comes to Naples to settle the estate of his long estranged "black sheep" brother...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Clark Gable</actor><actor>Sophia Loren</actor><actor>Vittorio De Sica</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Philadelphia lawyer Michael Hamilton (Clark Gable) arrives in Naples to
settle the estate of his philandering brother...He learns that his brother had taken a common-law wife who died with
him in an automobile accident, leaving a ten-year-old lovechild named
Nando...Nando (Marietto) is looked after by his attractive aunt Lucia (Sophia
Loren), a dazzling night-club dancer on Capri, who dreams of someday
becoming a movie star...Almost immediately, Mike and Lucia clash over the boy's upbringing...Lucia wants to keep the lad and let him live as he chooses... The
street urchin stays up half the night in the club, smokes cigarettes
and indulges in trivial theft... Mike is aghast, and insists he be
giving a proper formal and social education... The matter is put to the court, but during the struggle for Marietto's
affections, the couple fall in love and fight a lot when Hamilton makes
it clear that marriage is out... Photographed in Capri, the Island of Dreams, the pearl of the
Mediterranean sea, the film is a nice romantic comedy in which a sexy
Queen captures the 'King of Hollywood.'Gable delivers one of the most memorable lines of the movie when he
asks, at night, a waiter: 'How are people supposed to sleep on this
island?'
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0885866/comments</url><from>from Ile-de-France / Paris Region, France</from><name>Nicholas Rhodes</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This film really has to take the cake as being one of the most romantic
comedies ever made, I have watched it countless times and this year it
was finally issued on DVD with excellent picture quality devoid of
clicks, blotches and other compression artefacts.The film is plastically beautiful, the surroundings are out of this
world, Sophia Loren is beautiful, sexy, funny, what more could you ask,
Nando is a gorgeous character and Mark Hamilton ( Clark Gable ) carries
his rôle to perfection. The dialogues between him and Nando are
absolutely scrumptious. Yhe story line which alternates between moments
of pure romance then quarrelling and back again keeps the spectator on
his/her toes even if the outcome is guessed in advance. I just loved
the scene where Gable is in the train, listens to the comments of his
compatriots in the compartment, just gets up and goes .. an excellent
ending. The sets of the film are beautiful, I have never been to Capri but it
sure looks a beautiful and romantic place. The 100,000 euro question is
"Does it Still Look Like that in 2005" . Hopefully one or more of the
inhabitants will read this and let us know !!My only beef on this film is trying to get hold of the sound track, no
cd in the world seems to contain it - surprising when you consider the
number of film sound tracks now available. My favourite is actually the
title song ( instrumental ) which was composed by a certain Alessandro
Cicognini, and which appears at various intervals in the film,
including in a vocal version sung in Italian with a rhumba rhythm - no
one tells us what the title is - so God knows how this can be found.
The song "Tu vuo fa l'americano" sung by Loren in the nightclub has
fared better ! It has actually been sung by one of the artists well
known here in France, Dany Brilliant and his version, though not as
good as Loren's is not bad at all. As for the other tunes, no sign of
them anywhere. Hopefully one day, someone somewhere will have the intelligence to
issued the INTEGRAL sound track of this film on a cd. Given the amount
of time we have had to wait to have the film on DVD, there may still be
hope for a cd later. Brilliant !
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is the penultimate film of the career of Clark Gable, and his last
comedy. He is a Philadelphia lawyer named Michael Hamilton, who is
about to marry a suitable middle aged woman at home (we never see her),
and must delay the marriage while he goes to Naples to settle the
estate of his long estranged brother. He is unaware of the details, but
his brother was never a hard headed, hard working type - and he had
fled to Italy, where he seems to have drowned in an accident. Mike
discovers his brother was out fishing with his wife when a sudden
squall upset the boat and drowned them. He also discovers his brother
lived up to his reputation as a ne'er-do-well by specializing in making
great fireworks, and left a little boy named Nando (Marietto). But
Nando's mother had a sister named Lucia (Sophia Loren) who appears at a
local Capri nightclub. Mike and Lucia find themselves at odds about
Nando's present and future lifestyle: Mike wants the boy brought up in
America, while Lucia wants him in a happier, earthier life in Italy.
Soon Nando, Lucia, Mike, and Mike's lawyer Vitale (Vittorio De Sica)
manage to bring the blood uncle and blood aunt into a closer and closer
relationship. Eventually they fall in love.Gable's performance was similar to a middle class "Ugly American" as in
the contemporary novel and the movie with Marlon Brando. Mike is a
successful lawyer, and he wants his brother's son to get the breaks he
needs in good schools and with a normal home. He cannot believe that
the little fellow is not degenerating, but is actually in a loving
household with Lucia. In the first third of the film Gable makes a lot
of snide comments about the easy take it life style he sees around him
in Italy. It is only gradually that he realizes that the Italians can
be serious when they want, and that there is nothing wrong (as he
eventually admits) to being an elderly carriage driver singing "So Long
to Sorrento" for his fares' amusement. He also can see that his first
choice for marriage is even stuffier than he is, or that there were
some really unattractive aspects in his fellow American tourists
(witness that final scene in the railway car he is leaving Naples in).Lucia is also an interesting character - she mistrusts Americans (as
her song "Americano" spoofs their foibles), but her own ambitions for
success mirror the type of work ethic that is part of the American
persona. She also is a realist - she insists that Nando speak English
at home, rather than Italian. The reason (aside from the obvious
screenplay reason of allowing the audience to understand the
conversation) is that English is the international tongue of the modern
age. If Nando is to succeed, he has to speak English well. Her
affection for her nephew is deep - to the point that she is willing to
even consider losing him for his own good.Nando is trying to find a balance between his aunt and uncle. He loves
the aunt, and gets to really like Mike, but he can't understand why
Mike can't only leave him with Lucia, and then occasionally visit. When
Mike and Lucia become an item (or appear to be one), well that's fine
too - they can take up where his parents left off. But he is capable of
knowing if something is going wrong. When Mike says he wants to talk to
him "man to man" Nando's face drops, and he says he never likes it when
he hears "man to man".Vitale is an interesting supporting character. As the lawyer for Mike's
brother he is obliged to tell him what the deceased's estate was
(mostly fireworks and Nando). He begins processing Mike's legal moves
to get custody of Nando away from Lucia. Lucia confronts Vitale,
calling him a traitor to Italy for helping an American steal her
nephew, and calling him a pig (as his looks at the sumptuous
Lucia/Sophia Loren reveal). His helpless reply is that a man can be
both a lawyer and a pig. In the end, in the courtroom, he is so twisted
by his loyalties that he cannot give Mike a coherent (or even fair)
defense. One can understand his dilemma.It is a sweet comedy, that holds up very well. It makes one wonder if
Gable would have continued in roles like this one had he not died so
soon after THE MISFITS.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This was the first Clark Gable movie I ever remember seeing and I saw
it in the old Marine Theatre in Brooklyn. Turned out also to be the
last one Clark Gable got to see released as The Misfits was released
after Gable's demise.He's an honest to God Philadelphia lawyer who had a brother who
deserted his wife and took off for Italy where he lived with another
woman. The brother has died and Gable has gone to Italy to settle the
estate.The estate's one very tangible asset was the brother's son played very
winningly by Marietto. Mom is deceased also and the boy is living with
her sister and who wouldn't want an aunt who looked like Sophia Loren.
It's a custody battle and the question the movie asks is how will the
issue be settled, in or out of court?Gable's certainly a mature leading man playing about 15 to 20 years
younger than he is, but he carries it off well. And Sophia Loren is
wonderful to see.But the real star of this film is the Isle of Capri, one of the most
beautiful spots on this old planet. Capri was getting a lot of
publicity from Hollywood. Only a year before Mario Lanza's last film,
For the First Time, also was shot a great deal in Capri. After these
two films the tourist business must have boomed.Sophia Loren has a few nice numbers to sing and one of them was the
song Americano. It had a revival a few years ago in Matt Damon's The
Talented Mr. Ripley. But Sophia's version is soooooooooo much better.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1684266/comments</url><from>from Las Vegas Nevada</from><name>lonniebealeusa</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

What a wonderful movie starring two of filmdoms' greatest stars-Clark Gable
and the beautiful Sophia Loren. Set in Naples and the island of Capri this
is one attractive movie.Great story line and excellent music and a
wonderful
performance by the master himself Vittorio De Sica. Add to the cast a young
Italian actor by the name of Marietto playing a wise-cracking street kid
from Naples and you have the perfect afternoon treat. Though this was
Gables' second last movie before the ill fated Misfits (a movie I would
rather forget)he looks in excellent shape and still has that twinkle in his
eye that made him a star for over 25 years. This movie is just magic.
Enough
said.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4675011/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Kelly Still</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I just got this movie, as it was just released in July 2005 on DVD. I'd
seen it before on TV and had rented it before on VHS. Not sure what it
is about this movie, but it's so full of charm! The beautiful
landscapes and backdrops of Naples and Capri make it worth the view
alone (Not to mention Sophia Loren; Viva Italia!) This was Clark
Gable's second-to-last film, I believe, and as he was a bit miscast in
the role (he was 59 or so), he pulls off the role of pushy
Philadelphian lawyer, Mike Hamilton, with style. Sophia Loren's
character, Lucia Curcio, is so lovably "Italian", she really shines in
this role. It's also very interesting to see the evolution (or
de-evolution) of Hollywood's current concept of sexiness when watching
Sophia in this film; she exudes it while most modern-day actresses need
all the help they can get...with surgery! Marietto Angeletti plays an
8-year old Nando, the nephew of both leads; truly gifted young actor
and you'll love his character. And Also, veteran Italian actor Vittorio
De Sica seems so natural in his role as the Neapolitan lawyer Mario
Vitale, very believable.All in all, a thoroughly enjoyable film and I'd recommend it for
everyone. Who knows, it may start a resurgence of tourism to the area!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6180927/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>dcurrie623</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I've just seen this on a beautiful DVD and I want to echo the positive
comments. While not the funniest movie ever made it is amusing and a
good family-type picture---assuming that families watch this type of
picture these days.What makes it happen for me is seeing Clark Gable and Sophia Loren
together on screen with a beautiful background full of Capri Italy,
1960. The story is pretty basic but {like most good movies}provides a
framework, plot situations and dialog- a lot of it in Italian, but
still understandable- to keep the action moving and show off the Star
Power on screen.There is great chemistry between Loren and Gable as
well as co-star Vittorio De Sica and the young kid who plays the boy
Nando - a star turn at age 10. Charming,amusing with eye-filling
scenery and three legendary cinema personalities. Diverting and
entertaining.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2468182/comments</url><from/><name>little_general5</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This movie is a movie that just makes you feel good inside.  It was slow
at
the start, but once Gable started spending time with the boy and Loren,
the
story picked up and left a wonderful product.  My only complaint is that
it
was sometimes hard to pick up what the Italians were saying when they
spoke
in English.  And although it was pretty easy to sense what they were
meaning
when they spoke in Italian, I would have liked to see some
subtitles...just
to know what they were saying.  But that would have taken away from the
movie...so maybe it's best  just as it was.
Anyways, a fine film, with Gable his normal charming self, with
another
male to vy for Sofia Loren, this time being and eight year
old.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2774798/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>princesspink2003</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Truly a delightful film! Sophia was never funnier. And the little boy is a
treasure. Clark and Sophia were a delight to watch. I've seen Clark in
comedies before, but for this film Mr. Gable was at his best! Naples was
as
beautiful as Sophia.  Sophia and Naples! It was like being on vacation
watching this film.I would recommend watching this if you haven't seen it. It's worth
watching
more than once too!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
In many, many ways, this film appears to have later been made as AVANTI
(with Jack Lemmon and Juliet Mills). The plots have just too many
similarities to be a coincidence. While not exactly a remake, this
later film seems like a slight reworking of the plot--with a little bit
of gratuitous sex and nudity added to boot.The film begins with Clark Gable going to Italy to take care of
arrangements after his brother's accidental death. This no-good brother
had apparently been living a double life--with a wife back in the
States AND one in Italy! Gable is surprised to not only discover this,
but that there is an 8 year-old boy who is apparently his nephew! He's
also surprised that the boy's Italian Aunt (Sophia Loren) isn't
particularly interested in establishing a relationship with Gable or
having the boy go to live in the States. Considering that the boy is a
ragamuffin living in a rather bohemian existence, this might just be in
the kid's best interest--at least that is what Gable assumes. Over
time, the blustering Gable comes under the spell of the island of Capri
and Loren's ample charms.Oddly, however, the film makers thought that pairing Gable and Loren
romantically made sense and that the public would buy it--and they
didn't. The age difference was just too great. Additionally, the styles
and personalities of the two were just too different to make such a
pairing believable--though at least it worked better than Loren and
John Wayne (LEGEND OF THE LOST) and a bit better than Loren and Alan
Ladd (BOY ON A DOLPHIN). Why film makers insisted on pairing this sexy
starlet with significantly older established American actors is beyond
me.So, while the film isn't exactly believable, is it worth watching?
After all, although miscast, the film could still be enjoyable. And,
for the most part it was, though including a "cute and precocious" kid
was, at times, a bit too much of a cliché. He was too cute and way too
precocious to be realistic--walking, talking and acting like a 30
year-old man stuck in a kid's body--sort of like Tatum O'Neal in PAPER
MOON. Also, some might find its treatment of Italians as a bit
patronizing--as they all seem rather lazy and fun-loving--not like real
people. As for the look of the film, it was terrific--filmed in
exquisite color that really made this Italian island look its best.
Overall, it's an enjoyable and nice looking piece of fluff--not bad,
just not as good as it could have been.By the way, supporting actor Vittorio De Sica was also a very
accomplished director. He acted in quite a few films and was quite
good, but as a director he was one of the best, with such wonderful
films as UMBERTO D, MIRACLE IN MILAN and THE CHILDREN ARE WATCHING US
to his credits--among others.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
In many, many ways, this film appears to have later been made as AVANTI
(with Jack Lemmon and Juliet Mills). The plots have just too many
similarities to be a coincidence. While not exactly a remake, this
later film seems like a slight reworking of the plot--with a little bit
of gratuitous sex and nudity added to boot.The film begins with Clark Gable going to Italy to take care of
arrangements after his brother's accidental death. This no-good brother
had apparently been living a double life--with a wife back in the
States AND one in Italy! Gable is surprised to not only discover this,
but that there is an 8 year-old boy who is apparently his nephew! He's
also surprised that the boy's Italian Aunt (Sophia Loren) isn't
particularly interested in establishing a relationship with Gable or
having the boy go to live in the States. Considering that the boy is a
ragamuffin living in a rather bohemian existence, this might just be in
the kid's best interest--at least that is what Gable assumes. Over
time, the blustering Gable comes under the spell of the island of Capri
and Loren's ample charms.Oddly, however, the film makers thought that pairing Gable and Loren
romantically made sense and that the public would buy it--and they
didn't. The age difference was just too great. Additionally, the styles
and personalities of the two were just too different to make such a
pairing believable--though at least it worked better than Loren and
John Wayne (LEGEND OF THE LOST) and a bit better than Loren and Alan
Ladd (BOY ON A DOLPHIN). Why film makers insisted on pairing this sexy
starlet with significantly older established American actors is beyond
me.So, while the film isn't exactly believable, is it worth watching?
After all, although miscast, the film could still be enjoyable. And,
for the most part it was, though including a "cute and precocious" kid
was, at times, a bit too much of a cliché. He was too cute and way too
precocious to be realistic--walking, talking and acting like a 30
year-old man stuck in a kid's body--sort of like Tatum O'Neal in PAPER
MOON. Also, some might find its treatment of Italians as a bit
patronizing--as they all seem rather lazy and fun-loving--not like real
people. As for the look of the film, it was terrific--filmed in
exquisite color that really made this Italian island look its best.
Overall, it's an enjoyable and nice looking piece of fluff--not bad,
just not as good as it could have been.By the way, supporting actor Vittorio De Sica was also a very
accomplished director. He acted in quite a few films and was quite
good, but as a director he was one of the best, with such wonderful
films as UMBERTO D, MIRACLE IN MILAN and THE CHILDREN ARE WATCHING US
to his credits--among others.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>http://www.dvdtalk.com/reviews/read.php?ID=17212 /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1427098</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>DVDTalk.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/5
					</rating><comment>It's a quaint and pretty old movie, to be sure, but it's also more than a little boring.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-nusair/</url><url>http://www.reelfilm.com/para3.htm#it /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1422136</url><name>David Nusair</name><from>Reel Film Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
1.5/4
					</rating><comment>...an aimless, thoroughly predictable waste of time masquerading as a romantic comedy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/It-Started-in-Naples /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1412160</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>a fossil of a bygone age when comedies didn't require scatalogical humor, and romances didn't require any basis in logic</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1401394</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117792078.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1808104</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/76282/it_started_in_naples.html /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1480551</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=990CE1DC103FE63ABC4B53DFBF66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1389009</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/4675_IT_STARTED_IN_NAPLES.html /m/it_started_in_naples/comments.php?reviewid=1236940</url><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>