<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Comanche Station</original_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Budd Boetticher</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><producer>Ranown Pictures Corp.</producer><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
A man saves a woman who had been kidnapped by Comanches, then struggles to get both of them home alive.
</synopsis><actor>Randolph Scott</actor><actor>Nancy Gates</actor><actor>Claude Akins</actor><rt_rating>8.1/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Something seemed to come together on the half dozen or so cheap
Westerns that Oscar "Bud" Boetticher made with Randolph Scott and
writer Burt Kennedy, and shot mostly at Movie Flats, California. It all
seemed to work out pretty well.I think this may have been their last joint effort and it's one of the
better examples. The scripts seemed to fall into two general types --
town stories and journeys. This is a story about a journey, not too
different from the one Scott took in "Ride Lonesome," I think it was.
The one with Pernell Roberts.There is always an interesting villain, not entirely unsympathetic, who
has a code of his own. In this case it's Claude Akins, accompanied by
two younger men who have known each other for a long time. The two
youngsters provide a good deal of the humor. The two stand before a
couple of posters nailed on a wall and one of them reads aloud an
announcement about the stagecoach route, stumbling over the words. The
other stares at him open-mouthed and exclaims in genuine wonder, "Why,
I didn't know you could READ." In fact a lot of the humor comes from Kennedy's script, wittingly or
otherwise. He's given to phrases that enjoy a colorful twist. "Ma'am, if you was mine, I'd of come for you even if I'd of died in the
doin' of it.""He rides a little on the gentle side. Maybe too gentle.""A man can break with the wild life."And Kennedy gives us a Scott who is a man of few words and doesn't use
them over and over again. He has a tendency to answer a declaratory
sentence with a doubtful question. "It wasn't MY fault." Scott: "It
wasn't?"But the humor is in the acting as well. Claude Akins, admittedly, is no
barrel of laughs. He's played too many scoundrels for us to accept his
jokes. But the two youngsters are likably ingenuous. Planning to kill
their woman hostage, one tells the other, "It's a waste. It ain't like
if she was all ugly. It's a shame to do a woman as pretty as that."And Scott is the most amusing character of all. He's funny because he
plays it all absolutely straight. He smiles only grimly, and then only
once or twice. He understates outrageously. Akins: "If the Comanche cut
our track, we'll be between a rock and a hard place." Scott: "You CAN
say."By the way, if they're a day's ride from Lordsberg, New Mexico, they
shouldn't have to worry about Comanches, who were living in Texas, but
they might have to worry about Mimbrenos Apaches.The Indians are treated in an entirely uncomplicated manner. They are
wild animals who butcher whites, including the women and children.
("Surprising what a buck will do for a piece of calico.") Well -- okay
-- there IS a reference to Akins having murdered a village full of
"tame Indians," which one imagines are kind of like "tame black
panthers" or something.The score is generic, as in all the Boetticher/Scott films, but that's
okay because it fits in with the other constituents. It's tawdry and
simple. There is a "major theme" which plays while this merry group
ride their horses around the rocks. During chases, the same theme shows
up but up tempo. As I say, it all works out. Anyway, it's a fun movie, an interesting way to spend an hour and a
half.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2387620/comments</url><from>from U.S.</from><name>westerner357</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The last of the seven Scott/Boetticher collaborations and although it's
not one of my favorites {THE TALL T (1957) and RIDE LONESOME (1959)
come out ahead}, it's still worth owning on DVD if Columbia/Tristar
ever sees fit to release it.Randolph Scott plays a rancher named Jefferson Cody who's wife was
kidnapped by the Comanches a few years before. When he hears that the
Comanches are holding a white woman, he goes to them for a trade and
winds up with another man's wife named Mrs. Lowe (Nancy Gates).As they head back, they stop at Comanche Station in order to water
their horses and get fresh supplies. When they arrive there, they see
three men being chased by a bunch of Comanches on the warpath. Cody
recognizes one of them as Ben Lane (Claude Akins), a soldier he had
drummed out of the army for an atrocity against the Indians, many years
before. He also suspects Lane is trafficking in scalps and that's why
the Indians are after them.They manage to fight them off and when the coast is clear, Lane informs
Mrs. Lowe that she has a $5,000 reward put up for her by her husband.
Mrs. Lowe then suspects Cody of his intentions but it's apparent from
the beginning that Cody isn't interested in any reward money. He just
wants to find out what happened to his wife.Also Lane has a habit of saying "Ha-lo.." every time he's being
addressed. A nice script touch put in there by Burt Kennedy who wrote
the script. It gives Lane something to distinguish him by.It now becomes a battle of wills between Cody and Lane with Mrs. Lowe
and Lane's two dimwitted sidemen (played by Skip Homeier and Richard
Rust) looking on. When Frank (Homeier) is sent up the creek to see if
the Comanches have cut off their trail, he comes floating back down,
dead with an arrow in his back. And later when Dobie (Rust) has a
change of heart and wants to throw in with Cody, he gets shot in the
back by Lane for his efforts.That shot warns Cody that Lane is nearby and the inevitable showdown
takes place in the Lone Pine rocks. We all know who wins that one,
right? Cody finally brings Mrs. Lowe back to her husband only to learn
that he is blind and really doesn't care what's happened to her. He
just wants her back.Beautiful widescreen print that was remastered in the late 1990s, this
one would be a welcome addition to any western library. It needs a DVD
release.7 out of 10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0182695/comments</url><from>from Washington</from><name> (reynolds@ritzcom.net)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

A magazine article recently cited this movie as an underrated western. I
certainly agree. Randolph Scott made his best westerns in the latter part
of
his career, and this is one of those. The movie examines the old west
moral
code of right v. wrong and raps up with a surprising twist ending that
gives
cynicism a kick in the rear end. Not a big splashy western, but a solid
little one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Comanche Station is the last of several films Randolph Scott made for
Budd Boetticher with Columbia pictures. This would have been his last
film, but for being lured to do just one more, the immortal Ride the
High Country.The film combines elements of The Naked Spur and Two Rode Together and
blends them successfully. Scott is a man with one obsession, to get his
wife back from the Comanches who kidnapped here ten years earlier.
Whenever he hears of a white woman being put up for trade by the
Indians he heads out with trade goods and buys her in the hopes of
finding his beloved. On this trip he ransoms Nancy Gates away from the Comanches. Later on
he runs into an old enemy Claude Akins traveling with two young guns,
Richard Rust and Skip Homeier. It seems as though Nancy's husband has
put up a ten thousand dollar reward for her. Akins is a truly malevolent figure, a scalphunter who kills Indians and
sells their scalps for bounty. Unfortunately the two have need of each
other in hostile Indian territory.Randolph Scott's western heroes usually have an edge to them, they are
not pure heroes as Joel McCrea's are. But in this film he's poaching on
McCrea's territory in gallantry. His behavior towards Nancy Gates is at
all times chivalrous. I wouldn't be surprised if there was a medieval
origin to the plot of Comanche Territory.Had Scott not come back to do Ride the High Country, Comanche Station
would have been a good film to go out on.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218006/comments</url><from>from S. Paulo, Brazil</from><name>tmwest</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
John Ford could a make a great film that happened to be a western,
Anthony Mann could make great westerns with a dark side to them, Sergio
Leone could do great stylized westerns but nobody could like Budd
Boetticher do a pure, simple, conventional western, where the best
would be in what seems to be minor details. Comanche Station is the
story of a man, Randolph Scott obsessed with the idea of finding his
missing wife, captured by the Indians. To him money does not matter at
all, he is the opposite of Claude Akins who will do anything to get the
5000 dollars offered to deliver the woman Scott rescued from the
Comanches to her husband. The "bad guys" here are not just bad guys,
they are men who feel there is a chance to change their lives by
getting the reward and that will be one chance in a lifetime. They also
think that to survive in the west they have to be hard. Their sense of
morality goes down the drain surpassed by these other feelings. Richard
Rust (Dobie) is the one who in spite of everything has good feelings.
Boetticher is an expert in action scenes and here he is as good as
always. He does not need to make them in the dark because it is easier.
An excellent story, which is a quality of every "Ranown" film, Randolph
Scott at his best and the unique direction of Boetticher make "Comanche
Station" a film not to be missed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13251116/comments</url><from>from Ridgefield, CT, USA</from><name>ttbird2000</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Howard Hawks was once asked about his recipe for making a great film.
His reply: "Three good scenes, no bad scenes". I would humbly add two
other rules: A great film is one where no additional scene is needed,
and no existing scene could have been cut. Few competent directors
violate the first rule. The mark of a great director is the ability to
follow the second. Many inferior directors are too shallow or too vain
to understand this - they constantly strive to include superfluous or
redundant scenes - Just To Make Sure You Got The Point - when it is
wiser to let the audience decide what is important. John Ford was the
master at this. Hawks, Wilder, Eastwood, also come to mind. With
Commanche Station, Budd Boetticher showed that he knew how to distill a
great story (with many elements of a Greek tragedy) to its most basic
human elements - Obsession, Greed, Loyalty, Irony, and above all,
Honor.Not only did Boetticher direct a great film, Burt Kennedy (later to
become a fair director himself) constructed a great script. Some good scenes: A conversation between a woman who was taken captive
by Commanches (and held for a time) and the stranger who has just paid
her ransom... Nancy Lowe: If-if you had a woman taken by the Comanche
and-and you got her back... how would you feel knowing? Jefferson Cody:
If I loved her, it wouldn't matter. Nancy Lowe: Wouldn't it? Jefferson
Cody: No ma'am, it wouldn't matter at all.Or two friends, hired guns both, contemplating the need to commit a
horrible crime for money: Frank: You want to go to work, do you? Dobie:
Work? Frank: Making an honest living? Dobie: Oh, no, I don't think I
could do that. I could cowboy some. Frank: Well, what will that get
you? You work yourself to death for somebody and likely they will have
to take up a collection to bury you. Or a conversation between an honorable man and a young man trying to
decide whether he will try to become one: Dobie: A saddle and a shirt,
that's all Frank had. It sure ain't much. Jefferson Cody: Sure ain't.
Dobie: It wasn't his fault, though. Jefferson Cody: No? Dobie: No, he
never knew anything but the wild side. Jefferson Cody: A man can cross
over anytime he has the mind. As for the performances, they are uniformly good. Nancy Gates, Skip
Homier, Richard Rust, and Claude Akins hit the right tone - never going
too far for a laugh or a tear. And Randolph Scott was perfect - A word I do not use lightly. Roger
Ebert once said that Marlon Brando and Paul Newman started out on the
same path: Both came on the scene in the early 1950s, both studied the
Method, both looked good in an undershirt. But Brando went on to see
what else he could throw in to his performances while Newman went on to
see what he could leave out (Newman once said that he was dissatisfied
with many of his early performances because "you could see the
acting"). In Commanche Station, Randolph Scott provided the inspiration
for such an approach. This is what makes a performance (indeed, a film)
memorable - by distilling your performance to only that which is
necessary, you allow the viewer to remember what is important to them,
not what they are told should be important to them. If I were held to only half a dozen westerns to be labeled as
essential, this would be one of them (The others: My Darling Clementine
(1946), Shane (1953), The Searchers (1956), The Man Who Shot Liberty
Valance (1962) and Unforgiven (1992)).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Beautiful, crafted piece has Scott rescuing a woman abducted by
Comanche -- not from the Camanche (they're willing to trade her for
some rugs) but from Akins and his friends, who plan to return the woman
dead to her husband to get the reward. Like the other Burt
Kennedy/Boetticher films, the film's lack of scope is part of what
makes it good -- it is fierce, to the point, tells its story with no
bones or pretensions about it. Damn good show. This is the kind of western I like, and I'd just like to ad in comment
that John Ford, hallowed though he be in film fan circles, could not
have made a film this good. His "The Searchers" is, at best, a wannabe
Ranown film, and its psychological subtlety is nothing to compare with
Kennedy/Boetticher. I would say the same thing for Anthony and Delbert
Mann, and reserve my great appreciation in Westerns in the 50s for
Boetticher and Jacques Tourneur.p.s. it's been pointed out to me since writing this that of course "The
Searchers" came out before the Ranown films so obviously I was off my
rocker there. Also I've come to quite enjoy Anthony Mann's westerns and
at this point I hold them equal to Boetticher's and Tourneur's.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0805697/comments</url><from>from dublin, ireland</from><name>Alice Liddel (-darragh@excite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

The Western takes another step away from the traditional Fordian Western
towards Leone.  This is the West painted by Cezanne, a landscape familiar
enough on the surface, but chopped up into geometric grids and patterns. 
You could forget about the story entirely and just marvel at the way
Boetticher takes a recognisable  monolith, the vast, arid West, and uses it
as an easel; and takes the cumbersome film-making apparatus, cast and crew,
and uses it like a paintbrush.  Or scalpel.  Each astonishingly precise composition is riven by angles, lines, character
positions, patterns, which connect with the angles, lines, character
positions and patterns of the next frame, so that geometry of content meets
the geometry of montage.  These are not sterile theorems; within each frame
the camera moves with a complex simplicity, shifting or rearranging the
tenets of the composition, the relations of particular characters in space,
like a kaleidoscope.  I mentioned Cezanne, but there is Cubism too, the
classical Hollywood method of representation broken up, scenes taken from
different vantage points so that any stability on our part is impossible. 
It is truly beautiful.When the Cahiers critics started looking at films as films in the 1950s,
concentrating on their cinematic, formal elements, there was predictable
reaction from many old-fashioned reviewers, usually British, who saw film as
a humanist extension of literature.  Penelope Houston even said that the
proper study of film should not be spatial relations but character
relations.  She failed to see that the latter could not exist without the
first, a character's relation, and reaction, to space formed character.  It
is in space that a character performs the actions that reveal his character.
 It is space, and a character's position in it, that yields insights simple
narrative or dialogue would laboriously fumble at.  The great irony at the heart of 'Station' is that the vast, wide open spaces
of the West are imprisoned in this formal grid, entrapping characters - the
characters' reaction to this entrapment reveals, naturally, their character,
as well as shaping the narrative.  For instance, a man of Cody's decency and
integrity a few decades previously might have been a great frontiersman,
civilising the West, creating America.  In this world, however, where the
old monochrome values are no longer viable, where it's not simply a case of
slaughtering Indians, where the frontier spirit has congealed into genocide
and murderous greed, he must cut himself off from society, community,
fertility, in effect killing off his race, a dead man. Indeed, the beautiful idea of a man wandering the West for years looking for
his probably dead wife, broods with the force of Greek mythology, Orpheus in
the Underworld, say, seeking Eurydice, in this case never finding her.  The
West has become Hell - endless, repetitive, arbitrary, with the ghosts of
your past returning to haunt you, never totally exorcised.  The film ends
with the opening shot in reverse - there is no progress here - the final
scene with Nancy is tremendously moving.  Even the old hero/villain divide is ambiguous - Cody owes his life to a
genocidal enemy; the fundamentally decent Frank sees no economic choice
other than being an outlaw; Cody's stern values aren't adaptable enough to
comprehend everything.  There is a real homoerotic charge in the
relationship between Frank and Dobie which has lasted most of their lives -
when Dobie is found floating down the river, an arrow in his back, found by
his soaking, grieving buddy, the martyrdom of St. Sebastian comes
immediately to mind.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10353549/comments</url><from>from Austria</from><name>wmjahn</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This is the kind of movie, which is usually called "low key" ...
below-average movie-critic Leonard Maltin calls this the usual
interesting Boettcher/Scott-collaboration and gives it a 2,5 points out
of possible 4 ... come on ! This movie's a little gem, a gem !! OK, it was made fast and with little money, but does it show ...? No!
The story is simple, but is it simple-minded? No! This is a classic story in the "modern" setting of the wild west. This
is a Greek tragedy in modern clothes. Awesome! Let's talk details: 1.) Randolph Scott is just great, the perfect guy for the role! He
doesn't talk much (I bet there also was not much talk needed between
Boettcher and Scott, since this was unfortunately their last
collaboration and each one must have known the other inside out), he
does acting minimal style (perfect for the role), he IS the American
western loner in search for his wife (like Wayne in THE SEACHERS, which
is admittedly the better of the 2, but THE SEARCHES is more
existentialistic, at which COMANCHE STATION is not aiming). I would
even go so far as to say SCOTT is - in his acting style - the Charles
BRONSON of the 50ies! He is never over-acting, as many actors from the
Lee Strasberg school are, Scott just is. And what a presence!2.) The story unfolds lovely, there is no black-white, no good-bad, all
characters have their dark and their bright sides, all show emotion,
but all are tough when toughness is needed.3.) The dialog is sparse, but always on the spot. There are no forced
funny lines, but the characters are not without humor, even if it's a
bleak one or cynicism.4.) The scenery, where this little gem was shot, is just breathtaking!
What a countryside (that goes for all Boettcher/Scott-western)! And
it's so superbly photographed, it's one of the few movies, were I would
really love to see this countryside (thanx for the info on the
discussion board!).5.) It's just 70-something minutes "long", but there is more happening
than in lot longer movies and still there is no hectic in this one,
it's so lovely leisurely paced, which shows real craftsmanship. There
are no scenes just a few seconds long and heavy cutting to get suspense
out of short, hectic scenes, most scenes are long shots, lovingly
choreographed, beautifully shot, in short: this is the kinda movie like
an old armchair: you sit down and it just feels GREAT ! I have now seen this 4 or 5 times and always enjoyed it a lot. Although
there are some better western, these aren't many. I give this one a
hearty 10 out of 10 and in a list of the all-time best western ever
made, I'd put it around number 10 (after classics as GOOD, BAD UGLY,
OUTLAW JOSEY WALES, C'ERA UN VOLTA IL WEST, UNFORGIVEN, SEARCHERS and a
couple more).Prime stuff !
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5488899/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>OldAle1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A man riding, alone, silhouetted on a group of rocks in long shot, the
majestic Sierras in the distance behind him...a moment later, he's
riding through a narrow gully down below, towards us. He's soon met by
a group of Indians who surround him. He stares at them for a moment,
puts his rifle in its holster, and slowly gets off his horse. He's
attentive, but doesn't seem too worried. He spreads out some packages
of cloth on a blanket - trade goods? - and motions to the leader who
has come down closer. Little response. He moves to pack it all up and
this is met with a spear in the middle of the blanket. Still no words -
after a moment of suspense, we see the whole group riding across a
plain from the rocky outcrop towards a similar hillock, with a
still-larger group of men waiting. The blanket it again offered, this
time with the Winchester rifle the man - Randolph Scott, as Jefferson
Cody (how iconic is that for a western hero's name?) had put away in
the first scene; and a beautiful young woman is thrown out of a tent.
Cody tersely tells her to get moving, they might change their mind, and
away they ride. This opening is justly famed - beautifully composed and strikingly
photographed, with only a few words of dialogue in the first ten
minutes - it feels, after you've seen the rest of the Ranown films,
almost like a textbook example of the Randolph Scott character at work,
doing one of the things he's there to do (saving a woman) while
necessarily avoiding the other (gunfighting). Of course, there will be
some of the latter in this, probably overall the most violent of the
films and also perhaps the most serious and elegiac. The woman is Mrs Lowe (Nancy Gates) and her husband is in Lordsburg;
Cody's mission now is to get her back there, which will take two days.
She's nervous - as they stop for the night she asks him whether if his
wife had been captured by the Indians he'd still want her. "Wouldn't
matter at all" he says, and there's such an ache and gravity to those
words, in just this briefest of exchanges, that we know right away
there's more to his saving this unknown woman than the fact that he
heard about it from a "tame Indian" and it "seemed like the right thing
to do." But, in typical Burt Kennedy style, that's all we get, for now.
The next day they ride to Comanche station - deserted - and are quickly
met by three men (Claude Akins, Skip Homeier and Richard Rust) being
chased by a group of Comanches. A quick gun battle ensues and the
braves are driven off - there is a moment of recognition between the
older man, Ben (Akins) and Cody - and we soon find that Ben and his two
younger sidekicks were after the same thing that Cody was - and that
there's a ransom of $5000, not mentioned by either Cody or Mrs Lane,
for her return. Ben, though genial enough, and honorable in his way, is a little meaner
and more callous than even the typical bad guy in these films; he
treats his sidekicks as his inferiors, ordering them around with
military absolutism, and tells them that the reward was promised for
Mrs. Lowe's return dead or alive - and dead will probably be easier.
The youngest man, Dobie (Rust), doesn't like it and protests to the
other, Frank (Homeier), asking if maybe they should get away from Ben.
Frank doesn't like it either but "a man gets used to it". Without
saying more than a couple of lines, screenwriter Kennedy so often seems
able to summon up the problems and limitations for such men as these -
and so they continue on. Eventually the group gets close to Lordsburg, and Ben decides to make
his move - after saving Cody from an attack; again we see that in this
world, the thief's sense of honor is just as powerful as the hero's -
if perhaps a little more amenable to bending. Dobie makes his choice,
and pays for it; and in this case, unlike the finale of Ride Lonesome,
there is no second villain behind the story who is the real reason for
Scott's character's actions - Ben is the sole obstacle to be overcome,
and a showdown is necessary. In this case, too, the woman is actually
returned to the state she was in before the action of the film, to
husband and kids - and Scott, too, returns to the beginning, quite
literally riding off on the same rocks that he rode at the start of the
film. Perhaps his riding in the opposite direction, and perhaps the
brief comment he makes to Mrs Lowe shortly before the finish of the
film, that she's made him feel better than he has since he started his
quest, indicates a lightening of his soul, but this we have to imagine
for ourselves. There's a little less humor here than in the previous films, and Akins'
Ben is a little meaner and more typically villainous. The whole
conflict between money and sex, the subtext of loneliness vs
companionship, "hardness" versus "softness" out in the wilderness is
remarkably well developed, and the film is closer in spirit I think to
the elegiac westerns of Peckinpah and the later Ford. Though it is
closest overall to Ride Lonesome among the four Kennedy-scripted films,
there are specific elements that call to mind the first two films as
well - Akins' dialogue about a man losing his woman to another white
man is reminiscent of Marvin's little story in Seven Men from Now;
Homeier was in The Tall T - and as in that film it's clear that the
outlaws value money over a woman's life.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5488899/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>OldAle1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
A man riding, alone, silhouetted on a group of rocks in long shot, the
majestic Sierras in the distance behind him...a moment later, he's
riding through a narrow gully down below, towards us. He's soon met by
a group of Indians who surround him. He stares at them for a moment,
puts his rifle in its holster, and slowly gets off his horse. He's
attentive, but doesn't seem too worried. He spreads out some packages
of cloth on a blanket - trade goods? - and motions to the leader who
has come down closer. Little response. He moves to pack it all up and
this is met with a spear in the middle of the blanket. Still no words -
after a moment of suspense, we see the whole group riding across a
plain from the rocky outcrop towards a similar hillock, with a
still-larger group of men waiting. The blanket it again offered, this
time with the Winchester rifle the man - Randolph Scott, as Jefferson
Cody (how iconic is that for a western hero's name?) had put away in
the first scene; and a beautiful young woman is thrown out of a tent.
Cody tersely tells her to get moving, they might change their mind, and
away they ride. This opening is justly famed - beautifully composed and strikingly
photographed, with only a few words of dialogue in the first ten
minutes - it feels, after you've seen the rest of the Ranown films,
almost like a textbook example of the Randolph Scott character at work,
doing one of the things he's there to do (saving a woman) while
necessarily avoiding the other (gunfighting). Of course, there will be
some of the latter in this, probably overall the most violent of the
films and also perhaps the most serious and elegiac. The woman is Mrs Lowe (Nancy Gates) and her husband is in Lordsburg;
Cody's mission now is to get her back there, which will take two days.
She's nervous - as they stop for the night she asks him whether if his
wife had been captured by the Indians he'd still want her. "Wouldn't
matter at all" he says, and there's such an ache and gravity to those
words, in just this briefest of exchanges, that we know right away
there's more to his saving this unknown woman than the fact that he
heard about it from a "tame Indian" and it "seemed like the right thing
to do." But, in typical Burt Kennedy style, that's all we get, for now.
The next day they ride to Comanche station - deserted - and are quickly
met by three men (Claude Akins, Skip Homeier and Richard Rust) being
chased by a group of Comanches. A quick gun battle ensues and the
braves are driven off - there is a moment of recognition between the
older man, Ben (Akins) and Cody - and we soon find that Ben and his two
younger sidekicks were after the same thing that Cody was - and that
there's a ransom of $5000, not mentioned by either Cody or Mrs Lane,
for her return. Ben, though genial enough, and honorable in his way, is a little meaner
and more callous than even the typical bad guy in these films; he
treats his sidekicks as his inferiors, ordering them around with
military absolutism, and tells them that the reward was promised for
Mrs. Lowe's return dead or alive - and dead will probably be easier.
The youngest man, Dobie (Rust), doesn't like it and protests to the
other, Frank (Homeier), asking if maybe they should get away from Ben.
Frank doesn't like it either but "a man gets used to it". Without
saying more than a couple of lines, screenwriter Kennedy so often seems
able to summon up the problems and limitations for such men as these -
and so they continue on. Eventually the group gets close to Lordsburg, and Ben decides to make
his move - after saving Cody from an attack; again we see that in this
world, the thief's sense of honor is just as powerful as the hero's -
if perhaps a little more amenable to bending. Dobie makes his choice,
and pays for it; and in this case, unlike the finale of Ride Lonesome,
there is no second villain behind the story who is the real reason for
Scott's character's actions - Ben is the sole obstacle to be overcome,
and a showdown is necessary. In this case, too, the woman is actually
returned to the state she was in before the action of the film, to
husband and kids - and Scott, too, returns to the beginning, quite
literally riding off on the same rocks that he rode at the start of the
film. Perhaps his riding in the opposite direction, and perhaps the
brief comment he makes to Mrs Lowe shortly before the finish of the
film, that she's made him feel better than he has since he started his
quest, indicates a lightening of his soul, but this we have to imagine
for ourselves. There's a little less humor here than in the previous films, and Akins'
Ben is a little meaner and more typically villainous. The whole
conflict between money and sex, the subtext of loneliness vs
companionship, "hardness" versus "softness" out in the wilderness is
remarkably well developed, and the film is closer in spirit I think to
the elegiac westerns of Peckinpah and the later Ford. Though it is
closest overall to Ride Lonesome among the four Kennedy-scripted films,
there are specific elements that call to mind the first two films as
well - Akins' dialogue about a man losing his woman to another white
man is reminiscent of Marvin's little story in Seven Men from Now;
Homeier was in The Tall T - and as in that film it's clear that the
outlaws value money over a woman's life.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/boettich.htm#Comanche /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=2002611</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Strange Western with unusually sympathetic bad guys.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/comanchestation.htm /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1978673</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>Brilliantly scripted by Burt Kennedy.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/comstat.shtml /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1758687</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>Fans will notice the same general plot arc and the same general characters as the other six [films], but still told with the same expert economy, use of space and psychological detail.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1399333</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Gritty Randolph Scott western directed by Budd Boetticher.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1427318</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/thomas-delapa/</url><url>/m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1359656</url><name>Thomas Delapa</name><from>Boulder Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1216552</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/andrew-schenker/</url><url>http://www.notcoming.com/reviews/comanchestation/ /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=2017640</url><name>Andrew Schenker</name><from>Not Coming to a Theater Near You</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/69499/comanche_station.html /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1519828</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/adrian-danks/</url><url>http://archive.sensesofcinema.com/contents/cteq/04/33/comanche_station.html /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1334462</url><name>Adrian Danks</name><from>Senses of Cinema</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102216 /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=1148535</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/marjorie-baumgarten/</url><url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gbase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3a142135 /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=850730</url><name>Marjorie Baumgarten</name><from>Austin Chronicle</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dave-kehr/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/2077_COMANCHE_STATION.html /m/comanche_station/comments.php?reviewid=49235</url><name>Dave Kehr</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>