<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Saiyûki</original_title><imdb_rating>4.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Daisaku Shirakawa</director><producer>Alta Vista Productions</producer><producer>Toei Animation</producer><genre>Animation</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Family</genre><synopsis>
A monkey king who learns the secrets of magic goes on a spree and causes no end of aggravation for the gods...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Kiyoshi Komiyama</actor><actor>Noriko Shindô</actor><actor>Hideo Kinoshita</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2737479/comments</url><from/><name>phillindholm</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Like others on this site, I have warm memories of this film, having
watched it since I was a child. American International did a fine job,
in my opinion, of dubbing the picture. What makes their version of
"Alakazam The Great" for me though, is the truly beautiful score by Les
Baxter (an AIP regular) which perfectly complimented the visuals. A
soundtrack album was released back in '61, which I found 35 years
ago--at a thrift shop in excellent condition. HBO video released a
widescreen videotape of the film about 10 years ago. They did a great
job--wonderful picture and sound. Alas, it went out of print when the
AIP package changed hands. MGM (now Sony) holds the rights. Hopefully,
one day, they will release a DVD.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1273722/comments</url><from>from Boulder City</from><name>redbeard_nv</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Although it's not the spectacle of the greatness of Japanese Anime, the
Western release of Saiyu-ki was a testament to the early days of the art.Alas, like so many classics of animation, such as Toei's "Gulliver's Travels
Beyond The Moon (Gariba no uchu ryoko)" or Nelvana's "Rock &amp; Rule", this
film will never be seen again except on rare, pirated copies, for it has
been cast into the pit of Moritorium Hell, where major video chains
unceremoniously trash the remaining copies into a dumpster without the
opportunity to purchase them to try to salvage history. This disgusting form
of book burning for profits by the major studios that now run the major
video rental chains, leading to the demise of the Mom &amp; Pop stores of the
past will be remembered as corporate greed at it's worst.I hope there is a special Hell for these arrogant suits.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1468830/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>EL BUNCHO</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Over the years, I have seen many reviews that have mercilessly slagged
ALAKAZAM THE GREAT as a bad movie, and it even made it into the highly
questionable book THE 50 WORST FILMS OF ALL TIME. The question I have is:
did all of you who hate this movie see the same film that I did when I was a
youngster? I have shown many children this film over the years and not one
of them failed to enjoy it.ALAKAZAM THE GREAT is loosely based on the Wu Cheng-En classic JOURNEY TO
THE WEST, a landmark of Chinese epic literature, and tells the story of an
arrogant monkey king who learns the secrets of magic and becomes a cosmic
pain in the ass. After a brief rampage through the heavens, he is imprisoned
by the gods and eventually sent on a pilgrimage to atone for his sins and
learn humility. The monkey must escort a young prince (who is the son of the
gods) through a series of insanely lethal adventures in a land teeming with
demons and monsters of every description, picking up a couple of unusual
traveling companions along the way (an anthropomorphic pig-man and a
burrowing cannibal). Much magic and cartoon ass-whuppin' ensues, and despite
the (mercifully brief) musical numbers, this film has raw imagination to
spare. Fast-paced and fun, this is not the dud that some would lead you to
believe. Give it a chance!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2147886/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>pragmatic52</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I agree with EL BUNCHO! I saw this movie at a Saturday afternoon
matinée when I was about 11 years old and I loved it. At that time I
had never seen animation that wasn't childish in nature. This movie has
rather sophisticated themes and it was a real pleasure to watch a movie
that was made for children but didn't talk down to them. I actually
cared about the characters, something I can't say I ever really did
with American animation. This was back when essentially the only film
animation was coming out of Disney and Alakazam The Great had a totally
different style that I really liked. It was also my first exposure to
Japanese animation and created an interest in Japanese culture that I
never had before I saw this movie. It opened my eyes to whole new
worlds. I recommend it to anyone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0216375/comments</url><from>from Jakarta, Indonesia</from><name>shoalin (shoalin@ibm.net)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

I fortunately as a child was able to see this film twice, and the
memories
have out-lasted many of those of the Disney classics that bombarded my
adolescent senses at the same time.  For years I have scoured video bins
worldwide in an attempt to locate a copy of this long last classic, but
as
yet to no avail.  This, in my opinion, is one of the greatest and most
memorable animated films and stories presented to date (that is the
US-dubbed and scored version, for I've never seen the original Japanese
version).  Great characters and animation, awesome moralistic and
quasi-religious end messages, and a just plane fantastic story.  The
depth
is nearly as great as that of the Lord of the Rings Trilogy.  Putting
aside
all the lost cinema gems still kicking around the depths of my childhood
memories, this is the one I would most like to revisit and share with the
children of today.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0552951/comments</url><from>from Olathe, Kansas</from><name>Thomas Merritt Scofield (carolsco@concentric.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This excellent Japanese animated fantasy is an adaptation of the old
Chinese
Legend of the Monkey King.  Having seen the original Japanese version of
this film, I don't have any problems with what American International did
with this film, they have removed most of the religious references, but the
story is still more or less intact, and AIP hired good talent for the
voices.The American score is by film music great Les Baxter, and this is probably
the most symphonic score written for an animated film at the time of its
U.S. release as Alakazam The Great.  Gorgeous stuff, and the movie is lots
of fun for both children and adults, who will enjoy a lot of humor added to
keep parents awake.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0093896/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>Varlaam</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

I loved this movie in the 1960's when it used to play regularly on a
television channel in Buffalo, New York. What a shock when I saw it
recently! The dubbed American version is disjointed and pretty silly, but
that's not the big surprise. It is clear from watching it now that the
Japanese film underlying it is a retelling of part of the epic Chinese
classic, The Journey to the West, written by Wu Cheng-En in the 16th
century. In The Journey to the West -- the standard English translation is
by Arthur Waley -- the monk Tripitaka is travelling to India seeking rare
Buddhist scriptures, which were later housed in the Big Goose Pagoda still
standing today in Xi'an, a city best-known to Westerners for its terracotta
warriors. The monk has many adventures along the way, accompanied by his
friends Sun Wu-Kong / Monkey (here called Alakazam) and Chu Pa-Kie / Pigsy.
Throughout the Far East, these characters are known to everyone and are
fixtures of popular culture. Hot-tempered, impetuous Monkey / Alakazam is
the particular favourite of little boys of all ages. Watch this movie and
try to guess what is actually going on in the Japanese film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2065905/comments</url><from>from New Jersey</from><name>monkeygroin</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

I saw Alakazam first when I was quite young. I thought it was a good
cartoon
then and like it more now. It has a good moral to it and it's not made to
sell toys like most cartoons are made to do now. Comparing it to todays
cartoons is a bit silly since it was made over 40 years ago, the themes
and
characters are much different then the standard anime fluff we see now. I
can't see anyone going wrong renting it and watching it with their family.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1586140/comments</url><from>from Clinton, Maryland</from><name>Barry (Beauceron1)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I can remember getting lost in this Movie when I was about 4 or 5 years
old.
It took me on a wonderful journey. I recommend this for any imaginative 4
to
12 year olds. This monkey is incredibly powerful and has a great lesson to
learn about responsibility (ala, Peter Parker).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17425306/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>thechoirman</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I really did not want to vote on the movie, since I have not seen it
since I was a kid. But, this movie was such a great movie to me as a
kid, that almost 40 years later, I am trying to find it. If this was
such a bad movie (according to the critic), there needs to be more of
them made. The movie had classic good versus evil situations, was able
to teach morals in a very entertaining manner, and was light and dark
all at the same time. I can go so far as to say that it was the
loyalty, friendship, and mercy exhibited by the lead character and his
friends that indelibly burned this cartoon in my psyche all of these
years. I too find that I had no idea that all of these famous stars
were in the movie, but now that I know, when I finally get the movie
again, I will have another reason to love it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17425306/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>thechoirman</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I really did not want to vote on the movie, since I have not seen it
since I was a kid. But, this movie was such a great movie to me as a
kid, that almost 40 years later, I am trying to find it. If this was
such a bad movie (according to the critic), there needs to be more of
them made. The movie had classic good versus evil situations, was able
to teach morals in a very entertaining manner, and was light and dark
all at the same time. I can go so far as to say that it was the
loyalty, friendship, and mercy exhibited by the lead character and his
friends that indelibly burned this cartoon in my psyche all of these
years. I too find that I had no idea that all of these famous stars
were in the movie, but now that I know, when I finally get the movie
again, I will have another reason to love it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17425306/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>thechoirman</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>