<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Home from the Hill</original_title><alt_title>Celui par qui le scandale arrive</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Vincente Minnelli</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Captain Wade Hunnicutt is the wealthiest and most powerful citizen in his Texan town; he is also a notorious womanizer...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Robert Mitchum</actor><actor>Eleanor Parker</actor><actor>George Peppard</actor><rt_rating>8/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0414437/comments</url><from>from British Columbia, Canada</from><name>Dennis Schreiner (batjac@bc.sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I think this is Vincente Minnelli's great unsung film and may in fact stand
as his best. It features one of Robert Mitchum's most perfect performances.
The movie is provocative in terms of its ideas of manhood(some of its
themes, particularly those concerning hunting, are very Hemingway-ish)This
movie also presents a way of living that is today becoming increasingly
anachronistic and unpopular. It is for this reason also that it is so
fascinating - it presents a window to an ever diminishing way of life. Of
course it is first and foremost a melodrama, but this aspect I found to be
often overshadowed by the secondary themes and the little details, like
Robert Mitchum's den (was there ever a room that defined machismo the way
this one does?).  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0112405/comments</url><from>from Putney, VT</from><name>Arne Andersen (aandersen@landmarkcollege.org)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is a well written adaptation of the famous novel about a Southern
family torn apart by the socially unacceptable behavior of its patriarch
and
the resulting tragedies incurred by his offspring because of it.  All
performances are exceptionally fine and neither George Hamilton nor George
Peppard have ever topped these first outings for them both.  Hamilton
reminds one of Tony Perkins here - he would also have been perfect
casting.
He is also reminiscent of Hal Sparks.Mitchum does very well in one of his best roles and although Eleanor
Parker
is not on screen very much, she gives a very fine restrained
performance.The joy of this film is in the writing- all of the characters are somehow
flawed but they are all basically human and likeable because of it - there
are no caricatures, no stock villains or heroes.  The 2-1/2 hour running
time goes swiftly by.Bronislau Kaper's score is one of his finest. The unforgettable main
theme -
a combination of five notes, followed by four - with emphasis laid on the
first note of both sets, is extremely moving - filled with both passion
and
sadness.  It is available on CD from Film Score Monthly's series of
remastered soundtrack music.The only fly in the ointment is the VHS release - yes, this newest one- as
with MGM/UA's release of SWEET BIRD OF YOUTH, they use a pan and scan of
the
CinemaScope image and the print is very fuzzy and washed out color-wise.
The film is so good though, one is only minorly annoyed with
this.Do see it - it's very very well done.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4550143/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>sggar00</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
If you want lampooning small towns with big rich families with tons of
troubles; then you need to be watching "The Long Hot Summer" or "Cat on
a Hot Tin Roof". If you want a good enthralling movie with strong
character acting and a believable story line then this is the one for
you. Having grown up in the South, especially in a small rural town I
completely understand and can relate to this movie. It centers around
what most of my generation had in our small towns, that one rich family
who owned everything. Naturally this movie ratchets up the drama, so if
you are not from this region you may think it unrealistic. Robert
Mitchum is in one of his bests roles as the Cap'n. The troubles and
trials of their marriage spill over into their son's life. Theron's
youthful care free teenage life finally gives way to his budding adult
manhood but somehow is related to the problems of his parents with a
little of his own to throw in. I would recommend this movie to anyone,
its a past gone era of life that I remember so well and well acted.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Home From The Hill though it is located in Texas has the look and feel
of those southern stories made so popular back in the day by William
Faulkner and Tennessee Williams. This is not the Texas of say Giant,
this is East Texas which bares quite a lot of resemblance to the delta
country of Louisiana and Mississippi. And Robert Mitchum's Wade
Hunnicutt is not quite the same kind of local patriarch as Rock
Hudson's Bick Benedict.Whatever else Bick Benedict was he was certainly loyal to Elizabeth
Taylor. Whereas Robert Mitchum's been absolutely notorious for sowing
his wild oats around the whole region. Eleanor Parker stays married to
him, more for the sake of propriety than anything else, and for their
son George Hamilton. Some of Mitchum's good old boy drinking buddies like Guinn Williams and
Denver Pyle send young Hamilton on that southern tradition, a futile
snipe hunt. That little prank actually sets the whole plot of the film
into gear. It's supposed to be women who gossip, but these good old
boys also with some of their locker room gossip that Everette Sloane
overhears that sets the climax of the film going.Robert Mitchum is cast in one of his best roles and it's ironic that he
was a second choice for Clark Gable. I doubt that Gable could have done
better with this part. The always dependable Eleanor Parker matches
Mitchum all the way with her performance as the suppressed wife.George Hamilton and George Peppard got very good roles in Home from the
Hill in the salad days of their respective careers.Though Home from the Hill does veer into soap opera it's held together
primarily by director Vincent Minnelli and by a great cast he
assembled.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2005764/comments</url><from>from Scotland</from><name>BeccaHuffa (BeccaHuffa@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Though not one of its director's best, this film has to be one of the
best
ways to pass a rainy afternoon or dull night.  Robert Mitchum has two
sons:
one legitimate (George Hamilton, who is spoilt and preppy) and one
illegitimate (George Peppard, who is macho and resourceful but also one
of
nature's gentlemen, and lives in a hut with his dogs, waiting patiently
for
a word of kindness from his father).  Mitchum also has a Southern belle
wife
who's locked the bedroom door against him for 18 years.  Simmering
tensions
and overcooked dialogue make this just incredible fun - see it if you
can.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12761012/comments</url><from>from Oxford, Mississippi</from><name>Tim McLaurin (a1416811)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
First, my regards and condolences to those actors, actresses, and the
people involved with the making of this movie, who are still living and
those that are no longer living.Though it portrayed a family in East Texas experiencing many family
issues and situations that were real occurrences of the South, in the
1950's. It was actually made in Oxford, Mississippi. The home of
William Faulkner and was where, John Grishom, graduated from Law
School.I am not a big critic of movies, yet considering the times (the middle
to late 1950's), the audience, and man and woman's role during those
years, certainly, the movie portrayed many aspects that society was
confronted with, especially in the South. It may have been true of the
North as well, yet I have limited knowledge of that area of the
country, during the 1950's.As previously mentioned, I have watched this movie many times, and more
than most, and the reason is, because I was the infant (the baby in the
wedding near the end of the movie). I was only 2-4 months old at the
time of the wedding ceremony. I'm glad they got married!!! I have just
turned 48 years of age and find people are still watching the movie.
There must be something about the movie that keeps people in their
seats.I consider it an 8 out of 10 on the movie scale. It is a movie to
watch, take note of the past, and the interesting changes that have
occurred with man, woman, and family, over the past 50+ years. In
addition to what has not changed, over the past 50+ years.Actually, I think it is a 10 out of 10 on the movie scale, because I
was in the movie, and because they got married, I had parents!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1821331/comments</url><from>from WA, USA</from><name>Hal-900</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
"Home from the Hill" is perhaps a bit too melodramatic but Vicente
Minnelli's excellent direction and the strong cast make it irresistibly
slick entertainment. It is long, but well-defined characters and
unexpected situations, keep the narrative interesting. Robert Mitchum
gives a strong performance in the leading role. Eleanor Parker is great
too (her beauty and elegance are more evident than ever before). George
Hamilton and George Peppard perform well in secondary roles. Curiously,
the high production values (a trademark of MGM) are at odds with the
grim aspects of the narrative - it is a strange combination that works
beautifully. Fans of old Hollywood productions need to check it out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1416505/comments</url><from>from Groningen, The Netherlands</from><name>Boba_Fett1138</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a well made typical genre movie that features some solid
emotions and characters and offers some well written plot elements.It's a coming of age movie but it also is a (melodramatic) family
drama. These type of movies really had been popular in the past and
most of them also are really great ones to watch. Too bad they just
don't make movies such as these anymore. This movie might not be the
best in its genre but it has more than anything other elements in it to
compensate for this.One of them most definitely is the cast. Robert Mitchum once again
gives away one fine performance. The movie also features a great and
still young looking George Hamilton and George Peppard, though Mitchum
on the other hand still looks the way he did 20 years before this
movie.The movie handles all of the genre elements really well and know to
bring it in a good and original way. Definitely a surprising movie from
Vincente Minnelli, who got his fame for directing other type of- and
less serious movies. I especially like the way George Hamilton's
character gets developed and changes throughout the movie, from a
mothers-child to a real adult. It was also great how they handled the
Robert Mitchum character. They make him not-likable but at the same
time also intriguing and interesting enough to not hate him. It's sort
of too bad that they made the mistake to let his character slowly
disappear out of the movie for most of the last third of the movie,
while he starts off as the main character. The movie does a good job at
portraying the relationships between the characters, which is an
essential part for movies such as these.Despite the fact that the movie its story definitely has soap-opera
like dramatic developments in it, you still get drawn in to it, which
is I think due to the interesting characters and actors that portray
them. It keeps the movie real.The movie is set in the South of the United States, which gives the
movie that special kind of- and warm atmosphere. Its sets, costumes and
props all add to this. The time period the movie is set in also
definitely benefits the movie. The movie also has a surprising good and
likable musical score, by Bronislau Kaper.Worth seeing if you get the chance to.8/10http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14265640/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>pennygunter</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I loved this movie! I saw it originally as a teenager and am still in
love with it today. If they ever do a remake of it, I'd love to play
Eleanor Parkers, part! Robert Mitchum was at his all time best, as this
truly lovable yet misguided man of the world. George Peppard can still
make women fall in love with him, 47 years later and I don't believe
George Hamilton ever gave a better performance. Luana Patton was
believable as the scared teenager in love. As a whole, I'd say it was
one of the best movies of 1960, if not of all time. This is southern
life and love at it's best. If you play close attention, you'll see a
lot of older character actors, Denver Pyle, for instance, that make the
movie seem real, as though you were in Texas, living through the
heartache and break with them, great performances by all!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10760500/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lee1888</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a great unsung movie. Robert Mitchum plays the perfect strong
macho father of the fifties. If you're a bleeding heart or one of those
politically correct people, and an animal lover. Stay away from this
movie! When Dr. Phil was going to school, this was required reading on
how not to be a father, mother, son or family for that matter.Mitchum has two sons in this movie. One is by his wife's played by
Eleanor Parker, who is cold as ice to Mitchum affections, and the other
from a woman on the wrong side of town. But she is long dead and we
never get to see her. A young George Peppard plays that son. I think
this is one of Peppard greatest acting jobs.This is a great must see movie if you like hunting and watching a son
being brought up by a strong father and over loving mother. But I'm
afraid you will have to catch it on cable if you're lucky. This film
like many of Mitchum's films are not available on DVD
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10760500/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lee1888</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This is a great unsung movie. Robert Mitchum plays the perfect strong
macho father of the fifties. If you're a bleeding heart or one of those
politically correct people, and an animal lover. Stay away from this
movie! When Dr. Phil was going to school, this was required reading on
how not to be a father, mother, son or family for that matter.Mitchum has two sons in this movie. One is by his wife's played by
Eleanor Parker, who is cold as ice to Mitchum affections, and the other
from a woman on the wrong side of town. But she is long dead and we
never get to see her. A young George Peppard plays that son. I think
this is one of Peppard greatest acting jobs.This is a great must see movie if you like hunting and watching a son
being brought up by a strong father and over loving mother. But I'm
afraid you will have to catch it on cable if you're lucky. This film
like many of Mitchum's films are not available on DVD
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10760500/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lee1888</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/paul-brenner/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Home-from-the-Hill /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1803694</url><name>Paul Brenner</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Minnelli pulls back the stinky underbelly of this Texan-hell family in all his scope splendor</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/minn.htm#Hill /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1748057</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Powerful look at male roles, showing innovative approaches to story telling.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/diana-saenger/</url><url>http://www.reviewexpress.com/review.php?rv=402 /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1577286</url><name>Diana Saenger</name><from>ReviewExpress.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>A great drama enhanced by the terrific performances of Robert Mitchum, George Hamilton, George Peppard and Eleanor Parker.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-nusair/</url><url>http://www.reelfilm.com/vinminn.htm#home /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1577150</url><name>David Nusair</name><from>Reel Film Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/4
					</rating><comment>...just entertaining enough to warrant a mild recommendation.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/home-from-the-hill-4/ /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1546878</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>Along with Some Came Running, it ranks as Minnelli's finest family melodrama, lurid and flamboyant yet also deeply emotional and incisive in its critique of the patriarchal order; Robert Mitchum as the patriarch is superb.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117791721.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1770013</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/derek-adams/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/72165/home_from_the_hill.html /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1518966</url><name>Derek Adams</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9902E7DE143DE333A25757C0A9659C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1389818</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=104291 /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=1147505</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/10055_HOME_FROM_THE_HILL.html /m/home_from_the_hill/comments.php?reviewid=9427</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>