<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Saturday Night and Sunday Morning</original_title><alt_title>Samedi soir, dimanche matin</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Karel Reisz</director><producer>Woodfall Film Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
A rebellious, hard-living factory worker juggles relationships with two women, one of whom is married to another man but pregnant with his child.
</synopsis><actor>Albert Finney</actor><actor>Shirley Anne Field</actor><actor>Rachel Roberts</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
English history has been full of rebel heroes but the screen tradition
really came to fruition during the late Fifties and early Sixties when
England's postwar generation was in revolt… In the theater, this revolt took the form of the "kitchen sink drama"
and the era of the Angry Young Men… In the movie industry, it was the
era of "Free Cinema," an attempt by young filmmakers to break away from
established subjects and standard treatments… This raw melodrama deals with Arthur Seaton (Finney), a working class
young man who rejects the misery and grind of his home and factory, but
whose only possible rebellion takes the form of a cynicism towards
authority and a cheerful indulgence in sexual encounters with various
ladies of the town… His rebellion, though limited, is nevertheless
genuine and the film's situation in a working class milieu is, for the
habitually middle and upper class conscious British cinema, a much
needed step forward...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7537525/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>peter maddox</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
In 1960, in a small Black Country town, I went to see this movie, with
a male friend, at our local fleapit - it was a revelation. I found
myself in a cinema that was a real setting for what appeared on the
screen, for there Albert Finney was, not represented, was the working
class bloke that sat in the picture house near to me.Equally I knew that, on leaving, I would see his aunt (Hilda Baker) in
the local chippy, and that Norman Rossington would be cycling to some
nearby canal to fish. Indeed when Ben (my friend) and I left we went to
our local for a quick pint and, I swear,we both had the uncanny feeling
of being part of the film.Time has passed and the working class East and West Midlands have
change completely so it may not have such resonance for a new
generation but if you want to know what a good slice of England looked
and sounded like in the 1950s you should see it: it's better than any
documentary. Indeed it is a great film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1955998/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Peter Hayes</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The movie that made Albert Finney a star cannot, now, be viewed as
anything more than an a (UK) cinematic gem in it own glass case. At the
time of release it hit the audience like a bomb-shell due to its frank
portrayal of life, sex and double standards in the late 50's.Today some will be puzzled by the dilemmas and themes to the point of
"so what?"Writer Alan Silitoe (from his own novel) quickly draws us in the to
real world of a Nottingham factory worker. This is not the factory work
of normal movies with the made-up hero having a blob of black stage
paint across his forehead; more the dishevelled, sweaty, badly lit
world that he knows from first hand experience.In it we find Finney, smoking and gruff at his lathe. No actor, before
him or after has ever made so much of an impression in a mundane
situation as the ex-Shakespearen actor does here. Reality comes out of
every pore. His matter-of-fact speaking voice, as a voice-over
narrator, should not be underrated either - like someone giving
testimony partly against their will.His world of is one of petite rebellion and cheap thrills. The
"fighting pit prop that wants a pint of beer." He is immoral and the
wife of a friend is seen as fair game: Although the consequences are
beyond his immature mind.There is good supporting performances from British character actors
such as Norman Rossington and Hylda Baker, but this movie belongs to
one man and one man alone: Sir Albert Finney.Twenty five years after he is dead the cinematic world is going to wake
up and realize how brilliant an actor this man was: Like they did with
Humphrey Bogart
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0437504/comments</url><from>from boston, massachusetts</from><name>mike n</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I first saw this film during its original u.s. run in 1961, loved it, and
jumped at the chance to see it again at a local revival movie house. The
movie is justly famous for Finney's brilliant performance (I think it was
his first.), but has other virtues as well.  Karel Reisz and Freddie
Francis
succeed in making the film visually interesting, and it is well paced,
with
essentially no dead time.The thing that deserves the most praise, however, is Sillitoe's script,
which puts virtually all modern dramatic screenplays to shame.  In a
general
way, the working class british films of the late 50s and 60s launched the
tradition that leads to Loach, Leigh, Tim Roth, etc.  This film's subtlety
and ambivalence towards its leading character reminds me specifically of
Mike Leigh at his very best.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0408898/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>DC1977</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Its amazing to look at this film which transformed British Cinema and
introduced the angry young man that would later been seen in films like
'The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner' and 'This Sporting Life'.The fact that it shocked audiences and local authorities because of its
themes covering sex and abortion show that this was a time when a great
deal of change was taking place in British society. Although I wasn't
around then, things must have been changing very rapidly as six years
later 'Alfie' was able to confront these issues full on whereas Karel
Reisz's film merely hints at them.This film also established Albert Finney as a national star and he was
soon to become an international star with the wonderfully bawdy 'Tom
Jones'. Its always interesting to see the films that established the
actors we admire and I'm certainly a fan of Albert Finney so I was
shocked when I saw this film and felt that he wasn't really very good
in it.The opening scene where his character, Arthur Seaton, is counting the
parts he is making in his factory seemed to introduce a highly
overwrought man that shouted all the time. Thankfully the unnecessary
'anger' at the start was toned down later but I still felt at the end
that Finney could have done greater justice to his role.Walking around with a straight back and his chest out, talking twice as
loud as he needs to seemed to resemble an angry old man rather than an
angry young man and I almost expected him to talk about how kids
nowadays didn't know they were born.Its unusual that an actor from a working class background didn't
convince me when playing a character that was not that dissimilar from
himself whilst actors like Tom Courtenay in 'Loneliness...' and
particularly Richard Harris in 'This Sporting Life' did it much better.However, I gradually found myself being more and more absorbed in this
film as it started to develop a storyline and move away from a young
man being angry simply for the sake of it.Rachel Roberts excels in her role as the married woman who becomes
pregnant by Seaton and its a shame that this actress has been forgotten
when you consider her performance here and the marvellous one she gave
opposite Harris in 'This Sporting Life'.Shirley Anne Field also does well as Doreen the girl looking to settle
down and it is in her relationship with Seaton where I disagree with
many people's assessment of the film. Its generally said that Seaton hates the idea of conformity but in the
end accepts it. However I feel that the film is much more hopeful than
that as he realises that love and marriage is not necessarily a trap
that only fools rush into and that there is much more to conventional
life than he had originally anticipated.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13178622/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>st-shot</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Albert Finney is a rebel without a cause in this Kitchen Sink entry
from 1960 that depicts the mind numbing existence of the British
factory worker. Seaton is a hard worker but also a smart ass that rubs
his work supervisor ( who calls him a Red ) and neighbors the wrong
way. He is also sleeping with a co-workers wife.Albert Finney as the surly Seaton is uncomfortably excellent. His
bitter tone and attitude cuts like a power saw. Sooner or later his
arrogance will be rewarded and you can't wait. He does display a tender
side occasionally with Brenda the married woman but the softness is
soon washed away as he rails against the system and his predicament. He
is also a world class beer drinker which makes him even more unpleasant
as he insults pub patrons and takes a nasty fall down a flight of
stairs, only to lie there smiling. Pain is a major source of his
existence and rowdy nights out like this serve in a perverse way to
blunt it.Director Karel Reisz moves the storyline along at a rapid pace
capturing the grim existence of row house living and deafening factory
work. It is a world of gray skies and defeated characters trying to
make the best of what they have. They are not the "Happy Breed" of
generations past.Made in the first year of the tumultuous decade that changed the world
forever Night is pretty tame by today's standards. But in it's day it
was condemned by the Catholic Church for its blatant immorality. One
might venture that it had an influence on John Lennon who wrote
"Working Class Hero" and on many occasions was witnessed to act like
the unctuous Seaton in his life. It might also be argued that Seaton
was a prototype for the futuristic angry young man Alex the Droog in
Clockwork Orange.Betty Ann Field, Hylda Baker and Norman Rossington make up a convincing
supporting cast in ably assisting Reisz in the world he depicts. Rachel
Roberts is outstanding as the tragic Brenda. Smitten with Arthur and
doomed by her predicament she perfectly conveys her situation with a
tawdry lack of glamor.Saturday Night and Sunday Morning may be an unpleasant film but it is a
powerful and important one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1076041/comments</url><from>from Manchester, UK</from><name>shes_dead</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
As James Dean imitated Brando, so it would appear Malcolm McDowell
imitated Albert Finney. At least, McDowell's performance in A Clockwork
Oragne owes a lot to Finney in this. Both characters are undeniably
cocky and brimming with confidence and contempt, and both are highly
entertaining!While not much of a story to write home about - I believe this is
considered one of those 1960's British 'kitchen sink' drama's - this is
however captivating. Finney plays a working class lout, tired of his factory job and always
hoping for more, he goes about his business without care for any
consequences. He swaggers around as if untouchable but soon gets his
comeuppance when he is beaten by two army cadets, one of which is the
brother of the husband of the woman he is sleeping with, who he has now
got pregnant! But he is eventually tamed by the gorgeous Shirley Anne
Field.While I'm no expert at this genre, I can see it's similarity to Ken
Loach films and somewhat akin to (through it's simplicity) David Lean's
'Brief Encounter', though not as extravagant.A nice afternoon film with philosophies that still ring true today
("Whatever they say I am , that's what I'm not." Arctic Monkeys
anyone?). Even if you don't like the story you'll be in awe of Finney's
cock-sure performance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1034079/comments</url><from>from Teesside</from><name>Eric Albert Redfearn (e.redfearn@ntlworld.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is the film which made Albert Finney a star. Filmed on location at
Nottingham, Albert Finney plays Arthur Seaton a bored factory worker who is
having an affair with his workmate's wife (Rachel Roberts). Controversial at
the time because of its references to abortion, this film gives an idea of
what life was like amongst the working classes during the 1950s. Shirley
Anne Field also made her name in this film, but she never really fulfilled
her potential as an actress. A well acted and produced gritty drama which is
still watchable today.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2100394/comments</url><from>from Stoke</from><name>Leigh (leighinstoke)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is one of those types of films that actually lets you forget who the
big stars in it really are (a young Albert Finney) - and just lets you
enjoy
the film for what it is - a classic and gritty British film. I've watched
it
over and over and seen it again today - and forgot how good - and funny
in
places it really is.Director Karel Reisz used his skills perfectly in this - he took places
lit
and furnished as he found them, let people naturally perform and simply
laced together a piece of cinematographic brilliance.People forget that he also directed such films as The French Lieutenants
Woman and produced This Sporting Life, but I personally feel this
masterpiece, amongst his early and sadly rare work was the best by
far.If you've not seen this film and claim to be a fan of 1960s British
Cinema,
you'd better get it into your collection and view it very soon - be
prepared
for some smiles, some laughs, some hard scenes but, overall, a
treat.Enjoy!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0232941/comments</url><from>from London UK</from><name>Britlaw</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Albert Finney's first film is set in the North of England in the late
1950s.
Times are changing as living standards rise quickly and social attitudes
become more flexible - or are they? Whereby, of course, hangs the film.
Arthur Seaton is out for a good time within the confines of his life and
the
film foreshadows attitudes that became prevalent in later
decades.Shot in black and white, probably to give a realstic feel, and the scenes
at
the fairground are particularly good even today.I spotted a street and pub near to my home in London used as one of the
night exteriors, so although some must have been shot in the grim North,
parts of London stood in for Nottingham.The film is short, pithy and refreshing and even if the central character
isn't that nice a guy, your sympathy is with him. British cinema at its
best. 8 out of 10 from me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0232941/comments</url><from>from London UK</from><name>Britlaw</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Albert Finney's first film is set in the North of England in the late
1950s.
Times are changing as living standards rise quickly and social attitudes
become more flexible - or are they? Whereby, of course, hangs the film.
Arthur Seaton is out for a good time within the confines of his life and
the
film foreshadows attitudes that became prevalent in later
decades.Shot in black and white, probably to give a realstic feel, and the scenes
at
the fairground are particularly good even today.I spotted a street and pub near to my home in London used as one of the
night exteriors, so although some must have been shot in the grim North,
parts of London stood in for Nottingham.The film is short, pithy and refreshing and even if the central character
isn't that nice a guy, your sympathy is with him. British cinema at its
best. 8 out of 10 from me.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0232941/comments</url><from>from London UK</from><name>Britlaw</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/helldrivers.htm  /m/hell_drivers/comments.php?reviewid=1926438</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>The thriller is appealing for its no-nonsense approach.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/armond-white/</url><url>http://www.nypress.com/article-20187-brit-noir.html /m/hell_drivers/comments.php?reviewid=1836087</url><name>Armond White</name><from>New York Press</from></reviewer><comment>The working-class personal/political tension leads to a splendidly drawn immigrant characterization by Herbert Lom and the human drama of Baker dangling from a precipice. Both remain memorable.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-fear/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/newyork/reviews/71904/hell-drivers.html /m/hell_drivers/comments.php?reviewid=1777258</url><name>David Fear</name><from>Time Out New York</from></reviewer><rating>
4/6
					</rating><comment>This is the stuff that B-movie dreams are made of, and Hell Drivers does its damnedest to deliver bottom-of-the-bill bliss.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-fear/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/71904/hell_drivers.html /m/hell_drivers/comments.php?reviewid=2025508</url><name>David Fear</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>