<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Seddok, l'erede di Satana</original_title><alt_title>Le monstre au masque</alt_title><imdb_rating>3.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><director>Anton Giulio Majano</director><producer>Leone Film</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
A stripper is horribly disfigured in a car accident. A brilliant scientist develops a treatment that restores her beauty and falls in love with her...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Alberto Lupo</actor><actor>Susanne Loret</actor><actor>Sergio Fantoni</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
A brilliant but overly obsessive scientist has to kill young woman in
order to constantly supply his own beloved female patient with fresh
facial cell structures, since hers was incurably damaged in a nearly
fatal car crash. Nothing really new or innovating here, as this was
quite a popular premise the in late 50's/early 60's European
exploitation-cinema industry. The downright brilliant French milestone
"Les Yeux Sans Visage" launched the trend and also Jess Franco's "The
Awful Dr. Orloff" and Ferroni's "Mill of the Stone Women" revolve on a
similar theme. This dark and mean-spirited Italian production comes out
as very weak compared to any of the previous titles, mainly because of
its cheapness and lack of credibility. The other titles had convincing
and naturally evil-looking mad doctors in the lead roles, while Albert
Lupo in "Atom Age Vampire" more looks like an amateurish clown,
completely incapable of developing breakthrough medical treatments. The
fact that he spontaneously transforms into a hideous monster himself
doesn't really help, neither…In fact, that was rather awkward… Still,
there are some redeeming elements that Euro-horror fans might enjoy:
the atmosphere is sinister, there's some nice camera-work here and
there AND quite a lot of gore and icky make-up art to admire
(especially considering the time it was made and the non-existent
budget!). Too bad these positive aspects can't nearly make up for the
slow pacing and the total lack of tension. The dialogs are sometimes
hilarious although I'm quite sure they weren't intended to be. For
example, can you imagine a doctor saying encouraging words to his
desperate patient like: "Oh my God, your case is worse than leprosy!!"
Overall, I wouldn't recommend this film unless you're well trained in
seeing trashy exploitation junk.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1908551/comments</url><from>from Newfoundland, Canada</from><name>Space_Mafune</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

A crazed Professor Levin goes to rather bizarre and extreme lengths to
ensure his formerly disfigured young girlfriend remains beautiful,
desirable
and under his control.This Italian Science Fiction/Horror epic is really quite silly thanks in
large part due to the English dubbing and likely editing. But the film does
work somewhat on a soap opera level and has some better than average
transformation sequences. Actually it's quite entertaining but not always
for good reasons. Still it was better than I was expecting.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A young singer/dancer has a car accident and loses her good looks to
several large scars on one side of her face. She is soon visited by a
lady with a solution to her facial problem just as she contemplates
suicide with a revolver. The lady takes her to a doctor working out of
a lab in his basement that has come up with a drug/serum that will make
her face all better and supposedly cause the young, beautiful girl to
fall in love with him. Nothing real special here at all. The film is
very Italian and cheaply-made, but it does have some nice camera work
here and there. The acting leads are all hams(prosciutto)and way over
the top in terms of believability. The fellow playing the policeman
does do a fine job amidst the bacon around him! The film has a somewhat
grainy quality and some poorly lit scenes, but atmosphere is created
through the lens. Although the serum must have some component from a
living-turned-recently-dead woman, the scientific premises used in the
film are very big flights of fancy. I laughed quite a bit at the
serious turn the film tries to make explaining that the doctor's work
sprung from his experiences in Hiroshima/Nagasaki. The lines are
uttered with little conviction and carry virtually no plausibility in
them. Though a bad movie in many ways, one could do far worse as a
means of entertaining oneself on a cold evening.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0150803/comments</url><from>from Huntington, NY</from><name>Glenn Andreiev (gandreiev@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

    When the opening credits end on ATOM AGE VAMPIRE, there is a sloppy jump
cut to the opening scene (A bathrobe clad showgirl returning to her dressing
room) This tells us the film has been heavily censored.  This is an Italian
film, being released here in the states.  When somebody opens their mouth,
horrific dubbing, best suited for a bad porno film, takes over the
scene.
     The showgirl (the strangely beautiful Susanne Loret.  She has this hard
look to her face.  With her blonde peek-a-boo hairdo, she resembles a crazed
Veronica Lake) survives an auto accident that scars her face.  In a last
ditch effort, she goes to a mad doctor, who makes good on his promise on
restoring her face.  
     You can probably figure out what happens in this somewhat predictable
sci-fi offering.  The one thing that shines thru the censoring and dubbing
is this movie moves at a rapid pace.  It should be re-made with the same
haunting and disturbing qualities.  
 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Having read comparisons between this movie and Mario Bava's films, I'd
looked forward to seeing it for sometime. It's the story of a horribly
disfigured woman who goes to a doctor for some unconventional
treatments. It seems he has developed a serum that will restore the
woman's beauty. But, the serum must be applied regularly and the supply
soon runs out. As the doctor has fallen in love with the woman, he must
do whatever it takes to get the ingredients to make more serum – even
if that means killing other women.Let's see, comparisons with Bava. 1. Black &amp; white – so is Bava's Black
Sunday. 2. Well, there really isn't a 2 as far as I'm concerned. Atom
Age Vampire makes most other "slow" movies seem like roller coaster
rides. I actually had to wake myself twice and rewind the movie. Also,
while I'm generally one of those people that will defend dubbing in
Italian movies, I can't do that here. This is one of the first times I
can actually say that the dubbing got in the way of my enjoyment of a
movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0372846/comments</url><from>from DVD Drive-In</from><name>Casey-52</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

How many times have excellent European films from the 1960's even up until
the present been ruined by American distributors? Whether it's dubbing or
the
editing room, the European film industry has always been royally screwed
by
us. I think that this film and MANY MANY others have been horribly
misrepresented and misunderstood. Unlike others, this film still looks
good
with horrible dubbing and when it's a badly edited mess. I absolutely love
Susan Loret as the scarred beauty, she is the shining star of the
production. The plot is very common in European films and is usually
pulled
off better, but the film does have potential, it just doesn't meet it.
Anchor Bay, if you're reading, please consider obtaining a European UNCUT
print of this, preferably subtitled so the dialogue can make a bit more
sense. The cheap label ACME Video company offers the movie and the running
time is marked as 105 minutes. This is doubtful, but the tape is usually
only $10 anyway, so you might want to check it out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11238963/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Robert Meade (rmeade@loyola-nyc.org)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Like others, I saw this movie because I am working my way through the
50 Classic Horror Films DVD set. The dialog is sometimes hard to follow
because the dubbing is very uneven. Sometimes the volume fluctuates and
sometimes the dubbing races to sync up with the mouth movements.
Anyway, did anyone else notice that in the American edited version of
the film that someone stole the jazzy soundtrack from Streetcar Named
Desire (Kazan's 1951 film) and inserted it in the background during the
some of the "racy" almost-love scenes between the professor and the
stripper? I'm wondering if this soundtrack was in the original Italian
version or not? Would the Italians have stolen the Streetcar
soundtrack?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0643062/comments</url><from>from Virginia Beach</from><name>tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I don't suppose many people have the time for watching bad movies in
the hope of transcendent insights. If you are one of these, let me save
you some time. This might be on your list.Yes, I know it is yet another cheapo; made in Italy by hacks. It is
even more incoherent now because of heavy censorship and bad dubbing.
And yet, and yet... this has charm in a way because of the way they
assembled the thing. It as if a child assembled the potatohead doll and
put many of the pieces in the wrong place. If they had been in the
right place, the thing would be dull. Wrong place for that ear, hmm,
makes you think about ears, which are curious things indeed.The story here seems simple: a pretty woman in a sex-related trade gets
scarred then falls into the hands of an evil doctor, Frankenstein-like.
Tragedy follows, ending in the standard death: at the end of the movie,
the monster is on the ground. We see his torso diagonally in three
quarters shot. (It is always this pose and angle.) Then we go through a
stop-motion sequence where he is slowly turned back from monster to
human.But between the beginning and end we have a bizarre twist of the
formula. This is not like what Ed Wood unknowingly did, accidentally
shaping the profound out of the ordinary. This is more deliberate and
very much in the mold of the Leone westerns, which consciously
stretches and subverts the genre.The mad doctor is the one who gets the curse here. Usually it is the
girl. If it were an American film, the fact that she is a prostitute
and stripper would doom her. Not so in Italy, she escapes with her
manly sailor boyfriend. The idea that the doctor gets cursed and turns
into a "vampire" is unique, I think. Since this is cinema, he has to
look cursed, so we see horrible scarring. I think this copied "The
Hideous Sun Demon" of the previous year in the makeup and notion of
periodic, radiation-induced scarring (and madness).Sure, the magic here is from radioactive stuff instead of some evil
curse or force. We even have some explanation of the evil American bomb
over Hiroshima, complete with genuine photos of victims. Very strange,
knowing this comes from an Axis power and some of the same production
team used in war propaganda films.If you have the time, very weird, this.Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1234929/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gavin6942</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I've been attempting to watch all 50 films in my 50 Classic Horror
Films collection (a box set putting my total horror collection in a
very high range). But I'm already stuck on number 2, "Atom Age Vampire"
because of what I have heard about horrible editing and a slew of
scenes that were chopped to please Americans censors (the film is
complete in Italy). But if I want to get going through these, I must
watch them all, so here I go again on my own... see you in 2 hours.Okay, the film is not as bad as some make it out to be. Yes, the
editing is a little sloppy. And yes, some parts are chopped out (though
I would never know if I hadn't read about it). But the acting and plot
and everything else are just fine. It's a story of a stripper who gets
disfigured in a car accident (not unlike the car accident in "Carnival
of Souls") and is taken in by a scientist who has invented "Derma 28"
which can cure all skin blemishes and maybe even cancer. As you can
expect fro ma horror film, something goes wrong and hilarity ensues.
There is one big twist in the middle I never saw coming and I loved it.This film is worth watching if you're a horror buff, but otherwise has
little to offer. It works great as a smoking game, not unlike "In the
Mouth of Madness" due to the 20 times that a character talks about
their need to smoke. Strangely, i none scene a man asks to go outside
to smoke when he's sitting next to a man inside smoking. But maybe
that's the polite thing to do. Oh, and there's not a single vampire in
this movie.As I said, recommended for horror fans. Not so much for everyone else.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1274146/comments</url><from>from Tampa, Florida</from><name>dhalgren74</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I got this for a buck as a double-feature DVD with the
grossly-overrated "Carnival of Souls" and was floored by how much
better it was. Whereas Souls has developed a cult following over
virtually nothing (boring heroine, stilted situations, terrible
makeup), Atom is chock-full of moody lighting, a campy heroine who
looks like a drag-queen at some angles, and better makeup FX. There's
also a Sophia Loren lookalike as the mad doctor's assistant, a hunky
boyfriend, and the doctor himself who looks even better in the second
stage of his transformation into a Mr Hyde character. There's something
vaguely O. Henry about the plot, a kind of twist that might be better
played in a remake, but despite the slow points I enjoyed this piece of
trash.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1274146/comments</url><from>from Tampa, Florida</from><name>dhalgren74</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I got this for a buck as a double-feature DVD with the
grossly-overrated "Carnival of Souls" and was floored by how much
better it was. Whereas Souls has developed a cult following over
virtually nothing (boring heroine, stilted situations, terrible
makeup), Atom is chock-full of moody lighting, a campy heroine who
looks like a drag-queen at some angles, and better makeup FX. There's
also a Sophia Loren lookalike as the mad doctor's assistant, a hunky
boyfriend, and the doctor himself who looks even better in the second
stage of his transformation into a Mr Hyde character. There's something
vaguely O. Henry about the plot, a kind of twist that might be better
played in a remake, but despite the slow points I enjoyed this piece of
trash.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1274146/comments</url><from>from Tampa, Florida</from><name>dhalgren74</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/a/AtomAgeVampire.html /m/seddok-lerede-di-satana-atom-age-vampire/comments.php?reviewid=1849625</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>Wretched dubbing and chainsaw edits can't dim Anton Giulio Majano's assorted cinematic aperçus</comment></review></movie>