<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>All the Young Men</original_title><alt_title>Les marines attaquent</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Hall Bartlett</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><producer>Jaguar Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
During the Korean War, the lieutenant in charge of a Marine rifle platoon is killed in battle. Before he dies...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Alan Ladd</actor><actor>Sidney Poitier</actor><actor>James Darren</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0765063/comments</url><from>from St. Davids, Pennsylvania, USA</from><name>SgtSlaughter</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This is one of the few Korean War movies I have seen; I usually stick to my
WW2 interests. Sidney Poitier stars as a black Sergeant amongst a platoon of whites. When
the unit is ambushed, Poitier is the only noncom that survives. He must lead
the survivors to a strategic farmhouse and hold it against overwhelming
enemy forces. To complicate matters, he faces off with a more experienced
Private (Alan Ladd) and a bigot (Paul Richards) as he tries to keep the men
from mutinying. This movie does a fair job at commenting on racism. Although Sidney Poitier
always answers challenges to his authority by threatening to kill whoever
gets in his way, he plays the part quite passionately. This was an early
film to take a serious look at racism; it's a bit clumsy but makes a good
early effort.The supporting cast is good as well; they are given plenty of slow scenes to
make them seem like real people rather than just faceless soldiers. They
include singer James Darren; political satirist Mort Sahl; Ingemar Johanssen
as a Swedish immigrant; Glenn Corbett as the kindly medic; as well as a
Navajo Indian (Mario Alcalde) and the typical scared, green kid. The battle scenes are pretty well done but aren't too original. They
usually involve hordes of Red Army troops rushing the farmhouse and the
Americans dispatching them with grenades and small arms fire. As for complaints: I didn't think the tune "The Saints Go Marching On" at
all fit the bleak mood of the movie. The cinematography shows of some pretty
awesome snowscapes, but looks nothing like Korea. The continuity tends to
jump around during the middle portion of the movie as well -- characters
will be out in a foxhole one moment and the next they'll be inside the
farmhouse chattering away. The ending was somewhat unsatisfying as well. All in all, a pretty decent Korean War flick, most notable for the young
cast of stars-to-be and it's well-meaning efforts to deal with the huge
problem racism in the early 1960s.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16161013/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>JohnRouseMerriottChard</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
During the Korean War, up in the snowy mountains, a marine platoon is
attacked and their lieutenant is killed. But just before he dies he
places the platoon sergeant, Eddie Towler, in charge. Towler is black
and has to get his men to safety amidst racial tension and constant in
fighting.All The Young Men is a Saturday afternoon time filler of a movie. Not
brilliant, but certainly not bad. Sidney Poitier takes the lead role as
Towler and gives it his usual guts and emotional thunder. Alongside
Poitier is Alan Ladd, who at 47 was coming to the end of his career.
Now if one can cast aside that Ladd was a bit old to be bombing around
the snow laden mountains, then his interplay with Poitier is actually
very good. It certainly gives the character's edge, and thus keeps the
picture being the character driven piece it's meant to be.This is no stock war film with blitzkrieg battles and dirty dozen like
shenanigans, this is men holed up in a mountain station forced to win
the battles amongst themselves in order to win the war. Nicely shot in
stark black and white on location at the Glacier National Park,
Montana, All The Young Men is very much a mood piece. Odd then that the
makers shoehorn in some light relief courtesy of Mort Sahl's Corporal
Crane. It's not Sahl's fault of course, but it doesn't sit right in
context with the story. It's as if someone said to director and writer
Hall Bartlett, you can't make an overtly bleak mood piece, put some fun
in there!Still this was one I had a real good time with, partly because of its
two lead actors and partly because of the locale. It's recommended on
proviso that you expect character over action, oh yes sir. 7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This movie benefits from some striking monochrome photography which is
particularly well in evidence during its opening scenes ;these show a
US patrol proceeding through snow encrusted mountains when it comes
under attack from a Communist force .In the resulting battle the
platoon leader is killed and hands over authority to the unit's sole
black soldier (effectively played by Sidney Poitier)rather than to its
most experienced member ,Kincaid (Alan Ladd),to whom the men have
always looked up . Thus racial tension and bitterness are added to the
already fraught situation as the troop must find a place to make a
stand against superior numbers while awaiting reinforcements .There is
a difference of opinion over strategy between Ladd and Poitier and
other tensions between patrol members who include a Native American ,a
wisecracking New Yorker ( Mort Sahl) and a callow youth played by James
Darren who also contributes a forgettable song This is no better or worse than many another "patrol"movie with its
assemblage of stock figures and seems to have been assembled with an
eye to the widest demographic-Old Hollywood in Ladd , a rising newcomer
in Poitier and a pop star(Darren ) for the youth market.Even the race
angle was not new having featured in Home of The Brave over a decade
previouslyGood matinée fare but nothing special either way
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11228318/comments</url><from>from Baton Rouge, La.</from><name>tavm</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
In reviewing movies featuring African-Americans in chronological order
for Black History Month, we're now at 1960 with All the Young Men.
Sidney Poitier plays a marine sergeant during the Korean War who
suddenly becomes the leader of his troop after the lieutenant dies and
makes him so. Only two men seem to really object to him, an experienced
private (Alan Ladd), and a Southern racist soldier (Paul Richards).
Poitier's presence is felt throughout with his best scenes being with
the racist after catching him trying to rape a Korean woman whose house
they're temporarily staying at. Despite his production
company-Jaguar-being in charge, Alan Ladd leaves most of the picture to
Poitier though occasionally he has some good scenes like when he talks
to a fellow soldier about his wife and kid. Most of the picture was
pretty good but the way they ended it with the record of "When the
Saints Go Marching In" playing as the score as they gun down the enemy
struck me as blatantly jingoistic especially as they were making many
of the mixed nationalities in the troop human with many of their
back-stories revealed as they talk to each other in between battles.
Among the other men: comic Mort Sahl using some his amusing monologue
here and James Darren singing the okay title song. All in all, All the
Young Men was an okay war picture that I'd recommend to Poitier fans.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1630029/comments</url><from/><name>Jeff Hill (jeffhill1@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

1960 was an in-between year.   Between Eisenhower and Kennedy.
Between the Beats and the Hippies.  Between Elvis and Fabian.  Between
Korea and Vietnam.  And in that in-between year, there was a grab bag
of rehashed styles in fashion and music.   The 1920's were "in" for a
while and remakes of "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes" and "When the Saints Go
Marching In" became contemporary hits in 1960.   "All the Young Men" is
a grab-bag of a movie, apparently written by a committee composed of
agents and accountants, which tossed in music, themes, topics, scenes,
and personalities designed to appeal to the movie audience of 1960.  To
try to understand the film from any other historical or logical or
artistic or symbolic perspective would be an exercise in futility.  In
1960 we had has-beens Alan Ladd ("Shane") and Richard Davalos ("East of
Eden") marching along the Korean countryside with breaking-the-color-
barrier Sidney Portier, topical night club comic Mort Sahl, new face
Glenn Corbett, and teen heart throb James Darren all to the tune of
"The Saints" which, as mentioned, was an old song during the Korean War
but a re-vamped hit in 1960.
So, although the portrayed drama was of the Korean war of the early
1950's, "All the Young Men" is really a kind of filmed time capsule of
1960 America.  As such, it is a combination piece of nostalgia, a
reminder that 1960 really was a pretty "dumb" time in America, and a
kind of scary reminder that in 1960 America was living in blissful
ignorance of the horror and chaos that was to befall in a few years in
the form of a presidential assassination, counter-culture struggles,
and an eleven year quagmire in Vietnam.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17409002/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>gerdeen-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The U.S. armed forces were officially desegregated in 1948, and the
Korean War (1950-1953) was the first modern conflict in which Americans
of every heritage fought side by side. This less-than-spectacular GI
movie -- albeit with a couple of big names -- is one of the few
instances in which Hollywood has dealt with racial tensions in
"America's Forgotten War."The story, set in the dead of a Korean winter, focuses on a squad of
Marines holed up in a farmhouse behind Chinese lines. The two main
characters are the unit's only black member (played by Sidney Poitier)
and its oldest and most seasoned member (played by Alan Ladd). When the
young black man finds himself thrust into command of his comrades, the
white old-timer is resentful.Poitier and Ladd are the best part of the movie. These two pros have
great "anti-chemistry." They play off each other superbly, portraying a
mutual dislike that has a grudging undertone of respect. When "All the
Young Men" was made, Ladd's star was sinking and Poitier's was rising,
and that gives an added poignancy to their confrontation.Unfortunately, the movie doesn't give Ladd's character any identifiable
racial motivation, however misguided. Instead, the sin of bigotry is
embodied in a lone Marine, a stereotypical white Southerner (played by
veteran TV villain Paul Richards). He's not just a racist, he's
loathsome in every way. This is a cop-out. Institutionalized racism
would never have lasted so long without the acquiescence or subtle
support of many "decent" people.And speaking of cop-outs, why does a movie about racial issues give us
a Korea almost devoid of Asians? The "Chinese" soldiers keep their
faces covered. The main Korean character is played by an Argentine
actress wearing Charlie Chan-style eye makeup. In 1960, this sort of
thing should have been over. (Though the character sounds Latin
American, the movie's explanation of her looks and accent is that she
is half-French. The French presence in Korea was never very great, but
apparently Hollywood was already starting to confuse Korea with
Indochina.)I have to mention the motley crew of supporting characters. The casting
is truly offbeat, with such non-actors as comedian Mort Sahl and boxing
great Ingemar Johansson. James Darren is on hand to carry a rifle and
sing a song, and even Johansson warbles a tune. The least believable
scene in the film (and many are none too convincing) is when
combat-weary Marines laugh themselves silly over Sahl's meandering
monologue about bureaucracy and society. It's the kind of jabber that
would put real Marines to sleep.Returning briefly to the issues of race and realism, the character of
"Chief," who's supposed to be a Navajo Indian, is played by an actor
who looks nothing like a Navajo. But at least he's not wearing eye
makeup.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2721657/comments</url><from>from brooklyn NY</from><name>sol1218</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
***SPOILERS*** Picked off by a Communist Chinese sniper USMC Let. Earl
Toland, Charles Quinlivan, as he's abut to go under turns over command
of his squad to the green and inexperienced in leading men into combat
Sgt. Eddie Towler,Sidney Poitier. The thing that ticks off the men that
Sgt. Towers is now in charge of is not that he's green and
inexperienced but that he's black! And it's now up to Sgt. Towers, who
didn't want the job anyway, to lead them out of the wilderness, or
Communist North Korea, and across the 38th parallel before the Chinese
Communist and their North Korean allies make mince meat out of all of
them!Under Sgt. Towers' command and leadership the men in his unit capture a
key position, a farm house, that's the only place where a battalion of
some 1,000 retreating US Marines can make it to safety and link up with
UN forces to the south preventing them from being massacred by the
Communist forces. It's that position that Sgt. Towers is determined to
hold to the last man grenade and round of ammunition even if he ends up
being killed by one of his fellow Marines in doing it!As the Communist Chinese key in on Sgt. Towers position tensions beings
to build up between him an the Marines under his command. Sgt. Kincaid,
Alan Ladd, who felt that he being in the Corps for 11 years was passed
over in favor of Sgt. Towers never lats him forget about it. Still
Kincaid knows that by bickering with each other will only give the
surrounding Communist Chinese the advantage in overrunning the farm
house and reluctantly takes orders from him. It's the racist Pvt.
Bracken, Paul Richards, who never lets up in letting Sgt. Towers know
where to stay in his place ,the back of the bus or squad, that really
gets under Sgt.Towers' black skin.The both racist as well as horny Pvt. Bracken really goes over the top
when after getting good and drunk on Korean home made wine attempts to
rape Eurasian, half French and half Oriental, woman of the house Maya,
Ann Maria Lynch. It's then that Sgt. Towers who tried to tolerate him,
for the both good and safety of the Marine unit, lost his cool and not
only worked Bracken over but almost has him shot for undisciplined and
un-US Marine Corps conduct! The Communist Chinese using human wave
assault tactics slowly ground down the Marines defending the farmhouse
and it's now up to Sgt. Towers to make the faithful decision to either
abundant the farm house and leave the 1,000 US Marines who need it to
brake through commie lines to their fate or die defending it!The Chinese Communists bringing in their big guns, tanks and amour
units, for a final breakthrough has both Sgt. Towers and Kincaid try to
disable the lead tank with Molotov cocktails, they by then ran out of
grenades, with Kincaid ending up almost roasted alive in the fighting!
Needing an immediate blood transfusion as well as leg amputation to
save his life Kincaid is saved by both the skillful surgery, his in
fact first amputation, of medic Pvt. Wade, Glenn Corbett, and Sgt.
Towers who donated at least three pints of blood-O positive-to keep
Kincaid from going under just like Let. Toland did earlier in the
movie.***SPOILERS*** With what now looked like the end for Sgt. Towers and
his Marines with the Chinese Communist troops making a major assault on
the farm house the US Calvary or USAF finally comes to their rescue. As
the US Air Force saber jets start blasting the Chinese Reds to bits an
elated Sgt. Towers going along with them, as ground support, picks them
off one by one, sniper style, with his sub-machine-gun as they try to
run for cover! P.S The movie also has the then Heavyweight Champion of the World
Ingemar Johansson as recently naturalized American citizen and Swedish
immigrant GI Torgil. Despite his being the champ in real life Johansson
instead of fighting was seen in the film mostly singing Swedish folk
songs to keep the men in his Marine unit entertained!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
All the Young Men is a film about a marine patrol in Korean War where
the lieutenant in charge is killed in the first couple of minutes of
the film. His last words are to tell the sergeant that he's now in
charge, to complete a mission by taking a strategic farm house.Seems natural enough, there's a sergeant who's the next ranking one on
the scene. The joker in the deck is that this sergeant is black, played
by Sidney Poitier. In 1951 the Armed Services were newly integrated and
the civil rights revolution was but a few years off.Poitier has the support of most of the men. Two he doesn't have, the
first is southern redneck Paul Richards and the second is seasoned
marine Alan Ladd. Ladd's the guy who should have been in charge, but
Ladd hasn't the stripes of authority as he's been busted for doing
things his way in the past.The problem with the film is that Ladd just doesn't convey in it that
he is a maverick spirit. We see him doing things in the Alan Ladd
heroic mold and we're never given any reason to see why he wouldn't
still be a sergeant and in charge. His problem with Poitier isn't
racial, but there seems to be no reason for the conflict to be
happening at all.Alan Ladd and Sue Carol Ladd refused to see that he was growing older
and had to transition into character parts. They kept him going in
action films almost to the very end. In this case it was their own
doing as Ladd's Jaguar Productions was a co-producer.Even with an artificial conflict All the Young Men does have some good
moments. In addition to Poitier, Ladd assembled a good cast of young
players to guarantee some box office. Dick Davalos, Lee Kinsolving,
Glenn Corbett and most of all current teen idol James Darren are some
of the men on patrol.Mort Sahl who was the Bill Maher of the 1960s plays the patrol radio
operator and manages to work in some of his monologue from his comedy
act into the film. Definitely some needed comedy relief. And it has an appearance by the then heavyweight champion Ingemar
Johanssen. During that year 1959-1960 he was champion, the Ladds
befriended Johanssen and gave him a brief part in this film. It didn't
lead to a movie career after Johanssen lost the championship back to
Floyd Patterson while All the Young Men was still in theaters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

There isn't really much to be said about this movie.  Poitier gives the only
good performance but nobody can be said to have come out of this effort with
much pride.  The cast is filled with non-actors, including a stand-up comic
and an ex-prize fighter.  The singing is done by non-singers, including the
ex-prize fighter.  And the song after which the film is named is not only
sung poorly, it's poorly written.  The production values are low.  There are
some nice outdoor shots towards the beginning, a snowy mountainous slope. 
The majority of the time is spent in a single indoor set.  And some of the
outdoor shots are thoughtlessly done -- here are these marines dug into the
snow on a hill top and there is neither wind nor smoking breath.  The
obligatory woman is shoehorned into the plot, but fortunately doesn't act as
anyone's love interest; she's there mainly to provide a target for attempted
rape.  The action scenes aren't bad but they conform to every convention in
the book.  The marines occupy an isolated post and must prevent the Reds
from coming through the pass.  They are attacked by about two dozen faceless
extras, all of whom are slaughtered.  They die like flies, building up a big
body count.  Our guys die one at a time, and always live long enough to
utter a few last lines -- "Find that farmhouse and take it," or "Navahos
shouldn't have to die in the snow."  The humor is limited and is provided
entirely by Mort Sahl in monologues and occasional wisecracks.  Come to
think of it, the whole thing reminds me a bit of a Sam Fuller movie, maybe
"Fix Bayonets".  What in-group tension there is, is provided by the
competitive clash between Alan Ladd (looking too old for this kind of
business, but he was a producer) and Sidney Poitier as the sgt. who inherits
command of the unit.  There is also a racist Southern redneck who wises up
before the film ends.  There is no sociopolitical content to speak of.  All
in all, it's not a hateful movie -- there's nothing disgraceful about it --
but you can probably find better ways to spend your time.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
It must have been pretty awful filming this movie at Glacier National
Park. There was a lot of snow and ice as the film makers were trying to
re-create the cold winter in the Korean mountains. The movie is about a
group of soldiers who are cut off from the rest of their troops during
the Korean War. When their commanding officer is hit, he assigns the
black sergeant (Sidney Poitier) to be in charge. The other sergeant
(Alan Ladd) is mad he wasn't chosen and gives Poitier a lot of crap--as
does a racist man in the group who loudly voices his contempt for a
black leader. This all could have been interesting, as the Korean War
was the first fully integrated war for the US. Plus, there was a lot
going on in 1960 regarding racial equality--so the film actually was
dealing with 1960s social issues--not just the Korean War.Unfortunately, the film loses its way very quickly--mostly due to dumb
casting that shows that the film makers really didn't care about racial
issues. Instead, it looked almost as if the film was created by tossing
darts at a cork board filled with ideas! First, perhaps "All The Young
Men" started a small trend in Hollywood casting stand-up comedians in
war films! Here, we have Mort Sahl (a big name during his day but all
but forgotten today) and two years later, Bob Newhart was cast in "Hell
is for Heroes" and a few years later Don Rickles was cast in "Kelly's
Heroes". An odd mini-trend, I know. And, like Newhart's performance,
Sahl inexplicably does a stand-up routine during a tiny break in the
action! I am sure that happened all the time during the Korean War and
WWII!!!! In addition to this dumb casting decision, the film makers
also decided to insert James Darren. Now this alone is not bad--he was
lovely in "The Guns of Navarone". However, like Sahl, the insane movie
producers thought it would be great to have this 1950s/60s teen
heart-throb sing a number as well! Think about it...it's in the middle
of the snow during the Korean War and Darren's character breaks into
song!!!! What were they thinking?! Did they think audiences wanted this
is a war flick?! Who was their audience?! As a result, the film just
came off as fake--as fake as the eyes in the obviously white extras who
were cast as Koreans! The bottom line is that if the film makers didn't
care enough to get the film right, why should the audience care enough
to bother with the film? Plus, there are just a lot more films that
deal with racism without all the superfluous crap tossed in as well! By the way, Alan Ladd appearing in such a film isn't a huge surprise,
as his career was in a downward spiral--partly due to changing tastes
and partly due to his alcoholism.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
It must have been pretty awful filming this movie at Glacier National
Park. There was a lot of snow and ice as the film makers were trying to
re-create the cold winter in the Korean mountains. The movie is about a
group of soldiers who are cut off from the rest of their troops during
the Korean War. When their commanding officer is hit, he assigns the
black sergeant (Sidney Poitier) to be in charge. The other sergeant
(Alan Ladd) is mad he wasn't chosen and gives Poitier a lot of crap--as
does a racist man in the group who loudly voices his contempt for a
black leader. This all could have been interesting, as the Korean War
was the first fully integrated war for the US. Plus, there was a lot
going on in 1960 regarding racial equality--so the film actually was
dealing with 1960s social issues--not just the Korean War.Unfortunately, the film loses its way very quickly--mostly due to dumb
casting that shows that the film makers really didn't care about racial
issues. Instead, it looked almost as if the film was created by tossing
darts at a cork board filled with ideas! First, perhaps "All The Young
Men" started a small trend in Hollywood casting stand-up comedians in
war films! Here, we have Mort Sahl (a big name during his day but all
but forgotten today) and two years later, Bob Newhart was cast in "Hell
is for Heroes" and a few years later Don Rickles was cast in "Kelly's
Heroes". An odd mini-trend, I know. And, like Newhart's performance,
Sahl inexplicably does a stand-up routine during a tiny break in the
action! I am sure that happened all the time during the Korean War and
WWII!!!! In addition to this dumb casting decision, the film makers
also decided to insert James Darren. Now this alone is not bad--he was
lovely in "The Guns of Navarone". However, like Sahl, the insane movie
producers thought it would be great to have this 1950s/60s teen
heart-throb sing a number as well! Think about it...it's in the middle
of the snow during the Korean War and Darren's character breaks into
song!!!! What were they thinking?! Did they think audiences wanted this
is a war flick?! Who was their audience?! As a result, the film just
came off as fake--as fake as the eyes in the obviously white extras who
were cast as Koreans! The bottom line is that if the film makers didn't
care enough to get the film right, why should the audience care enough
to bother with the film? Plus, there are just a lot more films that
deal with racism without all the superfluous crap tossed in as well! By the way, Alan Ladd appearing in such a film isn't a huge surprise,
as his career was in a downward spiral--partly due to changing tastes
and partly due to his alcoholism.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>