<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sword of Sherwood Forest</original_title><imdb_rating>5.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Terence Fisher</director><producer>Columbia Pictures Corporation</producer><producer>Hammer Film Productions</producer><producer>Yeoman Films Ltd.</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
The sheriff of Nottingham plots to confiscate the estate of the Lord of Bortrey, who has died on Crusade...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Richard Greene</actor><actor>Sarah Branch</actor><actor>Peter Cushing</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2350989/comments</url><from>from Yorkshire, England</from><name>csrothwec</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
One of the big disappointments of my then very young life was setting
off with my pocket money to view this one many, many years ago. I was a
terrific fan of the Richard Greene TV series and used to gurgle and
splutter out the theme song from my first conscious days of television
viewing. When I learnt that a full FILM version was therefore showing
at the local Odeon, I was expecting great things. I have watched the
film now about four or five times since as it has appeared on afternoon
TV and must say that my disappointment has still been quite strong
every time I have viewed it! So what is the problem, (or, rather, what
are the problemS)? Firslty, the whole thing must have been made on the
then financial equivalent of 75 pence, i.e. the production values are
STILL those of the TV series and while shaky scenery and a small number
of bushes CAN be taken as a castle or a large forest in a half hour TV
programme, (with a break for commercials), it will not work over one
and a half hours on the big screen. Secondly, the acting is on a par
with the scenery. Richard Greene moves fairly effortlessly from the
small screen to the big, (mind you, he had had quite a few previous
roles in the cinema, such as in the 1939 Basil Rathbone version of "The
Hound of the Baskervilles"), but the rest of the cast, (with the
possible exception of Peter Cushing as the Sheriff of Nottingham), are
quite forgettable and it seems strange that NONE of the "familiar
faces" from the TV series was prevailed upon to appear in the film
version as well. At least it would have provided some continuity and,
presumably, would have made the inter-action between the actors come to
life more than is the case with the film that emerged. Finally, one
hardly expects Marlowe or Schiller in terms of plot development with
this kind of thing, (in fact I doubt if I had any idea of plot when I
first saw the film, probably just waiting more for the next fight
scene!), but, even so, this really is feeble in terms of story and
makes the Kostner and Flynn versions seem like high literature in
comparison. Mix in fairly flaccid direction, poor editing and
continuity and a "bargain basement" music score and what have you got?
Something to view while shelling peas or waiting for the rain to clear
on a Thursday afternoon or, if you saw the 1950s TV series, a clear
reminder of HOW really difficult it is apparently to transfer a TV hit
to one on the big screen. If you want Robin Hood for the LATTER, then
without question it is, (in ascending order of merit), still: Kostner's
"Prince of Thieves", the made-for-TV British version of the same year
as Kostner's, (and which was totally overshadowed by the latter), and,
(of course - you know already, don't you?), the Errol Flynn 1939 film,
(still unsurpassable as a talkie version).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This is Robin Hood without any zest...just plain dull.If you're going to do the Robin Hood story, at least a filmmaker should
blend in all the proper elements that make the legendary story so
popular, as the 1938 film did with Errol Flynn. But here we have Hammer
trying to justice to the tale and unable to disguise the fact that it's
done on a low-budget scale with less than impressive actors in all the
important character roles.RICHARD GREENE would have been a suitable choice if he'd played the
role on the big screen some fifteen years earlier, but he's clearly too
mature (and a bit tired looking) to be the dashing outlaw of Sherwood
Forest and this faulty bit of casting extends to the other roles too. I
never saw the television series starring Greene so I can't comment on
it or make a comparison.It gets off to a dull start with a meeting between Robin and Marian
(SARAH BRANCH) that (as in the Flynn film) has them on less than
amicable terms at first sight. The difference here is that she's been
bathing in the nude before Robin and his men come along but quickly
dresses modestly and has her first rude encounter with the outlaw.There's no "ye olde English" flavor to the dialog--it sounds more 20th
Century than anything else. PETER CUSHING turns up as the Sheriff of
Nottingham who wants a wanted criminal that Robin Hood is sheltering.
He promises Robin a free pardon if he delivers the criminal to him, but
Robin refuses the bargain.Just as well. The Sheriff turns out to be untrustworthy and never keeps
his word. NIALL MacGINNIS doesn't seem rotund enough to play Friar Tuck
but he shows up midway through the film to form an alliance with Robin.
A further plot device involves the Archbishop of Canterbury, but it's a
muddled bit of plotting that seems insufficiently interesting and takes
attention away from Robin and Marian.Summing up: Handsomely photographed in color with some interesting
archery scenes, but a lackluster script and so-so performances do
nothing to make the film anything but plodding and dull. The story
simply has no focal point.Trivia note: SARAH BRANCH's hair-style and make-up looks straight out
of the 1960s--a very modern looking Maid Marian.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13134536/comments</url><from>from Louisville, KY</from><name>Michael_Elliott</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Sword of Sherwood Forest (1960) ** (out of 4) Hammer made their name by reworking Frankenstein, Dracula and The Mummy
but here they try their hand at Robin Hood. Richard Greene plays Robin
Hood while Peter Cushing tackles the role of the Sheriff of Nottingham
but the end results are rather dull. Like their horror films, this film
has the sexuality and violence picked up but director Terence Fisher
doesn't bring anything else to the table. The 2.35:1 aspect ratio makes
for some good looking scenes but none of the scenes contain any energy
to keep the viewer going. Greene is pretty forgettable as Robin and
Sarah Branch as Maid Marian comes off even worse. Cushing is good in
his role and keeps the film from being worse than it is. Oliver Reed
also has a small role.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Hammer studios are, obviously, most famous for their horror films; but
the best of those tend to be the ones that are based on a classic
story, so, technically, this take on the Robin Hood legend isn't a far
cry away from what Hammer do best. Technicalities aside, however, this
definitely isn't one of the great studio's finer hours. The film is
flawed to oblivion, and it doesn't capture that Hammer essence that the
studio's better films did so well. I go into Hammer films expecting a
good time, but this one actually managed to be boring. There's still
some camp on offer, but the story plays out in a way that is neither
interesting nor fun. As usual with Hammer, elements of the story have
been changed; but unlike usual, they've been changed for the worse and
the script fails to deliver a story that even comes close to matching
the original. This is one of the rare times when Hammer would have been
better off simply filming the story that had been doing the rounds for
years before this film was ever put out.The dull and muddled plot follows Robin Hood and his merry men who,
after finding a man nearly dead, take him in. It soon becomes apparent
that the dastardly Sheriff of Nottingham wants this outlaw, and gives
Robin Hood a dubious offer of a full pardon. Robin is having none of
it, and ends up joining in a plot to assassinate someone or other. The
plot isn't overly complicated, but it's not very well handled and
because the film is rather boring, it makes it very hard to follow
what's going on. The best thing about this film is the fact that
Hammer's finest asset, Peter Cushing is in it. Under the direction of
Hammer's most punctual director, Terence Fisher, Cushing once again
turns in an excellent performance and shows that he can make good of
even the lamest material. Oliver Reed also has a small role, but the
fact that the lead went to Richard Greene brings it down. For a start,
he's too old to play Robin Hood; and secondly, he just doesn't have the
charisma to carry the film off. When you're cheering for the baddie
because a better actor is playing him, you know you're in the wrong
movie. All in all - Hammer completists only!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12277105/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>johncfc28</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
I'm a great fan of Robin Hood and maybe being too critical of this film
given its time of making. But it was hard work, it reminded me of a
school play, it was enjoyable purely from a look back at how they used
to do films sort of way. Peter Cushing and Oliver Reed will certainly
have looked back at this film and have a quiet chuckle on how bad it
was and ameteur. I'm trying not to be too critical and let it get away
with being an innocent and OK film but the more i think about it the
more i find myself wandering why i bothered to watch it. I suppose the
reason being that after watching an hour i thought i might as well see
it through. The language sorted of drifted from modern day to olde
English, if its raining and there's nothing else to watch then give it
a go but don't get too comfy or you will drift off.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4999220/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>timsmith37</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is not as bad as all that. Terence Fisher as ever does a competent
job, there are reasonable production values and some rather fetching
photography. I always thought Richard Greene a little too
schoolmasterly for an outlaw, and he is here rather portly, but he can
certainly handle a bow. Nigel Greene and Niall McGinnis are well cast
as Little John and Tuck, Peter Cushing is an excellent Sheriff, and
Richard Pasco does well as the ambiguous Lord Newark. Oliver Reed's
camp henchman is perhaps less successful.The conspiracy plot unfolds at a relaxed pace and resolves
satisfyingly. The weakest element is the tacked on romance with Sarah
Branch's rather bland Maid Marion.All in all a rather charming period piece, that gets closer to the
spirit of the original ballads than most versions.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur27146101/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>aramis-112-804880</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Hammer Film Productions delivered more than great horror. It produced
this (short) movie based on the 1950's television series, "The
Adventures of Robin Hood." Most of the television cast were dumped.
Richard Greene reprises his role as Robin Hood. Little John is Nigel
Green and the Sheriff of Nottingham is Peter Cushing, looking weird in
a mod wig. Maid Marian changed from a brunette on television to a
blonde (Sarah Branch). The one television cast member who is missed is
Alexander Gauge's Friar Tuck; he has been replaced by Niall MacGinnis.Also of note in the cast are Richard Pasco, and a very young Oliver
Reed. Reed plays such an effete character he even affects a lisp.
Derrin Nesbitt, my favorite no. 2 from "The Prisoner", has a small but
pivotal part in this movie as Martin of Eastwood.The amazing thing is that this movie does not try to track Robin Hood's
tale from his outlawry to the arrival of King Richard. This is just one
incident in Robin's life. Robin has to secure a pardon for Martin of
Eastwood so his family can inherit his lands. But the Sheriff of
Nottingham wants the land to revert to himself. There is also a
sub-plot, involving Richard Pasco and Oliver Reed, about an attempt to
assassinate the Archbishop of Canterbury. For a movie of less than
ninety minutes long, it has a lot going on.Though it is not another life of Robin Hood "Sword of Sherwood Forest"
does include the obligatory meeting with Marian. This time, she's
bathing in a river (in a strangely exposed place).But why "Sword of Sherwood Forest" when Robin's favorite weapon is the
longbow? If you are familiar with Richard Greene's Robin Hood, this movie is
worth checking out. The color is gorgeous after all this time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5020744/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>brownish33</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
...and that is looking at the main actress Sarah branch who plays maid
Marian. she is just oh so beautiful and its a shame she didn't do much
acting work, even if she wasn't that great, i thought she was one of
the most beautiful hammer women and i wish she did more films. other
then that, the film like others have said is not nearly on par with
other hammer productions. this was pretty boring and at times just
plain silly. but I'm glad i got to see this for peter cushing cuz he is
always good. i think this must have been one of his few villain roles,
i always see him as the hero. anyway, thats all, worth a watch if you
like these films, which i do.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5020744/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>brownish33</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
...and that is looking at the main actress Sarah branch who plays maid
Marian. she is just oh so beautiful and its a shame she didn't do much
acting work, even if she wasn't that great, i thought she was one of
the most beautiful hammer women and i wish she did more films. other
then that, the film like others have said is not nearly on par with
other hammer productions. this was pretty boring and at times just
plain silly. but I'm glad i got to see this for peter cushing cuz he is
always good. i think this must have been one of his few villain roles,
i always see him as the hero. anyway, thats all, worth a watch if you
like these films, which i do.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5020744/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>brownish33</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/sean-axmaker/</url><url>http://www.seanax.com/2010/05/11/dvds-for-05-11-09-mel-in-the-darkness-daybreakers-are-legion-and-a-quartet-of-robin-hoods/ /m/sword_of_sherwood_forest/comments.php?reviewid=1884661</url><name>Sean Axmaker</name><from>Seanax.com</from></reviewer><comment>Terence Fisher... seems at a loss to make sense of the confused story and weak script, and all thumbs when it comes to widescreen Technology and simple action direction...</comment></review></movie>