<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Jungfrukällan</original_title><alt_title>La source</alt_title><imdb_rating>8.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Sweden</country><director>Ingmar Bergman</director><producer>Svensk Filmindustri (SF)</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Set in beautiful 14th century Sweden, it is the sombre, powerful fable of wealthy land-owning parents whose daughter...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Max von Sydow</actor><actor>Birgitta Valberg</actor><actor>Gunnel Lindblom</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1725295/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Snake-666</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Legendary Swedish director, Ingmar Bergman's probable precursor to Wes
Craven's notorious 1972 shocker 'The Last House on the Left' is a far
more compelling and emotionally draining film that adroitly and
continuously switches the viewers sentiments up until the despondent,
tranquil and haunting ending. While one minute the viewer is laughing
along with the youthful, if naïve, exuberance of the young Karin
(Birgitta Petterssen), the following minute will encourage different
emotions as Bergman plunges the viewer into the middle of a nightmarish
crime perpetrated by nothing less than the evil inside man. Although
the portrayals of the acts committed in 'The Virgin Spring' are far
less graphic than the modern viewer may have become accustomed to, they
still retain an immense power to horrify as one cannot ignore the great
lengths Bergman has gone to in order to give his characters a base in
order to harden the impact of what we see. With just the simplest of
dialogue, the viewer continues to learn about the relationships and
personalities of each of the characters so that we may appreciate the
consequences and, in some ways, forgive the actions that we see. This
film is, after all, a tale of morality and repentance and therefore,
even while in some cases the actions may be evil, it is necessary to
accept the goodness that is still there. This thought is made no
clearer than during the solemn and subdued final scene which fades out
abruptly and leaves the viewer in a state of quiet reflection.Bergman's pacing and subtle direction which at one point leaves the
viewer in suspense for what seems like an eternity is surely the reason
for the greatness of this film. As if he were playing chess, he
manipulates not only the characters, but the emotions of the viewers
with intelligent and surprising maneuvers while pressing home his own
sentiments regarding the story so that we may at least take into great
consideration the events that we have seen. Bergman has an amazing
ability to flip the atmosphere of a movie in a split second using
various lighting and camera angle techniques as well as motivating his
performers to follow suit. The simple expression changes on the faces
of Birgitta Petterssen, Max von Sydow, Birgitta Valberg and Gunnel
Lindblom at various points throughout the film quickly alter the
mindset of the viewer and indicate that all is not well; so beautiful
in undeniable simplicity.'The Virgin Spring' is nothing short of a masterpiece and a film that
few will be able to forget. 9½/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2879105/comments</url><from>from Somewhere in Europe</from><name>BlueGreen</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
... and that's about all I can SAY about it. I saw this film four,
maybe five years ago. And to this day, I feel a blow to my gut whenever
I remember it. To this day, it haunts me - especially (and not
surprisingly) the figure of the little boy. This is a raw, uncompromising, unbiased parable on love and revenge; on
humanity. It is set in 14th century Sweden - but its "message" is
timeless: as timeless as love and vengefulness themselves. As timeless
as humanity itself. Because the mores may change, but today, as 800
years ago, people are still helpless in their (perhaps inevitable) core
existential ignorance, still subject to the immense pain of losing a
loved one, of the inexplicable torments that often befall just and
righteous, "good" people. And that is what makes this a brutal, heartrending, unforgettable film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7218116/comments</url><from>from Taiwan</from><name>rowan_h</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I have to agree with the previous comment, this is certainly a sad film
I would go further, it's actually a grim little tale. Bergman pulls no
punches, the medaeval world he shows is a hard, harsh, bleak place.
There is a sense of menace in almost every scene and the actual rape is
graphic and nearly unwatchable. The characters are not finely drawn,
but after all this is a fairy tale in the older mould. They are there
to represent types and conditions. The sad, doting mother; the
unbending Christian gentleman; the flawed cleric; the ferocious,
deceitful rapist-murderers. The tale on one level is very simple and
can be simply followed; jealous sister curses more favoured sister,
favoured sister is cruelly killed, killers ironically claim refuge of
her father, father exacts revenge on them. So far we have something
that could have come out of many a European ballad tradition. However,
on another level it contains fundamental comments on humanity and human
behaviour, Christian moral theology and our reaction to it. The
father's faith is tested, he is not the man he thinks he is and his
religion is not what he thinks it is either, though he submits and
adopts a position of blind hope. The killers represent the complete
absence of good that Aquinas maintained was the definition of evil. The
young brother is the pain of conscience. In many ways it is a play on
the deadly sins, apart from gluttony they are all there; wrath on the
part of the father and pride in his daughter; envy in the half-sister;
lust and avarice in the herdsmen and so on. It is truly an exemplary
tale, as a medaeval legend should be. I bought this film casually at a
street stall in Taipei for an absurdly small amount of money and it lay
on a shelf unwatched for quite some time. In a bored moment one night I
slipped it in the player and found myself enthralled until the finish.
The cinematography, of course, is excellent but the joy is the dark
threat that filigrees it, the simple but powerful emotions both quietly
and violently displayed. It lacks the grandeur of "The Seventh Seal".
It's a smaller and more compact number but it some ways the better for
it, the evocations are more direct and the violence unnerving. I
recommend it very highly indeed, you will be thinking on its themes
long after this simple little tale finishes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0223437/comments</url><from>from Brocktroit, Massatucky</from><name>Merely</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Brilliant, tragic, heartfelt story that will move all who see it...and it
certainly is a must for anyone serious about film. I originally wanted to
see it because I admire the work of Max von Sydow. Acting, directing,
story,
cinematography simply flawless. Haunting and superb.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2188681/comments</url><from>from usa</from><name>postmanwhoalwaysringstwice</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Sometimes Bergman's films, though full-fledged masterpieces (I AM NOT
DISCREDITING HIM), are visual expressions seen with the screen as a wall
between the viewer and the characters. I think that wall was taken down
with
"The Virgin Spring". Here he tells an emotionally intense story at the
perfect pace with perfect pitch. No matter how horrific the occurrences on
the screen, this film has been created with such an aesthetically
appealing
touch that the dichotomies and balance Bergman works towards is evident.
Terrific!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0540993/comments</url><from/><name>Gary</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Pauline Kael (who she? They cry in unison) denounced this stunning film as
revolting and the subject matter is harrowing and explicit for it's day.
Just because it is, doesn't mean the story, although a legend; is not worth
telling. The murdered girl is just like a dear friend of mine so it's
particularly distressing to sit through. I can see where Tarkovsky got his
floating pollen from, or maybe both he and Bergman were influenced by
Dreyer. Great scenes include the guilty boy staring up at the stars while a
grandfather torments him with a speech about conscience and the cruelty of
the heavens, and Sydow's stabbing of one of his daughter's killers. It
happens unsparingly in front of the camera, and is absolutely searing and
indelibly imprints itself upon the memory, as it shows the slow, hard
reality of taking a man's life from him. Sydow is also superlative after he
has killed the child and stares down at his hands, unable to reconcile them
as being his own. He brilliantly conveys a man who expected to be rewarded
for his virtuous life in service of the lord and his bitterness over God's
perceived betrayal. Or is it about betraying ones self?Bergman admitted that the ending with the spring was somewhat tacked on and
over didactic, even bogus, as he had already said what he had wanted to say
on the matter of religion in previous films and that the matter was 'closed'
in his mind to a certain extent. Perhaps this is why Kael questioned whether
the film really needed to exist. I can't answer that one but it is a film of
authority and power which makes you question what you would do in similar
circumstances, and how you might reconcile your actions with your faith.
Leaving aside the religious issue, which Bergman does appear to be half
hearted about, it unquestionably sides itself with the need for forgiveness
and the moral duty to do good. Recommended, and great performances.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1098460/comments</url><from>from Virginia, USA</from><name>Galina</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Based on the 14th - century Swedish legend, "Virgin Spring" is a moving
and haunting tragic story about a young girl who was raped and killed
while on the journey to the church. The killers unknowingly asked for
the shelter at her parents' house... One of three was a young boy who
only watched the crime.Max von Sydow gives one of his best performances as an outraged father.
Ingmar Bergman and his genius cinematographer Swen Nykwist
reconstructed the medieval world full of realities and life, stunningly
beautiful and deadly dangerous in the same time. Certainly a
masterpiece and one of my favorite Bergman's films after the repeat
viewing. Powerful simplicity.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3270789/comments</url><from/><name>ma-cortes</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
The picture is developed in Sweden,during the Dark
Ages,14th-century.This the story about a young naive virgin named
Karin(Petterson)who's sent by her parents(Max Von Sidow and Birgitta
Valverg)towards a church to hand over a candles for the holy
Virgin.She's accompanied by Inger(Gunner Lindblon),a pregnant and
envious young.They encounter a group peasants and the young virgin is
cruelly raped(whose images in some countries were classified R).Later
the killers ask for help and shelter from the parents.The movie displays haunting and powerful scenes,it's plenty of images
which stay forever in the mind.Although sometimes is slow moving
,however the thoughtful screenplay is narrated with intelligence and
sensitivity but are developed ethics and moral issues like as
death,God,religion and the vengeance.The movie realizes an excellent
Sweden reunion actors with usual Bergman's players( Sidow and Lindblon,
among others),showing the different characters and exploring their
apprehensions,ambitions,fears and circumstances.Glimmer and riveting
cinematography by Sven Nykvist(won an Oscar for Fanny and
Alexander),he's deemed by many to be one of the world's greatest
cameraman,he achieved give the movies on the most natural and simplest
look imaginable,he replaced to Gunner Fischer(The seventh seal) as
Bergman's cinematographer.He continued an American career working for
Lois Malle(Pretty baby),Bob Fosse(Star 80),Kauffman(The unbearable
lightness of being) and Woody Allen(Another woman,Crimen and
misdemeanors).The Virgin spring is wonderfully directed by Bergman,it's
a real masterpiece who made his major impact gaining international
acclaim and winning an Oscar for foreign film and a Gloden Globe.His
realization was during an impressive golden period from 1957-1968 when
Bergman(recently deceased)made a stunning masterpieces: The seventh
seal,Persona,The communicants,The silence,Hour of wolf.Rating:
Magnificent,but is considered by many(along with The seventh seal) to
be the Bergman's best.And please to forget the horrible and ¨Sui
generis¨ version made by Wes Craven titled ¨The last house on the
left¨.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15296172/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>esoderberg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The murder scene...I occasionally show this movie to my tenth graders;
when I first did, I hesitated: these kids have been raised on slasher
movies, I thought; they're going to think the murder scene is lame. No,
not a problem. Even with no splashing blood, or background music, or
extravagant muscle...they are silent and horrified. And it seems to
me--but I've never been sure--that you can actually hear the second
herdsman's spine snap, when Tore has him in that terrible bear hug.Re the scene where Karin's body is left abandoned. It begins to snow.
One of my most insightful students once commented on that: "the virgin
isn't a virgin any more, and spring is over." Finally: when my advanced
classes discuss the effectiveness of restraint, I bring up the scene
where one of the herdsmen offer's Karin's clothes to Mareta. No
swelling background music; she doesn't scream, or faint; but says "I
must ask my husband what a fitting price would be for such a valuable
garment." Brrr.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3441650/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>JoeKarlosi</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Now, this was a true work of art. A quietly designed yet devastating
story of a religious Medieval family and how their faith becomes
challenged when their young daughter is brutally raped and murdered by
three derelict brothers. Max von Sydow plays the father who is a
God-fearing believer, yet finds himself overcome by his own sweet
desire for revenge against those who wronged his little girl.I am happy to say I appreciated Ingmar Bergman's genius just by this
movie alone. It's a visually beautiful piece to look at, but also with
a story and strong convictions. So much is said without really needing
to go overboard. I can see there is a recurring theme in his work where
he questions the existence of God, or at least the complicated ways in
which God works things out on Earth. I'm not sure whether Bergman was a
full-blooded atheist or not at this point but I'd suspect he was at
least a questioning agnostic. I'm sure this is partly why Woody Allen
is so enamored with the director, as a similar religious thread runs
through some of Allen's own movies. For the record, I am a strong
believer in God, though these days I too have been faced with personal
issues which have had me having difficulties in understanding, much
like the father of THE VIRGIN SPRING. So this movie also touches a
personal nerve within me. The performances here are all first-rate,
with a special nod to Birgitta Petterson as the friendly and generous
young woman who we take an instant liking to, but becomes the victim.
What more can I say? An exceptional and deeply-moving film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3441650/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>JoeKarlosi</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Now, this was a true work of art. A quietly designed yet devastating
story of a religious Medieval family and how their faith becomes
challenged when their young daughter is brutally raped and murdered by
three derelict brothers. Max von Sydow plays the father who is a
God-fearing believer, yet finds himself overcome by his own sweet
desire for revenge against those who wronged his little girl.I am happy to say I appreciated Ingmar Bergman's genius just by this
movie alone. It's a visually beautiful piece to look at, but also with
a story and strong convictions. So much is said without really needing
to go overboard. I can see there is a recurring theme in his work where
he questions the existence of God, or at least the complicated ways in
which God works things out on Earth. I'm not sure whether Bergman was a
full-blooded atheist or not at this point but I'd suspect he was at
least a questioning agnostic. I'm sure this is partly why Woody Allen
is so enamored with the director, as a similar religious thread runs
through some of Allen's own movies. For the record, I am a strong
believer in God, though these days I too have been faced with personal
issues which have had me having difficulties in understanding, much
like the father of THE VIRGIN SPRING. So this movie also touches a
personal nerve within me. The performances here are all first-rate,
with a special nod to Birgitta Petterson as the friendly and generous
young woman who we take an instant liking to, but becomes the victim.
What more can I say? An exceptional and deeply-moving film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3441650/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>JoeKarlosi</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>