<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Brides of Dracula</original_title><alt_title>Les maîtresses de Dracula</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Terence Fisher</director><producer>Hammer Film Productions</producer><producer>Hotspur Film Productions Ltd.</producer><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
Vampire hunter Van Helsing returns to Transylvania to destroy handsome bloodsucker Baron Meinster, who has designs on beautiful young schoolteacher Marianne.
</synopsis><actor>Peter Cushing</actor><actor>Martita Hunt</actor><actor>Yvonne Monlaur</actor><rt_rating>6.2/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>71</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0366508/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Joe Stemme (gortx)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Certainly, one of the oddest successes for Hammer. Determined to make a
sequel to HORROR OF Dracula, but with a lead character turned to dust
and an actor refusing to be 'typecast' (Christopher Lee), the film
still manages to be one of the best "Dracula" films (as well as one of
Hammer's of the era).Set up with a narrated prologue (sublimely eerie photography) that
explains that Dracula has left a 'cult' legacy behind, BRIDES picks up
with a gorgeous French woman (Yvonne Monlaur) who is passing thru (does
one pass thru Transylvania??). From there she meets a Baroness (Martita
Hunt) who takes her in for the night. That night the young woman
unwittingly lets loose her son the Baron (David Peel). Peel is, of
course, a Vampire. It's at this point that Dr. Van Helsing (Peter
Cushing) enters the scene and so the story is set up. BRIDES OF Dracula has two main points of interest. First, the truly
creepy Oedipel relationship of the Baron and his Mother (if one thinks
about it, the Mother is one of the title 'Brides' - someone call
Dr.Freud!). There is also the overly protective Housekeeper (Freda
Jackson) who thoroughly abets The Baron and his Brides upon his
'release'. Second, there's Peter Cushing's magnificent performance as
Van Helsing. In only his second time out in the role, he thoroughly
owns it - and comes to dominate the picture. What's also amazing is
Cushing's physicality. While there no doubt are some stunt double
shots, the majority of the action scenes are clearly handled by the
actor himself. Something that too often is over-looked when commenting
on the nearly always reliable character actor.A couple of quibbles. Since Vampires can change into bats, why can't
the Baron escape a human sized shackle? And, since the Housekeeper is
so smitten with him, why doesn't she release him herself? One could
search and ponder why the script doesn't address these issues, but I
believe the simple matter of fact is that they just weren't thought
through. The film works quite well, nitpicks aside.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2982137/comments</url><from>from Edinburgh, Scotland</from><name>ian-433</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Probably Hammer's best horror, even though it doesn't have Christopher
Lee.
But David Peel is equally formidable as an aristocratic young disciple,
and
Peter Cushing's Dr Van Helsing is still the scourge of vampirism in
Victorian Europe.It begins with a wonderfully spooky tracking shot over a misty woodland
lake
(actually Black Park next to Pinewood Studios) and ominous narration
(`Transylvania, land of dark forests, dread mountains and black
unfathomable
lakes.  Still a place of magic and devilry as the 19th century comes to a
close.').  Hammer gothic depended heavily on photography for mood and
Jack
Asher lit their early horrors masterfully, but the always
budget-conscious
studio let him go as his often exquisite set ups took to
long.Pretty Parisian Marianne Daniel (Yvonne Monlaur), en route to her first
teaching appointment in a Transylvanian finishing school, is lured into
spending a night at the forbidding Chateau Meinster by its haughty
Baroness.
Explaining away the extra dinner place set by servant Greta, the
Baroness
says it is for her absent son, `feeble-minded' and locked away in another
wing (`We pray for death, both of us.  At least, I hope he prays.').
When
naïve young Marianne lets Meinster out, Greta cackles in demented glee as
a
wolf howls into the night (`There's a wolf down there.  And an owl.
He'll
get them all astir, trust him.').It all comes together in Brides of Dracula.  Script, characterisation and
acting (Cushing, Peel, Martita Hunt as the Baroness, Freda Jackson as
Greta
all splendid; even the comic turns - the inimitable Miles Malleson as a
sceptical country doctor and Henry Oscar as pompous schoolmaster Herr
Lang -
are just perfect).And its horrors, as directed by Terence Fisher, are sudden and violent.
Bitten by Meinster, Cushing purges the wound with a red-hot branding
iron,
doused by holy water.  But perhaps the single most macabre moment Hammer
has
ever devised is the scene where Greta sits astride a new grave like a
hellish midwife, urging Meinster's latest victim to rise out of her
coffin.Can Cushing save the village daughters from a fate worse than death?  The
stakes are high!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Dracula is dead, and one of his disciples carries on his wicked ways in
Eastern Europe.  This time around it is the young Baron Meinster(played with
credibility by David Peel).  A young woman is invited to the Castle Meinster
and unleashes the Baron from his shackles to allow him to slake his thirst
through the living.  This film lacks the star power of Christopher Lee in
Hammer's second vampire outing, yet does not suffer greatly due to the
wonderful performance of Peter Cushing reprising his role as Dr. Van Helsing
and the incredible direction of Terrence Fisher.  Fisher's ability to tell a
story through film is not to be overlooked, nor is his use of subtle and
bright colours to create wonderfully atmospheric sets and scenic
centerpieces.  Some of the scenes in this film are some of the best to ever
come by way of Hammer, including the scene where a servant taps on a buried
coffin to show a fledgling vampire the way, the incident with Van Helsing
and his wound, and the windmill finale.  The cast is very good with
particular honors going to Cushing, Martita Hunt as the vampire's
sympathetic mother, and Freda Jackson as the demented, crazed servant-nurse.
 Cushing is as ever implacable from his crusade to save the world from
vampirism.  Just a wonderful tale!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0943351/comments</url><from>from West Hollywood, CA USA</from><name>csdietrich (csdietrich@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Oedipus complex transposed to the vampire myth yielding two unforgettable
performances given by David Peel and Martita Hunt. A true pity Peel
preferred stage to screen acting (he also interpreted the role of DORIAN
GRAY on vinyl), he embodied a Victorian persona yet was handsome, fetching
and Wildeian. The classic status of this Hammer Film is yet another of the
Cushing/Fisher collaborations though Peel's groundbreaking performance is
rarely singled out. His most unusual portrayal of the vampiric disciple
Baron Meinster is one of the finest in Hammer's canon. Breathtaking set
design, atmosphere and mood place this film the rationale for Hammer's
reputation, the equal of HORROR OF DRACULA. The homoerotic cycle of
vampirism beginning with DRACULA'S DAUGHTER is made complete here which
perhaps influenced Anne Rice and her body of work. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0732762/comments</url><from>from Bayonne, NJ</from><name>modrock62</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is my favorite Hammer Film! Wonderfully written, superbly acted! Peter
Cushing is a joy to behold as the "not always playing with a full deck" Van
Helsing. His memorable scene in which he exsises the vampires bite from his
neck is brilliant! The set pieces and atmosphere are second to none and
gives the film an entirely uneasy feeling yet the movie is so brezzy and
fun! There are also quite a few chilling scenes which will stick out in your
mind for a while after the conclusion. And what a conclusion it is! Fast
paced, exciting and quite unique in vampire lore. David Peel is unique to
say the least as the king vampire and although Dracula is not to be found in
this one, SO WHAT!!! A brilliant film on all counts!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0178741/comments</url><from>from Oakland CA</from><name>funkyfry</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"The Brides of Dracula" is one of the best films produced by the
legendary "Hammer House of Horror" during the British studio's heyday
in the late 50s/early 60s (IMHO Hammer Films' decline began when they
made a distribution deal with Fox's Seven-Arts division). In fact only
a small handful of color horror films made by any company would really
compare to this Gothic delight. That's not to say that the film
actually achieves the kind of cultural or social relevance that some
later vampire films (i.e. the mis-leadingly titled "Bram Stoker's
Dracula") tried in vain to reach for – on the contrary this film's
goals are simple and easily achieved by the excellent craftsmen who
designed and created this film. They were simply trying to make a film
that was sexier, more violent and grotesque, and more visually
arresting than the original "Dracula" film from Hammer – but this time
without Christopher Lee and indeed without "Dracula" himself. I'm happy
to report that, like the film's intrepid Van Helsing (Peter Cushing),
they did not accept failure or compromise. Of course that's not to say
that "no expense was spared", but rather to emphasize that in these
early days the Hammer artists and technicians were still carefully
keeping the camera lens focused on the best aspects of their production
– in this case lovely Yvonne Monlaur, some well-dressed Bray Studios
interiors, a memorable exterior windmill set-piece, and yet another
unforgettable protagonist courtesy of the great Peter Cushing.Hammer's best films are a model of efficiency and economy, and this
film definitely looks a lot better than it should. Great credit should
be given to director Terence Fisher (who directed many of Hammer's best
films, including "Revenge of Frankenstein", "The Devil Rides Out" and
the original "Dracula") but perhaps even moreso to photographer Jack
Asher and art designer Bernard Robinson. The departure of Asher and
Robinson in later years was yet another cause of Hammer's decline, and
the reason why they were so essential is evident in this film's
sometimes breathtaking designs. The sets are so intelligently designed
and so well-lit that you really don't even notice how cheap they are –
not only that but they add a lot to the experience of the film by
affecting the audience's mood in overt ways. I love the splashes of
deep purple in the background when Van Helsing enters the windmill, for
just one example. The film uses a consistent red color scheme to infuse
everything with the psychological association of blood and
blood-letting. This effectively emphasizes and exploits the fetishism
associated with that color and the sensual qualities of the color red.That's just the first of many fetishes lightly touched upon in this
work, though of course it's all done in good taste. Obviously the blood
fetish is most pronounced, and the film-makers have done an admirable
job of using color film to enhance the appeal in this regard – when we
do actually see blood on screen it's in small quantities and very
effective. The vampire theme is more explicitly associated with
homo-eroticism in this film than in any previous horror film I've seen.
This became more and more explicit as the Hammer horror cycle
progressed, perhaps reaching its zenith in "Frankenstein Created
Woman". Here we have both female and male homo-erotic scenes as well as
a strong implication of incest between the vampire (David Peel) and his
mother (Martita Hunt). In fact Peel is a far more sensual vampire in
general than anything I've seen in previous films, highlighted by his
light blonde hair and soft features. This makes him a strong contrast
to Christopher Lee's animalistic portrayal of the vampire in the first
Hammer Dracula film. It was great near the conclusion when Peel emerged
with those chains and the look that Cushing gave him…. Oh boy! Van
Helsing was in serious danger of being the victim of some
sado-masochistic "fun" and he was definitely NOT into it! In fact I
think other than the great photography and visual style of the movie in
general Cushing is it's greatest strength. He is very adept at
modulating the level of energy in his performance, and in this film he
achieves a steady escalation of emotion and intensity. He starts out as
the very dry scholarly type and slowly reveals how deep and emotional,
indeed spiritual, his feelings about vampirism are. By the end of the
film he's in full action-hero mode, and I found myself clapping and
cheering out loud as he put all his impressive physicality on display
to vanquish the blood-sucker. Peter Cushing appeared in a lot of bad
movies, and usually manages to make them worthwhile. So when he appears
in a good role in a good film, it's really something that shouldn't be
missed, and something that fans can enjoy again and again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2951437/comments</url><from>from Mountains of Madness</from><name>fertilecelluloid</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Entertaining non-Christopher Lee vampire flick from Hammer and genre
stalwart Terence Fisher. A beautiful young woman (Yvonne Monlaur) is
sucked into the world of the undead by a handsome vampire (the
excellent David Peel) who takes advantage of her kindness. This outing
focuses on the cursed Meinster family and never mentions the word
"Dracula". Peter Cushing crashes the vampire party and is in top form
as he races around trying to prevent Mr. Peel from turning every pretty
woman within earshot into one of his brides. In one silly scene, Peel
proposes to Ms. Monlaur, whom he hardly knows, and seconds later she's
accepted his offer. The climax at an old mill is rich in atmosphere and
invention (note how Cushing locates a cross big enough to do in the
bloodsucker), and the parade of lovely ladies is a fine sight. This is
an engaging Hammer production filled with mostly great performances and
classic vampire situations.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1683802/comments</url><from>from The Void</from><name>suspiria10</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Baron Meinster (David Peel) picks up where Christopher Lee's Dracula
last left off. The Baroness Meinster (Martita Hunt) has an interesting
little scheme working for her, she plays the evil little spinster while
picking up to stray ladies to feed to her vampire son. The Baroness
tries to keep him safe at the castle by locking him up but when he puts
the moves on a lovely French school teacher passing through to her
destination. Only one man can rescue the countryside and that man is
Dr. Van Helsing (Peter Cushing}.Peel is an interesting choice as the lead vampire. Handsome and
charming he's basically the complete opposite of Chris Lee's Dracula.
He also lacks the intensity but at least Cushing pops in to pick up the
slack. The production design is on par with nearly all Hammer
productions. You may say that their films are a bit stuffy but I say
that is part of their charm. The company made Gothic horror and they
did it well.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A disciple of the famed blood sucker seeks new life extending elixir in a
private school for girls. Very entertaining. Great atmosphere. Outstanding
performances from David Peel, Martita Hunt and the always impressionable
Peter Cushing. Above average vampire flick.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19981632/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Alias_De_Large</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Hammer's 'Brides of Dracula' is a film fraught with irony. In the very
first scene, we see what is apparently a corpse that tuns out to be a
log, then we meet a handsome and debonair man who is in fact a fiendish
vampire who clearly had several skeletons in his closet even before
becoming a vampire, it is reflected in how the character we are
expected to consider the villain at first is in fact the most harmless,
it is reflected in how a woman who wishes to be the vampire's bride
ends up becoming his bride in the worst way possible. Most ironically
of all, it is also reflected in how this is probably the best vampire
film Hammer ever made, and despite the title; Dracula is nowhere to be
seen, but that doesn't stop this film from becoming a first rate
chiller.While traveling through the Transylvanian countryside to her new job; a
young french student-teacher named Marianne(Yvonne Monlaur)'s coach is
stolen after a highwayman bribes the driver, and she is stood up by the
villagers, but finds temporary refuge in the castle of the mysterious
Baroness Meinster(Martita Hunt)and her creepy maid Greta(Freda
Jackson). It becomes clear that the Baroness is not quite sane, and
apparently madness runs in the family as she keeps her purportedly
insane son locked up in another room and chained. Marianne spots him
from the balcony across the court yard, and visits him; finding him to
be a handsome and sophisticated man; Baron Meinster(David Peel; who
looks like he's in his late teens, very similar to Robert Pattinson of
'Twilight', in fact, but was apparently in his mid 40's!)who has been
kept prisoner so his mother could inherit the land. In a suspenseful
scene, she steals the key that keeps him chained, only to discover
after releasing him that she's made the biggest mistake of her life.
It's Dr. Van Helsing(Peter Cushing)to the rescue!The plot is extremely simple, so there's no use going into detail, but
what makes the film stand out is it's vividness. The film really
captures the feel of the era it's set in, from clothing, beliefs,
prejudices and superstitions all feel real enough that it becomes
genuinely involving. Great performances by the entire cast helps too.
Cushing, it goes without saying, is incredible. You see him as the kind
man Van Helsing is, but also brief flashes of a man as ruthless and
conniving as any of his enemies. He has an excellent scene where he
cures himself of a vampire bite with a branding iron and holy water
that looks very convincing(and hence cringe inducing; you actually hear
flesh sizzle)and where we feel his jubilation as the wound heals.
Yvonne Monlaur is great as Marianne, her character may be very naive,
but one feels this is not because of misogyny on the writer's part, but
genuine characterization, she manages to come off as a compassionate,
if easily deluded woman, but only because of inexperience, everything
she does is because she feels it is right. Martita Hunt is sympathetic
as the Baroness, torn between guilt and motherly love, yet one can't
help but feel, and this is supported by a monologue by both her and
Greta, that it is her fault that the Baron turned out the way he did,
many years before he became a vampire. It gives an icky, incestuous
atmosphere to the proceedings: Hammer, Tennessee Williams-style!(It's
like we never left the' Old Dark house With Crazy Families' theme of a
few weeks ago!). David Peel is amazing as the Baron; he seems so
cultured and dashing with his impeccable manners and rich, James
Mason-like voice. It's a shame he did very little work before or after
this film. Freda Jackson is genuinely creepy as Greta; her laugh is
guaranteed to give you shivers. Victor Brooks &amp; Fred Johnson have
moving bit-parts as a grieving father and a befuddled priest. Miles
Malleson(as a stupid doctor)&amp; Henry Oscar(as a tyrannical
headmaster)provide comedy relief that is genuinely funny('I'm no tenant
of yours, you young jackass!").There are several genuinely disturbing scenes as well, such as a truly
nightmarish sequence where Van Helsing finds Greta bidding a vampiress
to rise from her grave while cackling madly; seeing the hand emerge and
grasp while sinister organ music plays enhances the atmosphere, it
frightens even the seasoned vampire hunter. Then there's a scene where
Marianne's friend Gina(who had earlier spoken wistfully about how she
admired the Baron)rises as a vampire and zeroes in on Marianne, it has
a lesbian vibe which would be imitated much more, with much less class.
It puts the purported 'lesbian' scenes in 'Dracula's Daughter'(1936) to
shame in it's implications. This creepiness makes the film much easier
to take seriously than most vampire films, and makes the ending even
more amazing; love it or hate it, it's one of the most unique ways to
kill a vampire I've ever seen.The only reason it doesn't deserve a full 10? Gaping, gaping plot holes
and continuity issues and a story which can be summed up simply as
'Chick releases vampire, then doctor shows up, saves everyone'. With
that in mind, this may just be the best triumph of style over substance
I've ever seen. And with it's bizarre sexual subtext and conservative
message(Mothers shouldn't let kids get involved with the wrong crowd,
they may then corrupt others and seduce decent women); I think this is
where director Terrence Fisher found his voice and that this is his
first masterpiece, if not that, then of his early films, it's certainly
the most re-watchable.~
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19981632/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Alias_De_Large</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Hammer's 'Brides of Dracula' is a film fraught with irony. In the very
first scene, we see what is apparently a corpse that tuns out to be a
log, then we meet a handsome and debonair man who is in fact a fiendish
vampire who clearly had several skeletons in his closet even before
becoming a vampire, it is reflected in how the character we are
expected to consider the villain at first is in fact the most harmless,
it is reflected in how a woman who wishes to be the vampire's bride
ends up becoming his bride in the worst way possible. Most ironically
of all, it is also reflected in how this is probably the best vampire
film Hammer ever made, and despite the title; Dracula is nowhere to be
seen, but that doesn't stop this film from becoming a first rate
chiller.While traveling through the Transylvanian countryside to her new job; a
young french student-teacher named Marianne(Yvonne Monlaur)'s coach is
stolen after a highwayman bribes the driver, and she is stood up by the
villagers, but finds temporary refuge in the castle of the mysterious
Baroness Meinster(Martita Hunt)and her creepy maid Greta(Freda
Jackson). It becomes clear that the Baroness is not quite sane, and
apparently madness runs in the family as she keeps her purportedly
insane son locked up in another room and chained. Marianne spots him
from the balcony across the court yard, and visits him; finding him to
be a handsome and sophisticated man; Baron Meinster(David Peel; who
looks like he's in his late teens, very similar to Robert Pattinson of
'Twilight', in fact, but was apparently in his mid 40's!)who has been
kept prisoner so his mother could inherit the land. In a suspenseful
scene, she steals the key that keeps him chained, only to discover
after releasing him that she's made the biggest mistake of her life.
It's Dr. Van Helsing(Peter Cushing)to the rescue!The plot is extremely simple, so there's no use going into detail, but
what makes the film stand out is it's vividness. The film really
captures the feel of the era it's set in, from clothing, beliefs,
prejudices and superstitions all feel real enough that it becomes
genuinely involving. Great performances by the entire cast helps too.
Cushing, it goes without saying, is incredible. You see him as the kind
man Van Helsing is, but also brief flashes of a man as ruthless and
conniving as any of his enemies. He has an excellent scene where he
cures himself of a vampire bite with a branding iron and holy water
that looks very convincing(and hence cringe inducing; you actually hear
flesh sizzle)and where we feel his jubilation as the wound heals.
Yvonne Monlaur is great as Marianne, her character may be very naive,
but one feels this is not because of misogyny on the writer's part, but
genuine characterization, she manages to come off as a compassionate,
if easily deluded woman, but only because of inexperience, everything
she does is because she feels it is right. Martita Hunt is sympathetic
as the Baroness, torn between guilt and motherly love, yet one can't
help but feel, and this is supported by a monologue by both her and
Greta, that it is her fault that the Baron turned out the way he did,
many years before he became a vampire. It gives an icky, incestuous
atmosphere to the proceedings: Hammer, Tennessee Williams-style!(It's
like we never left the' Old Dark house With Crazy Families' theme of a
few weeks ago!). David Peel is amazing as the Baron; he seems so
cultured and dashing with his impeccable manners and rich, James
Mason-like voice. It's a shame he did very little work before or after
this film. Freda Jackson is genuinely creepy as Greta; her laugh is
guaranteed to give you shivers. Victor Brooks &amp; Fred Johnson have
moving bit-parts as a grieving father and a befuddled priest. Miles
Malleson(as a stupid doctor)&amp; Henry Oscar(as a tyrannical
headmaster)provide comedy relief that is genuinely funny('I'm no tenant
of yours, you young jackass!").There are several genuinely disturbing scenes as well, such as a truly
nightmarish sequence where Van Helsing finds Greta bidding a vampiress
to rise from her grave while cackling madly; seeing the hand emerge and
grasp while sinister organ music plays enhances the atmosphere, it
frightens even the seasoned vampire hunter. Then there's a scene where
Marianne's friend Gina(who had earlier spoken wistfully about how she
admired the Baron)rises as a vampire and zeroes in on Marianne, it has
a lesbian vibe which would be imitated much more, with much less class.
It puts the purported 'lesbian' scenes in 'Dracula's Daughter'(1936) to
shame in it's implications. This creepiness makes the film much easier
to take seriously than most vampire films, and makes the ending even
more amazing; love it or hate it, it's one of the most unique ways to
kill a vampire I've ever seen.The only reason it doesn't deserve a full 10? Gaping, gaping plot holes
and continuity issues and a story which can be summed up simply as
'Chick releases vampire, then doctor shows up, saves everyone'. With
that in mind, this may just be the best triumph of style over substance
I've ever seen. And with it's bizarre sexual subtext and conservative
message(Mothers shouldn't let kids get involved with the wrong crowd,
they may then corrupt others and seduce decent women); I think this is
where director Terrence Fisher found his voice and that this is his
first masterpiece, if not that, then of his early films, it's certainly
the most re-watchable.~
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies.tvguide.com/brides-dracula/review/120118 /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1851113</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
2.5/4
					</rating><comment>Chilling special effects highlight a rather gory production.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-biodrowski/</url><url>http://cinefantastiqueonline.com/2008/10/21/brides-of-dracula-1960/ /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1775375</url><name>Steve Biodrowski</name><from>ESplatter</from></reviewer><comment>The film features the familiar elements (beautiful color cinematography, lavish sets, solid writing, strong performances), making this a worthy heir to its predecessor.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tim-brayton/</url><url>http://antagonie.blogspot.com/2008/10/female-vampires.html /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1760699</url><name>Tim Brayton</name><from>Antagony &amp; Ecstasy</from></reviewer><rating>
7/10
					</rating><comment>If it isn't as iconic and elemental as its predecessor, that's no reflection on how well it works as a vampire entertainment on its own...an unusually original way to continue the closed-off story of Bram Stoker's novel.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/tom-milne/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/68436/the_brides_of_dracula.html /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1515652</url><name>Tom Milne</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Patchy but striking, and directed with Fisher's usual flair.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/The-Brides-of-Dracula /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1436552</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>When the story lags (and it often does), at least you have copious eye candy to feast on.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/staci-layne-wilson/</url><url>http://www.horror.com/php/article-922-1.html /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1431303</url><name>Staci Layne Wilson</name><from>Horror.com</from></reviewer><comment>While the plot is over the top and certainly contrived, there are enough spooky sequences to keep horror fans occupied.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9B00E2DB1F3EEF3ABC4E53DFBF66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1388817</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>Here is but another repetition of the standard tale of the vampire bugaboo who likes to sink his oversized dentures into the necks of pretty girls.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=101523&amp;section=review /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1146945</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment>Fisher directs with characteristic fluency, and the cast is splendid.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>http://www.mountainx.com/movies/review/brides_of_dracula /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1137621</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
4.5/5
					</rating><comment>Kind of Dracula Meets Tennessee Williams.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-sanford/</url><url>/m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=746973</url><name>James Sanford</name><from>Kalamazoo Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>"lusty vampire romp"</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/bridesofdracula.htm /m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=316122</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C+
					</rating><comment>One of the better horror films put out by the schlock Hammer studio.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1428901</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/randy-shulman/</url><url>/m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=1335062</url><name>Randy Shulman</name><from>Metro Weekly (Washington, DC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/philip-martin/</url><url>/m/brides_of_dracula/comments.php?reviewid=747360</url><name>Philip Martin</name><from>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>