<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>House of Usher</original_title><alt_title>La chute de la maison Usher</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Roger Corman</director><producer>Alta Vista Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Thriller</genre><synopsis>
After a long journey, Philip arrives at the Usher mansion seeking his loved one, Madeline. Upon arriving...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Vincent Price</actor><actor>Mark Damon</actor><actor>Myrna Fahey</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1112373/comments</url><from>from Queens, New York</from><name>Bill Treadway (treads22@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

"House of Usher" is an excellent start for Roger Corman's cycle of films
based on the work of Edgar Allan Poe. There have been many remakes, but the
Corman films remain the definitive statement. Corman was able to capture the
feel of Poe's work and that's something that the remakes couldn't even
touch. It also provides a tour de force for Vincent Price and establishes
him as a great actor.The film was shot on a budget of $270,000 and it looks GREAT. "House of
Usher" is a fabulous calling card for American International Pictures, the
distributor. Mostly known for making grade Z schlock, Corman's films gave
AIP real class. This is also Corman's first film in CinemaScope and he makes
the most of the widescreen here. It earns him a distinction of mine as a
"Master of the Widescreen", or filmmakers who create complex and worthwhile
compositions in the widescreen frame. The only problem is that the Poe films
die on TV, due to the horrific "pan-and-scan" process. Luckily for us,
American Movie Classics show these Poe films often in letterbox and MGM is
releasing the cycle on letterboxed DVDs.For a film that runs 85 minutes, "House of Usher" packs a lot into its'
narrative. It is the most faithful of the Poe adaptations, although
screenwriter Richard Matheson does take some liberties with the source
material, as any great adaptation should. Floyd Crosby's CinemaScope
photography is excellent as usual and Daniel Haller's elaborate sets make
this look more expensive than it really is. Vincent Price's performance as
Usher sets the tone for his future appearances in other Poe films. It neatly
combines calm and frenzy together and I can't think of anyone else who would
have done a better job. He should have received an Oscar nomination and
maybe even the Oscar itself.Note: "House of Usher" introduces the infamous "Burning Rafters" sequence.
If you watch these Poe films back-to-back, you'll see this same sequence
repeat itself over and over in several of the films (Tomb of Ligeia and The
Raven come to mind). It is a mild criticism, but it is such a great sequence
and it is so effectively shot that I didn't mind seeing it again and
again.**** out of 4 stars
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
The first of Roger Corman's adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories
stars Vincent Price as the head of the Usher house; Roderick Usher.
Roderick Usher believes that there is an evil curse on his family, a
curse that is also the reason for his and his sister's affliction.
Because of this curse of evil, he doesn't want the Usher family line to
continue and so he has decided to do all in his power to stop it.
However, his sister, Madeline's fiancé has come to the Usher house to
take her back with him, but Roderick knows that this will mean that the
Usher family line will continue and he cannot allow the evil to spread
across the world....Roger Corman is often seen as a 'cheap' director because of the vast
amount of films that he has made. Although this is certainly somewhat
true as a few of them aren't particularly good; if you take a look at
his Poe films, this couldn't be further from then truth. Here, Corman
creates a constantly morbid and foreboding atmosphere; not with shocks
or other cheap methods, but by simple things such as smoke, an old
house and it's creepy inhabitants that utter the most malevolent of
lines, some of which are truly bone chilling. Of course, this movie
benefits implicitly from the presence of a man that is maybe horror's
purest actor; Vincent Price. Price was born to play roles like Roderick
Usher, and anyone that sees this film wont find it hard to see why.
Vincent Price delivers his lines with just the right tone in order to
make him obviously evil, but yet pathetic at the same time; just how
the character should be played. When it comes to the 'greatest actor of
all time' awards, Vincent Price never gets mentioned, but this is a
great injustice; as anyone who has seen a number of films will know.Corman also succeeds in creating a constant sense of intrigue, and the
audience is left hanging on every moment, as we can't wait to see what
happens next. Of course, Edgar Allen Poe can take much of the credit
for this as the great man did write the story that it was based on, but
Corman comes off looking good as well as it is his direction that makes
the story so consistently thrilling. The movie also benefits from some
very lavish sets, which gives the movie it's upper class dinosaur feel.
The house itself is a great piece of horror imagery; it is responsible
for most of the atmosphere that is present in the movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1675392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>squeezebox</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Roger Corman's brilliant adaptation of Edgar Allan Poe's chilling tale is
one of the greatest achievements in cinematic horror.  It's hard to pick one
of Corman's Poe adaptations as the best, but this, the first, might be
it.The movie is fairly faithful to the story, but extremely faithful to the
tone of Poe's writing.  No one but the team of Corman and writer Richard
Matheson could pull it off like this.  Poe's deranged sense of dread and
sardonic humor are all here, in every shot.Vincent Price turns in one of his finest performances as Roderick Usher, a
man who is glad that he and his sister, Madeline (the wonderful Myrna Fahey)
are the last of their bloodline, as he believes the family is doomed to all
eventually go mad.  He also suffers from hyper-sensitivity, and must have
quiet, dim light, soft clothing and bland food, otherwise he suffers extreme
pain.  Whether this is a physical or psychological anomaly is never
confirmed.Madeline's fiance Philip (Mark Damon) comes to the house to claim Madeline
as his wife.  Roderick forbids it, believing he and his sister should die
together, thus ending the Usher line of insanity.  But it may be too late,
as Madeline is already showing signs of flipping out, and Roderick has some
pretty twisted ideas of how to stop that from happening.The movie leads up to a spine-tingling finale that's as intense and scary a
climax as anything I've seen.  HOUSE OF USHER is a great horror movie, and
perhaps the most faithful adaptation of Poe, both in content and style, ever
filmed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1821331/comments</url><from>from WA, USA</from><name>Hal-900</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Corman's first Edgar Allan Poe adaptation triggered one of the most
successful (and beloved) series of movies in the history of the
American cinema. Later on, Corman gained notoriety for discovering new
talent and producing many low-budget movies, but we tend to forget that
he is a talented filmmaker too. "House of Usher" is a small-scale, very
low-budget production, inventively directed by Corman. The emphasis is
on characterizations and atmosphere, not on plot devices. In fact, very
little occurs during the course of the movie. Characters talk and talk,
while the story unfolds at a snail's pace. Sure, the film is slow
moving, but it is never boring. From a technical point of view, it is
very satisfying. But great aesthetics is not the movie's only strong
card. The acting is excellent too. Vincent Price became a horror star
on the strength of "House of Wax," but I think this is the movie that
really establishes him as a force to be reckon with. Price is
wonderfully restrained in one of his best roles. I also liked Mark
Damon's performance as the movie's hero. The script by the great
Richard Matheson is rock-solid and Floyd Crosby's color cinematography
is simply extraordinary. Corman made seven more films based on Poe's
work, but this is still one of the best films of the well-regarded
series.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0610628/comments</url><from>from Ohio, USA</from><name>capkronos (capkronos00@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Corman's first Poe film (out of eight) is one of the best adaptations
of the familiar story (rivaled only by French director Jean Epstein's
superb, yet completely different, 1928 version) and was a critical and
commercial success in its day on a meager $125,000 budget. Vincent
Price is superb as Roderick Usher, an eternally tortured soul who lives
in a crumbling castle with his sister Madeline (Myrna Fahey) and
faithful butler Bristol (nicely etched by Harry Ellerbe). When Philip
Winthrop (bland Mark Damon) shows up to take Madeline away, Roderick's
incestuous feelings come to surface and the terror begins. Highlights
include Damon's colorful nightmare sequence and Price's explanation of
the Usher family history.HOUSE OF USHER is intelligent, subtle and effective, with good sets and
costumes and excellent work from scripter Richard Matheson, composer
Les Baxter, cameraman Floyd Crosby and art director Daniel Haller--all
united by Corman's smart, stylish, fluent direction. Truly deserving of
it's reputation as horror classic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0808464/comments</url><from>from Buenos Aires, Argentina</from><name>pablo-74</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is Roger Corman´s first Edgar Allan Poe-based movie and probably the
best of them all in terms of direction, acting and script. It´s certainly
the best adapted one, because it manages to build a larger story around
the
events of the tale without borrowing material from other tales and without
making it seem obvious, unlike the sequels. Anyway, probably my favorite
is
still "Masque of the red death" which is also my favorite Poe tale. The
rest
deserves a look, of course, but it doesn´t get any better.Vincent Price stars as Roderick Usher, a man obsessed with the tragic
history of the Usher clan, filled with psychopats, murderers of all kinds
and people who die of incurable illnesses. He forces his sister Madeline
(Myrna Fahey) to stay in the house waiting for death to spare the world
the
horrors of the Usher family in years to come and even builds two separate
coffins for them. Madeline´s fiancee (Mark Damon) goes looking for her to
the house and is received by the obedient butler Bristol (Harry Ellerbe).
From there on this four characters will go through a lot of arguing,
running
around the House (which, like in the Poe tale, is a character itself, one
of
a really menacing nature) and digging on ancient secrets. Any Corman or
Poe
afficionado can figure out the rest of the story by himself, but it´s a
joy
to watch it evolve here.The star of the show is Vincent Price, of course. He puts in a black robe
or
a red silk suit and speaks in a low, soft, modulated voice, throwing his
overwrought dialogue while the others just stare at him with surprise and
fear. He has a special weakness of the hearing (I have the same problem,
BTW, although not to this extent) and in one scene the fiancee screams at
him hard enough to make him twitch in pain. In that scene you realize just
what a genius he is. The set decoration is also to be noted (you
won´t forget easily the paintings of the Usher family members by Burt
Schonberg), as is the music and practically everything that sets the
unbelievable mood this movie has.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2885836/comments</url><from>from Puerto Rico</from><name>spacemonkey_fg</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Title: The Fall of the House of Usher (1960)Director: Roger CormanCast: Vincent Price, Mark Damon, Myrna FaheyReview:Vincent price is one of those actors everyone knows about, almost
everyone is aware of his horror legacy, and if anything they know him
as that creepy voice in Michael Jacksons "Thriller". And maybe some of
us also recognized him as Edwards creator in Tim Burtons "Edward
Scissorhands" or as the narrator in Burtons stop motion animated short
film "Vincent". Recently I decided to venture into Vincent Prices
horror legacy. I decided to start watching all of his films, after all
the man has got a huuuge library of horror films all waiting to be
slowly digested by yours truly...boy was I in for a treat! The story is about Roderick and Madeline Usher. The last two remains of
the Usher family. A family that according to Roderick is cursed
forever, and he is very decided to end the family line with him and
Madeline. So naturally when a young strapping man by the name of
Phillip Winthrop comes in and has all the intentions of marrying
Madeline Usher, well Mr. Roderick completely opposes and tries to stop
the wedding from ever occurring at all costs. This movie has many good things going for it. First off: The House of
Usher is based on Edgar Allan Poes "The Fall of the House of Usher" so
its no surprise that the story is poetic in nature and beautifully
written. It also helps that the screenplay for this story was written
by non other then another one of horrordoms greatest writers. I'm
speaking of course of Richard Matheson. And on top of all those
bonuses, the film has Vincent Price in the lead role as Roderick Usher,
the man who lives a tormented life, thinking that his family is cursed.
Combine Edgar Allan Poes story, with Richard Mathesons screenplay and
Vincent Price acting, and my friends you have got yourselves a bonafide
horror classic. Having Roger Corman, the producer and director of hundreds of low
budget b-movies had me worried for a second. I mean he has got some
really bad films under his belt, but in between those there's some
really good ones as well. But of course I am only familiar with some of
the schlock that he has produced as of recently (like the Carnosour
films for example) but I wasn't fully aware of the high quality
directing that he had done in his past and I fully intend on continuing
my exploration of his Vincent Price/Poe films. Now let me put this to you straight. This is the type of film that you
watch on a dark stormy night with all the lights out and nothing to
disturb you. The films atmosphere can be cut with a knife, you get your
spooky castle in the middle of nowhere, the fog rolling in like there's
no tomorrow, the wind blowing the curtains, the fullmoon, ghosts...you
get the whole enchilada my friends. I had Tim Burtons Sleepy Hollow as
my all time spookiest movie ever made, but I have to say that this one
takes its place, well if anything, its definitely a heavy contender.
This movie had both the look and feel of a slightly more expensive
Hammer film. The films story is its great asset. The mystery of the Usher family
curse pulls you in. You want to know if something is really up with
this strange family or if its just Mr. Roderick Usher that has a boner
for his own sister...is it all in their minds? Or is there really a
curse? What will happen to the poor bastard who wants to marry
Madeline? These questions pull you in and finally when you get all the
answers, well, you will be nothing short of being blown away. In short, if you want one of those old fashion spooky films where the
winds always blowing, the full moon is always at its peek and the
thunder and lightning is always rumbling...well go rent/buy this flick
right now, you wont be disappointed. Rating: 5 out of 5
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
House of Usher is the first Edgar Allan Poe adaptation in a series
(seven, to be exact) directed by Roger Corman, and probably my number
one recommendation if you're looking for a good old-fashioned spooky
tale. Corman merely lays the stress on the comedy-factor in his later
efforts, but House of Usher still has the ability to frighten the
bejezus out of you through a complex plot, a nightmarish atmosphere and
horrific decors. The screenplay is very loyal to Poe's tale of the
Ushers…Two remaining siblings, cursed and constantly punished for the
evil of their criminal ancestors. Price is brilliant as usual in his
role of the over-concerned Roderick Usher, convinced that his fade is
sealed and his remaining days are doomed. Multiple memorable highlights
in this film, like for example a ghoulish dream-sequence, a breath
taking decent in the family vault and a truly petrifying act of
vengeance! Classic and successful combination of mysterious Gothic and
stylish horror, not to be missed if you're a fan!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4888011/comments</url><from>from Portland, Oregon, USA</from><name>Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
In one of the many classic adaptations of Edgar Allan Poe tales,
Vincent Price creepily shines yet again. When Philip Winthrop (Mark
Damon) goes to an estate to pick up his fiancée Madeleine Usher (Myrna
Fahey), he learns from her brother Roderick (Price) that she and he
both suffer from a degenerative disease that gives them both acute
senses. Sure enough, it turns out that all is not quite what it seems.Probably the most noticeable thing about this movie is that Vincent
Price lacks his famously eerie moustache. But in a way, that almost
makes him more mysterious. Roger Corman scored another triumph here.
You're sure to love it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Director Roger Corman does his thing with a classic piece from Edgar Allan
Poe. A visually fantastic production. A tense and moody horror tale of a
young Bostonian (Mark Damon)traveling to the Usher family mansion to
collect
his beautiful bride-to-be(Myrna Fahey). The eager suitor is told by her
brother(Vincent Price)that the family's blood has been cursed and he should
rethink a marriage.The mansion, surroundings and atmosphere bring a chill. The evasive Price
is
very convincing in his role as doting brother and master of the house.
Great
spooky movie to watch on a rainy night.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Director Roger Corman does his thing with a classic piece from Edgar Allan
Poe. A visually fantastic production. A tense and moody horror tale of a
young Bostonian (Mark Damon)traveling to the Usher family mansion to
collect
his beautiful bride-to-be(Myrna Fahey). The eager suitor is told by her
brother(Vincent Price)that the family's blood has been cursed and he should
rethink a marriage.The mansion, surroundings and atmosphere bring a chill. The evasive Price
is
very convincing in his role as doting brother and master of the house.
Great
spooky movie to watch on a rainy night.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449021/comments</url><from>from Muskogee OK</from><name>Michael O'Keefe</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>