<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hideout in the Sun</original_title><imdb_rating>5.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Larry Wolk</director><producer>Wica Productions</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Two brothers rob a bank and take a young girl hostage. They find out that the girl is a nudist, so they force her to take them to a nudist colony so they can hide out.
</synopsis><actor>Earl Bauer</actor><actor>Dolores Carlos</actor><actor>Greg Conrad</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0867063/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>FilmFlaneur</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
When her husband died, Wishman was already part of the film
distribution industry but, as she explained years later: "I needed to
do something that would be so different that it would keep me occupied
every second. I didn't know what I was doing when I started
production.." The title which kick-started her long career as a cult
exploitation director in such uncertain fashion was Hideout in The Sun.
The first of several nudist films made by the director until, along
with most of the industry she abandoned the genre in the mid-60's,
Hideout may not on the level of Nude on The Moon (1961) which was to
follow, let alone the delirious excesses of some of her other films as
Deadly Weapons (1974) it still retains enough charm, and is
characteristic enough of Wishman's work, to be eminently watchable.
Whether or not the film is worth such lavish treatment as it has now
been accorded in the recently released deluxe 2 disc set will be down
to fans and viewers to decide.Combining Dragnet melodramatics and naked frolics in one cheaply
constructed package, Hideout is the tale of two brother heisters, Steve
and Duke (Earl Bauer and Greg Conrad), on the run after a payroll
robbery, forced to hole up in the Hibiscus Country Club which, oddly
enough, turns out to be a nudist colony. Along the way they kidnap
Dorothy (Delores Carlos), a member of the club, and during their brief
stay with the naturists she and Steve find a mutual liking for each
other. But even as the anxious and humane Steve finds a new happiness
in arms of his winsome nude and her lifestyle – "I feel healthy in body
and mind for the first time in my life" he says - so equally does the
permanently cross and resentful Duke, in hiding and so excluded from
the naked goings on, want to leave – he's in a hurry to get the
ill-gotten gains off to safety. Finally (courtesy of the sparsely
attended Miami Serpentarium) events come to a head in a show down with
some snakes, a croc and a lone policeman.Hideout in the Sun is distinguished by a title song of the same name
that appears, to good effect, thrice in the movie: a mellow ballad
which fits in well with the laid back jazz permeating the rest of the
soundtrack. The film was also shot on bright Eastman Colour stock
which, although the print here (apparently salvaged from a sole
remaining version which the director held on to) suffers a bit from the
odd tramline and the distraction of missing frames, is still enough to
give a vivid evocation both of Dorothy's familiarly innocent lifestyle,
as well as being a product of an adult movie industry moment now long
past. Much of the dialogue is looped or post-synched, thereby gaining a
dreamlike, or distancing effect familiar to those who relish this sort
of genre. It also allows Wishman to play on the disassociation between
the cruel world outside the Hibiscus club and it's Eden-esquire
interior; a timeless sunlit place where naked folks wander around
amongst tame flamingos, swans and emus, splash contentedly (if coyly)
in pools, play the jiggling handball variant that's was such a
prerequisite of contemporary nudist cinema, shoot archery, or just
stretch out in the sun with over emphatic casualness. At this stage in
the cycle pubes were verboten; instead strategically placed towels and
crooked legs cover the necessary areas in studied ways which quickly
became a stereotype all of their own.If the Hibiscus Club is a sort of Eden, then it's apt that bad Duke is
ultimately consigned to expulsion from the enclave, onto a fate amongst
the serpents. But how you respond to Hideout overall depends on how you
accept the budding director as the genre 'auteur' that some argue she
became. If nothing else, although she was never a woman's libber,
Wishman was a feminist role model, a survivor in an industry where men
predominated. And if for some 'trash' remains trash, no matter how much
fancy pleading is made, I'd argue there is a form of art here, even in
her first film, and not just of the naughty postcard variety. (One can
imagine how the some story would have been treated, full of sniggers
and studio flatness, if it had been given the Carry On treatment, for
instance.) It's art of a guileless type, but sneaked in under the cover
of 'bad movies'; one of narrative non-sequiturs, where already there's
the feeling that the director is going her own fledgling way
disorganising narrative just as eventually, in both time and with
greater respectability, Godard was to do in the art house much further
down the cinematic road. As critic Andrea Juno put it in his piece on
the director in the seminal book Incredibly Strange Films: 'behind her
economically deprived visuals lies a wealth of imagination: wildly
improbable plots, bizarre "method acting" and scripts yielding freely
to fantasy '. Whilst the recently long-lost Hideout remains a minor
work in Wishman's extensive oeuvre, still unsteady on its feet, it
remains junk not to be just thrown away.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3517136/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blah020122</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I don't understand the voters who scored this movie a 1/10. What the
heck were they expecting? This movie does exactly what it tries to do:
lots and lots and lots and lots and lots of T&amp;A with very attractive
women, with a delightfully campy plot and performances.If you're the kind of viewer who would be interested in a film like
this in the first place, there is no way you won't like it. The
audio/video sync is poor at times (they somewhat get around this by not
showing the faces of the characters who are speaking a lot of the time)
and there are a few spots where part of the print is missing (never
more than a fraction of a second), but these "flaws" only add to the
charm. The video quality of the DVD is actually quite good. Video
quality is often a problem with obscure films rescued from a half a
century ago, but Something Weird got a good print of this one.It is the epitome of its genre. If you're interested enough in this
kind of movie to be reading this review, you will love this movie. See
it. You will not be sorry.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0419768/comments</url><from>from Miami, Florida</from><name>Beau-20</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Pound for pound, Doris Wishman is the toughest filmmaker in the history o'
the silver screen, and "Hideout" is the film that launched the most
prolific
career of any woman director *ever*.
"Hideout" was missing for 40 years after it's original distributor died in
jail and took the prints with him.  This picture deserves wider exposure
and
its worth seeking out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0419768/comments</url><from>from Miami, Florida</from><name>Beau-20</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Pound for pound, Doris Wishman is the toughest filmmaker in the history o'
the silver screen, and "Hideout" is the film that launched the most
prolific
career of any woman director *ever*.
"Hideout" was missing for 40 years after it's original distributor died in
jail and took the prints with him.  This picture deserves wider exposure
and
its worth seeking out.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0419768/comments</url><from>from Miami, Florida</from><name>Beau-20</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>