<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Kidnapped</original_title><alt_title>L'enlèvement de David Balfour</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Robert Stevenson</director><producer>Walt Disney Productions</producer><genre>Family</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><synopsis>
Kidnapped and cheated out of his inheritance, young David Balfour falls in with a Jacobite adventurer...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Peter Finch</actor><actor>James MacArthur</actor><actor>Bernard Lee</actor><rt_rating>liked it</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0423897/comments</url><from>from Little Rock, AR, USA</from><name>Keawe</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Walt Disney's 1960 film of Robert Louis Stevenson's _Kidnapped_ is not only
the best movie version of the 1886 novel but is also one of the finest
cinematic treatments of any of the author's works.  Filmed on location in
Scotland and featuring an outstanding ensemble of mostly British actors,
this _Kidnapped_ is faithful to the spirit -- and even, for the most part,
to the letter -- of the RLS masterpiece, which is half adventure tale and
half meditation on Scottish history, culture, and character.  Director
Robert Stevenson (presumably no relation to Tusitala) never dumbed down the
story or the 18th-century context, which may account for the movie's
present
limited appeal.  It's atmospherically and thematically darker than the
ususal Disney fare, and adult viewers may find it surprisingly rewarding.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1117480/comments</url><from>from Washington, D.C.</from><name>kevinmc (kevinmc@smart.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Equating Disney movies to "family entertainment" is a bit trite, but here
it
works. Young men looking for adventure in their lives will be as pleased
with this film as parents looking for a quality movie to which they can
take
their kids.
This is the brilliant Scottish raconteur Robert Louis Stevenson's
tale
of two Scotlands, Highland and Lowland, as personified by the dour young
Mr.
David Balfour and the spirited Highlander Alan Breck Stewart (who proudly
"bears a King's name"). On the run for their lives in their own native
country of Scotland, now occupied by English redcoats and their Hessian
merceneries, the protagonists must overcome their mutual distrust of one
another, which is based primarily on political differences (but also on
cultural differences as well). In fighting to keep their health and lives,
they come to respect and even appreciate one another, in part because
(ironically) they are from different worlds.
The acting is simply first-rate; the producers could not (and did
not)
rely on special effects to make this movie work. The scenery of the
Scottish
Highlands is breathtaking. But it's the plot and character development
made
so viable by the brilliant acting of Peter Finch and James MacArthur that
make the movie a stand-out. Rent it, bring it home, and watch it with your
girlfriend, your boyfriend, nephews, nieces, aunts, uncles, friends,
parent,
grandparents, or perfect strangers. By the end of the movie, you'll value
the friendship that young Mr. Balfour and the spirited Highlander find for
themselves. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Kidnapped is based on the novel by Robert Louis Stevenson and has been
made several times. This Disney version is excellent.David Balfur's uncle arranges for him to be kidnapped and is taken
aboard a ship but gets shipwrecked along the way but eventually manages
to get back to Scotland after teaming up with adventurer Alan Breack
Stuart. The journey takes them across the Scottish Highlands and face
dangers along the way including soldiers in Redcoats.This movie is shot on location in the Scottish Highlands and contains
some great scenery.The cast includes James MacArther, Peter Finch, Benard Lee (before his
role as M in the James Bond movies), John Laurie (Private Frazer from
Dad's Army), Finlay Currie, Nial MacGinnis and Peter O'Toole (Lawrence
of Arabia). Excellent parts from all.Watching Kidnapped is an ideal way to spend an hour and a half one
afternoon. Excellent.Rating: 3 and a half stars out of 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Robert Louis Stevenson, born in Scotland in 1850 and sick with
tuberculosis most of his adult life, was one prolific author of books
of travel and adventure that are read and enjoyed even today. The
imagery he creates in his books is so vivid that cinematic adaption is
real easy. In fact this version of Kidnapped won high praise in the
British Isles for being remarkably faithful to the book.The story was also filmed on location in Scotland lending a real
authenticity to the story. A whole slew of Scots players got work in
this one and Australian Peter Finch and American James MacArthur fit
right in with them. Impossible for me to believe, but this Walt Disney film did not do as
good in America as in Europe. I suppose it was both the accents and the
knowledge of the political situation in Scotland post the rising in
1745 that Americans did not appreciate or were ignorant of. This
American certainly did.Young David Balfour the heir to the manor of Shores has one big problem
collecting his inheritance, the presence of his uncle who is the
reigning laird. Uncle Ebenezer who is deliciously played by John Laurie
arranges a snatch by a sea captain friend of his and David (James
MacArthur) is to be sent to the Carolinas in the American colonies as
an indentured servant. On the boat young David whose politics and heritage make him a
supporter of the Hanoverian George II who is the reigning King of Great
Britain finds himself having to make common cause with Scottish soldier
of fortune Alan Breck Stewart who is played by Peter Finch and boasts
proudly of bearing the name of the true House that ought to be running
things. He's a Jacobite, a supporter of the claim of James III, who is
exiled in France and who fought at Culloden with Bonnie Prince Charlie. These unlikely allies affect an escape from the ship and make their way
back to the House of Shores to set things right. Being a Jacobite and
by dint of that, a traitor in Hanoverian eyes makes it all the more
dangerous for both of them.James MacArthur, son of playwright Charles MacArthur and Helen Hayes,
was a young Disney star during that period, doing a whole bunch of
roles for Disney on the small and big screen. Peter Finch makes his
second and last appearance in a Disney film, he was memorable as the
Sheriff of Nottingham in Disney's Robin Hood film. They have a good
easy chemistry between them and if it were not so the film wouldn't
have worked at all.Three other players of note here are Bernard Lee as the sea captain who
kidnaps Balfour, Finlay Currie as a fellow Jacobite clan leader who
gives Finch and MacArthur shelter, and Peter O'Toole who bests Finch in
a bagpipe playing contest.Robert Louis Stevenson died in Tahiti in 1894, but in his short life
left us a remarkable output of literature like Treasure Island, Dr.
Jekyll and Mr. Hyde, The Master of Ballantrae, and so much more. Though
he went to the South Seas for health reasons and a love of adventure,
if that can be combined in one individual, his love of Scotland was
never shown better than in Kidnapped and in this classic adaption of
that story.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
If most people are asked what story by Robert Louis Stevenson they are
acquainted with, more than likely they will say either TREASURE ISLAND
or DR. JECKYLL AND MR. HYDE or KIDNAPPED. KIDNAPPED is a close second
to TREASURE ISLAND as Stevenson's most popular complete novel (DR.
JECKYLL is a novella). Like THE MASTER OF BALLENTRAE it deals with the
great trauma of Scotland's 18th Century history - the failure of the
1745/1746 Jacobite Rebellion of Bonnie Prince Charlie which came so
close to success. But it does not deal straight with the events of
those years, but rather with the aftermath for Scotland, for England,
and for Scottish society.David Balfour (James MacArthur) is a lowlander - he is from the urban
centers of Scotland like Glasgow and Edinburgh and Dundee. These
commercial centers play a serious role in his story, for David is
returning to the home of his ancestors, which is also a business run by
his uncle Ebenezer(John Laurie). He is met by a stingy miser who is
hardly welcoming - actually he is quite hostile for awhile. But he
gradually acts more quietly, if not more friendly to the nephew. At one
point he asks him to retrieve some item in an upstairs section of the
house they live in, and the stairs is in disrepair (nearly causing
David to fall to his death). That settles it, and David just demands
his inheritance and he'll be quit of this inhuman uncle. David goes to
bed, and is awaken violently: he unknown men. They kidnap David (hence
the title of the novel), and he is soon on board a ship commanded by
the frequently drunken Captain Hoseason (Bernard Lee - "M" in the Sean
Connery "James Bond" films) and his first mate Mr. Shaun (Niall
MacGinnis). Soon David finds the ship (which is headed for America,
where he may be sold as an indentured servant) has picked up a small
boat, containing a single man, one Aleck Breck (Peter Finch). Breck is
quite secretive of his being alone in such a desolate area, but
Hoseason and Shaun suspect he is involved in some type of Jacobite
treason.KIDNAPPED is set in the year 1752. Most people think that Jacobite
activity ended with the defeat and destruction of Charlie's Highlander
army at Culloden in 1746, and the "clearances" in the Highland of
Charlie's supporters. It didn't. Jacobite activities would continue
into the period of the Seven Years War. Stevenson shows that the tide has turned against the hard core of the
Jacobites in Scotland - the strength were the Highland Clans, and they
were purposely decimated . The lowland clans had hedged about their
support (as in THE MASTER OF BALLENTRAE). But most, especially the
Campbell family, went fully for the German Hanovarian Royal Family. The
Campbells were rewarded, becoming the dominant noble family in Scotland
(to this day). And that is the basis for the tragedy that is at the
center of the story. A true tragedy and a murder mystery that has never
been explained.Alec is actually Alec Breck Stewart, a relative of the Old Pretender
and his son Bonnie Prince Charlie. He is in Scotland to contact
surviving Jacobite leaders. This does not really sit well with David, a
lowlander who had little use for the Highland clans or their leaders.
But they become close friends and allies against Hoseason and his crew,
and in surviving in Scotland's Highland area (where David is totally at
sea). But David is also realistic enough to note his friend's two worse
habits: he's a heavy gambler and he drinks too much.They have to make their way south, to get Alec through his mission and
back to France, and for David to settle his accounts with Uncle
Ebenezer. But they happen to meet with one of the most hated men in
Scotland, Colin Campbell, known as "The Red Fox". He has been appointed
by his cousin the Duke of Argyle to collect rents and help in the
clearances. David has separated from Alec when he meets the arrogant
Red Fox in the forest of Appin, and he is present when, from out of the
forest, a shot is fired killing this man. David flees, and shortly is
confronted by Alec. And David, despite his best endeavors, remains
uncertain that Alec's secret mission was not tied to this
assassination.The "Red Fox's" murder was never solved, although a major judicial
murder, the hanging of James "of the Glen" Stewart, followed within a
year (before a judge and jury entirely of Campbells). But it turns Alec
and David into fugitives, increasing their dangers immensely. They
might end up dangling from English ropes.I'll leave it at this point. Finch and MacArthur make a good pair of
friends and adventurers, with Finch also showing Breck Stewart's
failings (his temper, his loud mouth, his alcoholism, and his
gambling). MacArthur (Helen Hayes' adopted son) also had a great scene
regarding a dangerous confrontation with a greedy Highlander (Duncan
Macrae) at a river in the highlands. The best recalled scene in this
version is a bagpipe contest before one of their hosts (Finlay Currie)
that was won by Currie's kinsman, a youngish man who movie goers would
see more of later: Peter O'Toole. John Laurie is properly despicable
(yet comical, in a pathetic way) as Ebenezer. Although there is a trace
of more dignity in the Freddy Bartholemew - Warner Baxter KIDNAPPED
from the 1930s, this one is actually the best movie version.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1894409/comments</url><from>from Burke, VA</from><name>The_Rook</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I know an honest appraisal when I see one. Add to that
droits_de_l_homme is from Scotland so he knows what he is talking
about. I just know I have always loved this movie. I have always been a
fan of classic writers like Stevenson and Dickens. This Disney movie is
long overdue for putting on DVD. Why such a great piece of work with a
stellar cast has not been put on DVD before now is beyond me. I bought
the VHS many years ago and I am glad I did as it is OOP now. If you are
lucky enough to catch it on TV I am sure you will agree it is a
masterpiece of family entertainment with an accurate depiction of
Scottish history thrown in for good measure. I always hoped this would
come out on DVD with Disney talking about the story behind it as he
often did when these were made for the Disney TV show.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4671699/comments</url><from>from United States (formerly of Uddingston, Scotland)</from><name>droits_de_l_homme</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
As good as cinema has been in retelling the Robert Louis Stevenson
classic. It also happens to be my favourite novel, as it was the first
I read (age 11) where the central character, David Balfour speaks with
my accent and dialect. Furthermore, as a young man growing up I related
to David's character, beliefs and values which reflect those of my own
upbringing in a loving secure Lowland Scots Presbyterian (Church of
Scotland) family. My biggest criticism is that the character of David
as portrayed by James MacArthur spoke with the petulance of a spoiled
American kid which did not ring true for a country bred but well
educated Lowlander ,who is the recently orphaned son of a Dominie
(parish schoolmaster). The late John Laurie played Ebenezer Balfour
pretty much as I imagined him from reading the book. Peter Finch made a
surprisingly good Alan Breck Stewart, and his speech patterns were
faithful both to the book and to a Gaelic speaker speaking in Scots.
Many of the incidental characters were well cast and acted as well. The
two that stick in mind were the Carter (Tinker) and Jennet Clouston,
both characters from whom David seeks direction to the House of Shaws.
A great piece of wholesome family entertainment that credits the viewer
with intelligence and knowledge of Stevenson's understanding of
Scottish History.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0830421/comments</url><from>from Wauwatosa, WI</from><name>caramh</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

When I watched this movie as a child, I was amazed and in awe by this
adventure story that unfolded before me.  In spite of the fact that I'm
now
older and more critical of the films I view, I couldn't help but admire
the
acting of Peter Finch and the others.  Upon a recent viewing, I realized
that much of the depth that makes this film so enjoyable was extremely
overlooked in my youth.  While the adventure is no "Jurassic Park," the
story that unfolds about friendship, courage and determination allows me
to
recognize this film, not only as a childhood favorite, but as a timeless
classic which I think people of all ages can and will enjoy.  Rent it, buy
it or borrow it--you won't be disappointed!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20552756/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>TheLittleSongbird</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I am a big fan of Disney and Kidnapped! is no exception. While dragging
in spots, it is a rollicking good time and very faithful to the spirit
of Robert Louis Stevenson's fine book. The costumes, cinematography and
sets are typically splendid, and the score is very rousing. The story
is exciting with plenty of cool and intelligent moments and also some
energetic action sequences, the script is literate, the direction is
solid and we are further treated to a brilliant performance from Peter
Finch in one of those roles I will best remember him by. The support
performances are equally impressive, in particular it was great to see
a handsome Peter O'Toole. Overall, a fine adaptation and for me one of
the better live-action Disney films. 9/10 Bethany Cox
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7058339/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>petersj-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This a rollicking good story and even if you not seen the movie for
many years you are in for a pleasant surprise. The scenery is wonderful
and there are wonderful characters in the film and plenty of
excitement. The scenes of the grand old ships on the mighty ocean
really do look rather like boats in a bath tub but forget all that its
a finely paced adventure movie. There are a few of Disneys favourite
young actors in it and they are all very good but its Peter Finch who
brings that special distinction to the film. He was a brilliant actor
and even though its a Disney kids flick he gives it all he has got.
Finch is brilliant and it is his film. There is a lovely scene with the
incredibly handsome Peter O Toole.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7058339/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>petersj-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This a rollicking good story and even if you not seen the movie for
many years you are in for a pleasant surprise. The scenery is wonderful
and there are wonderful characters in the film and plenty of
excitement. The scenes of the grand old ships on the mighty ocean
really do look rather like boats in a bath tub but forget all that its
a finely paced adventure movie. There are a few of Disneys favourite
young actors in it and they are all very good but its Peter Finch who
brings that special distinction to the film. He was a brilliant actor
and even though its a Disney kids flick he gives it all he has got.
Finch is brilliant and it is his film. There is a lovely scene with the
incredibly handsome Peter O Toole.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7058339/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>petersj-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eugene-archer/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9902E7DA153DE333A2575AC1A9639C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1011511-kidnapped/comments.php?reviewid=1390559</url><name>Eugene Archer</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>