<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Crowded Sky</original_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Joseph Pevney</director><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Action</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
An navy jet with a defective radio system and a passenger plane get in danger of collision. In flashbacks we learn about the personal problems of the pilots and most of the crew.
</synopsis><actor>Dana Andrews</actor><actor>Rhonda Fleming</actor><actor>Efrem Zimbalist Jr.</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1423117/comments</url><from>from Excelsior, Minnesota</from><name>Lee Blaske (lblaske@pclink.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This movie had a lot of things that I enjoy: vintage commercial airplanes,
old military airplanes, radios, radar, art, drama, romance, special effects,
etc. In some respects, it must have served as a template for future airliner
disaster movies. I don't know why, but I really enjoyed the heavy handed use
of flashbacks and scenes where there's a close-up of a character, the
surrounding lights dim, and we hear the character's private thoughts.
Crowded Sky might not be your cup of tea, but it certainly was mine.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1280866/comments</url><from>from New Jersey, USA</from><name>David Powell (David_Powell3006@msn.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Pretty nice movie, interesting for the plot and effects of the time.
(And the appearance of a prop airliner, this movie coming right at the
transition from the age of propeller planes into the jet age.) People
have commented on connections between this movie and "Airport 1975" in
that Dana Andrews and Efrem Zimbalist, Jr. appear in both, with their
roles reversed in each. (Andrews is the pilot of the airliner in this
one, Zimbalist is the airline pilot in "Airport 1975.") There is
another similarity between the movies, as well, which I won't spoil. I was sort of surprised to see that this one isn't out on DVD. So many
movies are coming out in that format, and there have to be people who
would want to own this one. When I was a kid (1980s, maybe the late
1970s) this was on the local TV stations as an afternoon movie several
times. So there are plenty of people besides those who caught the
original release who might want to own this one.Also there is something that interests the modern airline passenger in
all these airline movies from 20+ years ago.... those larger seats, how
polite people were on a plane, and how people used to actually dress up
to fly. Ah, as Ray Walston said in "Damn Yankees," those were the good
old days!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3156963/comments</url><from>from Pompton Plains, NJ USA</from><name>vmwrites</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

One of the first modern day airline disaster movies, this 1961 film
contains
all the elements of suspense, humor and drama that one would expect of its
genre.  With the only drawback of a weak supporting cast, the story line
is
a solid one.In this film, Efrem Zimbalist, Jr. plays a navy pilot on a collision
course
with a commercial jet piloted by Dana Andrews.  Years later, in one of the
later Airport series, the roles are reversed and Andrews plays the pilot
of
a small plane on a collision course with a commercial aircraft piloted by
Efrem Zimbalist.Troy Donahue does a creditable job as a young sailor hitching a ride with
Zimbalist to get home.  An interesting device in this film is the close-up
thought technique, particularly when used with the character played by
Keenan Wynn.If you consider this film only among the other members of its generation,
it
comes out well.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0683496/comments</url><from>from Adelaide, Australia</from><name>MuggySphere</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Yes I loved it. What a gem of a movie.I taped this just on a whim as it was on a very late night run here and
I have to say I loved it. I found it a treat and a gem. My favourite
part of the film is when a character is thinking out loud the camera
focuses in on that person and the lighting around them dims as we head
into their world either via voice over or a flashback scene.I would not mind adding this movie to my collection if it ever comes
out on DVD. This is one of the movies, no doubt that paved the way for
movies like "Airport" and all those awful disaster movies of the 70s
and 80s. Good going I'll give it 7/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0043975/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ronnie</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

The disaster does not occur until the last half-hour of this frenzied time
capsule. With a motley group of passengers on an aircraft, including a
stunning stewardess (Anne Francis) in love with the co-pilot (John Kerr),
each time a passenger has thoughts, the camera zooms in for a closeup, with
the actor's thoughts voiced in the background. It's a kick! My favorite
character is Jean Willes, a beauty in the Ava Gardner mold, portraying a
thrice-married woman who sits next to an old boyfriend (Keenan Wynn), who
does not recognize her. She still is stewing even after the air disaster.
When the aircraft is hit by a smaller plane, Francis advises passengers to
get ready for a crash position, and to take false teeth out, even jokingly
saying she won't tell anyone. All this when they don't even know that they
will live or die! Trivia note: Dana Andrews pilots the big aircraft, while
Efrem Zimbalist, Jr. commands the small plane; in 1974 their roles were
reversed for the similar "Airport 1975."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0633423/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>Pete Schnapps</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I saw this movie on television at 2am on a Monday morning. i was so
damn tired, but after the initial 10 minutes i could not look away.
basically through flashbacks we are told the stories of characters on
two planes. how did they get there? what motivates them? will we be
told this? no. no, we won't. random thoughts and odd conversations that
float around in these characters heads don't do much for the story, but
still somehow just manage to keep you interested. the acting is
terrible, the story is foul and confusing and the end is laughable. so
why did i love this movie? was it because there was nothing else on?
yes. that is the answer. if you find yourself in the same situation i'm
sure you'll agree.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur9318697/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mstapleton</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
One aspect of the cast that really intrigued me was actor Tom Gilson
who played Rob Fermi - the actor doing a right on target Marlon Brando
impression and Saundra Edwards who had a very small part as Didi - the
other stewardess along with Anne Francis. Apparently Gilson and Edwards
began dating,married and had a son. On October 6, 1962, Edwards,now
estranged from her husband - shot and killed him as he tried to force
his way into her sister's home. The police had been called to their
home several times in the past because of Gilson's rages while
drinking. Ms. Edwards was cleared of any criminal charges when the
Gilson's death was ruled justifiable homicide. The incident brought her
career to a complete halt. A photo of Tom Gilson and his grave can be
found on the Find A Grave website , more information on Saundra Edwards
can be found on the Glamour Girls of the Silver Screen website. A sad
footnote to this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12012245/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jeanaz8</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
It has been a long time since I saw this movie but it is pretty good. I
keep wondering why it and other airplane disaster movies have not been
released on DVD. Another one I have looked for is Fate is the Hunter.
Maybe it is because of 9/11. The airplanes are obsolete compared to the
kind we fly in today but they are still good movies. The original
airplane disaster movie (not just my opinion) is The High and the
Mighty from 1954 I believe. Maybe it has been released due to the star
being John Wayne. Talk about obsolete planes and the passengers in
Hawaii having to go thru customs as Hawaii was not yet a state. It is
still a great movie with a lot of suspense. The Crowded Sky is the same
type of movie and should be released on DVD. What can I say, I like
this type of movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
And it isn't until all the necessary back stories are told that we get
to the crux of the matter--the fact that an airliner and a two-man jet
plane are on a collision course. DANA ANDREWS is the tense pilot at the
controls of the airliner and EFREM ZIMBALIST, JR. is in the small plane
with TROY DONAHUE.Unfortunately, none of the back stories are really interesting enough
to invoke anything more than moderate interest, but at least we get to
see ANNE FRANCIS as an attractive stewardess saddled with some bad
dialogue and a lifeless romance with JOHN KERR.The story only gets into high gear late in the proceedings and by that
time you'll notice that the storytelling technique is the same one used
to even lesser advantage in THE HIGH AND THE MIGHTY.Summing up: Nothing special but worth a look as an example of what
eventually led to all those Airport movies of the '70s.Trivia note: A diner scene with Troy Donahue and Efrem Zimbalist, Jr.
has the juke box playing "The Theme from A Summer Place," Donahue's hit
film from the year before.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Warner Brothers had an opportunity to exhibit some of its popular
television stars of the period and took it with The Crowded Sky. Though
the plot is very similar to the more well known The High And The
Mighty, The Crowded Sky definitely has enough merit to stand on its own
as good and exciting entertainment.Like The High And The Mighty the crew and passengers of a commercial
airline which consists of pilot Dana Andrews, co-pilot John Kerr,
navigator Joe Mantell, and stewardess Anne Francis are on westbound
flight on one of those old propeller jobs all have their little
vignettes and we see their stories.But the danger here isn't from mechanical failure resulting in a
dangerously low fuel capacity as in The High And The Mighty. Coming
eastbound and heading for them is a navy jet with Efrem Zimbalist, Jr.
and a sailor Troy Donahue who is just hitching a ride with Zimbalist.
These guys were starring in popular Warner Brothers television series
at the time, Zimbalist with 77 Sunset Strip and Donahue leading the
cast of Surfside 6. They too have their stories.Zimbalist's is the most interesting, he's got a neglected wife in
Rhonda Fleming who's been seeking love outside the marriage. Donahue is
heading to marry a girl he's gotten pregnant. Zimbalist has been down
this road before.As for Andrews he's a stickler for protocol and he and Kerr don't get
along because a bad report denied Kerr the captaincy he was seeking.
Among the passengers I liked Patsy Kelly very much as the agent of a
rather vain player in Donald May who also starred in Warner Brothers
Colt 45 television series.The climax with the two planes colliding in midair and the aftermath is
gripping, you will not want to blink for missing something. The special
effects are good for their time and Warner Brothers did accomplish its
purpose of getting its television stars on the big screen for exposure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Warner Brothers had an opportunity to exhibit some of its popular
television stars of the period and took it with The Crowded Sky. Though
the plot is very similar to the more well known The High And The
Mighty, The Crowded Sky definitely has enough merit to stand on its own
as good and exciting entertainment.Like The High And The Mighty the crew and passengers of a commercial
airline which consists of pilot Dana Andrews, co-pilot John Kerr,
navigator Joe Mantell, and stewardess Anne Francis are on westbound
flight on one of those old propeller jobs all have their little
vignettes and we see their stories.But the danger here isn't from mechanical failure resulting in a
dangerously low fuel capacity as in The High And The Mighty. Coming
eastbound and heading for them is a navy jet with Efrem Zimbalist, Jr.
and a sailor Troy Donahue who is just hitching a ride with Zimbalist.
These guys were starring in popular Warner Brothers television series
at the time, Zimbalist with 77 Sunset Strip and Donahue leading the
cast of Surfside 6. They too have their stories.Zimbalist's is the most interesting, he's got a neglected wife in
Rhonda Fleming who's been seeking love outside the marriage. Donahue is
heading to marry a girl he's gotten pregnant. Zimbalist has been down
this road before.As for Andrews he's a stickler for protocol and he and Kerr don't get
along because a bad report denied Kerr the captaincy he was seeking.
Among the passengers I liked Patsy Kelly very much as the agent of a
rather vain player in Donald May who also starred in Warner Brothers
Colt 45 television series.The climax with the two planes colliding in midair and the aftermath is
gripping, you will not want to blink for missing something. The special
effects are good for their time and Warner Brothers did accomplish its
purpose of getting its television stars on the big screen for exposure.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>