<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Macario</original_title><imdb_rating>8.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Mexico</country><director>Roberto Gavaldón</director><producer>Clasa Films Mundiales</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><genre>Mystery</genre><synopsis>
Poor, hungry peasant Macario longs for just one good meal on the Day of the Dead. After his wife cooks a turkey for him...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ignacio López Tarso</actor><actor>Pina Pellicer</actor><actor>Enrique Lucero</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0440091/comments</url><from>from Chicago, Illinois, USA</from><name>Bobs-9</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I was grateful for the rare opportunity to see the 1960 Mexican film
`Macario.'  Without going over the plot again, suffice it to say that it
is
a spooky, black and white film reminiscent of Bunuel's `Los Olvidados' and
Bergman's `The Seventh Seal.'  If that sounds appealing, `Macario' is
definitely for you.  Films with this sort of elemental power, and which
tell
an enthralling story devoid of marketing strategy, focus-group tweaking,
or
commercial gloss are increasingly rare.  When you find one, it's usually
an
old film that you stumble upon by accident (as I did with this one).  It's
always a delight to find an old gem like this one.  Great
film!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0586910/comments</url><from>from Monterrey, Mexico</from><name>valdezlopez (valdezlopez@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
It is said that movie's were made to transport us out of our reality
and immerse us in a different world.When watching Macario I'm happy to say that kind of magic has endured
for this picture since 1960.It has been throughout almost than 45 years, the example of good
Mexican cinema. It has a peculiar effect: this movie begins to make
some distance from the happy, naive and joyful musical movies made in
the Golden Years of Mexica cinema, nonetheless it still lacks the
cynicism and irony of later films.Parallel to the main character behavior, beneath that surface of the
plot and narrative, lies a fully formed story: Even though Macario
speaks little, we know he thinks a reflects a lot.Igancio López Tarso made a classic with is quiet character, and I was
amazed to find in Pina Pellicer one of the most beautiful women in
Mexican movies.It is sad to see movies like this are no longer made. Mysticism has no
place in Mexican cinema right now.(with a few... quite a few, and I mean quite a FEW -near to NONE-
exceptions)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0028450/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn, New York</from><name>jaialai</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
One of the finest Mexican films I have ever seen. The casting is
excellent as each character is perfect for the role chosen. The film
will leave you feeling that justice eventually does prevail. I am
pleased that Ignacio Lopez Tarso is still with us and still acting. It
is a real shame that the actress playing his wife left us so soon. The
wife's love for her husband is so evident in the film as she is totally
unselfish. The actor playing death is superb and will never leave you.
I wish I could find the names of the actors that played the members of
the Court because I believe they may be from Spain and I would like to
look up their other credits. I highly suggest for you to see this
film!!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1531451/comments</url><from>from usa</from><name>shoolaroon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

this is truly a great, and rarely seen movie.  it's beautifully
photographed, wonderfully acted, and has the feel of a classic
grimms brothers fairy tale (although this is too serious a movie for
children).   i was totally unfamiliar with the mexican film industry
and basically only knew mexican wrestler movies, etc.  this proves
that there were and maybe, are, great movies coming out of
mexico that deserve attention and prominence.  great movie - 10
out of 10. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0325386/comments</url><from/><name> (vertraeumen@mindspring.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I know that Mexican cinema has suffered greatly from repulsive movie makers.
Macario is probably "THE" Mexican film that will define the country's cinema
at its best.Macario is a beautiful classic Mexican film about the tale of a poverty
stricken woodcutter. Taking place when Mexico was still under Spanish rule
(For the ignorant reader "a person from Spain!") and racism between
Spaniards and Mexicans took place. The Spaniards are the holders of the
moneymaking businesses, while the Mexicans do the work of the poor.A woodcutter by the name of Macario becomes frustrated of seeing rich people
getting richer and the poor getting poorer. Macario becomes sick of being
hungry all the time. He becomes determined to become rich to make himself
and family happier. One day his wife steals a chicken for her husband
Macario. He kindly accepts and takes it to the wilderness to eat by himself.On the way he encounters the devil dressed as a Mexican gunslinger. The
devil asks Macario to share the chicken with him and in return, he will give
all the land to Macario. Macario refuses and replies by saying "This is not
your land, how can you give me something that is not yours". Macario
continues deeper into the wilderness in hopes to eat his chicken in peace.
He then comes across God disguised as a shepherd. God asks, "Could you
please give me a small morsel of that chicken?" Macario replies "My lord,
you do not need my chicken". Macario finally hides in a cave where he comes
across another man who too asks for some chicken. Macario sees that the man
has not eaten because he is so bony, so Macario kindly shares the chicken.
As the two men finish the chicken, Macario notices that he has shared the
wealth with "Death". Death is grateful and gives him a gift; a canteen
filled with water that will cure any illness.This is one of the most symbolic movies I have ever witnessed. Not realizing
that Mexicans could to great movies they have proved themselves greatly with
this magnificent tale of religion, poverty, and wealth. One of the most
memorable scenes is the valley of candles. Strong character development and
the depressive themes makes this a tale that is not intended for the weak of
heart. A true masterpiece for those who love tales of deals between good and
the dark side of life. See this film in its Castilian tongue (for the
ignorant reader "the official and literary language of Spain based on this
dialect").
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1243480/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>tostinati</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Spoilers --see this great film first.This film will make you feel ashamed for ever being discontented
with your job --which to a certainty is better than poor Macario's,
which is bringing sticks of wood he has cleared from the forest to
a local baker for a few cents a day. His children, of which there are
many, are always hungry. --As is he. Therein hangs the tale. After
going to the baker during the Day of the Dead festivities, and
seeing turkeys baking in his great ovens, Macario vows never to
eat again, until he can have a whole turkey to himself, and eat until
he has no trace of hunger left. He proclaims that had he such a
meal, he would not share with anyone, not even his children. --Is it
for this un-Christ-like desire, understandable as it is, that Macario
pays during the unwinding of this scenario? I do not know. But the
specters of injustice and death and human want and misery hang
over this film like the thick aroma of cooking food. A candlemaker,
especially busy during the Day of the Dead, tells Macario he
should buy candles for the dead to show respect and pity,
because, as he puts it, "We spend a lot more time dead than
alive." That is perhaps the signal line of dialogue in this sad,
thought- provoking film. Ten stars. See it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2843647/comments</url><from>from Noctropolis</from><name>insomniac_rod</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I am ashamed to admit that I didn't find about "Macario" until 2000
when it gained some attention because "Amores Perros" was about to get
nominated for Best Foreign Picture at the Academy Awards. "Macario"
went to the spot light because it was Mèxico's first movie to get
nominated for such an award. So I took away my prejudgments towards
classic movies and I tracked down a "Macario" DVD.And I am extremely glad that this movie has worldwide recognition
because it truly is one of Mexico's best movies of all time (if not the
best)."Macario" is more than a fairy tale with macabre overtones such as
displaying The Devil, or The Death. No, "Macario" has a social and
humanitarian message PLUS it displays in a beautiful way Mexican
culture towards the dead and how we (Mexicans) feel about Death.
There's also a strong criticism against authorities and noble titles in
the 18th century. This movie is rich in all the sense of the word.Meet Macario, a Mexican campesino or land worker who isn't completely
happy with his life because he desires what rich people have;
specifically, eating turkey. Macario works hard for his family but it
isn't enough for establishing a life full of comfort.One good day, Macario's wife gets a turkey for him; a turkey that cost
her a lot of effort and work. Macario is thrilled and delighted with it
and decides to eat it all by himself, not sharing it. He walks too far
until he gets tired and takes a rest in the woods. On his eating turkey
journey Macario meets Satan, The Death, and God. The three iconic
figures want a bite of that turkey but Macario won't share it. But
Death makes a deal with him... a deal that will give Macario all the
power, money, fame, respect and all the turkey goodies he always
wished. But in exchange for what? True, he will be the savior for many
souls but will also risk his own soul.I don't want to give much away from this wonderful piece of cinema. It
is a tender tale with dark overtones and Horror references but to be
honest, this is more of a fantasy story displaying interesting facts of
Mexican culture.Ignacio Lòpez Tarso delivers an amazing performance as Macario. That's
all I can say about him. He's the master. Also Pilar Pellicer delivers
a great performance. Too bad that she committed suicide at such a young
age.The direction is flawless and sometimes looks way ahead of it's time.
The same with the fantastic art direction and cinematography. The final
scene where Macario is in front of thousands of candles it's a visually
stunning and rich piece of art direction and cinematography. A
memorable movie designed to charm everybody.Please watch "Macario" if you haven't. You won't find a better Mexican
movie than this. It has everything to become a favorite.To be honest, I haven't seen it in 3 or 4 years but some scenes just
keep repeating in my memory. This is a memorable movie in all the sense
of the word. This movie makes me proud of being Mexican.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2630196/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>Prof-Hieronymos-Grost</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Macario is a simple peasant, struggling to make ends meet. He gathers
firewood in the nearby woods, to sell at market to help feed his large
family. However no matter how hard he works, he still finds his
children are starving and this hits him hard. With the Day of the Dead
festival approaching, he finds it difficult to take that wealthy
families are able to make such large offerings of food to their
deceased relatives, while he and his family can barely get the bones of
a good meal together. He goes on a hunger strike so that his children
can have his share, this naturally worries his wife. His wife presents
him with a large Turkey for him to eat all by himself, a craving he had
confided in her some days previous, he gladly takes it and sets off
into the forest to eat it before he starts his working day. Suddenly a
man appears all dressed in black, the man beckons him to share the
turkey, but despite the man offering him immense wealth in return,
Macario refuses. Macario is then confronted by a bearded man dressed in
white, again he is asked to share his feast, but Macario refuses yet
again. Hungry and more frustrated Macario goes deeper into the forest,
where once more he is asked for a share or the turkey, this time by a
starving peasant, this time Macario agrees, the man is delighted and
offers Macario a rare and special gift in return, he fills his flask
with water from a spring and tells him that but one drop from the flask
will cure any illness, with one proviso, that the third man will appear
at the foot of the bed of the ailing if they are to be cured, but if he
appears at the head of the bed, then they must die. Macario gets a
reputation as a healer after saving his own sons life and after helping
a local richman to save his dying wife, they go into business together
and Macario is soon just as wealthy, as people from all walks of life
arriving in his town looking for a cure make donations in thanks. Not
everyone is happy however, the towns doctor and coffin maker find
business hard to come by and its not long before Macario is reported to
the Inquisition, they have him arrested and against the odds he must
prove he is not a heretic or a sorcerer, his life depends on it. After two years of gathering dust on a shelf, i decided it was finally
time to watch this highly rated Mexican film. A tale of poor peasants
struggling to get by is not the most attractive of premises to me, so i
was quite surprised at how the film immediately struck a chord. From
the opening credits where peasants carry skulls in a Day of the Dead
procession, i was hooked, as visually the film is a real treat.
Gavaldon is a multi award winning director and it shows, the film is
beautifully structured, the story is unfolded with impeccable pace as
both visuals and characters are given equal importance, a striking
dream sequence with skeletal marionettes and the grand hall of the
Inquisition being particularly memorable. There's a wealth of
characters that are all interesting to watch, their plights are
intriguing to follow as they struggle with differing lessons in life.
The film is full of symbolism and metaphor, some of which even Macario
is aware of, in particular concerning the three strangers he meets. The
First being a metaphor for Evil, Greed and represented by a Satan
figure, The second representing Good, Generosity and represented by a
God figure, the third one would seem to be an Angel of Death, The Grim
Reaper, Starvation and represented by the lost soul of a peasant. Like
in a Christmas Carol, All three come back to haunt Macario, giving him
guidance or leading him astray and guiding him to his ultimate fate. Macario is a wonderfully captivating film, that has plenty of great
horror imagery, it has a great fantasy element too and also delivers
some good wholesome life lessons, both comic and tragic and is pretty
much intriguing on every level, i loved it. It also has a fantastic
twist at the end.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2954240/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jjedif</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"Macario", the movie, is a fairly faithful adaptation of a very good
short story and worth seeing. The movie is suspenseful and the
characters real. However, it really stinks that the movie makers
changed the provenance of Macario's turkey, which his wife bought with
money that she had saved up over the years (I'm guessing that someone
either thought that an Indian saving up money was not believable or
possible, or that an Indian stealing the turkey was more exciting
and/or somehow more believable). B. Traven's "The Night Visitor and
Other Stories" and "Canasta de cuentos mexicanos" are must-reads for
the Traven fan. The story in the later book of the priest who tries in
vane to convert a group of Indians is a fantastic story about what is
wrong with western religion.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2954240/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jjedif</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"Macario", the movie, is a fairly faithful adaptation of a very good
short story and worth seeing. The movie is suspenseful and the
characters real. However, it really stinks that the movie makers
changed the provenance of Macario's turkey, which his wife bought with
money that she had saved up over the years (I'm guessing that someone
either thought that an Indian saving up money was not believable or
possible, or that an Indian stealing the turkey was more exciting
and/or somehow more believable). B. Traven's "The Night Visitor and
Other Stories" and "Canasta de cuentos mexicanos" are must-reads for
the Traven fan. The story in the later book of the priest who tries in
vane to convert a group of Indians is a fantastic story about what is
wrong with western religion.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2954240/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jjedif</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/macario-mexicos-oscar-nominee/ /m/macario/comments.php?reviewid=1992282</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B+
					</rating><comment>Gabriel Figueroa's cinematography is the best element of this Mexican folk tale, which was the country's first nominee for Foreign Language Oscar.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/macario.htm /m/macario/comments.php?reviewid=1396030</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>First Mexican production to earn an Oscar nomination for Best Foreign Film.</comment></review></movie>