<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>High Time</original_title><imdb_rating>5.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Blake Edwards</director><producer>Bing Crosby Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Musical</genre><synopsis>
Widower and hamburger restaurateur Harvey Howard decides to go to college at 51 years of age. Resisting the easy path...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Bing Crosby</actor><actor>Fabian</actor><actor>Tuesday Weld</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5337448/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>legwarmers1980</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This Bing Crosby film is just a good old time of fun. A great Sunday
evening movie on a rainy night. Bing is great in one of his best screen roles. He captures the humor
separating the generations, yet in the end shows that there really
wasn't much difference after all. High Times captures the college life of the late 1950s, a time of fun,
enjoyment, friendships, and romance. The movie captures a time before
drugs, booze, and hazing turned into the Animal House of the 70s and
the dismal destruction of today. One of the film's best scenes was Bing
in drag for his frat party.So, if you like Bing Crosby, college fun, light comedy, romantic fluff,
you will enjoy watching High Times.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is one of the best Bing Crosby's later films.  He only gets to
sing
two songs in it, The Second Time Around and It Came Upon A Midnight Clear
during a Christmas hayride with some of the rest of his
younger
cast members.Bing is 53 year old Harvey Howard, self made millionaire restaurantfranchise owner, who's decided to go back and do a lot of the thingshe missed when he was younger which included a college education. 
That
in itself is an intriguing character for me.  I've met a lot of
self
made types in my life who think because they are successful and make
a
lot of money in one field, they're omnicompetent.  Just the fact
that
Harvey Howard IS going back to college to improve himself
intellectually
and broaden his horizons is a plus for me with this character.I read an interview with Fabian once who said that Bing was great towork with and put him right at ease.  Fabian had just done one
feature
film called Hound Dog Man and it was less than a success.  After
High
Time he went on to a pretty good career in films during the
sixties.The Second Time Around was the last of 15 songs that Bing introduced
in
films that was nominated for an Academy Award, a record not likely
to
be broken.  It lost to Never On Sunday.  It was a million selling
song,
but ironically not by Bing.  Frank Sinatra took the song and he made
it
a big hit, probably the only time in Bing's career this ever
happened.The kids are just fine, Fabian, Tuesday Weld, Richard Beymer (a
year
away from West Side Story)Patrick Adiarte.  Gavin MacLeod has some
very
funny moments as Bing's comic nemesis and absent minded chemistryprofessor and Nicole Maurey strikes the right note as the French teacher
that widower Crosby falls for.A really great feel-good movie.   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1591795/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>alc01</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A fun romp of a 50 year old Bing Crosby returning to college after becoming
a multi-millionaire.  He seeks to be just one of the gang.  I really enjoy
this Blake Edwards "clean" movie.  A "Happy Days" type look at life in the
late 50's or early 60's.Of course Tuesday Weld and Fabian add spice but it is Gavin MacLeod that
steals many scenes.  (Is it just me or has anyone else notice how the
younger he was when the movie was made, the older he looks? And the older he
gets the younger he looks?)It is just a plain fun easy time with lots of giggles and a few good
laughs.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1293671/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn, NY</from><name>Maureen Finebesser (m.finebesser@ivillage.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Bing Crosby plays a millionaire in his sunset days who decides to get his
college degree.  It is very reminiscent of the 1982 Dangerfield vehicle,
Back To School, only this one has entertaining songs in addition to light
screwball comedy.  This is a very good movie to relax to when you're in a
mode to laugh, smile, and avoid anything challenging.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0231348/comments</url><from>from Louisville, Colorado</from><name>William Kucharski</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I discovered this delightful film in the late 1980s when I saw it on TV
and enjoyed it immensely. Bing Crosby gives a wonderful performance in
this film and exudes a warmth much like that in "White Christmas"
(1954) and Nicole Maurey does an excellent job as his French
teacher/love interest. The duo of Tuesday Weld and Fabian add 1960 star
power, and this is a great opportunity to see a young Gavin MacLeod and
Yvonne Craig before they became even more famous as TV stars. Patrick
Adiarte is also wonderful as Indian student T.J. Padmanabham. The story
is well crafted and involving and of course family friendly, perhaps
the most family friendly of Blake Edwards' work. The Henry Mancini
soundtrack is IMHO one of his best and will stick with you for a long
time. (It was available on CD but is currently out of print.) Of course
any time you hear a Jimmy Van Heusen/Sammy Cahn song it's a treat, and
"The Second Time Around" is one of their best.As far as highlights, the scene when the gang visits one of Harvey's
own Smokehouses will have you both laughing and pining for a time when
such restaurants existed. You could see the movie's end stunt coming a
mile away, given Harvey's fondness for the key phrase involved, but
it's still wonderful.However, being shot in 2.35:1 CinemaScope, the presentation does suffer
from horrific pan and scan when shown on TV; I've no idea why, given
the success of the virtual remake Back To School, this film hasn't been
released on a widescreen DVD as it deserves; I suspect some type of
conflict with the film or music rights that hopefully will be resolved
soon.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0392403/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name>louis biasiotta (louisb@ameritech.net)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is Bing Crosby at his comical best.  A very over-the-hill millionaire
decides to return to college and get his degree.  He goes through all the
usual trials and tribulations of the normal undergraduate, including
initiations, all-night crash studying, and falling in love.  Unfortunately,
at his age, his "girl" happens to be one of the faculty, and dating or
marrying faculty members is forbidden.   Even his kids (he's widowed) frown
on his decisions and add to the comedy and light drama.  This is one of
director Blake Edward's best.  A wonderful family movie with something for
everyone.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5755522/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vranger</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
High Time is a wonderful Bing Crosby vehicle that has a successful
middle aged businessman with grown children (and a widower) indulging a
whim by taking a step back in his life to get the college education he
missed the first time around.While a seeming slam dunk to be a "fish out of water" comedy, instead
Crosby's character finds a way to integrate successfully with his
younger classmates, learning from them as they also benefit from his
experience.An earlier reviewer, Moonspinner, panned plot points in this movie out
of sheer ignorance. He should actually have some knowledge of a film or
its time before commenting on it. His criticism of the Phys Ed scene is
off base. When I went to college, 15 years AFTER this film, 3 semesters
of Phys Ed were still required, during which you had to do such things
as run a 6 minute mile. Some say ignorance is bliss, but actually
ignorance is just ignorance, spinner.This is a wonderful film that stands up well. Things such as fall
bonfires were and still are common campus traditions. Fraternity
pledging pranks ... still around. Dormitories ... still around.
Hamburger/Barbecue restaurants ... still around. LOLIs the movie a touch simple and innocent compared to modern life and
modern comedy fare? Sure it is. But trust me, that is NOT a bad thing.Sit back and enjoy this very entertaining and relaxing film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6819259/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jeaniebnz</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I caught this movie on the AMC morning movie yesterday. It was
charming, bouncy and fun- everything a good, clean comedy should be. I
enjoyed the music and the wholesome-ness of the show. Too bad we don't
have movies like this made any more. The cast is full of fresh faced
kids (Richard Beymer, Tuesday Weld, Fabian) who later went on to bigger
projects. The storyline is upbeat and it is a pleasure to watch the
time progress in the movie by using holidays and activities as a
dateline. Ben Crosby is generally not a favorite of mine, but I
actually enjoyed him in this role. High Times made me yearn for the
days of simpler times (bonfires, hay rides, cotillions). The remake
(Back to School) is just not the same. High Time is a thoroughly
enjoyable movie to watch!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1340169/comments</url><from>from Marietta, Georgia</from><name>Jeff Weiner</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This movie does two things to you after you have seen it. It make you feel
good and makes you want to go college. Besides being a feel good movie, it
also teaches us a lesson that it is never too late to go forward in life no
matter what age you are as Bing Brosy did so well in this movie. A good
cast
and script, some good music and you have a winner of a movie. No violence
and it does very well for itself. I wish they would make more movies like
this now
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0654152/comments</url><from>from Camano Island, Washington USA</from><name>joe-495 (joe@actionline.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Although I have not seen this film for more years than I can recall, it was
so memorable that I think of it frequently and wish that I could see it
again.  Too bad that so few (if any) films of this quality and calibRE seem
to be made any more.  The theme song, "Love is lovelier the second time
around" was an Academy Award nominee or winner I
believe and deservedly so. High Time would be one of fewer than a dozen
films that I would rate a "10."   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0654152/comments</url><from>from Camano Island, Washington USA</from><name>joe-495 (joe@actionline.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Although I have not seen this film for more years than I can recall, it was
so memorable that I think of it frequently and wish that I could see it
again.  Too bad that so few (if any) films of this quality and calibRE seem
to be made any more.  The theme song, "Love is lovelier the second time
around" was an Academy Award nominee or winner I
believe and deservedly so. High Time would be one of fewer than a dozen
films that I would rate a "10."   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0654152/comments</url><from>from Camano Island, Washington USA</from><name>joe-495 (joe@actionline.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-e-grost/</url><url>http://mikegrost.com/edwards.htm#HighTime /m/high-time/comments.php?reviewid=1951673</url><name>Michael E. Grost</name><from>Classic Film and Television</from></reviewer><comment>Inventive, delightful comedy also has memorable scenes of social protest and commentary.</comment></review></movie>