<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Two Way Stretch</original_title><alt_title>Le paradis des monte-en-l'air</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Robert Day</director><producer>Vale Film Productions</producer><producer>John Harvel Productions</producer><producer>Shepperton Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
Peter Sellers has planned the perfect robbery while in prison. He intends to break out of prison, steal a fortune in diamonds...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Peter Sellers</actor><actor>David Lodge</actor><actor>Bernard Cribbins</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7850750/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>ianlouisiana</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Despite "Two way stretch" usually being described as a "Peter Sellers
film" it is an ensemble piece featuring some of the best British
character actors of the 1950s and 60s.Maurice Denham,George
Woodbridge,Thorley Walters,Wilfred Hyde-White and the wonderful Lionel
Jefferies decorate this movie.Mr Jefferies in particular was never
better than as CPO Crout the slightly mad successor to the kind-hearted
veteran George Woodbridge. "Basket weaving?.....I'll get you baskets
weaving !" he rants on being told that the cons are being taught that
country craft. The usual lovable Cockneys and middle-class dunderheads
make up the rest of the cast. It is the sort of film knocked out in a
few weeks for silly money that the British Film Industry once excelled
at.It wasn't "Great Art" but it was great fun.Now you need millions
from the Lottery to make something a first-year Film Studies person
would leave on the cutting-room floor. "Two way stretch " had no sex,no
violence and no bad language,three of the requisites for comedy writers
these days.It still makes a lot of people laugh.Not many modern
comedies do.Is this a "Duh" moment?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0918963/comments</url><from>from Liverpool, England</from><name>ianski-4 (ianski@btinternet.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

A wonderful film, a classic with so many brilliant performances from
almost
everybody involved.A clever plot with a plan so cunning you are willing the "bad guys" to get
away with it. It stands the test of time and seemed to improve with every
viewing. Sellers, David Lodge and Bernard Cribbins are likeable rogues and
Lionel Jeffries fits the sadistic warder part like a glove. Liz Fraser and
Irene Handel are their usual excellent selves and Wilfred Hyde White shows
his versatility throughout.A splendid film - when it's scheduled for TV again, watch it or tape it -
an
underrated British Classic!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1090123/comments</url><from/><name>grstmc</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

     This effort may not have been all that taxing on the considerable
talents of the great Peter Sellers, but the character of Dodger Lane is an
original, and the star gives a sly, confident performance as an unreformed
"model prisoner" and untrustworthy trustee.     TWO-WAY STRETCH involves a trio of prison cell-mates who help to devise
a crime with a twist.  All they have to do is sneak out on the night before
they're due to be released, pull off their latest heist, and then return
before being missed, thereby providing themselves with a foolproof alibi in
addition to their ill-gotten gains.     Huntleigh Prison is a very liberal institution, and Dodger (Sellers)
takes full advantage of this, making his cell a home away from home.  With
the assistance of his two partners, Lennie Price (Bernard Cribbins) and
Jelly Knight (David Lodge), he's practically running the place, and the
three of them make a great comic team.     They don't plan on having any trouble sneaking out of Huntleigh, but
that was before the appointment of the new head guard, Sidney "Sour" Crout
(played by Lionel Jeffries), a tough disciplinarian, who barks rather than
speaks.  Why, he even expects the inmates to actually do some work in the
rock quarry . . .before the arrival of their morning newspaper.  Although
Crout's presence disrupts their escape plans, the intrepid Dodger refuses to
give up.     Also on hand is old reliable Wilfrid Hyde-White as Soapy Stevens, a
crony who enlists Dodger for the heist; Maurice Denham as the hopelessly
well-meaning warden; Irene Handl as crooked Ma Price; and the indispensable
Liz Fraser as Ethel, Dodger's shapely girlfriend.     Everything clicks and there is never a dull moment in this hilarious
comedy.  There's nothing profound or insightful about it but that's one of
the reasons why it's good.  My rating of TWO-WAY STRETCH is a definite four
stars out of five.          
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0069858/comments</url><from/><name>bobj-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

One of a brace of classic comedies to come out of Britain in the late
50s-early 60s, "Two-Way Stretch" combines all the elements: great comic
actors, tight little story line, fast pace, and not overbroad slapstick.
Sellers, Cribbins, and Jeffries reprise (sort of!) their roles in "Wrong
Arm
of the Law," with Sellers and Cribbins the crooks and Jeffries
representing
the Law.  But this time Jeffries is a delightfully wicked "screw," out to
"get" the two lay-about inmates in any way he can.  A brilliant piece of
work, as was his more "Clouseau"-like performance in "Wrong Arm."  And
kudos
to Wilfrid Hyde-White, masterminding the whole thing from his vantage
point
as a venal vicar!  As usual, there is strong support, as well, from the
unsung females, the buxom and zany Liz Fraser as Sellers' girlfriend,
Ethel,
and the incomparable Irene Handl as Cribbins "mum."  A delight
all-round!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2876002/comments</url><from>from March (or Die), ENGLAND</from><name>johnson50</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A very influential film in the history of the British cinema that spawned
one of the most popular TV series that there has ever been in
Britain.The characters are all wonderful. Peter Sellers as the suave and crafty
Dodger, Bernard Cribbins as the not too bright Lenny, David Lodge as the
old
lag Jelly, Lionel Jeffries in a masterful performance as Mr. Crout (who
bears more than a passing resemblance to Hitler), Wilfred Hyde White as
the
slippery and devious Soapy Stevens and, my favourite, Liz Fraser as the
ravishing Ethel. Most of these characters plus others were lifted
wholesale
from the film, with name changes, to form the cast of the hit TV series
'Porridge', still one of the funniest things on British TV, even 30 years
down the line.The plot is inventive and extremely silly, if a little predictable, and
there are plenty of laughs even if some of the vehicles are pretty well
tried. The film stands the test of time well I feel. The characters are
well
stereotyped and so live on and prison doesn't change much, I suppose, and
so
it retains its relevance.Quite what non-British viewers would make of it, I'm not sure, as there is
much British slang in the dialogue and much of it would be meaningless,
but
if you can get round that, this film is well worth a watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0730547/comments</url><from>from Dublin, Ireland</from><name>Garrett McGovern</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This 1960 M. Smedley Aston production has everything lovers of classic
British comedy could hope for.Sellers plays Dodger Lane,a lag who is
having
such a cushy time in the clink he couldn't care less whether he gets out
or
not.'Rooming' with two old chums they plan an unlikely heist of priceless
diamonds while still inside.
This is probably my favourite Sellers comedy of all
time
with marvellous performances from all concerned.Star of the show, hands
down,has to be Lionel Jeffries as the hard-boiled prison officer 'Crouty'
who is hell-bent on making the lads last few days of incarceration as
miserable as possible.
If you haven't seen this movie you're in for a treat.Forget
Inspector Clouseau,this is the definitive Peter Sellers.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2549960/comments</url><from>from Nottingham, England</from><name>John Downes</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I found this film hilarious when I first saw it on general release as a
small boy, and if anything I find it even funnier now. This film is
listed as an early Peter Sellars vehicle, but his fans should be warned
that the great Lionel Jeffries steals every scene he is in, starring as
the disciplinarian Chief Prison Officer Sidney Crout, "The most evil
twisted screw that ever crept down a prison corridor". Great
performances too from David Lodge, Bernard Cribbins, Maurice Denham,
Irene Handl and Wilfred Hyde-White make this a real repertory ensemble
production. And what a witty script. Definitely one of my top ten
favourite films of all time (and I bet it didn't cost more than
£100,000 to make).EditHow could I omit to mention the ravishing Liz Fraser? Funny and
gorgeous!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2863432/comments</url><from>from Lincoln England</from><name>Stephen Bailey (diana@bailey6770.fsnet.co.uk)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

(Small SPOILERS):Now why can't we Brits make films like this any more.
Hilarious. Peter Sellers is a prison inmate and along with his 2 buddies
they plan a robbery with the ultimate alibi; they break out of jail, do the
deed and then slip back in before anyone's the wiser. At least, that was the
theory. Lionel Jeffries plays a deliciously horrible "screw" and the whole
caper is masterminded by Wilfred Hyde White (RIP) as "Soapie Stevens", a
fake vicar. I don't want to give away any details which might spoil it,
however, the scene where Chief Officer Crout finally recognises Soapie at
the rail station is an absolute classic. No one in the history of cinema has
EVER uttered "Cor Blimey" with more conviction :) I agree with what others
have said, that this movie probably inspired the - equally wonderful - tv
series Porridge, 14 years later. It's a shame that all the reviews of this
film have come from British folks. I'd like to see what Americans make of
it? Anyway, a lovely classic British comedy. Look out for Warren Mitchell in
a small early role as the prison's slimey tailor. Who'd ever guess Alf
Garnett was actually Jewish? 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5232598/comments</url><from>from Dundee, Scotland</from><name>ShootingShark</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
A trio of convicts, Dodger, Jelly and Lennie, get involved in a diamond
heist with the ultimate alibi - they plan to break out of prison, nick
the swag, and then break back in. However, their plans are given a
serious setback when the kindly chief guard retires and is replaced by
the pathologically meticulous Sidney "Sour" Crout ...This is a classic British comedy, with a fantastic script by John
Warren and Len Heath. The central idea, the characters and the dialogue
are all brilliant, as is the wonderful cast. Sellers is tremendous, at
that perfect point in his career where he was totally focused but not
yet overcome with international stardom, and Jeffries gives the
quintessential ramrod-back, no-nonsense, bark-at-everything, British
comedy authority figure ("Silence when you're talking to me !!" he
screams at a prisoner). White, Cribbins and Handl are especially
terrific - there's a lovely visiting-day scene where Handl is berating
Cribbins for bringing the family name into disrepute by not attempting
to escape more often. The movie is full of wonderful banter ("Close the
window Lennie, there's a bit of a George Raft coming in."), and each
sequence builds beautifully into a wonderful comedy heist picture. This
film, which I always consider a companion piece to the equally
brilliant The Wrong Arm Of The Law, represents the very best of British
film comedy, nestling somewhere between Ealing and Monty Python. Magic.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0008691/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, England</from><name>Megabuck</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Describing a film as 'lightweight' shouldn't always be seen as a criticism.
Two Way Stretch deserves the description, but it should be seen as praise
rather than a put-down.Back in the 50s and 60s, the British film industry seemed able to churn out
these comedy films at the drop of a hat. The Ealing Comedies are the best
known, but there are also any number starring Norman Wisdom, and also a few
gems with Peter Sellers in them.Sellers takes the leading role here, that of a criminal in the last weeks of
his sentence. He and his three cell mates are drawn into a daring robbery -
one that involves them breaking out the night before their release, then
breaking back in again, thereby ensuring they have a watertight
alibi.
Just about every character in the film is a caricature - the kind-hearted
chief warder, the bumbling prison governor intent on seeing only the best in
everyone, the army chief in charge of moving the jewels. Yet it all works,
so long as you don't go in expecting some significant piece of
cinema.An excellent cast, with Sellers on top form. Maurice Denham, as the
governor, Lionel Jeffries, as the control-freak warder, and Wilfred
Hyde-White, as the crook planning the robbery, are worth singling
out.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0008691/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, England</from><name>Megabuck</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Describing a film as 'lightweight' shouldn't always be seen as a criticism.
Two Way Stretch deserves the description, but it should be seen as praise
rather than a put-down.Back in the 50s and 60s, the British film industry seemed able to churn out
these comedy films at the drop of a hat. The Ealing Comedies are the best
known, but there are also any number starring Norman Wisdom, and also a few
gems with Peter Sellers in them.Sellers takes the leading role here, that of a criminal in the last weeks of
his sentence. He and his three cell mates are drawn into a daring robbery -
one that involves them breaking out the night before their release, then
breaking back in again, thereby ensuring they have a watertight
alibi.
Just about every character in the film is a caricature - the kind-hearted
chief warder, the bumbling prison governor intent on seeing only the best in
everyone, the army chief in charge of moving the jewels. Yet it all works,
so long as you don't go in expecting some significant piece of
cinema.An excellent cast, with Sellers on top form. Maurice Denham, as the
governor, Lionel Jeffries, as the control-freak warder, and Wilfred
Hyde-White, as the crook planning the robbery, are worth singling
out.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0008691/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, England</from><name>Megabuck</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1444332</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1299888</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117795979.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1807413</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/79970/two-way_stretch.html /m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1482654</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9903E1DA1739EE32A25757C2A9679C946091D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1388488</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=109672 /m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1249692</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pat-graham/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/8724_TWO_WAY_STRETCH.html /m/twoway_stretch/comments.php?reviewid=1249690</url><name>Pat Graham</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>