<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>'Carry on Constable'</original_title><imdb_rating>6.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Gerald Thomas</director><producer>Peter Rogers Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
With a flu epidemic running rife, three new bumbling recruits are assigned to Inspector Mills police station...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Kenneth Williams</actor><actor>Sid James</actor><actor>Eric Barker</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2171244/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lastliberal</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Joan Sims (The Last of the Blonde Bombshells) the gym teacher in Carry
On teacher is here as a constable. Just out of the Academy and wanting
to do a good job. Unfortunately, she has caught the eye of a fellow
copper.Shirley Eaton from Goldfinger is also here looking as good as ever.The usual antics and sight gags with the normal Carry On gang; only
this time in a police station. Bonus nudity that has not been in any of
the other ones I have seen. Sorry, it bare butts on guys running to the
shower.It is kind of cute, even if the formula stays pretty much the same,
just in different locations.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0731316/comments</url><from>from Urmston, Manchester, UK</from><name>dis-6</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This was the fourth of the Carry On series and although dated by the police
uniforms is one of the best simply because all of the regulars are equally
well used and for once Sid James is kept under control and used as a foil
for some of the situations which works well with his expressive face.
Kenneth Williams is still in the intellectual role which eventually gave
way
to the over-the-top persona in the later films. Leslie Phillips gels well
with the others ( even better than he did in Carry On Teacher
)If anything this film underuses the female stalwarts with Hattie Jacques
and
Joan Sims being love interests.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239310/comments</url><from>from Norwich, England</from><name>Bing-18 (n.ferris@uea.ac.uk)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

This is one of the first Carry-On films and, consequently is one of the
best. The chemistry of the stars is already there and Connor's as the
superstitious constable in love with a co-workers from afar, and Williams as
the scientific deduction 'expert' both shine above the rest.Sid James is surprisingly poorly used as the Sargeant supervising the chaos,
but still a very funny movie throughout and one which should be included in
anybody's Carry-On collection.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur12210023/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>nellybly-3</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
This was the first Carry On movie I ever saw and that was by accident.
My father took me (10 years old) and my brother (4 years old) with him.
He was wanting to see a Danny Kaye movie. It was probably during the
summer otherwise I wouldn't have been going to a picture show at night,
especially in the middle of the week when the program changed. What I
remembered most clearly the shower scene. When the movie hit
television, part of that scene was cut out (three guesses, first two
don't count, as to which part).It was shown as a double feature with "Please Turn Over". What _was_ my
father thinking??? It was both of those movies that started my love
affair with British comedies. Though I never again saw any of the Carry
On movies in a theater, I did see most of the '50s-early '60s
installments on television. Sometimes I wonder what I missed since TV
at that time (1960s) wouldn't have shown certain things (such as that
"au natural" part of the shower scene).The Carry On movies haven't been shown in the U.S. in several years. :(
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13977076/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Tweekums</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This early outing for the Carry On team includes many of the regulars
including Sid James, Kenneth Williams, Charles Hawtrey, Hattie Jacques,
and Joan Sims. This time they are police officers. When many of the
officers at a small police station go down with the 'flu four some
recruits are drafted in; their first day does not go well when they
accidentally help a group of thieves before they have even arrived at
the police station! The three new coppers are the superstitious PC
Constable, womanising PC Potter and PC Benson who believes that
criminals can be detected by their facial appearance. The fourth new
recruit is WPC Passworthy; the only one who is competent. The first
hour of the film just follows the recruits and their sergeant as they
get to know their beats and have amusing dealings with the public and
the last half hour gives them the chance to prove their worth when a
wages robbery takes place on their patch.While there weren't too many laugh out load moments there were a decent
number of chuckles to be had and the cast did a good job; it was nice
to see Sid James playing a character that wasn't devious or lecherous.
The jokes do seem very innocent by today's standards; even when Leslie
Phillips' character bursts in on a woman taking a shower nothing even
slightly naughty is shown. This innocence means the film is suitable
for people of all ages; in fact I suspect children might enjoy it even
more than adults due to the slapstick elements.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20552756/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>TheLittleSongbird</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I enjoy the Carry on movies, they are entertaining, cheeky and witty
and make my day when I need it. While a tad too short and rather basic
and cookie-cutter in the story structure, this fourth entry known as
Carry on Constable is an enjoyable one and lifted by the Carry on debut
of regular Sid James, and he is funny as always. The rest of the cast
are rock solid as well with Kenneth Williams and Joan Sims especially
standing out. The writing is cheeky in alternative to smutty, a trait
that plagued some of the later entries, and while not the original on
the block the gags are equally amusing. The film looks good too with
nice locations and the like, musically it is quite quirky and it is
snappily directed. Overall, very enjoyable. 8/10 Bethany Cox
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1864966/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>w22nuschler</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Sid James makes a stellar debut as a police sergeant constantly under
fire from his boss. He must manage four new recruits because of a flu
epidemic that has hit the regular officers. The four are played by
Kenneth Conner, Kenneth Williams, Charles Hawtrey &amp; Leslie Phillips.
Hattie Jacques also plays a sergeant and Joan Sims plays a lady
constable. Shirley also shows up in her last Carry On. The men use the
cells as their place to sleep. There is a quick scene of bare butts
when the men get into a cold shower. That scene was not needed. I was
shocked to see that in a movie made in 1960. This is a different role
for Sid James. He usually plays the guy causing trouble and here he
must keep things under control. The four guys have some funny moments
that make this an enjoyable entry. Add Sid James and you can't lose, he
is the best. I root for him when he plays the bad guy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7058339/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>petersj-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
The wonderful thing about watching some of these lovely early Carry ON
movies is the small cameos of wonderful British actors. Some were never
really house hold names but the thing is that every time they appeared
in a movie they would light up and bring something very special to even
the most mediocre movies. Esma Cannon as a deaf old woman in this movie
is a superb example. This lovely actress always added something very
special to every film she was in and after reading the biog on IMDb she
had what looks like an incredibly impressive career. Joan Hickson just
about steals the film as the tipsy lady fond of a tickle of booze. She
is absolutely fabulous. We all know in later years she played a very
understated Miss Marple but in this movie you see her at her glorious
best.The great Irene Handl is there too and she lifted every film she
was in. Miss Handl came to Australia to star in Goodnight Mrs Puffin
and BusyBody. She was a brilliant actress but few would know who she
was by name. Sid James is less tacky in this movie and I really enjoyed
him in this. Kenneth Connor is still rather annoying and I still find
him the weak link. I wonder if the shower scene in this film is the
first time we saw some bum in a movie. Its very brief. The Hawtrey and
Williams drag scene when they go under cover is delightful. Hawtrey
remains my personal favourite, he was indeed camper in this than the
early ones. Hatti Jaques and Joan Sims are wonderful as always. Hatti
is becoming my favourite apart from Hawtrey. It is interesting to see
Sid James before they made his characters tackier and tackier. I found
this a very pleasant little romp, I cant say I really laughed but I did
enjoy it The production values considering the budget in these films
was very impressive. For me its the small cameos I loved the most.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I wasn’t as taken with this one as the three previous “Carry Ons” I
watched: truth be told, law and order is one of the most popular themes
with star comedians (Chaplin’s EASY STREET [1917], Keaton’s COPS
[1922], Laurel &amp; Hardy’s THE MIDNIGHT PATROL [1933], Will Hay’s ASK A
POLICEMAN [1939], Norman Wisdom’s ON THE BEAT [1962], etc.), so it
couldn’t very well fail to find an audience – but I also felt the level
of gags this time around to be curiously uninventive! The film marks the series debut of Sidney James as a police sergeant
under duress (and constantly threatened with a transfer by Inspector
Eric Barker) during a flu epidemic who’s assigned a quartet of rookies
to help him – the trouble is that these are none other than Kenneth
Connor, Kenneth Williams, Leslie Philips and Charles Hawtrey (the
station, apparently, is so hard-up that the prison cells are to serve
as their quarters)! The boys deliver their typical schtick: Connor is
nervous as the constable whose last name happens to be Constable (and
especially given his uncommonly superstitious nature), Williams is a
snobbish know-it-all (he figures himself an expert in picking out
criminal types – except that the one he approaches to steer on the path
of righteousness turns out to be Scotland Yard man Victor Maddern!),
Philips the lothario (he falls for a pretty blonde policewoman – but
who conveniently comes down with the flu to make way for series
stalwart Joan Sims – and then offers advise to guest star Shirley Eaton
on matters of romance), while Hawtrey is the prissy but wisecracking
member. Cyril Chamberlain is on hand once more, and CARRY ON NURSE
(1959)’s Terence Longdon cameos as a confidence trickster plying his
trade on rookie Williams.Again, there’s some tentative romance among the regulars – with James
hitting it off with female sergeant Hattie Jacques and, as ever, Connor
aching to attract the attention of a serious-minded colleague (in this
case, Sims). As for flaws, I guess it boils down to a basic lack of
plot: the film practically resolves itself into a series of sketches,
some of which even turn repetitious – such as the rookies walking
Barker’s dog or bursting into houses only to be met by scantily-clad
females (which is how Eaton herself is belatedly introduced), while
their helping old ladies in various ways is either unappreciated or
greeted with outright hostility. Predictably, too, the quartet finally
makes amends by taking the initiative to capture a gang of crooks.
Incidentally, the film features some surprising male nudity as the
rookies – intending to take an early-morning shower – are scalded and
run out in panic; in the same vein, there’s definite camp value to
seeing Williams and Hawtrey in drag (having gone undercover to catch
potential shoplifters)! All in all, however, I must admit that I’m having a great time with
these early “Carry Ons” – which I find generally more rewarding than
the later bawdier, i.e. rather tasteless, entries.P.S. For some reason, the on-screen title of this one includes a comma
after the “Carry On” epithet.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
With a flu epidemic decimating the ranks of the local bobbies, the
police are forced to quickly take on some new recruits who in other
circumstances may not have quite made the ranks – a decision made by
Inspector Mills and then dumped on Sergeant Wilkins to deal with.
However not even Wilkins' low expectations are met when at least a
handful of the new recruits turn out to be barely able to manage
themselves, never mind the wider community.This is quite an enjoyable little film that is never funny but manages
to be amusing if you are in the mood for a light, dated comedy. The
story is simply a rerun of Carry on Sergeant in the way that an
efficient Sergeant (in this case Sid James) is charged with turning a
bunch of bumbling, inept recruits (this time into the police) into an
effective unit of men, encountering much amusing bumbling along the way
(with even some of the same actors playing the same sort of
characters). In this regard it is pretty much a cookie-cutter of a
story but to look down on the film for being unoriginal and basic is to
really miss the point when it comes to the Carry On films. Aside from
the poor story, the film is actually quite amusing but never really
made me laugh more than once or twice; certainly those not in a
forgiving mood will dislike this because it doesn't have much life to
it but those looking for a movie for a wet Saturday afternoon will
maybe enjoy it.The cast are a selling point and do manage to do quite a bit with the
basic material even if they don't raise it that much. Sid James has a
minor role in his first Carry On film and, although he is a good
presence, he is less effective than he was in other films. Barker is a
nice straightman and holds up that side well enough while the main
comedy is brought off by the recruits themselves. Connor repeats his
"uptight and resisting love" performance to reasonable effect. Hawtrey
and Williams do good work with their usual stuff (Williams playing
upper-class early in the series) while Phillips makes a nice addition
with his usual stuff. Sims and Jacques are OK but have very little to
do around the edges but are nice filler.Overall this is nothing special but it is amusing in its own way
despite never making me laugh. The script does throw up a few nice
touches and is cheeky rather than smutty or anything like that and,
despite being a rerun of Carry On Sergeant, it is still enjoyable in a
rather amusing and light sort of way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
With a flu epidemic decimating the ranks of the local bobbies, the
police are forced to quickly take on some new recruits who in other
circumstances may not have quite made the ranks – a decision made by
Inspector Mills and then dumped on Sergeant Wilkins to deal with.
However not even Wilkins' low expectations are met when at least a
handful of the new recruits turn out to be barely able to manage
themselves, never mind the wider community.This is quite an enjoyable little film that is never funny but manages
to be amusing if you are in the mood for a light, dated comedy. The
story is simply a rerun of Carry on Sergeant in the way that an
efficient Sergeant (in this case Sid James) is charged with turning a
bunch of bumbling, inept recruits (this time into the police) into an
effective unit of men, encountering much amusing bumbling along the way
(with even some of the same actors playing the same sort of
characters). In this regard it is pretty much a cookie-cutter of a
story but to look down on the film for being unoriginal and basic is to
really miss the point when it comes to the Carry On films. Aside from
the poor story, the film is actually quite amusing but never really
made me laugh more than once or twice; certainly those not in a
forgiving mood will dislike this because it doesn't have much life to
it but those looking for a movie for a wet Saturday afternoon will
maybe enjoy it.The cast are a selling point and do manage to do quite a bit with the
basic material even if they don't raise it that much. Sid James has a
minor role in his first Carry On film and, although he is a good
presence, he is less effective than he was in other films. Barker is a
nice straightman and holds up that side well enough while the main
comedy is brought off by the recruits themselves. Connor repeats his
"uptight and resisting love" performance to reasonable effect. Hawtrey
and Williams do good work with their usual stuff (Williams playing
upper-class early in the series) while Phillips makes a nice addition
with his usual stuff. Sims and Jacques are OK but have very little to
do around the edges but are nice filler.Overall this is nothing special but it is amusing in its own way
despite never making me laugh. The script does throw up a few nice
touches and is cheeky rather than smutty or anything like that and,
despite being a rerun of Carry On Sergeant, it is still enjoyable in a
rather amusing and light sort of way.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>