<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Day They Robbed the Bank of England</original_title><alt_title>Jour où l'on dévalisa la banque d'Angleterre</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>John Guillermin</director><producer>Summit Film Productions</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
London at the turn of the century. Three men is on a mission from the IRA to steal all the gold in the vaults of the Bank of England...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Aldo Ray</actor><actor>Elizabeth Sellars</actor><actor>Peter O'Toole</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4084399/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>devoniangoldwing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
An enjoyable film. Low budget, however, the film does not suffer in the
least. Typical of this era of British films, with a solid American
actor (Aldo Ray), as the lead. Broody, but not really convincing. Good
acting by Albert Sharpe played "Tosher". Cameos aplenty from stock
actors. First time seeing Peter O'Toole in a supporting role, playing
the guards officer in charge of security at the Bank. In my opinion he
stole the show, if you will pardon the pun. I see that the film is
based on a novel, so wishful thinking as far as the plot goes. I was
born and now work in the City of London, so I know that there was
obviously a lot of research concerning the sewers and the streets above
them. This made the film even more enjoyable.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663392/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>whpratt1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Enjoyed this B&amp;W film from the 60's and the great acting of Aldo
Ray,(Norgate),"Terror Night",'87, who planned a very interesting bank
robbery which I thought could never be accomplished. Elizabeth
Sellars,(Iris Muldoon),"Jet Storm",'59, gave a great supporting role
trying to give aid and good judgment to a bunch of robbers in a back
breaking bank robbery! Peter 0'Toole(Captain Fitch," Troy",'04, was an
outstanding military officer who had a keen sense of alarm when the
gaslights started to dim in the passageways. I never saw bank robbers
who took on such a horrible way about robbing a bank, my back was
giving me trouble after viewing this picture. If you want to see a very
young Peter O'Toole at his best, catch this film on TV sometime!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Aldo Ray is sturdy and handsome as Irish-American recruited to help a
group of disparate Irish characters rob the "impregnable" Bank of
England in the early 1900s. Some suspense and neat ideas in this
low-keyed, minimally-budgeted MGM production (one which rarely turns up
on the Turner Classics channel). There's some confusion later on about
the purpose of the bank robbery and why the wily coot who started the
whole thing wants to pull out, but Peter O'Toole is wonderfully intense
and suspicious (and incredibly young) as the chief soldier guarding the
gold bullion, and Ray is always good to watch: he's not only the leader
of this operation but the driving force behind the picture as well; his
quick-thinking nature is mirrored in his eyes, and he never overdoes
anything (he's all business). Straight-forward drama is given good
direction and the supporting cast is colorful. As for the ending...do
they get away with it? You may have to buy a bootleg copy to find out!
**1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
For a chance to see Peter O'Toole before Lawrence Of Arabia, I would
highly recommend The Day They Robbed The Bank Of England. It's a period
caper film set at the turn of the last century about some Fenians
attempting to rob the Bank Of England itself.The Irish cause as personified by Hugh Griffith as acquired the
services of an American Irish patriot in the person of Aldo Ray. Among
his other qualifications is that of a miner if a tunnel job is needed
and he surveys it and says it is.He also cultivates Coldstream guardsman Peter O'Toole who is glad to
have a new drinking companion and he furnishes all kinds of information
about the bank and its security. He also begins to suspect something is
terribly amiss at the bank though he can't put his finger on it.Ray's crew consists of Albert Sharpe in his farewell performance who's
more of a hindrance than a help, Elizabeth Sellars with whom he has a
past and Kieron Moore who Sellars has a present. That does not make for
a smooth running operation.John Guillermin who later directed such films I liked as Death On The
Nile and Guns At Batasi directed The Day They Robbed The Bank Of
England at a really nice pace and brought out some good
characterizations from his players. As for the job itself will it
succeed is up to both the caprices of men and politics. Hugh Griffith
who is one of my favorite actors and who has the wildest most
expressive eyes ever in cinema represents the politics of the Irish
cause and quite well.A very nice film, The Day They Robbed The Bank Of England and for his
fans a wonderful opportunity to see Peter O'Toole before he became a
star.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0342623/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>blanche-2</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Aldo Ray and Peter O'Toole star in "The Day They Robbed the Bank of
England," a 1960 film directed by John Guillerman. Ray plays Norgate,
an American who sympathizes with the Irish republican movement. To this
end, he and his cronies plan to rob the Bank of England. He and his
cronies plan to rob it. Befriending a guard, Captain Finch (O'Toole)
while in a pub, and over time manages to gather many details about the
layout of the bank and the whereabouts of the vault with the gold
bullion.This is the type of "caper" film very popular in the 1960s. It's a
small British film and a little slow in spots, but intriguing. The
Captain is one of O'Toole's early roles, so it's definitely of interest
to see him. One of my problems with this movie is the weak script - it
seemed odd to me that the Captain didn't realize pretty quickly what
Norgate was up to. The acting, however, is very good, with some fine
character actors offering great support: Kieron Moore, Albert Sharpe,
and others. The lovely Elizabeth Sellars plays a woman widowed as a
result of the cause who is the liaison with Ireland.Entertaining.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0347234/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>vahab</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

I just saw The day they robbed the Bank of England. It is not a bad film.
I
think it was very low budget. I have no idea whether the story is true,
but
at times it was very suspenseful. Peter O'Toole gives a splendid and
convincing performance. He was more at ease in this film than any other
film
that I have seen him. Aldo Ray, who is the main character, at times looks
wooden and does not look like someone who cares for Ireland or a woman or
anything.  I recommend it if it is on TV
and for 1 1/2 of relaxation.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1416505/comments</url><from>from Groningen, The Netherlands</from><name>Boba_Fett1138</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This is actually quite an original heist movie, not because of its
story or characters but more because of the fact that the movie is a
period movie as well. The movie is set around 1900, thus making this
not just your average normal bank robbers movie.Yet the movie does not work out as good as it potentially could had.
The movies takes too much time to build up to the actual heist. It
makes the first halve of the movie mostly dragging and not interesting
or exciting enough to watch. It even manages to throw in a love
interest, which is completely redundant.It's true that the movie only really gets off the ground once they
start the break-in. From that point on the movie becomes actually quite
good to watch. It only then becomes obvious that the movie its
characters are actually quite interesting and its story can be actually
quite clever and intriguing. A bit too late though, making this only a
so-so movie, with one good second halve and one weaker first halve.For 1960 standards its definitely a good and professional British
looking movie, despite the fact that this obviously wasn't a movie with
a very high budget. It knows to create a good, typical for its period,
kind of atmosphere.All of the actors in the movie are some big unknowns and none of them
also really know to impress. At leas they don't leave a lasting
impression. Except for the at the time still young Peter O'Toole. This
actually was only O'Toole's second movie he ever appeared in but he
already had his own trademark style of acting at the time. His
character is also easily the best of the movie, which also makes you
cheer more for him than his actual 'enemy' and main character of the
bank, the professional thief and bank robber, played by Aldo Ray. Come
to think of it, why should you even cheer in the first place for the
movie its bank robbers? It's not like they are doing it for a good
cause, which just doesn't make them the most sympathetic main
characters for a movie.Perhaps it would also had been a better movie if it was just a tad bit
more entertaining. It should had paid some more attention to its 'fun',
rather than its serious aspects.A watchable movie, that however also leaves you with the feeling that
it isn't as good as it truly could had been.6/10http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This modest but proficient thriller pretty much tells you its plot in the
title.It deals with an attempt by the Irish republican movement at the turn
of the twentieth century to break into the vaults of the Bank of England and
extract the fortune in gold bullion stored there.They call in an American
-woodenly played by Aldo Ray -to mastermind the venture and he extracts key
information from a Britsh officer ,an early screen role for Peter O'Toole
and from a Thames vagrant with knowledge of the sewer system.
The climax sees the gang tunneling under the bank in a race against the
military who have begun to suspect something is amiss.
Cheaply made and slackly written this is still worth watching for the parade
of British character actors who pop up and add substance to minor roles and
for the touch of cynicism about politics -the Irish movement having plotted
the heist find it politically expedient to try and stop it when the
political scene changes in their favourAlso on the plus side is its brevity -the movie is under 90 minutes and
never drags
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This modest but proficient thriller pretty much tells you its plot in the
title.It deals with an attempt by the Irish republican movement at the turn
of the twentieth century to break into the vaults of the Bank of England and
extract the fortune in gold bullion stored there.They call in an American
-woodenly played by Aldo Ray -to mastermind the venture and he extracts key
information from a Britsh officer ,an early screen role for Peter O'Toole
and from a Thames vagrant with knowledge of the sewer system.
The climax sees the gang tunneling under the bank in a race against the
military who have begun to suspect something is amiss.
Cheaply made and slackly written this is still worth watching for the parade
of British character actors who pop up and add substance to minor roles and
for the touch of cynicism about politics -the Irish movement having plotted
the heist find it politically expedient to try and stop it when the
political scene changes in their favourAlso on the plus side is its brevity -the movie is under 90 minutes and
never drags
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>