<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Summer of the Seventeenth Doll</original_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Australia</country><country>UK</country><country>USA</country><director>Leslie Norman</director><producer>Hill-Hecht-Lancaster Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Two men continue a traditional summer rendezvous only to discover that life has changed for them all.</synopsis><actor>Ernest Borgnine</actor><actor>Anne Baxter</actor><actor>John Mills</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2340670/comments</url><from>from Canberra, Australia</from><name>Neil Cammack</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Many years ago I unwisely took part in an amateur production of
Thornton Wilder's "The Matchmaker". I can still hear the mayhem created
by those of us who tried, and failed miserably, to achieve an American
accent and those (including, bizarrely, a stray Welshman) who just gave
up and spoke their native idiom. Luckily out home-town audience was
very forgiving and the local rag took pity on us.This dire experience came back to me when I saw "Summer of the
Seventeenth Doll", but even so, not having seen the original stage play
by Ray Lawler, I didn't realise how badly it had been butchered until I
saw a TV performance by the Melbourne Theatre Company. The first
reaction of an Australian audience will be to switch off because of the
hilarious mangling of their native speech by an all-star cast who
deserved better and would have been more gainfully employed on another
project. Maybe that wouldn't matter to a foreign audience, but then
again, perhaps the resultant strange mixture of assorted Cockney, Bronx
and other sounds would have a subtly disturbing effect on any listener.Of more concern is the fact that the play's essence can't be divorced
from its Australian roots, which include deceptively dry, laconic and
understated speech cadences, without making it pretty meaningless. In
fact it's the very antithesis of the overwrought, borderline-
histrionic style of "serious" Hollywood films of the era. Anyone less
like a laconic Queensland canecutter than the furiously emoting Ernest
Borgnine would be hard to imagine. And switching the location from
Melbourne to more photogenic Sydney settings, while trivial in itself,
is symptomatic of the filmmakers' imperfect understanding of their
vehicle.I don't know that "Doll" is a great play, but it is a good one.
However, given the need for some audience-pulling names there was no
real prospect of doing it properly in 1959. The accent problem, which
is just part of the underlying cultural mismatch, is not to be
dismissed, and I've never heard an American or British actor come close
to a convincing Australian accent - even Meryl Streep. Even nowadays,
with many high-visibility Australians in Hollywood, it would be a
problematic vehicle because at bottom it's pretty stagy. It's just one
of those movies that shouldn't have been made.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0682175/comments</url><from>from adelaide, australia</from><name>leask81</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

The success of this film can be attributed to Ray Lawler, responsible for
the characters and story, from his play SUMMER OF THE SEVENTEENTH DOLL -
they are easily the best aspects of the film.  The acting is also
surprisingly good, but the accents are horrible - but this was typical in
most of the Australian "location" films of the period (eg ON THE BEACH and
A
TOWN LIKE ALICE).  It's a well-written story with great flawed characters
and an okay script, it appealed to me but I could forgive those who didn't
like it.  Rating: 7/10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Ray Lawler's play about two tempestuous sweetheart couples coping with
the layoff season in Sydney, Australia comes to the screen without much
humor and a misguided heart. Sugar cane cutters Ernest Borgnine and
John Mills take Kewpie doll collector Anne Baxter and manicurist Angela
Lansbury to South Australia to rest up and look for holiday work--but
trouble brews with Borgnine, who has mysteriously left his job after
fifteen years. Practically without plot, this character study has
become, on film, a visual journey rather than an emotional or
personable one. Paul Beeson's cinematography is certainly striking,
even as the entangled relationships and mercurial tempers at the
forefront of the story quickly wear themselves out. Forget about
accents, these actors (interestingly, if unsuccessfully, cast) don't
even look like Aussie natives. Borgnine's strong sense of character and
natural way with a complicated chunk of dialogue nearly saves him, but
it was a fundamental error to surround these stars with unknown players
who really do sound like Australians. The lively section at the
amusement park is full of raucous vitriol and Beeson's playful visual
composition, but every scene back at the boarding house is a lost
cause. A very strange project, indeed. ** from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5335700/comments</url><from>from Hampton Park, Victoria, Australia</from><name>Kyle Rata</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
I Have read the play and seen the film, Ray Lawler wrote the play
extremely well. He did something interesting, in writing the play with
accents. This is something i haven't seen before.Leslie Norman however did a poor adaptation of the text version, simple
things like getting the city wrong that the play was set in and
Australian accents. The accents were bad, the actors did not even seem
to try to talk like an Australian. Ernest Borgnine was the main
culprit. He had a full blown yank accent happening during the whole
film.This film was a waste of my time, and a waste of everyone else's time
who has ever watched it. I does not even deserve a 3 out of 10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6176268/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>morphion2</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
I must note that my rating of one star is NOT based on what I thought
of "Summer of the Seventeenth Doll" as a film. This film was not
terrible , in the traditional sense. It was moderately entertaining,
acting was adequate and due to the work of Ray Lawler, the writing was
good. However, all these things are invalidated by the basic and
fundamental demolition of what made Lawler's play great.For one thing, an American production of "The Doll" is in and of itself
a terrible idea, not to mention American actors. The play is
unanimously considered the most historically significant in Australian
theatre history, its status as the first authentically Australian play
is celebrated widely by scholars of Literature. Any form of
"Americanization" subsequently destroys it. Here it should be made
clear that American films are some of the greatest in the world, but
only Australia should ever have laid there hands on this project.The second terrible, fatal flaw of the film is the need it felt to
drastically change key plot points (one key plot point in particular)
and thereby change the entire message and atmosphere of the story. If
one didn't know better, they would think that such a change was a
mockery. Sadly this is not the case.All in all, this was not a bad film, but rather an awful, deeply
lamentable butchering of a iconic classic in Australian history, and
while a film of "The Doll" is not a bad idea, this was amongst the
worst treatment it could have been given.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6176268/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>morphion2</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
I must note that my rating of one star is NOT based on what I thought
of "Summer of the Seventeenth Doll" as a film. This film was not
terrible , in the traditional sense. It was moderately entertaining,
acting was adequate and due to the work of Ray Lawler, the writing was
good. However, all these things are invalidated by the basic and
fundamental demolition of what made Lawler's play great.For one thing, an American production of "The Doll" is in and of itself
a terrible idea, not to mention American actors. The play is
unanimously considered the most historically significant in Australian
theatre history, its status as the first authentically Australian play
is celebrated widely by scholars of Literature. Any form of
"Americanization" subsequently destroys it. Here it should be made
clear that American films are some of the greatest in the world, but
only Australia should ever have laid there hands on this project.The second terrible, fatal flaw of the film is the need it felt to
drastically change key plot points (one key plot point in particular)
and thereby change the entire message and atmosphere of the story. If
one didn't know better, they would think that such a change was a
mockery. Sadly this is not the case.All in all, this was not a bad film, but rather an awful, deeply
lamentable butchering of a iconic classic in Australian history, and
while a film of "The Doll" is not a bad idea, this was amongst the
worst treatment it could have been given.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6176268/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>morphion2</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>