<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hell Bent for Leather</original_title><alt_title>Le diable dans la peau</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>George Sherman</director><producer>Universal International Pictures (UI)</producer><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
When Clay Santell stops in the town of Sutterville after having his horse stolen, he is mistaken by townspeople for a murderer named Travers...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Audie Murphy</actor><actor>Felicia Farr</actor><actor>Stephen McNally</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1487738/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>lorenellroy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Audie Murphy plays Clay Santell ,a horse dealer whose hospitality to a
stranger who stumbles on foot and on the verge of collapse into his camp is
to have his horse stolen by the man in question.Santell wounds his assailant
who drops his lavishly embossed shotgun as he flees Santell's camp.The man
is Travers ,a wanted outlaw .and the local townsfolk believe Santell is
Travers,based on his having the gun .Corrupt Marshall Deckett (Stephen Mc
Nally)takes him into custody ,knowing full well he is not Travers but hoping
to pass him off as the outlaw ,and boost his reputation as the man who saw
Travers hung.Santell escapes ,taking with him a young woman ,Janet Gifford ,and Deckett
and a posse set out in hot pursuit.
Can Santell avoid capture and clear his name ?That is the central issue of
this modest but brisk Western that benefits from some striking location
shooting and some decent performances especially from McNally and that
splendid character actor Robert Middleton .Based on a novel by pulp Western maestro Ray Hogan this moves briskly and
energetically and will appeal to most devotees of the genre.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2842258/comments</url><from>from Paris, France</from><name>ColeArmin (westernmovies@fr.st)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Very entertaining western directed by George Sherman (who did Big Jake
with John Wayne and produced The Comancheros 1961). The actors are
excellent. We get Audie Murphy and Stephen McNally back altogether 8
years after Duel at silver creek 1952, but here they are enemies.
Felicia Farr acts in her last western. And very good supporting cast
with Jan Merlin as Travers, John Qualen and Bob Steele among others.With a very good screenplay, I really liked the character, Stephen
MacNally plays. The three main actors are perfect, and they carry the
movie. So if you have the luck to have the opportunity to see this
movie: GOOOOO!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1035465/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>shoshone</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This Western is persistently harsh and downbeat.  Although I think it was
good vehicle for Audie Murphy in that it was a departure from the
'kid/gunman' role, I cannot say I enjoyed this one too much.  A point of
interest is that it depicted his character as having to fight for his life
from beginning to end, which is something he had to do in real life and
which, therefore, made his anxiety and struggle more believable.
I love Audie and he looked good in this, as always but I would need to see
it a few more times to appreciate it, I guess.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The most decorated combat soldier of the war,Audie Murphy, plays the
part of a man,falsely accused of being a gangster by a marshal .This
embittered cop has been searching for the true culprit for months and
he needs to find one ,his claim to fame.Stephen Mc Nally is the stand
out ,the audience realizes little by little he has gone completely nuts
,heading the posse on his victim's trail.The girl the horse-trader
meets (Felicia Farr,better known for her part in " kiss me ,stupid"
)and who takes up his cause is some kind of outcast for her father was
not a good man .She was taken in by neighbors but she has not really
been received at the community :she takes care of the children when the
inhabitants attend the service.This is a modest but entertaining western with good suspense and a
great finale when the wrong and the right man meet in the mountain.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17033155/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>milwhitt702</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Since I watch Westerns very closely, taping them and watching them
over, sometimes I see things I missed earlier. This movie kept you at
the edge of your seat much of the time, especially when Santee did not
have a gun or any money. One part of special interest was when he and
the girl went into a saloon and asked for a glass of water because he
had lost his money in a scramble to get away from R. Middleton and his
boys earlier. At the bar was a rifle that Santee had his eye on. Next
to the rifle, standing, was an old timer I recognized to be Kermit
Maynard. In the list of actors, he was not even credited as being in
the movie. I watched it over and over, and I am pretty sure K. Maynard
was the guy at the bar, who picked up the rifle and left. Anybody see
it that way??? Thanks.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0415271/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn NY</from><name>chipe</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Fans of Western movies will not be disappointed. While not a great or
even distinguished Western, it also LACKS the faults of so many other
Westerns. On the plus side it can boast good colorful outdoor
mountainous locations and cinema-photography , leading and supporting
actors, a believable situation and a literate imaginative script. On
the negative side: zero; I can't think of anything laughable, offensive
or jarring. Audie Murphy looked and acted good. Felicia Farr looked
better, even gorgeous. And Stephen McNally stole the movie with his
acting chops. Robert Middleton was his usual excellent self in a brief
suspenseful scene during Murphy's chase from McNally. Jan Merlin did
well as a villain.I thought it was an interesting and unusual motive for Sheriff
McNally's lying that Murphy and not Merlin was the criminal being
chased. I won't reveal it in this review, though it is spelled out in
most of the other reviews here. The reason puzzled me throughout
watching the film, and it was finally revealed at the conclusion. Also
intriguing was how Murphy would extricate himself from his predicament.
Finally, kudos for Farr's back story. Surprising that there were no
romantic scenes (embraces, kisses, etc.) between the two leads, Murphy
and Farr, though the last scene had then leave hand in hand.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2079400/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Van Roberts (zardoz@bellsouth.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Big Jake" director George Sherman's "Hell Bent for Leather" is a
routine little oater about the theme of mistaken identity. The action
takes place against some rugged scenery as our hero and heroine
struggle to elude a determined posse so the protagonist can prove his
innocence. Scenarist Christopher Knopf provides a couple of modest
surprises in this B-western. Stephen McNally has the plumb role as a
villainous lawman hunting for glory.Clay Santell (Audie Murphy of "To Hell and Back") is minding his own
business when a stranger toting a double-barreled shotgun enters his
camp and requests water. After Clay gives Travers (Jan Merlin of
"Illegal") his canteen, he rustles him up some grub. Travers strikes
Clay a glancing blow at the head and steals Clay's horse. Before
Travers clears out, our hero fires at him and knocks the shotgun out of
Travers' hand. Now, poor Clay wanders on foot into town looking for a
fresh mount. The blacksmith, Old Ben (John Qualen), dispatches a rider
to alert the important officials about the stranger's arrival.
Meantime, Clay has no idea Travers' shotgun has incriminated him and he
sticks around long enough for three horsemen to catch him at the corral
and arrest him. Naturally, Clay protests his innocence, and the town
leaders are prepared to mete out justice despite never having seen
Travers. All these law-abiding citizens know is that Travers killed to
well-liked people. Indeed, only Marshal Deckett (Stephen McNally of
"Duel at Silver Creek") can identify Travers. Anyway, Clay catches his
captors with their guard down and almost escapes. Luckily for Clay,
Deckett intervenes and rides away with Clay as his prisoner. Later,
when they are safely out of town, Clay asks Deckett to release him.
When Deckett refuses , Clay escapes and takes refuge in a rancher's
bunk house where Janet (Felicia Farr of "The Last Wagon") has been
babysitting with a group of children during a funeral. Deckett alerts
the citizens that Travers has escaped, and they assemble a posse. After
Deckett and the posse ride off, Clay forces Janet at rifle point to
drive a two-horse buckboard.As Janet and Clay are pulling out in the buckboard, they are spotted
and Clay shoots at the man who sees them. Deckett and the town citizens
pursue them. During the chase, Janet struggles to get the rifle away
from Clay, and together they fall off the buckboard and tumble down a
slope. Deckett and company catch up with the buckboard and their Native
American tracker, William (Eddie Little Sky of "The Hallelujah Trail"),
assures them that Clay is making for the mountains. Clay discovers to
his chagrin that he used the only bullet in the long gun when he fired
at the man back at the ranch. As they climb the mountains, Clay tells
Janet that he is not Travers. He complains that Deckett is so inclined
to end the chase and he is prepared to claim that Clay is Travers. They
clamber into the mountains. Eventually, Clay realizes that he isn't
getting anywhere with Janet so he releases her. She promises to bring
Pennick (Herbert Rudley of "The Young Lions") back to talk to him. Clay
sits down and awaits Janet's return. Janet descends the ridge and
William catches her. Deckett rides up and sends William after the rest
of the posse while the lawman forces Janet to take him to Clay. Clay
jumps Deckett and Deckett calls him Santell in Janet's presence. Clay
and Janet escape from Deckett just as the posse arrives. Deckett and
Moon unleash a volley of rifle shots at Clay and Janet as they ascend
the ridge. Everybody thinks the ridge is impassable until somebody
observes that the only man to cross it was Janet's father. William
takes Deckett and the posse on a four hour ride around to the other
side while Clay and Janet forge ahead.They get caught in a rain storm and take refuge in an abandoned
stagecoach relay station. As it turns out, Janet knows the place well
because her father used to run it. She regales Clay with her hard luck
story about how her mother died and her father went bonkers. They are
surprised when three men burst into the station. Ambrose (Robert
Middleton of "The Law and Jake Wade") and two friends invade the
station and Janet tends to Ambrose's wounded leg when the latter tells
them about their encounter with Travers. Clay inquires about buying one
of their horses and shells out forty dollars. Outside, Ambrose's two
friends, Shad (Joseph Ruskin of "Smokin' Aces") and Grover (Steve
Gravers) try to take all Clay's money, but our hero thwarts them and
Janet and he escape on separate horses. It doesn't take Deckett and his
posse long to find Ambrose and company and beat the information out of
them because they find Clay's money pouch. Shad tells Deckett that Clay
was heading for the town of Paradise.Our hero and heroine ride into Paradise on one horse and Clay spots his
horse. Travers spots the posse and hightails it. Clay and Janet steal
mounts and pursue Travers with Deckett and his posse hot at their
heels. No sooner have Janet and Clay caught up with Travers than the
posse rides in and Clay tries to make a deal with Deckett. Deckett goes
out to meet him and Clay bluffs him and almost gets his six-gun until
Travers appears armed with a shotgun. Clay and Janet listen as Travers
talks about what a treacherous fellow Deckett is and Deckett tries to
cut a bargain with Travers. If they can kill Clay, Deckett will lead
the posse away from Travers, but Travers shoots Deckett. Clay grabs a
six-gun and kills Travers. Reluctantly, Perrick and the posse believe
Clay's hard-luck story now and he is free.Altogether, "Hell Bent for Leather" qualifies as an adequate
sagebrusher. If you look closely, you'll spot legendary B-movie western
stars Allen Lane and Bob Steele.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0819382/comments</url><from>from Deming, New Mexico, USA</from><name>Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
It's all here in this inexpensive Western from Universal Studios. Audie
Murphy as the fresh-faced hero mistaken for a ruthless shotgun killer.
Felicia Farr as the misunderstood local woman swept up in his escape.
Stephen McNally as the crooked Marshall consumed by self
aggrandizement. The angry townsfolk seeking revenge. The buckboard
bouncing in a frenzy along the rough roads, pursued by the galloping
posse. The pause at the empty cabin during a rainstorm so Murphy and
Farr can exchange a few understanding words before falling in love.
But, come to think of it, there are no fast draws and no clips on the
jaw that render anyone unconscious for as long as the plot requires.
Maybe it ISN'T all here.But Mount Whitney is here, or at least nearby. Most of the movie was
shot at Movie Flats, near Lone Pine, California, on the eastern side of
the Sierra Nevada mountains. You'll probably recognize the location.
It's been used in a hundred movies. I was there a few years ago and can
swear to it that I found some pieces of welding left over from "Gunga
Din" (1939), although it must be said that I lie constantly.Felicia Farr is a pleasant and attractive woman, Jack Lemon's wife. She
never had a major career. Perhaps her talent was modest or maybe she
just didn't get the challenging parts. I wonder how she'd have done if
she'd tackled Blanche DuBois.More often than not, Audie Murphy was a little embarrassing. His range
was so limited. It's painful here watching him struggling to project an
emotion like fear, as if in a high school play in Cedar City, Utah. He
STILL looks innocent here, fifteen years after the end of the war from
which he emerged with more decorations than any other soldier -- and he
earned them too. When a role was within his range and when he had the
right director, he could be entirely convincing, but that only happened
once that I know of -- in John Huston's "The Red Badge of Courage." This isn't a bad movie. It's mediocre in almost every respect, helped
by a couple of accomplished actors in smaller roles. Well, I'll give an
example of something that keeps the film from being aimed at a more
sophisticated or mature audience. Throughout, Felicia Farr is
glamorously made up. It doesn't matter -- rain or shine, night or day
-- he false eyelashes are flawless and her no-smear lipstick a
perfection in scarlet. Couldn't they have mussed her up a little? After
all, she has to hoof it for dozens of miles across the mountains and
deserts.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218006/comments</url><from>from S. Paulo, Brazil</from><name>tmwest</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Hell Bent for Leather, from what I gathered was used, in the 19th
Century to mean breakaway speed or great determination. This is not an
Audie Murphy western, with great action scenes like "The Cimarron Kid"
or "Duel at Silver Creek", but it is one of his best. It has a very
good plot and two remarkable actors, Felicia Farr and Stephen McNally.
Felicia is very attractive as Janet, a tough woman, who ends up helping
Clay Santell (Murphy) who gets mistaken for a killer. But it is the
Marshal Deckett (McNally) who makes the strongest impression, a man
driven by his need for a false glory, which will compensate the
humiliation of his past. Old timers Allan Lane and Bob Steele show up
on the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218006/comments</url><from>from S. Paulo, Brazil</from><name>tmwest</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Hell Bent for Leather, from what I gathered was used, in the 19th
Century to mean breakaway speed or great determination. This is not an
Audie Murphy western, with great action scenes like "The Cimarron Kid"
or "Duel at Silver Creek", but it is one of his best. It has a very
good plot and two remarkable actors, Felicia Farr and Stephen McNally.
Felicia is very attractive as Janet, a tough woman, who ends up helping
Clay Santell (Murphy) who gets mistaken for a killer. But it is the
Marshal Deckett (McNally) who makes the strongest impression, a man
driven by his need for a false glory, which will compensate the
humiliation of his past. Old timers Allan Lane and Bob Steele show up
on the film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>