<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Boy and the Pirates</original_title><imdb_rating>5.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Bert I. Gordon</director><producer>Bert I. Gordon Productions</producer><genre>Family</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis>
Young boy is magically transported back in time to a pirate ship on the high seas.
</synopsis><actor>Charles Herbert</actor><actor>Susan Gordon</actor><actor>Murvyn Vye</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Basically the story is about little Jimmy, a boy who has no interest in
anything but pirates, finding a bottle with a genie in it, and
accidentally wishing he were part of Blackbeard's pirate ship. So the
genie makes the wish, and little Jimmy goes back to the late 1500's for
what should have been rollicking, fun pirate adventure but turns out
instead to be less interesting than any adventure on the Love Boat on a
bad day. What else happens: little Jimmy meets a Dutch girl with no
accent(Susan Gordon, the director's daughter), argues with the genie
over some story about how the genie must be thrown back in the same
spot where found otherwise Jimmy will take his spot in the bottle, and
accidentally leaves bubblegum in the kitchen for the cook to use in a
stew. These were the film's highlights(no lie!). Charles Herbert, the
child actor from The Fly and Thirteen Ghosts, does an adequate job as
Jimmy. He was a very natural child actor with some obvious talent.
Susan Gordon is cute if nothing else, and the rest of the cast is,
well, adequate at best. Murvyn Vye is actually pretty decent as
Blackbeard and Joe Turkel as the genie is also likewise. Paul Guilfoyle
as Snipe - the lone pirate with any compassion for the two children -
is the only actor; however, that even tries to add any depth to his
character and performance. The rest, although not bad, are
one-dimensional stereotypes of characters we've seen again and again.
The biggest problem with this film is the direction and script. In a
film that could and should have created some wonderful scenes for
children, The Boy and the Pirates would be lucky to keep even a row
boat afloat. Director and screenwriter Bert I. Gordon does a lackluster
job bringing this story to the screen. The script has too many
non-conventional conventions(once you see it you might know what I am
trying to say here). The characters don't have any depth, and the
comedy isn't all that funny. That notwithstanding, The Boy and the
Pirates has some heart - if only it had a little more blood to give it
more life!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1418197/comments</url><from>from chicago, Illinois</from><name>rpniew</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This is another film that was regularly shown on the Chicago-area
television program "Family Classics," remembered fondly on other posted
for other films ("Snowfire" and "Journey to the Beginning of Time," to
name a couple.) I am certain that re-watching it at my age would be a
real mistake; even though it makes the occasional TCM appearance, I
think I'll pass on it. But when I was six, boy, what a film! I looked
forward to it every year. The old WGN, in it's pre-superstation days,
was a haven for fans of movies, classic and otherwise, between Frazier
Thomas's "Family Classics," the Saturday night "Creature Features," and
the Sunday night "When Movies Were Movies." Those were the days when
local programming was important. I am thankful to WGN TV for filling my
childhood fantasies with these films. For now, Though, with this
particular film, I'll let sleeping dogs lie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2630796/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>xerses13</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
Some films you remember with fondness even over their short-comings
like THE MAGIC SWORD (1962) IMDb****Stars, directed by MR. B.I.G.
himself, Bert I. Gordon. Which my Father and Mother took my Brother and
I to see in original release, at a 'Drive-In' theater. Then there is
this effort from 1960, a film which would bore any five (5) year old
too tears in the 21st Century and drive their Parents to drink. Our
recommendation, some heavy duty Martini's. Heavy on the Gin and/or
Vodka, light on the Vermouth!The film illustrates typical MR. B.I.G. features. Inept SFX assisted by
his wife MRS. B.I.G. (Flora Gordon). The usual intrusive and
over-bearing musical score by hack composer Albert Glasser. Finally a
cast of mediocrities, including his daughter Susan, the worse being
lead Charles Herbert as JIMMY WARREN.The young Mr. Herbert in the late 1950s' to the late 1960s' was the
face of Child-Stars of the time. He popped up in Commercials, Movies
and T.V. shows. Maybe back then he had some sort of endearing features,
he does not now. His life though is a cautionary tale of how Parents
should NOT handle their Children's hard earned assets. Being left
destitute at the end of his career, sound familiar?! Thought the
'Coogan Law' was supposed to have prevented such tragedies, wrong
again.Do yourself a favor and take a pass on this one. There are FAR better
Pirate films out there. This film rates up with junk like SWASHBUCKLER
(1976) or CUTTHROAT ISLAND (1995) both IMDb**Stars. Those films show
that 'big' Actors and 'big' budgets can also create as big of a bore as
THE BOY AND THE PIRATES.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0088731/comments</url><from>from Ontario, Canada</from><name>F A Chang (fachang@mailexcite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Cute 12 year old Charles Herbert stars in this kiddie movie about a boy who
dreams of being a pirate. To get him away from his hum-drum life of school,
chores, and nagging parents. O to be free like the pirates, and do what a
boy wants!Walking on the Massachusetts shore, little Jimmy (Herbert) finds a genie in
a bottle. The genie makes his dream come true. But the boy finds out to his
dismay that the life of a pirate is not what he thought it would be. And he
longs for home.Lots of boyish adventure. Blackbeard, and sloops, and man-o-wars, treasure
chests, rum and adventures.The cute Herbert made many movies and also starred in "Houseboat" as the
little son to Sophia Loren as his stepmother. See also "Don't Eat the
Daisies" also made in 1960 when the lad was 12. Such a comely lad, he should
have gone on to other movies but seems to have vanished into high school
obscurity. Pity, he was such a cute boy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0088731/comments</url><from>from Ontario, Canada</from><name>F A Chang (fachang@mailexcite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Cute 12 year old Charles Herbert stars in this kiddie movie about a boy who
dreams of being a pirate. To get him away from his hum-drum life of school,
chores, and nagging parents. O to be free like the pirates, and do what a
boy wants!Walking on the Massachusetts shore, little Jimmy (Herbert) finds a genie in
a bottle. The genie makes his dream come true. But the boy finds out to his
dismay that the life of a pirate is not what he thought it would be. And he
longs for home.Lots of boyish adventure. Blackbeard, and sloops, and man-o-wars, treasure
chests, rum and adventures.The cute Herbert made many movies and also starred in "Houseboat" as the
little son to Sophia Loren as his stepmother. See also "Don't Eat the
Daisies" also made in 1960 when the lad was 12. Such a comely lad, he should
have gone on to other movies but seems to have vanished into high school
obscurity. Pity, he was such a cute boy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0088731/comments</url><from>from Ontario, Canada</from><name>F A Chang (fachang@mailexcite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-biodrowski/</url><url>http://cinefantastiqueonline.com/2010/08/tormented-1960-on-mystery-science-theater-3000-a-50th-anniversary-review/ /m/tormented/comments.php?reviewid=1924418</url><name>Steve Biodrowski</name><from>ESplatter</from></reviewer><comment>Bert I. Gordon is most well known for his low-budget 1950s sci-fi pics, but this little seen relic of 1960 is actually one of his better efforts. It is also one of the more entertaining installments of the always enjoyable Mystery Science Theater 3000. </comment></review></movie>