<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Beyond the Time Barrier</original_title><alt_title>Le voyageur de l'espace</alt_title><imdb_rating>4.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Edgar G. Ulmer</director><producer>Miller Consolidated Pictures (MCP)</producer><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
Experimental pilot testing a new rocket powered craft (actually a Convair F-102 interceptor) manages to fly into the future and land at the now deserted airbase he left...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Robert Clarke</actor><actor>Darlene Tompkins</actor><actor>Vladimir Sokoloff</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1229491/comments</url><from>from Fayetteville, GA</from><name>Bruce Cook (brucemcook@windstream.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

From Edgar G. Ulmer (director of `The Man from Planet X' and `The Amazing
Transparent Man') comes this likable little sc-fi tale.  A test pilot
(Robert Clark) is catapulted into the future by a freak phenomenon, where a
post World War III society lives in futuristic cities that protect them from
the lingering radiation.  However, the populace is having fertility
problems, and the head of the government (Vladimir Sokoloff) hopes that his
daughter (gorgeous  Darlene Thompkins) and Clark will get together. The costumes will meet with male approval; the women all wear short dresses
and high heels (if you like it,  guys, check out `World Without End'). Okay, back to the plot:  a group of dissidents conspire to take over the
government by releasing a horde of imprisoned mutants.  They do, and the
first thing the mutants do is attack all the women.  Girls, be forewarned:
if you dress provocatively, you'll suffer the consequences, especially if
imprisoned mutants get loose. Hats off to Ulmer for efficiency:  he filmed this enjoyable effort in a
matter of weeks, and he saved money on sets by using an exhibit of
futuristic art-and-design at the 1959 Texas State Fair in Dallas.  The
interior architecture is appealing, despite being relatively simple.  The
doors, walls, and pillars are all based on triangles and pyramids.    Don't'
expect any elaborate special effects, but the film does manage to invoke a
pleasant Buck Rogers feeling. Unfortunately, I've never seen this movie shown on local or cable TV, and
it  doesn't seem to be avail on VHS or DVD.  Dedicated sci-fi fans will have
to work to get a peek at this lost gem.  But it's worth the effort if you're
a 1950s sci-fi fan.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Beyond the Time Barrier is an old-fashioned science fiction film made in
1960 that has the look and feel of a science fiction serial.  It has some
obvious flaws, most of which spring from its low budget.  The special
effects are woefully un-special.  The sets are cheap-looking as are the
costumes and any make-up used.  Acting is mediocre at best with a few actors
doing reasonable work.  Darlene Tompkins is a lovely actress and does a
pretty good job in her role as a deaf princess.  Robert Clarke should be
nicknamed Robert "Stonewall" Clarke for his stone-like performance.  His
performance isn't wooden, it's petrified.  Nonetheless he is fun to watch. 
Boyd "Red" Morgan is, on the other hand, painfully bad a a captain(earlier
referred to as a major?).  The film tells a very complex story about Clarke
leaving the year 1960 and crossing a time barrier and reaching the year 2024
where plague and pestilence are common.  The human race has divided into
factions of mutants and non-mutants(really people in the very first stages
of being mutants).  I found the story quite interesting despite not really
believing the scientific aspects behind it.  Sure the film is talky, but
that was okay with me as I liked the story.  The film was directed by Edgar
Ulmer and it has some wonderful Ulmer moments.  I particularly liked the way
the mutants were locked up...a well-shot scene.  Also, the climatic fight
scenes were very good too. Ulmer uses a triangle of another scene
interspersing into the already existing shot quite often as well for a neat
little effect.  An interesting science fiction film with a
message.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3221986/comments</url><from>from Beltsville, Maryland</from><name>wdbasinger (wdbasinger@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I have always been fascinated by the philosophical aspects of space and
time, for example, such as the possibility of time dilation. That is
why movies such as "The Time Machine", "World Without End" (especially,
"World Without End" being one of my all-time favorite SF films), and
this one, "Beyond the Time Barrier" have a great deal of appeal.The highlights of the film and worth far more than the price of
admission are the scenes in which Robert Clarke first breaks the time
barrier up in space (in physics, this sounds like what is currently
referred to as a "wormhole" in contrast to the older concept of time
dilation) and the scenes after he touches back down to earth. The scene
in which Robert Clarke observes the exterior of the futuristic city
along with the pulsating solar energy tower is fascinating. (I first
saw this when I was ten years old and never forgot it.) Also the scenes
of Darlene Tomkins are also a delight for the eyes (especially the
swimming pool scene - I never forgot this either). I also liked the
triangular designs. They looked almost out of Die Blaue Reiter (The
Blue Rider) Gruppe - the Munich Art School that specialized in abstract
expressionism (producing such greats such as Klee, Marc, Kandinsky,
others) or, perhaps out of the Bauhaus School of Architecture which
produced such greats such as Ludwig Mies van der Rohe and others who
pioneered modern futuristic design. For this, the art designer for the
movie, Ernst Fegte should take a bow. However, the overall plot is somewhat disappointing after Robert Clarke
is captured. The idea that the human race can bring the earth to such a
state in which it is perilous to walk the actual surface of the earth
due to excessive radiation because the protective atmospheric screens
had been decimated (the ozone layer in the stratosphere, for example)
seems very dreary indeed (The scientist played by Istvan Bekassy
mentions the ionosphere being contaminated by nuclear particles).
Furthermore, what happened to the various animal and plant species ?
Were they decimated, too ? Perhaps the writers could have planned a
less dismal story. As the story progresses, the plot becomes even more
pessimistic with the sterility of the population, the evil scientists,
the barbarity of the mutants, the almost complete resignation to the
eventual extinction of the human race as voiced by the Supreme,
Vladimir Sokoloff, and the murder in the final reel of Trirene, his
daughter, played by Darlene Tomkins. In general, the writers could have
done a lot better, in terms of plot, theme, and characters.Not the best, not the worst.Worth watching for the art design and certain aspects of the story
which make a person think.6/10Dan Basinger
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0972645/comments</url><from>from utah</from><name>tabuno</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
A prelude to a couple of television's original Outer Limit episodes,
BEYOND THE TIME BARRIER for all its low-budget, fake looking special
effects, subpar acting performances, comes across as an attempt at
serious sci fi with elevated concepts and a flare for an fascinating
effort of futuristic set design. The consistency of plot and the
elements of both substantive sci fi drama, emotive relational
interactions make this movie an above average depiction of a future
world that would be replicated and copied by future sci fi movies,
PLANET OF THE APES (1968), eight years later, and eerily BENEATH THE
PLANET OF THE APES (1970). The same year that BEYOND THE TIME BARRIER
was released THE TIME MACHINE came out that also had a similar theme
and has since become a classic. Unfortunately for BEYOND THE TIME
BARRIER, it is apparent that lack of serious support, directorial,
budget, or time prohibited this movie from having a real chance at a
much more compelling and credible depiction of the future. The
storyline, the scientific rationalization, and even the more rounded
and developed characters held out hope that this movie might have be a
solid and memorable sci fi classic. Nevertheless, it failed to realize
its potential.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10169091/comments</url><from>from Staten Island, New York</from><name>copper1963</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Major William Allison (Robert Clarke), our reluctant hero (Is there any
other kind in this type of cinema?), has reached the speed of light in
his sonic-busting jet, shattered it, and has found himself on the other
side of the time barrier. No small feat. But when he returns to his
home base of operations, he finds it lifeless and ravaged by time.
Little would he know how ravaged and by how much time. Also, as he will
later find out, a victim of a nuclear conflict. Whew! That's a lot to
swallow in one afternoon. Major Allison has definitely seen better
days. He is then zapped by a paralyzing ray (a lavish matte shot)
emanating from a futuristic metropolis and nestled next to a city in
smithereens. Major Allison now finds himself hauled off--against his
will--to an underground lodging facility. The Citadel, as the locals
refer to it, is inhabited by a race of humans cowering in fear from the
radiation scarred mutants living above. The city has a triangle motif
everywhere: doorways, hallways, video screens, etc. Labeled a "'scape,"
an outsider, by both the mutants and tunnel dwellers, Allison finds
solace and comfort in the arms of the super lovely Darlene Thomkins.
She plays a deaf mute who remains the only fertile female within
screaming distance. Or so says her father, "The Supreme." We know where
this is going--don't we? Allison meets several other 'scapes,
scientists from his future, who have other ideas on how he should spend
his time: less time with the horny chick and more time seeking a return
to his own time. Scientists are never any fun. In the end, the film is
a cautionary tale against the arms race. I think it works well enough
to be called a minor classic. If not--the mute female in the short
skirt should suffice. For now.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The basic idea behind "Beyond the Time Barrier" isn't bad--it's just
painfully obvious it was a super-low budget film. Too many set and
script problems lingered that would have been worked out if the film
makers had more than $45 to make the entire film. Despite this, the
film does have two minor stars in it--Victor Sokoloff (a familiar face
but a name you'll not readily recognize) and Robert Clark (who made a
few sci-fi films and guest starred on TV shows like "Dragnet").The film is set in 1960. Clark is a Major in the Air Force and is
flying a sub-orbital high altitude experimental flight. However,
something odd happens and he's somehow transported 64 years into the
future! And, unfortunately, the future completely sucks! It seems some
plague killed most of the folks on Earth and left most of the rest as
either mutants or total jerks! So, Clark has to somehow get back to his
time to alert the folks on Earth. Can he do it? And, is there any way
they'll believe him? And, will the complete and total jerks of the
future even let him attempt this...after all, they ARE jerks! Overall, despite the crappy sets, I could recommend this to lovers of
cheesy sci-fi. That's because the basic story isn't bad at all and it
ended very well. On the other hand, be forewarned--it is cheap--REALLY
cheap. The worst are the 'mutants' kept in prison. The ones near the
top of the steps and those down inside the pit are OBVIOUSLY from
different movies--and look NOTHING like each other!! The stairs ones
are guys (no ladies?) wearing the absolute worst skin-head wigs I've
ever seen! They are hilariously dumb. But, the folks living down in the
pit look almost like extras from "Island of Lost Souls"--all covered in
hair and looking a bit primordial!! Duh! So, if you can ignore the dumb
parts, it's not bad...but still uneven.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1488816/comments</url><from>from Australia</from><name>Mozjoukine (Mozjoukine@yahoo.com.au)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Britain's short lived magazine "Movie" pronounced BEYOND the TIME
BARRIER "a little miracle." The film, made in the Texas State Show
ground, back to back with The AMAZING TRANSPARENT MAN, has all the
features of the cheesiest of fifties B features -obvious stock shots,
tacky effects, walk-ons recruited from the crew (I was
advised
"Any one who said 'union' in Texas was a Communist and they shot him")
with a plot cobbled together from Buck Rogers and "The Time Machine."
Where then does this ringing endorsement come from?
In the fifties, it had been decided that the film's director was a
genuine auteur. Edgar G(orge) Ulmer has one of the most curious
filmographies of all, starting in the art department of the
Expressionist classics of the German silent Cinema, he
worked
with Murnau in Berlin and Hollywood. After Murnau's scandalous death,
Ulmer was,we were told, the only person game to show up at his funeral
and the master's mantle settled on his shoulders, getting him direction
of  The BLACK CAT from the tail end of the big budget Universal
horrors.
However, after refusing to be loaned out to the Shirley Temple unit, he
spend the decade knocking out Race Pictures on Poverty Row and did Z
films with the Producers Releasing Corporation, among which we note
DETOUR and BLUEBEARD. Flirting with more ambitious productions proved
unproductive and Ulmer returned to fringe activity including a nudie
movie.
Ulmer had already done the presentable MAN from PLANET X with Robert
Clarke who was attempting to forge a career as a leading man in what
would come to be called Psychotronic Cinema and they worked with a crew
of specialists in this area among who the great Vladimir Sokaloff (Loves
of Jeanne Ney, Mayerling, Life of Emile Zola and For Whom the Bell
Tolls) found himself playing a futuristic overlord.
Also on hand was master design Ernst Fegté, one of the few talents
embedded in Hans Dreier's art department to make his presence visible in
vintage Paramount productions. Fegté got an Oscar for 5 GRAVES to CAIRO.
His décors, made up of modular triangular blocks, provide Beyond TIME
BARRIER with a visual aspect not normal in these barrel scrapers - white
overalled scientists among the tapering pillars.
Plot has pilot Clarke shot into the upper atmosphere in the latest
supersonic airplane - "What we learn from the flight will pretty much
determine our next step in space." Occasionally the cut pricing pays as
with our hero, in his flying suit, wandering the derelict airport
rendered eerie by the lack of natural sound - who came up with
the
smashed piano?

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>2/10</rating><comment>
It's always interesting to watch futuristic films made in the past and
see how they turn out. The plague of cosmic rays foretold in Beyond The
Time Barrier has not occurred and it's already 2011 and it started in
1971 according to the film and Robert Clarke returns in 2024. Still though the cause of the plague is destruction of the atmospheric
barrier which is the ozone layer though not called that in the film and
in that sense the film is curiously relevant though they got the
immediate cause wrong.Robert Clarke plays a Chuck Yeager like test pilot who breaks the time
barrier and arrives in a world where some folks are living in a
hermetically sealed dome near what used to be White Sands Air Force
base. The rest are mutants who are sterile, mute or both. The head of
the group inside the dome, Vladimir Sokoloff decides to use Clarke with
his healthy sperm as the savior of civilization if he'll only mate with
his daughter Darlene Tompkins.The film spared every expense in the making it looks like it was shot
with an old Bell&amp;Howell home movie camera. Still it's an interesting
bit of work and you can't expect all that much from
American-International Pictures unless Roger Corman is involved
somewhat and even that's a dubious proposition.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7991675/comments</url><from>from Portland, OR, United States</from><name>flapdoodle64</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
After the release of 'Forbidden Planet' in 1956, and before the release
of 'Planet of the Apes' in 1968, the overwhelming number of science
fiction films were ultra-low budget affairs, generally produced to fill
out double-bills at drive-in theaters. I would posit that this period
should be called the Golden Era of Schlock.Schlock Scifi was not all bad...in fact, some of it was actually good,
and a lot of it is interesting, and sometimes fascinating. There is a
certain rough and ready charm to the earnestness and creativity of the
actors, writers and directors, with some Schlock films being like the
experience of watching community theater.This film contains creative usage of a derelict airfield, filmed and
edited to give the impression of a future of ruin and decay. The
director also made good use of some strange architecture at the Texas
State Fairgrounds, allowing the audience to make believe they are in
fact seeing the underground dwellings of the future.Stock footage of the F-102 'Delta Dagger' fighter plane is used to
represent an experimental rocket...and in an unusual move, the director
actually had a miniature created that matched the stock footage...the
FX are extremely primitive even by 1960 standards, but I have to give
them credit for finding a model of an F-102, because usually these
films just show stock footage of say, an A-4 rocket and then a model of
a B-52 or something completely unrelated. (BTW, the F-102 is what
former president George Bush flew when he was in the 'Champagne Unit'
of the Texas Air National Guard, avoiding Viet Nam.) There are some mildly scary screaming mutants here, who for some
reason, the civilized people of the future keep in a huge dungeon
inside their fortress, as opposed to a safer location outside the city.
The mutants are bald and wear coveralls in close ups and medium
shots...but when the camera looks down the stairs into the dungeon, the
mutants have long hair and wear caveman clothes. Obviously, director
Ulmer obtained some stock footage of the cavemen types and edited in to
save money and time. The mutants yell a lot.Robert Clarke is pretty decent as Our Hero the square jawed USAF pilot,
and Darlene Tompkins is strangely charming as Tirene, the cute mute in
the short skirt. In the city of the future, everyone is sterile except
for Tirene...until the arrival or Our Hero. The Supreme Leader of the
City of the Future, as well as Tirene, want Our Hero to impregnate
Tirene so as to perpetuate the human race.Apocalyptic Futures were in vogue during this era, but this film is
unusual in that rather than forecasting an atomic war, it instead
predicts Future Earth as a place where the atmosphere is gradually
degraded from unrelenting atomic testing, and the human race is
decimated by a series of plagues.This film somehow manages to convey a mood of melancholy and anxiety,
appropriate for the story of a man who learns that his world is going
to hell. The subplot regarding his role as a sperm-donor, admittedly an
adolescent male fantasy, is handled as plausibly as possible under the
circumstances. Perhaps Gene Roddenberry was influenced by this film,
since his 1964 unsold Star Trek pilot is also a story of a
science-fiction sperm donor.Many reviewers like to discuss ne'er-do-well director Edgar Ulmer's
style in this film. Certainly there are some elements of 1920's German
expressionism that help this film be a little more creepy and moody
than it would otherwise.In summary, this is a fun and interesting excursion into the land of
Schlock, and it is better and more interesting than most Schlock...yet
it was created as Schlock, and Schlock it will always be. View it in
this context, and you will be happy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17951941/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>dirk-crockett</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This movie is, in fact, available on DVD through Movies Unlimited
(moviesunlimited.com). However, don't expect a DVD-quality print of
this movie; it looks just like it did when you watched it on those late
night sci-fi showcases in the 60s (which, to me, is part of its
appeal). Not listed on the DVD case is the trailer for the movie, which
is tacked on at the very end. I was glad to add be able to add this to
my movie collection. I gave the movie 4 out of 10 stars based on it's
"cheese factor". Sometimes the cheapest movies are the most endearing,
and this one is a prime example. Silly dialog, homemade sets and
costumes, and laughable special effects. This is not a movie to watch
in prime time. This is a movie to plug in either late at night when
nothing else is on and everyone else is fast asleep and you're feeling
a little groggy yourself, or early afternoon when you're home from work
with a bad cold and drowsy from all the medicine. Then you won't take
it so seriously. Enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17951941/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>dirk-crockett</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
This movie is, in fact, available on DVD through Movies Unlimited
(moviesunlimited.com). However, don't expect a DVD-quality print of
this movie; it looks just like it did when you watched it on those late
night sci-fi showcases in the 60s (which, to me, is part of its
appeal). Not listed on the DVD case is the trailer for the movie, which
is tacked on at the very end. I was glad to add be able to add this to
my movie collection. I gave the movie 4 out of 10 stars based on it's
"cheese factor". Sometimes the cheapest movies are the most endearing,
and this one is a prime example. Silly dialog, homemade sets and
costumes, and laughable special effects. This is not a movie to watch
in prime time. This is a movie to plug in either late at night when
nothing else is on and everyone else is fast asleep and you're feeling
a little groggy yourself, or early afternoon when you're home from work
with a bad cold and drowsy from all the medicine. Then you won't take
it so seriously. Enjoy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17951941/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>dirk-crockett</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>