<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Angry Silence</original_title><alt_title>Le silence de la colère</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Guy Green</director><producer>Beaver Films</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
A young factory worker decides to stand up against his work-mates and fellow union members when they want to hold a wildcat strike.
</synopsis><actor>Richard Attenborough</actor><actor>Pier Angeli</actor><actor>Michael Craig</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0235840/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, England</from><name>Adrian Bailey (dadge@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This film doesn't seem to be very well known but it has a lot to offer.I've seen 50s/60s comedies based around factories but I can't remember
many
serious dramas like this. The plot holds few surprises but that leaves
plenty of room for us to judge the acting, and I'd say it's consistently
good. Richard Attenborough and Pier Angeli are a great combination as the
young married couple - it's a shame Pier made so few films in
English.A lot of scriptwriters could do worse than watch this film and learn its
lessons about how to tell a story in 90 minutes. And this is a good film
for
classroom use - leads nicely into a discussion of peer pressure and
bullying.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1683855/comments</url><from>from Derry, Ireland</from><name>Martin Bradley (MOscarbradley@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This brilliant, deeply contentious film has largely been ignored over
the years. It came out just as 'the kitchen sink' was kicking in and,
although dealing with the working class, was very much an establishment
film. It's right-wing and anti-Union and it quickly became very
unfashionable to think highly of it. But dramatically, it's first-rate;
it has the feel of those good BBC 'Plays for today' that came out in
the sixties even if does leave a very bad taste in the mouth.It's about a man sent to coventry for not supporting an unofficial
strike. He's played by Richard Attenborough and it's a great piece of
acting. As written, the character isn't developed in dramatic terms but
Attenborough is wonderfully naturalistic. It's an intuitive
performance; he gets inside the character's skin and thought processes.
He's very moving.There is very fine work, too, from Pier Angeli as his Italian wife.
(Angeli was probably brought in to sell the film in America, and
there's an easy-going, unforced quality to her acting that is very
'un-British'). And Bernard Lee is excellent as the dictatorial shop
steward. The film also has an unfortunate Mephistopolean character in
the form of an infiltrator. He's evil and cowardly and used in such a
blatantly metaphorical way you can't be sure exactly what his purpose
is. And being a political, Union bashing film you may feel uneasy
watching it. But there are very fine. sustained dramatic sequences, too
and it is utterly unsentimental.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0137908/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>didi-5</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

"The Angry Silence" can be read in two ways: one, it is a pretty accurate
depiction of the way union relations were run in the late 1950s and the
shadow of the far left; or, it is a propaganda piece for the far right and
nothing like the truth.  There are strong arguments for both camps to be
correct.What struck me about the film was the central performance from Richard
Attenborough as the lone worker standing up against bullying and blackmail
from his trade union colleagues.  One scene in particular which takes place
in the canteen is a masterclass in screen acting of its type, and there are
also good scenes between Attenborough and his screen wife, played by Pier
Angeli, and his work colleague and lodger, played by Michael
Craig.Bryan Forbes always seemed to be veering off in different directions with
the various movies on his CV, and this is an odd one.  Whatever your
politics, it is a good film and provokes a reaction.  Whether the reaction
is one which matches the reality has to remain open to
question.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1624054/comments</url><from>from Hartlepool England</from><name>toonnnnn</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A film which shows how Britains factories worked in the 50s,a place which
employs thousands of people,usually on low wages.The workers only
protection
is their union which of course is only fair.Then the union is taken over
by
a few dedicated  socialists who then are manipulated by the far lft.
.Everything that happens in this film is true to life,and shows that adults
soon behave like spoilt children when they don't get there own way.The
rights of the individual are soon gone,violence and bullying follows,the
film ask questions and leaves you asking your self questions at the
end.Well
worth a watch 8/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8746884/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Arthur Crown</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Guy Green's (1960) film of Bryan Forbes' screenplay is based on a
treatment by Michael Craig and, brother, Richard Gregson. Set in London
in the late 1950's it was the first release of the joint venture
production company Beaver Films set up by Bryan Forbes and Richard
Attenborough.As the film opens, we join Tom Curtis (Richard Attenborough) at work in
a small engineering factory beset with labour problems. Single-minded
and fiercely independent, Curtis is slow to grasp the implications of
the fomenting unrest among his workmates as they band together to
challenge the management head-on in a dispute that ultimately leaves
Curtis out in the cold.We follow Curtis home at night where his workmate Joe Wallis (Michael
Craig - also writer) lodges with Curtis, his wife Anna (Pier Angeli)
and their young family.But as industrial relations deteriorate at work we see Curtis becoming
increasingly isolated and intimidated by his determined colleagues.With solid performances from Bernard Lee (Bert Connolly), Geoffrey Keen
(Davis) and Alfred Burke (Travers) as the sinister agitator, the
audience sees Curtis left high and dry as even the management feel
compelled to abandon him.Increasingly out of his depth, we are drawn into Curtis' worsening
situation as his family are also intimidated in an effort to break his
indomitable will.This film captures something of the early struggle for recognition by
employees in small firms like this before employment protection became
enshrined in the law of the land. It gives us a feel for the situation
of the casualties along the way and the forces at play.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7845463/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>fcasnette</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
to anyone who lived through these times and these types of factory
settings this film resonates.The Burke character of the communist agitator invokes criticism of left
bashing but anyone who had experience of the British motor/engineering
industry in these times knows that it is much closer to the truth than
many people want to believe.However to those that think the film has right wing bias you only have
to look at how the useless fat cat directors are portrayed (having no
knowledge of the business they are taking large salaries from), hardly
an advertisement of capitalism. Plus even the "sympathetic" management
end up not supporting the worker who supported them, as bad as the
agitator in their own way.Good performances all round, outstanding from Richard Attenborough,
Pier Angeli, an unusually good turn by Michael Craig and dependable
Bernard Lee as the dim union man manipulated easily by the agitator.A style of film-making gone now but interesting social commentary of
the times. Recommended for social historians and affectionados of good
acting.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0112405/comments</url><from>from Putney, VT</from><name>Arne Andersen (aandersen@landmarkcollege.org)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is one of the finest of the late 1950s-early 1960s British "kitchen
sink" dramas - the gritty, realistic looks at working class folk and their
very real social problems.  Attenborough is against a strike at his factory
and although he initially rebels, he eventually gives in - but the other
workers bear a grudge and make his life ever more miserable.   An excellent
study in the costs of taking a stand against the mob and the brutal animal
mob mentality - or lack thereof.   Attenborough is fine and Pier Angeli
gives her best screen performance as his distraught wife.  Watch for Brian
Bedford and Oliver Reed in small roles.  This is well worth going out of
your way for - a thoughtful and absorbing, excellently written script - it
earned an Oscar Nom - and fine acting.  Editor was later director Anthony
Harvey.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0885866/comments</url><from>from Ile-de-France / Paris Region, France</from><name>Nicholas Rhodes</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Although I saw this film many years ago when I was a university in the
1970's, it would not appear to be very well known. A couple of years
ago it came out on DVD in the UK and I gobbled it up the day I found it
! In fact, the film is a masterpiece of acting. It depicts an age in
Britain's Industrial Relations which was ( fortunately for us all )
swept away when Margaret Thatcher's government came to power in 1979.
Prior to this, the British Economy was in a mess and all people could
think about doing was going on strike. The film, made in 1959
presumably depicts somewhere around the beginning of this period.
Nowadays, people don't speak of "closed shop" agreements, presumably
because it has been made illegal, but at the time, if you weren't a
member of a union, you had difficulties to be employed. T The film is
extremely violent in its ideas and although the physical violence is
limited, the underlying and implied violence in thought and ideas is
rather frightening. Scenes of Attenborough trying to enter the factory
to work and being intimidated by other striking workers really are very
shocking and difficult to watch. Attenborough's wife on the screen the
Beautiful and much regretted Pier Angela brings a soft and feminine
touch to this world of bigoted louts and layabouts. Watching someone
being sent to Coventry ( ie being ignored ) is no easy matter and I
felt quite sick at the way Attenborough was treated by his colleagues,
just because he refused to strike. Nowadays that sort of thing wouldn't
happen but at the time the mentality was different ( which just goes to
prove that the old mentalities are not always the better ones ) I was
curious to know about the person who arrives on a train at the
beginning and leaves just as furtively at the end. I don't know the
actor's name but he certainly had a face corresponding to the part. I
assume he was an agent from a competitor company sent by them to stir
up trouble amines the Martindale Employées so that another company
would get the orders. We don't have confirmation of this during the
film by that is my own idea. I originally thought he was a commy
infiltrator but then changed my mind after a few viewings of the film.I personally found the film very nourishing and very intense, true it
depicts a long lost era in British Labour Relations but the sheer
intensity of the acting and the violence means that one cannot get it
out of one's mind. What a shame we no longer have British Cinema today
producing films of this intensity on problems in current-day Britain!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0750451/comments</url><from>from Shropshire, England</from><name>whisperingtree</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Filmed in Ipswich, this screenplay, challenging in its time, gives a clear
portrayal of British Industrial relations during the time 'We never had it
so good.'
Alfred Burke's agent provocateur with his sinister telephone calls does
just
enough to suggest that the cold war was blowing through British
engineering.
Attenborough's innocent at the power lathe is nicely offset by the
underrated
Michael Craig as his friend and lodger forced to go along with the Union's
decision to send the strikebreaker to Coventry.
Good location shooting and the knowledge that things were not so very
different in reality makes this a handy movie from several perspectives.
Viewed with 'I'm Alright Jack' you can gain a fair impression of Britain
in
the days of Black and White Television
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10962676/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Alison Fairgrieve</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I remember the reviews of this film in 1960 but did not manage to see
it. Now (2007) I have seen most of it for the first time on afternoon
TV. It struck me at first as an anti union film, but so much water has
flowed under the bridge that it might be taken as a film about the herd
instinct; about how unthinking people are so easily led whether by
politicians of all persuasions or union reps with agenda of their own.
I deplore the near destruction of the unions by Thatcher, but one can
never return to voting by a show of hands any more than we can return
to the the industrial Britain of the post war era. Unions need to be
rebuilt but in another form. The young couple are too saintly by half but there is an attempt to
provide a certain amount of balance. Curtis actually says he can see
"both sides".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10962676/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Alison Fairgrieve</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I remember the reviews of this film in 1960 but did not manage to see
it. Now (2007) I have seen most of it for the first time on afternoon
TV. It struck me at first as an anti union film, but so much water has
flowed under the bridge that it might be taken as a film about the herd
instinct; about how unthinking people are so easily led whether by
politicians of all persuasions or union reps with agenda of their own.
I deplore the near destruction of the unions by Thatcher, but one can
never return to voting by a show of hands any more than we can return
to the the industrial Britain of the post war era. Unions need to be
rebuilt but in another form. The young couple are too saintly by half but there is an attempt to
provide a certain amount of balance. Curtis actually says he can see
"both sides".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10962676/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>Alison Fairgrieve</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>