<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Saffo, venere di Lesbo</original_title><alt_title>Sapho</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Pietro Francisci</director><producer>Documento Film</producer><producer>Orsay Films</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>History</genre><synopsis>She stormed the battlements of love and war!</synopsis><actor>Kerwin Mathews</actor><actor>Tina Louise</actor><actor>Riccardo Garrone</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0556157/comments</url><from/><name>Bryce David</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
When HERCULES, starring Steve Reeves and directed by Pietro Francisci,
became a phenomenon, a dizzying number of Sword &amp; Sandal (also known as
Peplum) films soon followed. Nearly 300 such films were made between
1958 and the mid-1960s thanks to the success of HERCULES. It's one of
the most unique film trends ever seen in cinematic history. Not even
STAR WARS generated so many films after its massive success. The Peplum
genre was diversified and many sub-genres proliferated, such as
Peplum/Comedies, Peplum/Sci-fi, Peplum/Historical and most notably the
Peplum/Romance sub-genre. Most Peplum films were made with kids or male
viewers in mind but female viewers were actually quite important for
the success of the genre and it was only logical that S&amp;S films
specifically made for female audiences were also produced. And this
film is part of that Peplum/Romance sub-genre.Known as THE WARRIOR EMPRESS in the US, which doesn't make any sense.
There is no Empress in the movie and even less a Warrior Empress. The
original Italian title translates to SAPPHO, VENUS OF LESBOS, which is
what I'll use for this review.SAPPHO, VENUS OF LESBOS is one satisfying S&amp;S film. Directed also by
Pietro Francisci, SAPPHO is fast, kitschy fun and dreamy. I'm memorized
by it. After I initially saw it, I watched it once a day 4 days in a
row. Regardless of the fact that there are no bare-chested men in it
(which is THE main ingredient for a Peplum) SAPPHO hits all the right
Peplum notes. Even if it's a romantic film filled with the usual
conflicts of two men fighting over Sappho, it still has a lot of sword
fights, chariot race, an impressive big battle, ramming ships and, of
course, killer lions, all set to a great swirling score.Take the beginning, for example, which I find brilliant. The set-up is
amazing: the first 10 minutes has minimal dialogue, mainly music and
sound. It introduces the characters in action and creates a wonderful
world that swept you up and never lets go till the end of the film. The
direction is mesmerizing. All the main actors give their all. Tina Louise is perfect as Sappho,
"the world's boldest beauty", as the film's tag-line says. The handsome
Kerwin Mathews (who died last year, RIP) gives a thoughtful energetic
performance. Kerwin was definitely an overlooked actor.But best of all is the uniquely dashing Riccardo Garrone as Hyperbius,
who almost steals the film from the American actors. Garrone gives a
forceful performance that could have easily fallen into caricature but
here he's totally believable. In contrast, the actor who plays the King
is a caricature and is one of the weak notes in the film. Susy Andersen
(credited as Susy Golgi), the actress who plays Actis, Sappho's close
friend, is a stunning beauty. What happens to her character is one of
the most pivotal moments.This film has the best named cast of characters ever: Sappho, Phaon,
Hyperbius, Actis, Laricus, Melanchrus, etc. The soldiers' costumes are some of the coolest ever designed. Dark and
detailed, with impressive Rooster-like helmets and short skirt line
which accentuates, if anything else, the men's legs. And the girls'
unique blue &amp; black "nightgowns" are fetching even if they're probably
not historically accurate. The score by Angelo Francesco Lavagnino is truly a thing of beauty.
Lavagnino is, like so many who worked in the Peplum genre, underrated,
to say the least.By now this film is totally forgotten. Heck, this will be the first
review here at IMDb. And it's a shame because it's great fun and near
perfect Peplum kitsch! Thanks Pietro Francisci!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
To begin with, I watched this patiently expecting the titular figure to
turn up somewhere along the line but, after 90 minutes, no such luck!
For what it is worth, the film does mark a potentially intriguing
overlap of epic exponents – namely director Francisci (who, with
HERCULES {1957}, led the peplum into its most popular phase) and star
Kerwin Mathews (who had been the protagonist in many an effects-filled
fantasy/adventure). However, what we have here is a thoroughly routine
effort with the emphasis on romance and dancing – the heroine (played
by Tina Louise) is one of a group of scantily-clad Vestal
Virgins-cum-Amazonians (they even get to demonstrate their ostensible
ruggedness by organizing a chariot race amongst themselves!) who, while
engaged to soldier Riccardo Garrone (best-known as a comic and for his
TV ads publicizing coffee in the guise of Saint Peter!), becomes
involved with wounded fugitive agitator Mathews when he takes refuge in
their remote temple ("an island within an island", as Garrone describes
it solely for the viewer's benefit).A semi-interesting revelation concerns Mathews' true métier; however,
the film falters mainly because we are supposed to believe that the
people are oppressed yet, not only do we get scarce evidence to this
end but the tyrant (hammily played by Enrico Maria Salerno) is, at
best, an eccentric obsessed with his own cleanliness (he is constantly
asking whether his bath has been prepared)! In fact, the potentate is
merely exiled at the end, leaving the jilted Garrone to bear the brunt
of the villain's expected come-uppance (at the hands of a lion, since a
den filled with these animals conveniently lies just outside the
Vestals' temple-gate, presumably to prevent anyone entering or
exiting). By the way, the original Italian title of this one is highly
suggestive – SAPPHO, VENUS OF LESBO (for the record, a real-life Greek
poetess/muse)! – but the only other tell-tale sign (apart from the
girls' afore-mentioned athletic prowess) of any homosexual activity
going on behind closed doors is the fact that Louise's room-mate proves
jealous of her attentions for the hero, reports him to the
naturally-annoyed Garrone (though he fails to notice her own pining for
his fiancée!) and, predictably, gets her just desserts by eventually
becoming lion-fodder.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5488899/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>OldAle1</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
The Italian title is "Saffo, venere di Lesbo" which I guess is
something like "Sappho, Venus of Lesbos" but anybody who can read
Italian go ahead and correct me (Babelfish was no help). Doesn't
matter, you get the idea - this is a peplum, Italian sword-and-sandals
cheapie, and Sappho (Tina Louise) happens to be the main character. Of
course this bears little or no resemblance to the historic poetess, and
anybody thinking that "sappho" and "lesbos" means there's going to be
some girl-girl action here had best be disabused of that right away.
"The Warrior Empress" is probably as good a title as any for this
cheesy romp, when it comes down to it.Sappho is one of the heirs of Melanchrus, a slovenly and sybaritic king
who keeps taxing the people beyond their means and ultimately inciting
a revolt. Kerwin Matthews is Phaon the double-agent in the king's guard
who leads the revolt and, of course, falls for Sappho who is however
promised to Hyperbius (Italian actor Riccardo Garrone in the sole good
performance in the film). Fighting and declaiming over freedom, and a
really badly staged and laughable sea battle between two triremes
follow.The sets are as cardboard and pathetic as anything out of the original
"Star Trek" and Matthews' and Louise' acting is of a par. Still,
laughable fun and I look forward to exploring more of this genre
someday.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5488899/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>OldAle1</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
The Italian title is "Saffo, venere di Lesbo" which I guess is
something like "Sappho, Venus of Lesbos" but anybody who can read
Italian go ahead and correct me (Babelfish was no help). Doesn't
matter, you get the idea - this is a peplum, Italian sword-and-sandals
cheapie, and Sappho (Tina Louise) happens to be the main character. Of
course this bears little or no resemblance to the historic poetess, and
anybody thinking that "sappho" and "lesbos" means there's going to be
some girl-girl action here had best be disabused of that right away.
"The Warrior Empress" is probably as good a title as any for this
cheesy romp, when it comes down to it.Sappho is one of the heirs of Melanchrus, a slovenly and sybaritic king
who keeps taxing the people beyond their means and ultimately inciting
a revolt. Kerwin Matthews is Phaon the double-agent in the king's guard
who leads the revolt and, of course, falls for Sappho who is however
promised to Hyperbius (Italian actor Riccardo Garrone in the sole good
performance in the film). Fighting and declaiming over freedom, and a
really badly staged and laughable sea battle between two triremes
follow.The sets are as cardboard and pathetic as anything out of the original
"Star Trek" and Matthews' and Louise' acting is of a par. Still,
laughable fun and I look forward to exploring more of this genre
someday.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5488899/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>OldAle1</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>