<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Dinosaurus!</original_title><imdb_rating>4.7</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Irvin S. Yeaworth Jr.</director><producer>Fairview Productions</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
After undersea explosions near a Caribbean island, prehistoric creatures are unleashed on the unsuspecting population...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ward Ramsey</actor><actor>Paul Lukather</actor><actor>Kristina Hanson</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1059975/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, Canada</from><name>reptilicus</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I admit it, I am a fan of stop motion animation. It can be excellent or
hideous but if it's stop motion I am so there! I was first attracted to
this movie when I was very young because it had dinosaurs in it (yes it
had a caveman too but he was secondary to me).Anyway, so why is this particular movie forever tied to my birthday?
Therein lies a tale. 20 July 1969 will be forever remembered as the day
Neil Armstrong walked on the Moon. That day was also my 5th birthday
and I was watching DINOSAURUS in my room on my 12 inch b/w TV. Just at
the scene where the mortally wounded Brontosaurus lumbers into the
quicksand the movie faded out for a commercial break. Then it cut to
the TV newsroom where they were talking about the landing on the Moon.
My uncle came into my room to ask if I was watching the news and I said
"No, I'm waiting for the movie to come back on." This made him start talking about how history was being made and I
should be proud I could see this moment live and so on. Okay so to-0day
I am aware of how important it was but back then I was 5 years old and
this was a movie that had DINOSAURS in it for cryin' out loud! Let's
just say my priorities were a lot different back then.When the movie finally came back on I was as happy as could be and it
had my undivided attention all the way to the end.Now I make it a point to watch this movie every year on my birthday and
at the scene where the Brontosaurus dies I cannot help but think about
the first Moon landing. Curious how completely unrelated memories
somehow get joined together isn't it?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0663294/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>ClassixFan</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Now, that doesn't necessarily mean this is a bad film....quite the
contrary, in my humble opinion. Sure, the story has some huge holes,
but don't you watch a film to be entertained and just to let yourself
relax without the need to think every minute? This film is definitely
right up your alley, if you enjoy dinosaurs and stop-motion animation.Basically, this is the story of a construction crew that finds the
bodies of a T-Rex, Brontosaurus and caveman frozen in the waters off a
tropical island. With the help of lightning, the beasties and the
caveman are brought back among the living and the remainder of the
story is all the action that takes place when you place three
pre-historics out of their element. Good clean fun, some decent
stop-animation effects and a great way to spend an afternoon.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2027849/comments</url><from>from Seattle, Wa.</from><name>drsmcduncan</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I have an emotional attachment to this movie, as it was the first movie I
ever went to a theater to see.  As a six year old living in Fairbanks,
Alaska, I begged my mother to take me to see this move about my childhood
passion, dinosaurs.  Thirty years later, I stumbled across a copy of this
film at a video store and purchased it.  I was surprised to find that,
despite the rather unrealistic dinosaur animation, the movie holds up
pretty
well.  Although much criticism has been directed against the leads in
this
film, Wayne Treadway as Dumpy ("Dinosaurus!"),
Jack Younger as Jasper (Jasper: "Well, we're looking for a caveman,
right?
So, I think we ought to look in a cave!"  Hacker: "Very good, Jasper, I
had
no idea you were an anthropologist."  Jasper:  "Not a very good one,
boss.
I haven't been to church in years.") and Gregg Martell as the Neanderthal
Man turn in excellent performances in supporting roles.  Martell,
especially, combines comedy and pathos in his portrayal of a man caught
out
of his time but still very much a human being.  The scene where Julio
(Alan
Roberts) rides the back of his pet brontosaurus thrilled me and the final
battle between the T-Rex and the steam shovel gave me nightmares for
years.
How many good movies can you say that about?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16231491/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Michael Hall (mikecowboy1996@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Honestly, 4.4/10?!? It wasn't that bad! I haven't seen this film in
awhile and I decided to watch in again today.Its a pretty good film for
its time.Sure, the acting is a little cheesy, but its a great movie!
Ahh, yes, IMDb's plot for the movie. ''...After undersea explosions
near a Caribbean island, prehistoric creatures are unleashed on the
unsuspecting population. Freed from his watery tomb, as well, is a very
friendly Neanderthal man who proceeds to befriend a local orphan boy.
The boy, Neanderthal and irritated dinosaur make for an interesting
dramatic climax.'' Couldn't explain the plot any better.The Neanderthal
man who has also come back along with the dinosaurs, is actually a
caveman! He can give you a good laugh every once in awhile.He is just
hilarious.This is an awesome movie to pop in the VCR and watch on a
Saturday night.You should really check it out if you're a into
dinosaurs, like I am.10/10!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0356617/comments</url><from/><name>G.Spider</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Underwater bomb-testing at an island causes the unearthing of two
dinosaurs
and a caveman, who are then revived by lightning during a tropical storm.
Before long the locals are stranded and in danger from the flesh-eating
Tyrannosaur.People seem to complain about how cruel the film-makers are to the
dinosaurs
in this and other similar films like 'Valley of Gwangi'.  But how they can
rant about the treatment of latex models and yet not care one iota about
the
abuse of real animals used in some 'dinosaur' films such as the 1960 'Lost
World' is a mystery.  This film has a more moody atmosphere than many
films
of this genre, it's true, but so what?  Many of the scenes are wisely set
at
night, and the sequence involving the two dinosaurs which have just been
dragged up onto the beach is a genuine edge-of-seater.  The
authority-abusing island manager is excellently villainous, the music is
superbly atmospheric and there are humorous little pieces of
dialogue.The film does have a few failings, however.  The dinosaurs themselves look
on the cheap side and scenes involving the caveman all too often descend
into comedy.  But overall this is a highly watchable and entertaining
story,
which is more than can be said about the effects-dependent dross of
today.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur19368298/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ctomvelu-1</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I was 10 when I saw DINOSAURUS in a theater. While the acting left much
to be desired, and the film was obviously shot on a shoestring, the
animated dinosaurs seemed pretty awesome for the time. Ray Harryhausen
this ain't, but for a dinosaur-loving kid like myself, it definitely
hit the spot. A caveman and two dinosaurs, one of them a T-Rex, are
discovered and accidentally revived in 1960. In the end, it takes a
modern mechanical marvel to subdue the rampaging T-Rex. The caveman
befriends a little boy, whom I assume we tykes in the audience were
meant to identify with. Good fun. Best seen on a big screen with
booming sound, and today that's possible right at home with a large
flat-screen digital TV and a 5.1 Dolby home theater setup.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I've seen Dinosaurus several times and is quite a good dinosaur movie.
I taped it when Channel 4 screened it some years ago.Off a remote island in the Caribbean, bomb testing in the sea frees a
T-Rex, a Brontosaurus and a caveman and the two dinosaurs are pulled
ashore while the caveman is washed ashore. That night during a
thunderstorm, they are struck by lightening and come to life. The T-Rex
takes away O'Leary (who was assigned to guard them) and eats him and
his shack blows up. The Brontosaurus and caveman start exploring the
island and the T-Rex and Brontosauris fight near the end and the
Brontosaurus sinks in some quick sand. The island's residents are all
evacuated to the fortress for safety and the T-Rex is pushed into the
sea at the end by a bulldozer but may not be dead...The highlights of Dinosaurus are the caveman exploring a house and
frightening the woman who lives there and the battle between the T-Rex
and bulldozer at the end.The T-Rex and Brontosaurus never fought each other in real life as they
are from different ages, the T-Rex being a Cretaceous dinosaur and the
Brontosaurus is from the Jurassic Peroid.The cast is mostly made up of unknowns lead by Ward Ramsey with Greg
Martell as the caveman.Dinosaurus is worth seeing especially if you like dinosaur movies.
Great fun.Rating: 4 stars out of 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17458773/comments</url><from>from Tampa FL</from><name>Mutakk</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
A harmless low-budget movie from one of the people responsible for the
original "The Blob" and "The 4D Man". Hurricane pulls up perfectly
preserved dinosaur bodies from the ocean floor; Tyrannosaur and
Brontosaurus, and a caveman. Lightning strikes, dinosaurs come to lift
and terrorize bad actors. Caveman comes to life also, befriends kid,
and ends up riding the brontosaurus.I saw this years ago, and remember it as being kinda cool. Always
remembered the caveman trying to eat plastic fruit, then wondering into
the bathroom and flushing the toilet. The FX were OK, I guess. Think
they used puppets, and some stop-motion. Final confrontation with the
Tyrannosaur vs a tractor was cool. Kind of a precursor for Ripley's
duel with the queen in "Aliens.""Dinosaurus!" certainly won't make you forget "Jurassic Park," but it's
an enjoyable little movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0166205/comments</url><from>from NC</from><name>BaronBl00d (baronbl00d@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

A group of Americans come to a remote island to find minerals only to
uncover dinosaurs from the bed of the ocean with underwater explosives.  Not
only do they find two frozen and incredibly intact dinosaurs millions of
years old, but they also find a million year old caveman.  The premise is by
itself somewhat plausible, but when you add trite and inept dialogue, some
of the worst acting imaginable, cheap dinosaur effects, and one ridiculous
caveman you have one funny picture.  Dinosaurus will leave you in stitches
if you appreciate badly made films.  The dinosaurs themselves really are not
that bad, but the acting....the acting...is on par with something found in
an H. G. Lewis picture.  Almost no one has any acting savvy whatsoever.  The
best actor in the film is a young teenage boy who befriends the caveman and
the brontosaurus.  Once again the T-Rex is the bad one, chasing anything
that moves across the island.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10436262/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>jurandyrsf</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Would you believe if you were told that two of the most memorable
scenes of the worldly famous Jurassic Park franchise are direct copies
taken from a mostly obscure, B-class movie shot decades before Michael
Crichton conceived his blockbuster, genetic dinos? A T-Rex crushing a
land rover under its foot in J.P. I; and a dinosaur killing another by
twisting and breaking its neck in J.P. III. The land rover scene is
almost a replica of the original; in the second case, the main
differences in the remake are that the T-Rex is now the victim instead
of the culprit, and its neck is snapped broken, in contrast with the
slow twist the T-Rex applied to kill its opponent, a friendly
brontosaurus. As the old saying goes, imitation is the sincerest form
of flattery...But this is just one reason I chose to review Dinosaurus! It was my
first dinosaur movie in the big screen, and I left the theater in
ecstasy. In fact, the second one was Jurassic Park, twenty years plus
later, and the feeling was about the same. I watched all other
dino-movies in-between on TV.That was a time when the only book published in my country about the
wonder-beasts was a great little book authored by Roy Chapman Andrews.
I was blessed to have a set of slides of prehistoric animals. TV was
black-and-white. So that movie did leave an impression! Dinosaurus! fed
my imagination and my soul for a very long period, so I'm very fond of
it, and that's why Í chose to review the title.On the technical side, one should compare it to other of the same
technological batch. Yes, it would still be a B- or C-movie in what
regards to dino-mation, but sufficiently passable for an eight-years
old kid who hadn't seen anything alike, even less superior to it. All
in all, it "delivered".About the story, who cares??!! I was seeing gigantic, in-color
dinosaurs at the cinema! It was good enough to make the story flow. Take a look and watch for yourself...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10436262/comments</url><from>from Brazil</from><name>jurandyrsf</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Would you believe if you were told that two of the most memorable
scenes of the worldly famous Jurassic Park franchise are direct copies
taken from a mostly obscure, B-class movie shot decades before Michael
Crichton conceived his blockbuster, genetic dinos? A T-Rex crushing a
land rover under its foot in J.P. I; and a dinosaur killing another by
twisting and breaking its neck in J.P. III. The land rover scene is
almost a replica of the original; in the second case, the main
differences in the remake are that the T-Rex is now the victim instead
of the culprit, and its neck is snapped broken, in contrast with the
slow twist the T-Rex applied to kill its opponent, a friendly
brontosaurus. As the old saying goes, imitation is the sincerest form
of flattery...But this is just one reason I chose to review Dinosaurus! It was my
first dinosaur movie in the big screen, and I left the theater in
ecstasy. In fact, the second one was Jurassic Park, twenty years plus
later, and the feeling was about the same. I watched all other
dino-movies in-between on TV.That was a time when the only book published in my country about the
wonder-beasts was a great little book authored by Roy Chapman Andrews.
I was blessed to have a set of slides of prehistoric animals. TV was
black-and-white. So that movie did leave an impression! Dinosaurus! fed
my imagination and my soul for a very long period, so I'm very fond of
it, and that's why Í chose to review the title.On the technical side, one should compare it to other of the same
technological batch. Yes, it would still be a B- or C-movie in what
regards to dino-mation, but sufficiently passable for an eight-years
old kid who hadn't seen anything alike, even less superior to it. All
in all, it "delivered".About the story, who cares??!! I was seeing gigantic, in-color
dinosaurs at the cinema! It was good enough to make the story flow. Take a look and watch for yourself...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/dinosaurus/comments.php?reviewid=797754</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Too goofy to dislike</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/mark-r-leeper/</url><url>/m/dinosaurus/comments.php?reviewid=1334904</url><name>Mark R. Leeper</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/65476/dinosaurus.html /m/dinosaurus/comments.php?reviewid=1474903</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9C01E1DA1F3EEF3ABC4153DFBF66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/dinosaurus/comments.php?reviewid=1390460</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102806 /m/dinosaurus/comments.php?reviewid=1148490</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>