<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>There Was a Crooked Man</original_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Stuart Burge</director><producer>Knightsbridge Films</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
When a law-abiding demolition expert is duped by a gang of criminals into helping them he is caught and jailed...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Norman Wisdom</actor><actor>Alfred Marks</actor><actor>Andrew Cruickshank</actor><rt_rating>7.2/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3569359/comments</url><from>from basildon, essex</from><name>robreel-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Despite this not being seen since it's general release, i was lucky
enough to see this classic comedy. This really stretches Normans
talents to the full, This really deserves a DVD release of some sort
cause it's probably lost or forgotten, someone needs to save this
film!!!!!! There are however some fine performances from certain other
actors, but norman steals the limelight, accidentally getting in
trouble for robbing a safe, it's probably his best work in a movie,
other wisdom films at the time were "the bulldog breed" and "on the
beat" both classics by far, but this one glimmers alone on a shelve in
an achieve somewhere waiting to be cleaned up for our general viewing.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17642902/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>trevorwhitnall</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Out of the 20 films the great Sir Norman has made this is the only one
I have yet to see- but why? All film books say it is one of his best,
and yet it has never been screened on TV or released on video/DVD. Come
on, whoever can make it possible, show this film, or make it available
for all die-hard Sir Norman fans so we can experience more of this
amazing mans talents. Sir Norman is a national treasure to be cherished
for all time and, having met him 6 times I can honestly say what a
lovely, down to earth person he is, and I am sure he would want this
one missing film of his to be available to his legion of devoted fans,
so come on, someone, put right this glaring oversight.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17140073/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>rstout3526</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
This long lost classic is out there somewhere. During the last
Christmas break I joined a group of people in our local pub to watch
Norman Wisdom in The Bulldog Breed on someone's laptop. It was from one
of those streaming sites. At the end of the film someone mentioned
TWACM and this chap brought it up on his screen. I sat and watched it
right through - full titles, music, credits etc. Therefore if it is
available to screen on the internet then surely it must be available to
buy on DVD? I have tried to find a copy without luck, however, on the
Darwen, Lancashire web site there is mention of this film being
screened recently in the town hall in celebration of films made in
Darwen - Brief Encounter etc. Apparently the town hall scenes in TWACM
were filmed there.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20552756/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>TheLittleSongbird</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
While there are those who are left cold by Norman Wisdom, I am not one
of those people. In fact, I am quite fond of him. There Was a Crooked
Man is my favourite film of his, and he couldn't have been more perfect
here in his role as he teams up with crooks to outwit the mayor of a
northern town. His role here allows him to maintain his poor but honest
persona and his wide eyed innocence that makes him so endearing to me,
but it is probably the most versatile of his roles as well. There Was a
Crooked Man benefits further from striking filming, quirky music, fun
direction and sparkling dialogue. In terms of performances, Wisdom
makes the film for me, but he has some excellent foils also in the form
of Alfred Marks and Andrew Cruishank. Then there is the comedy, There
Was a Crooked Man in my opinion contains some of the best things Wisdom
ever did. The bank robbery, the battle with the factory machinery and
Brian Oulton taking a shower unaware that Wisdom is in the stall with
him particularly stand out. In conclusion, a divine comedy and my
favourite of a talented performer. 10/10 Bethany Cox
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur23690546/comments</url><from>from SEAVIEW, I.W., United Kingdom</from><name>whiffletree-814-954847</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film in 1960 (at The Theatre Royal Cinema?)in Ryde Isle of
Wight. As always with Norman's films, I enjoyed it a lot. Why this film
stuck in my mind for so many years, was that suddenly on screen, to my
amazement, a shot of Ryde Pier's entrance appeared. I also wonder if
the town that was "blown up" was Ryde too... The three cinemas in Ryde
were; The Theatre Royal, The Scala (later Plaza) and The Commodore. The
Scala became a supermarket, The Theatre Royal burned down (being
replaced by a Natwest Bank), the last film shown there was a film by
Tony Hancock, as I found a small scrap of the film in the street after
the event. It occurred to me today, that I haven't seen "There Was a
Crooked Man" for FIFTY YEARS!!! The only remaining cinema in Ryde now
is The Commodore.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14474383/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>delval-7</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film in London as a child. It is a first rate Norman Wisdom
film, shot on the south coast, where Norman's inept 'crook' manages to
blow up half of a seaside town. It was released on the Rank circuit and
shortly after showing in South London, was pulled due to threatened
legal action over ownership of rights. As far as I know, it has not
been screened since and there have been no television showings, so one
can only guess that the problem has not been solved. Hopefully this is
an incorrect assumption and the matter has been resolved so that once
again this excellent comedy will be available for all to enjoy. If
anyone has any further information about this matter, I would be
delighted to hear about it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14474383/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>delval-7</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film in London as a child. It is a first rate Norman Wisdom
film, shot on the south coast, where Norman's inept 'crook' manages to
blow up half of a seaside town. It was released on the Rank circuit and
shortly after showing in South London, was pulled due to threatened
legal action over ownership of rights. As far as I know, it has not
been screened since and there have been no television showings, so one
can only guess that the problem has not been solved. Hopefully this is
an incorrect assumption and the matter has been resolved so that once
again this excellent comedy will be available for all to enjoy. If
anyone has any further information about this matter, I would be
delighted to hear about it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-nusair/</url><url>http://www.reelfilm.com/wardec06.htm#there /m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1572492</url><name>David Nusair</name><from>Reel Film Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
3/4
					</rating><comment>...a solid little Western that's worth a look if only for its refreshingly cynical sensibilities.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pablo-villaca/</url><url>/m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1572172</url><name>Pablo Villaca</name><from>Cinema em Cena</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>O senso de humor do filme desarma de maneira brilhante o espectador, pegando-o completamente de surpresa com o cinismo de seu terceiro ato.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/chuck-oleary/</url><url>/m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1621245</url><name>Chuck O'Leary</name><from>FulvueDrive-in.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1415538</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/robin-clifford/</url><url>/m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1281103</url><name>Robin Clifford</name><from>Reeling Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dragan-antulov/</url><url>http://reviews.imdb.com/Reviews/218/21833 /m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=770867</url><name>Dragan Antulov</name><from>rec.arts.movies.reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
8/10
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117795599.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1806607</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/geoff-andrew/</url><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/79189/there_was_a_crooked_man.html /m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1519067</url><name>Geoff Andrew</name><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/vincent-canby/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9E0CE5D61431E336A05755C2A9649D946190D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1389852</url><name>Vincent Canby</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=109195 /m/there_was_a_crooked_man/comments.php?reviewid=1147633</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>