<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ein Toter hing im Netz</original_title><alt_title>L'île du sadique</alt_title><imdb_rating>2.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>West Germany</country><country>Yugoslavia</country><director>Fritz Böttger</director><producer>Intercontinental Film GmbH</producer><producer>Rapid Film</producer><genre>Horror</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
Survivors of a plane crash on a remote island find it is covered by spiders. When bitten, the survivors start turning into spiders!
</synopsis><actor>Harald Maresch</actor><actor>Helga Franck</actor><actor>Alexander D'Arcy</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2074560/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Gafke</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Silly, stupid, bad acting, worse dubbing, non-existent plot...I liked
this movie!Manly and ruggedly handsome Gary and his sweet and shrewd girlfriend
Georgia are taking a team of dancing girls down to Singapore. Too bad
their plane catches fire and slams into the ocean at full speed.
Miraculously, Gary, Georgia and most of the dancers survive this
horrific accident with not a broken limb or even a bruise in sight.
They wash up on an uncharted desert isle and find a cabin containing a
corpse hanging in a giant spider web. Momentarily upset, they soon
shrug it off and strip down to their underwear while a sultry sax
plays. Gary wanders off into the stormy night after Georgia catches him
playing tongue wars with one of the sluttier dancers. He never returns.
Georgia and the other girls are now alone on the island...or are they?
Some unknown menace strangles the slut and then disappears again,
leaving the rest of the girls to go skinny dipping and wrestle each
other in their underwear. When a small boat arrives, carrying the
partners of the dead man in the web, there's time for a wild dance
party and lots of making out before sailing home. Unfortunately, Gary
has been waiting all this time (having done nothing but hide inside of
a tree for the entire middle of the movie) and makes his appearance on
this last night, ready to wreak bloody carnage! Gary has been bitten by
a mutant spider and is now one himself...sort of. Actually, he looks
kind of like Neanderthal Man with glue- on vampire fangs but we're
supposed to believe that he is now a spider monster! The horror elements of this film seemed almost an afterthought, thrown
in to attract a larger crowd. Really, this is just an exploitation
film, featuring lots of curvy young women gadding about in their
underthings, dancing, cat-fighting, swimming, bathing and seducing the
young men who find them. It's a terrible movie, but it's amusing
nonetheless. If you like cheap exploitation and aren't picky about
things like plot, then you'll enjoy this one. It's a really poor man's
Russ Meyer film...with spiders!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0888000/comments</url><from>from Minneapolis, MN</from><name>eegah-3 (eegah@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Basically this is an excuse to watch a bunch of shapely Eurobabes in
bikinis
frolic on an island.  There is one little spider monster that gets killed
off pretty quick and Alex D'Arcy running around as a half-man/half-spider
monster but all he does is slowly stick his claw hand out to grab some of
the girls with no real menace whatsoever.  Maybe he's supposed to be one
of
those tragic sympathetic monsters.  Anyway, the English dubbing is
entertainingly bad and the jazzy score gives the film the right aura of
burlesque.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4103048/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>FranklinTV</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
It doesn't take you long to suspect that this movie was made quickly
and cheaply, and the opening scenes with the 'dance girl' auditions is
definitely a large signpost which says "Bad Movie Buffs Only".As you might expect from the title, there needs to be a way to quickly
get our girls (and guy) to Spider Island, and the obligatory plane
crash helps. It's the highlight of the film, as the stock footage
suggests we are no longer watching a DC-3, but rather a Kamikaze plane
in a ball of fire rapidly dropping from the sky into a raging sea. The
fact that they all manage to survive almost confirms the amazing
optimism expressed by the girls manager back on shore, where he tells a
distressed relative on the phone "No need to fear the worse, all we
know is the plane caught fire and we lost radio contact".OK, I think its best come clean and reveal that the real horror of
Spider Island is the appalling overdubbing of the voices. In fact,
after a while, you start listening to the secondary sound effects, to
see if they are as equally bad. I particularly like a scene where
someone is showering in a waterfall, but the actual sound effect is
that of someone gargling water. So, the film does manage in this way to
keep your interest.And, in a strange way, as the plot and women begin to be revealed, you
begin to wonder what will happen next, only because you know it will
not be logical, and probably will involve women fighting. And the women
are great, a flash back to when buxom was in, women could really
cat-fight, and they had no trouble in throwing themselves shamelessly
at an ordinary man.So overall, a few agreeable moments for the bad film buff. In
particular, I suggest you watch out early on for the logical jump when
they find an extended-handle hammer, and the guy concludes: "Ahh, an
extended-handle hammer, they must be mining uranium". Now, as well
known in bad film land, uranium is the universal cause of giant nasty
animals, so you are ready for big spiders to start appearing. Yet, in
this film, uranium also seems to be an aphrodisiac, making the
extended-handle hammer metaphor even more poignant.This movie was on the Treeline 50 sci-fi classics compilation – I
suspect it is not readily available as a single release. The type of
film you wouldn't seek to watch, but if you are stuck on the lounge
after a heavy pizza and it came on, you probably would end up watching
it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0441725/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>B Murphy</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The HORRORS of being trapped with lovely women for days and days!  One
cannot imagine the terrible, horrible, mind-blowing pressure that must have
been gnawing at Gary's very soul...oh, who am I kidding?  Character depth is
all three dimensional here, as in "I wish this movie had been filmed in 3D".
 Girls in ripped dresses, towels, bikinis, and floral panties, and is there
a downside? Well, yes, there is the terror of bad dubbing, and the fear of
back story being told in a painfully ungainly way.  Thank God for MST, and
it is a crime they are gone.  I miss them.  Anyhoo, if ya get the chance, and can take the intense heat, check out this
rockin' flick.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0382348/comments</url><from>from Frankfort, IN</from><name>Timothy L. Fox</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

After seeing First Spaceship on Venus, I thought all German films were
intellectual. Then I saw Hamlet on MST3K. Too bad. But then this wonderful
piece of schlock shows up on MST3K. Sheesh! Not since Wild Wild World of
Batwoman have I seen such a uh, shall I say, appealing movie (I love its
alternate title, "It's Hot in Paradise"). Plot? Pheh! Some high-panted
manager (who crosses legs to show if he likes the dancers or not) crashes
on
an island with a bunch of buxom women. Then they find a dead professor in
a
web, the manager gets bitten by a spider and turns into Michael Landon's
werewolf monster, some sailors come and find they girls, and they all have
a
great time.Did I mention the best part of the film? Yes, the reason why I compared
this
with Batwoman was the obvious sexploitation. The girls appear in tights,
bras, nightgowns, towls, go swimming in the buff, dress in "island
clothes"
for the sailors (they look like bras and panties designed by Luther
Burbank;
you'll have to see it to get it) and there's a catfight. As Tom Servo said
when a girl took off her shirt, "And now the film reveals it's true
purpose."So, if you want to have a good time and don't have enough money to go to
the
theater, watch this on MST3K. And be weary of the girl who keeps changing
accents. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0443668/comments</url><from>from Frederick, MD</from><name>Brian Manville (Sterno-2)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When I watched and later reviewed "The Sinister Urge", I made the comment
that pornography, as was defined by Ed Wood, consisted of women in
non-revealing bikinis.  I must amend that statement.  Pornography in the
case of "Horrors of Spider Island" consists of women wearing furry bikinis,
as well as prancing, preening, and stripping at the drop of ANY
hat.Our story concerns the "tragic" plane flight of a group of dancers and their
manager on their trip to Singapore.  I guess the nice people of Singapore
needed evidence of a morally bankrupt society before they went with their
fundamental Islamic state.  Anyhow, the girls are more seriously threatened
by one of the guys who comes to rescue them.  There's a dead professor, some
uranium, and this mutant spider that's about the size of the Taco Bell dog
who tries to strangle people.  The only problem is, there's more scenes of
women wiggling than there is of the spider that's causing all the
"horror".It's obvious what the real purpose of the movie is when one of the dancers
says, "Ohhh, it's SOOOOO hot!" and then begins to strip for the camera. 
Notice also that the dancers come in every flavor from tall to short, meek
to wild, and from non-athletic to athletic; all the better that every man
find at least one of the ladies he likes.  Be sure to keep your eyes on the
very athletic one; she's a cross between Steffi Graff and "Chyna" from the
WWF.This is a German movie -- the dialog is dubbed, and not well in some places.
 It is quite racy even for the early 1960s.  It's obvious that this bomb
never was shown in America.Sterno says this movie is number one...I just can't show you the digit that
says so.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4145056/comments</url><from>from Brentwood, USA</from><name>AngryChair</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
Plane crash leaves dancers stranded on island and in danger when a big
spider turns their manager into a monster... sort of.Cheap, utterly awful foreign film was originally shot as a 'skin flick'
over seas, but re-edited and released in America as a horror picture.
As you may have imagined the story is laughable, the acting (and
dubbing) horrid, the music is flat as a piece of paper, and the
'special FX' non-existing.Sure, B fans may find it a worth laugh or two, but even to this B movie
lover it's too bad for words or your time.BOMB out of ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0475366/comments</url><from>from Massachusetts</from><name>postman-13</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Oh God, was this painful, the most deepest of Deep Hurtings.The plot seems to have been improvised. Actually, the plot was only
partially concealed in those dancer's slit skirts, (some of which were more
slit than skirt!) That is to say, scenes were mere contrivances to film the
girls in various states of (un)dress as they lolled about this deserted
cabin.All female voices were obviously dubbed by one actress. She'd simply change
her accent to differentiate. One line, she changed accents three times on
the same actress! Just beautiful!Many scenes were filmed murkily. The two fight scenes ivolving male cast
members were laughably ridiculous. Watch as one guy, holdinga a chair over
his head, WAITS for the other guy to get out of the way before he throws
it!Again, I digress. I realize this was just a thinly transparent effort for
voyeurs. It's interesting to note what the concept of beauty was 40 years
ago. It was different than today, because, like it or not, those grls had
more meat to them than the anorexic models of today!Oh yeah, I think there were spiders on the island, (plastic models, of
course.)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1590118/comments</url><from>from Oceanside, Ca.</from><name>rosscinema (rosscinema@comcast.net)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
European films often went through an editing process to try and make
them more commercial for American audiences but this German effort
obviously went through more than one metamorphosis to become the clunky
film it is now. Story is about a plane load of female dancers headed by
the talent agent Gary Webster (Alex D'Arcy) and his faithful assistant
Georgia (Helga Franck) and while on their way to Singapore they crash
into the ocean. Everyone except the pilots survive and after floating
in a raft for a few days they find an island to paddle to where they
find fresh water and an old shack.*****SPOILER ALERT***** Inside the shack the girls and Gary find a dead
scientist in a giant web which scares everyone but they figure out that
the island is being used to mine uranium. One night Gary heads out for
a walk and is bitten by a humongous spider which promptly turns him
into a half man/half spider creature and now he prowls the area. 4
weeks later the troupe of girls are visited by Bobby (Rainer Brandt)
and Joe (Harald Maresch) who are from the mining company and they tell
them that they are going to be saved at last but while waiting for
their ship to come Gary the spider monster starts attacking again.This was partially directed by Fritz Bottger (aka Jaime Nolan) but in
interviews actor D'Arcy stated that he took over control of the film
and directed all the sequences involving the giant spider and the
monster. Originally this was just going to be an exploitive nudie with
a bunch of women on an island getting naked but all the nude scenes
were edited out and it was changed to a horror film. It's too bad that
the nudity didn't make the final cut because this attempt at a horror
film needed more than a big puppet spider that looks like it belongs in
a sketch with The Count from Sesame Street. There were a few things
that I noticed while watching this and right off the bat it's hard not
to catch the dreadful excuse at dubbing with actors and actresses
moving their mouths to nothing! The cinematography is a complete joke
and most of the shots have that low budget grainy look to it and the
plane crash itself is just stock footage from another source. Speaking
of the plane crash how could they all survive something like that? And
while floating in the raft the women continue to wear their high heels!
Couldn't they puncture the raft with those inappropriate shoes? Once
they land on the island the character Gary starts exuding his male
dominance by ordering all the females to do everything he says such as
"Come girls, water", "That's enough, lets look around", "Come on
girls". Gary and the rest of the men on the island take off their
shirts and spend the duration of the scenes trying to suck their big
guts in and on the first night in the shack one of the girls starts
putting the moves on Gary and it takes Georgia to bust them up in which
Gary exclaims "Damned heat, I don't know what I'm doing anymore". I had
to laugh at the women who after landing on the island keep tripping and
bumping into one another as they attempt to keep their high heels on
and when they find some spare clothing in the shack they start to argue
and Babs and Nelly get into a cat fight. Actress Barbara Valentin who
plays the slutty Babs looks something like Jayne Mansfield and she
would actually have a pretty good acting career and work several times
with the great German director Rainer Werner Fassbinder. As far as
being an exploitation/horror film this doesn't work on either level but
it is a curio and those who are interested in early attempts at schlock
might find this intriguing enough to warrant a viewing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13976217/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Rod-man65</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
A plane load of dancers and their manager crash (at high speed into the
ocean) and end up on a secluded island.The only point of this movie is to show curvy dancing babes. I see
nothing wrong with that. They added a spider to sell it as a horror
film. Full figured women in underwear and guys with their shirts off,
pants pulled above the navel and guts sucked in. The skinny dipping
scene in the print I saw was shot from a great distance. I understand
that there is another version with close-ups. The disappearance of the
spider-man for 28 days was interesting.A goofy movie, but worth watching for historical purposes. The ideal of
feminine beauty circa 1960. Where did those days go?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13976217/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Rod-man65</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
A plane load of dancers and their manager crash (at high speed into the
ocean) and end up on a secluded island.The only point of this movie is to show curvy dancing babes. I see
nothing wrong with that. They added a spider to sell it as a horror
film. Full figured women in underwear and guys with their shirts off,
pants pulled above the navel and guts sucked in. The skinny dipping
scene in the print I saw was shot from a great distance. I understand
that there is another version with close-ups. The disappearance of the
spider-man for 28 days was interesting.A goofy movie, but worth watching for historical purposes. The ideal of
feminine beauty circa 1960. Where did those days go?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13976217/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Rod-man65</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>