<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>One Foot in Hell</original_title><alt_title>Les hors-la-loi</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>James B. Clark</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
In this Western, Alan Ladd exacts revenge on a small town the best way he knows how -- by becoming sheriff.
</synopsis><actor>Alan Ladd</actor><actor>Don Murray</actor><actor>Dan O'Herlihy</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1136492/comments</url><from>from STOKE-ON-TRENT, ENGLAND.</from><name>DAVID RAYNER (HONEYWALL1)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
   ***SPOILERS***   ***SPOILERS***
I went to see this movie in 1961, when I was fourteen, and I thought it
was
an excellent psychological Western with an offbeat theme. Alan Ladd plays
a
hate-crazed ex-Confederate who takes a violent revenge on the townsfolk of
Blue Springs, Arizona, whose initial indifferance led to his wife dying in
childbirth when they first arrived in the town. The townspeople are
contrite, doing all they can to make amends...even giving Ladd the job of
Deputy Sheriff. But secretly, Ladd is full of hatred for them and, while
out
hunting rustlers with the Sheriff, he murders him in cold blood and,
bringing his body back to town, blames the outlaws for the killing. Now,
the
townsfolk make him Sheriff and he sets about forming a gang in nearby
Royce
City to help him rob the Blue Springs bank of $100,000, kill all those he
blames for his wife's death, and burn the town to the ground. Two of the
gang (Don Murray and Dolores Michaels), left to look after the gang's log
cabin hideout, fall in love and want no part in the plans. After the raid
is
over, Ladd guns down the other gang members (Dan O'Herlihy and Barry Coe)
and goes after the lovers, intent on killing them, too. A terrific fight
ensues between Ladd and Murray and Ladd is killed. Hoping the town will
forgive them, Murray and Michaels take the stolen money back to Blue
Springs. Although Ladd is unusually convincing as a baddie, the film
really
belongs to Murray and Michaels. Their romantic scenes together on the
banks
of a sunlit woodland stream are beautifully played against a haunting
score
by Dominic Frontiere. If the film has a message, it must be that hatred is
like an acid. It will eat into your soul and kill you before you die.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11987301/comments</url><from>from Argentina</from><name>ragosaal</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
I saw this film on TV a couple of nights before and I must say that
either I never heard of it or I didn't remember about it. The story is
rather good and somehow original for a western: a man that blames a
whole town for his wife's death and while earning their trust he plans
his revenge that will be accomplished with its complete destruction
aided by a group of outcasts he has selected carefully. But the result
comes out as a kind of "cheap" product.If you consider that the 50's gave us perhaps the best westerns in
Hollywood history ("High Noon", "The Gunfighter", "Shane", "3:10 to
Yuma", "Warlock", "The Searchers" and so many others) "One Foot in
Hell" comes out as a minor product. Perhaps with a more skillful
director and therefore a strongest and less standard direction the
picture would have worked well.Alan Ladd (as the patient avenger) was not at his best in the 60's and
his severe alcoholism problems showed in his clearly damaged psychical
appearance. Don Murray (as one of the members of the gang) overacts in
most of his scenes. Perhaps the best acting piece comes from pretty
Dolores Michaels as a prostitute also a member of Ladd's group.This film could have been better qualified perhaps if it had been
released in the 40's just before the western genre took a high and
serious impulse in the 50's with extreme good products. It looks cheap
and minor for the 60's.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0018365/comments</url><from>from Savannah, GA</from><name>Bob-45</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
During the first fast moving 20 minutes of "One Foot in Hell," I was
treated to a terrific performance by Alan Ladd. Ladd, one of the most
underrated leading men of the 40s and 50s could easily carry a movie.
Like the underrated Glenn Ford, it's uncanny how Ladd does it. Ladd's a
better lead than ensemble player; his performances in "Shane" and "The
Carpetbaggers" are practically colorless. However, in "One Foot in
Hell," Ladd's performance hearkens back to his pre-alcoholic days of
"This Gun For Hire" and "Chicago Deadline". Too bad the movie shifts
gears till, by two-thirds of the way through, Ladd has become a
supporting player in his own movie. Instead of Ladd, we are now
subjected to the hammy dominance of Don Murray, one of the worst
over-actors of the 50s. This decision seems to have been made
mid-production, as the story could have certainly gone another way.Ladd plays a husband whose life is irrevocably changed by the cynicism,
suspicion and downright stupid actions of four prominent citizens of a
small town over a 20 minute period. These actions collectively result
in the death of Ladd's wife. While appearing to stoically accept this
tragic situation, Ladd plots revenge against the citizens and the town.WARNING: SPOILERS Instead of opting for the relatively predictable
"good man turns bad" plot device, and making Ladd thoroughly
reprehensible, a far better decision would have been for Ladd to have
discovered at a late date from the doctor that the medicine denied his
would wife would have only relieved her suffering, rather than saving
her. This would have been more realistic, even given today's
technology, and it would have left Ladd with a moral dilemma: should he
go through with the gang's plans or save the town which had tried so
hard to gain his forgiveness. Had the producers allowed such a
storyline, "One Foot in Hell" would be remembered right up there with
"Red River," "The Searchers," "High Noon" and "3:10 to Yuma," rather
than dismissed as a run-of-the-mill western."END OF SPOILERSDan O'Herlihy, another great 50s actor is wasted in what should have
been a much more interesting role. The last third of "One Foot in Hell"
appears rushed, again leading to suspicions the ending was not the one
originally intended. Who knows? Maybe Ladd's alcohol demons were
becoming too much of a problem.Even as presented, "One Foot in Hell" has too many good elements to be
casually dismissed. Rather than remaking "3:10 to Yuma" I'd much prefer
they do this one with the ending I have suggested. Russell Crowe would
be perfect in the Ladd role.I give "One Foot in Hell" a strong "6".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17559480/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I first discovered it when I was a kid. 13 years old. I suddenly knew
what an offbeat film was. It's a cult movie for me. I will not say
better than the other users, but just tell my personal feelings, if you
don't mind.It begins with the usual hero scheme. Poor one. Alone against all,
against injustice. You expect him to get repair for what he lives. You
suffer for him.And during the movie, you discover that he is in fact the heavy, the
bad guy of the feature. With palliating circumstances, OK, but
notwithstanding the bad guy. You understand that when he seems to point
Dolores Michaels with his gun, in the hotel room, during the recruiting
moment. Recruiting crew for robbing the bank of the city which killed
his wife. And then you are astonished. You don't expect that at all.
It's a wonderful moment for me. Surprising.SPOILERS SPOILERS SPOILERS SPOILERSAnd, at the end, just before he dies after his struggle against Don
Murray, killed by the girl - Dolores Michaels, Don Murray's girlfriend
- you can see him watching, and for the last time, the little locket
with his wife's picture in it. The genesis of his tragedy. And you
remember why he came such a monster.It's absolutely poignant. I LOVED THAT. UNFORGETTABLE.This film is perhaps not a masterpiece, but probably my favourite one
above thousands of others. Period.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6694516/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>keandre2004</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I absolutely loved this movie.I saw it on Encore for the first time a
few nights ago.I've never seen Alan Ladd in a sinister type role.This
movie reminded me of a more romantic earlier version of High Plains
Drifter.Revenge is sweet!Maybe I'm just an Alan Ladd fan at heart but I
thought this movie was great and I'm looking for a copy of it.I can't
understand why he is referred to as "psychotic".I could almost feel his
pain when he finally got to his wife with the medicine 2 minutes too
late because of compassion-lacking townspeople.I didn't fall in love
with the ending;I thought of his character as the good guy in the
entire movie.Wish he had've gotten revenge without killing yet making
those responsible pay for what they helped cause.Overall,great
"western"!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5053645/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>panamint</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This is the kind of 1950's revenge plot that could have been a great
film (some 1950's revenge westerns are classics). It has some
positives, such as a pretty good script and a cast that is just right
for their roles. However, this film must have had a relatively low
budget and it also has a slow, unimaginative style of direction that
drags it down.In fairness you should say that despite some slow periods the movie
builds more excitement towards the end, so stick with it.Ladd is convincing as a bad guy but partly because of his personally
tormented condition. Ladd was only 46 years old but was in an
irreversible state of decline much like the character he portrays. Both
the real-life Ladd and the fictional Mitch have sunk into a personal
quagmire. In this case art mirrors life and vice versa, in a tragic
sort of way. This is a similar situation to Barrymore's film "The Great
Man Votes". Barrymore's real-life drunken condition added to his strong
characterization of a drunk in that 1939 film, much as Ladd's real-life
torment adds to his characterization of the doomed Mitch here.Michaels and Murray are fine as the young leads and add greatly to the
film. They and Alan Ladd keep it watchable.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Alan Ladd's last western is this strange little item that did not get
much play back in 1960, confined to second place on double bills. He
should have done this one earlier when he was a much bigger box office
name.Ladd plays a settler traveling west and his wife comes down with some
prairie malady. Going off to the nearest town he gets a prescription
for a $1.87 worth of medicine. But then he runs afoul of some of the
town louts and gets delayed long enough so that his wife sickens and
dies.The town fathers feel real sorry for him. In fact they feel so bad that
they offer him the job of deputy sheriff. But when the sheriff dies and
Ladd becomes sheriff it's the first step in an elaborate plan for
revenge on the town. He hates each and every citizen of this place
because of the death of wife Rachel Stephens.Ladd puts together a gang in secret to rob the town bank at a proper
moment when it's bulging with cash. Among others in his scheme are
drunken cowboy Don Murray and working girl Dolores Michaels. Murray's
part is very similar to the one he had the year before with James
Cagney in Shake Hands With The Devil. In fact if you've seen that film,
you know what happens in One Foot In Hell.What could have been a great comeback role for Ladd goes for naught.
I'm not sure it was his drinking at the time. More like it was wife Sue
Carol who at this point was mismanaging his career. And face it, his
day had past.But next to what he was about to do over in Italy in Duel of the
Champions, One Foot In Hell comes out like Stagecoach. It's not a bad
film, as good as any of the B westerns that Audie Murphy was doing at
this time. Still had he been 10 years younger and the film had been
distributed differently, say with Paramount's studio power back in the
day when he was their biggest star, One Foot In Hell could have been a
classic.As it is, it's not bad viewing. Note the script was by an up and coming
television giant, Aaron Spelling.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is one of the last performances in Alan Ladd's career and it
shows. The effects of alcoholism have left him puffy and only a shadow
of his former self. In a few scenes, his acting was lethargic and poor
(particularly in the beginning when Ladd should have played it much
more emotionally charged), though at others he did look like the old
Alan Ladd. However, despite this less than stellar performance, the
film still is well worth viewing because the story idea is so unique.
While NOT always executed well and having a few lulls here and there,
there are enough twists and turns and surprises to make it rise above
the glutted Western genre. In fact, in general I don't like Westerns
because so many seem formulaic and routine--but this one has a few nice
and unique twists.The film begins with Ladd and his pregnant wife arriving late at night
in a small town in the old West. Despite the woman being in obvious
pain and being on the verge of dying, Ladd is amazed to see how
indifferent most of the men are who he appeals to for help. The motel
clerk, the druggist and the sheriff all expend no effort to help and in
fact hinder Ladd getting needed medicine to his wife, who subsequently
dies. Ladd appears grief-stricken but accepting of this as an accident
and agrees to stay on as the town's deputy sheriff--though beneath it
all he has a plan for exacting his revenge upon the townsfolk.While covertly assembling a motley group to rob the town, it becomes
clear that Ladd is indeed crazed--sort of like a land-bound Captain
Ahab. And, it also becomes clear that the town isn't that bad--just a
few jerks who initially tainted Ladd's view of the place. How all this
is resolved actually surprised me, as by this point in his career, Ladd
always seemed to play a good guy--here he was rather terrible and
conniving.As I said above, Ladd's performance is the biggest weakness in the
film. However, if you get past this and a couple lulls here and there,
there are enough good moments and plot ideas to make this a keeper.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This mean little film, written by Spelling of all people, could almost
have made due as an installment of a one-hour TV western anthology. As
it is, it's an interesting (peculiar, as Leonard Maltin aptly put it)
movie with an unusual premise. Ladd plays a Confederate following the
Civil War who is en route to the frontier with his pregnant wife. When
she can go no further, he stops in a small town to get a room and find
a doctor for her. Unfortunately, he is delayed by several of the
townsfolk from getting her medicated in time and the wife and baby are
allowed to die. He is then offered a job for recompense and opts to
become the deputy sheriff. From here, he begins to recruit several
disparate types in order to pull off a sizable heist, though there may
be more to his plan than initially meets the eye. Murray plays a boozy,
fellow ex-Confederate who is taken in by Ladd. O'Herlihy is a mildly
foppish pickpocket and delectable Coe is a fast-draw gunman, both of
whom are hired by Ladd as well. Rounding out his collection of schemers
is Michaels as a washed-up saloon girl. Though it does no real
disservice to his haggard role, Ladd looks positively awful here. His
face is shot, his voice is a cig-infested rattle, his "hair"consists of
a floppy, strawberry-blonde toupee, he can barely maneuver around and
he's swimming in his clothes, often looking in long-shots like a little
boy dressed up in Grandpa's pants. He's also saddled with a ridiculous
hat that does nothing to help (except perhaps add height, so that all
of his costars can stand in a bit shallower trench around him than
would normally be the case.) And the real shame of it all is that he
was 46, a testament to the ravages of alcohol and tobacco if there ever
was one. His performance suffers from all of the above and more, though
his character wasn't meant to be a peppy young guy in any case. Murray
overacts some of his scenes tremendously, but manages to come through
with a good performance by the end. O'Herlihy doesn't have a lot to
work with, but acquits himself nicely. Coe is fine. With his looks and
ability, he should have gone much further in Hollywood than he did. The
best acting probably comes from Michaels who is affecting and appealing
most of the time. She retired before really making a mark in films and
it's a shame. Recognizable townspeople include Swenson as the sheriff
and Gates, in a rare sympathetic role, as the doctor. It's a neat,
tough little film that holds up just until its somewhat too altruistic
and idealistic ending.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22119002/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>pjyork88</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
One Foot in Hell (1960) Dir: James B. Clark Production: Twentieth Century-Fox Film Great premise for a story, but the execution stops it from being fully
realized. Mitch Garrett (Alan Ladd) and his pregnant wife enter the
town of Blue Springs, just as their baby is to be born. Courtesy is not
immediately extended to the stranger (ie. payment is expected upfront
for services), and due to complications (and a perhaps crucial delay in
the administering of $1.87 worth of needed medicine--or perhaps not, a
neat ambiguity), the wife and child die. In a conciliatory gesture,
Mitch accepts the town's offer of a job as deputy. But all the while,
Mitch is methodically planning his revenge on the town with a
bank-breaking heist, and a little something extra for the men he thinks
are responsible for his wife and baby's death. To carry out his plan,
he recruits the "scum of the earth", those like him he feels are "tired
of living"; a drunkard ex-Confederate soldier (Don Murray), a saloon
whore (Dolores Michaels), a dandy conman (Dan O'Herlihy) and a
cold-blooded gunfighter (Barry Coe).So, intriguing set-up, no? Like Cornell Woolrich in the Old West (but
actually Aaron Spelling, his and Sydney Boehm's script is taken from
Spelling's teleplay for an episode of Playhouse 90 called 'The Last
Man', dir. by John Frankenheimer with Sterling Hayden as 'Mitch'). But
I found it a little drab looking, no doubt partially (or maybe, mostly)
due to the MAR'ed TV print that wreaked havoc on the CinemaScope frame.
Ladd plays the chilling single-mindedness of Mitch nicely (and I
appreciated that the film didn't devise some pat change-of-heart), but
you sense his real-life weariness at the time. Murray is miscast. He
flirts with an accent early on but casts it adrift before long. His
romantic sub-plot is spark-less and drags (and his one scene of
shirtless posturing around Michaels is laughable given his less than
stellar physique). O'Herlihy and Coe were fine in the small chances
they were given to do something with their stock characters. The heist
scene was well done, including a wild shot of a building blowing up as
a cattle drive is rumbling through the streets, rather startling the
cattle. I liked the film, but was left with the feeling it might have
been better.**½ out of 4
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22119002/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>pjyork88</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
One Foot in Hell (1960) Dir: James B. Clark Production: Twentieth Century-Fox Film Great premise for a story, but the execution stops it from being fully
realized. Mitch Garrett (Alan Ladd) and his pregnant wife enter the
town of Blue Springs, just as their baby is to be born. Courtesy is not
immediately extended to the stranger (ie. payment is expected upfront
for services), and due to complications (and a perhaps crucial delay in
the administering of $1.87 worth of needed medicine--or perhaps not, a
neat ambiguity), the wife and child die. In a conciliatory gesture,
Mitch accepts the town's offer of a job as deputy. But all the while,
Mitch is methodically planning his revenge on the town with a
bank-breaking heist, and a little something extra for the men he thinks
are responsible for his wife and baby's death. To carry out his plan,
he recruits the "scum of the earth", those like him he feels are "tired
of living"; a drunkard ex-Confederate soldier (Don Murray), a saloon
whore (Dolores Michaels), a dandy conman (Dan O'Herlihy) and a
cold-blooded gunfighter (Barry Coe).So, intriguing set-up, no? Like Cornell Woolrich in the Old West (but
actually Aaron Spelling, his and Sydney Boehm's script is taken from
Spelling's teleplay for an episode of Playhouse 90 called 'The Last
Man', dir. by John Frankenheimer with Sterling Hayden as 'Mitch'). But
I found it a little drab looking, no doubt partially (or maybe, mostly)
due to the MAR'ed TV print that wreaked havoc on the CinemaScope frame.
Ladd plays the chilling single-mindedness of Mitch nicely (and I
appreciated that the film didn't devise some pat change-of-heart), but
you sense his real-life weariness at the time. Murray is miscast. He
flirts with an accent early on but casts it adrift before long. His
romantic sub-plot is spark-less and drags (and his one scene of
shirtless posturing around Michaels is laughable given his less than
stellar physique). O'Herlihy and Coe were fine in the small chances
they were given to do something with their stock characters. The heist
scene was well done, including a wild shot of a building blowing up as
a cattle drive is rumbling through the streets, rather startling the
cattle. I liked the film, but was left with the feeling it might have
been better.**½ out of 4
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>