<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Tirez sur le pianiste</original_title><imdb_rating>7.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><director>François Truffaut</director><producer>Les Films de la Pléiade</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Music</genre><synopsis>
Charlie Kohler is a piano player in a bar. The waitress Lena is in love with him. One of Charlie's brother...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Charles Aznavour</actor><actor>Marie Dubois</actor><actor>Nicole Berger</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0805697/comments</url><from>from dublin, ireland</from><name>Alice Liddel (-darragh@excite.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

'Shoot the Pianist' opens with the insides of a playing piano, the inner
machinations of a musical instrument.  This image points to the film's
ambiguity.  it says that this film will similarly uncover the insides
(heart, soul) of a man who gives nothing away on the surface.  it will
suggest that his insides are like the piano's insides, the the only way he
can express what's buried inside of him is through piano-playing - this is
what gives the film its emotional pull.  but it also suggests that Charlie
Koller's fatal emotional timidity has warped or deadened that soul, made it
a mere mechanism, alive only in a technical sense.  More objectively, it
amounts to a manifesto for Truffaut's intentions with the film, the way he
will turn the gangster genre inside out, a genre he confessed to not really
liking.Although Truffaut would go on to make self-conscious and superficial
tributes to his hero (e.g. 'La Peau Douce', 'The Bride Wore Black'), 'Shoot
the Pianist' is his most Hitchcockian film.  Most obviously, it is a
reworking of 'Vertigo', the story of a homme fatal (Koller - black widower?)
who kills two women because he couldn't say the right thing, because he
behaved like a man should, rather than the way he really feels.  Lena is in
effect a reincarnation of his dead wife, a woman who wants to reinstate his
'original' identity.  Like Scottie Ferguson, Charlie is a man paralysed by
memory, shellshocked by his experiences with an elusive love that could so
easily have been his.  But, again like 'Vertigo', 'Pianist' is the study of masculine identity and
its dissolution.  When we first see Charlie he is literally in a scrapheap,
getting dressed in front of a mirror.  This mirror motif recurs throughout,
and with it the question: who is Charlie Koller?  The farmboy sibling of
gangsters; the renowned pianist; the back-room tinkler; the father to his
young brother; the man who desires but cannot ask, who keeps destructively
pulling back?  Throughout the real 'man' is deluged by different names,
images (posters, paintings), stories etc. about himself: his own personality
is divided by the talks he conducts with himself.  Even the heartbreaking
flashback sequence about his past is related to him by someone else.  In the
fear of losing his identity, of giving himself in union, Charlie loses
everything.But 'Pianist' is also reminiscent of early, British Hitchcock films like
'The 39 Steps' and 'Young and Innocent', in its playful irreverence with
genre.  David Thomson has said it was a film Laurence Sterne might have
made, and, like 'Tristam Shandy', like those Hitchcock movies, the main
genre narrative is frequently broken off by digressions and bits of
business.  The film plunges us in media res in the gangster genre, a man
being chased in the obscurity.  He bangs into a lamppost, and is helped by a
passer-by.  They start talking about marriage.  This is emblematic of the
film as a whole - a gangster film that keeps stopping to talk about love,
women, family, music, the past etc.  When the genre kicks in again - Chico
(gangster name, yes, but Marx Brother too) rushes into his brother's bar,
the tension is somewhat undermined by the comedy bar-room singer bouncing to
the cymbals.  When Charlie and Lena are kidnapped by the two hoods, a
fraught situation turns into an hilarious banter about women and dirty old
men.  the most frightening sequence - the abduction of young Fido - provokes
the funniest scene, where captor and captive debate the authenticity of the
former's Japanese metal scarf.But the film works the other way too, when the comic unexpectedly flashes
into the tragic.  In an early scene, Charlie agonises to himself about the
proper etiquette to be used in handling Lena - this is a touching, sad
scene, but full of the comedy of embarrassment.  Suddenly, having dithered
so long, Charlie realises she's gone.  The scrunched pain on his face is
devastating.'Pianist' is my favourite film.  For Charles Aznavour's performance, the
embodiment of shy timidity leading to emotional paralysis, and my altar ego.
For the Godardian style, mixing abrupt, immediate, hand-held location
shooting, and natural sound excitement, with a grasp of mise-en-scene worthy
of the great 1950s melodramatists (the framing, cutting characters off from
one another, trapping them in their decor; or the elaborate, Ophulsian
camerawork, such as the 'Le Plaisir' gliding outside the bar; the circular
narrative that sees continuity tragically affirmed in the shape of the new
waitress).  'Pianist' couldn't have been made without Melville's 'Bob le
Flambeur', and its flippancy and humanising of genre, but the influence of
this on Cassavetes, Penn, Scorcese etc. was immense, for its generosity to
all its characters, showing, despite Eustache, that a good woman can be a
maman and putain.  For the comic chutzpah, the dazzling abduction scene, the
triptych revealing the boss's betrayal, the clumsy murder, the wonderfully
bumbling hoods, Fido's Hawksian little dance.  For Truffaut's concern with
time and decay and art.  For the haunting scene with the cello girl.  For
the music, fulfilling Noel Coward's dictum about the potency of cheap music,
giving this short, strange movie its generous soul, a film that so humanely
departs from genre it makes the generic climax grotesque, a DW Griffith
nightmare in blinding white.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1173088/comments</url><from>from UK</from><name>MovieAddict2011</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
François Truffaut's second feature, Tirez sur le pianiste, is a
deliberately wild and chaotic satire of the American gangster pictures
of the 1930s, '40s and '50s. Truffaut tried to make Tirez sur le
pianiste, or Shoot the Pianist, the complete opposite of his first
picture, The 400 Blows, doing away with the sentimentality of the
predecessor and making his second feature far more vicious, nonlinear
and, occasionally, quite funny.Based off of a pulp novel by David Goodis, the movie is about a
once-famous piano player (Charles Aznavour) who gives up looking for
the reason his wife left him, and now plays piano in a run-down Paris
bar where he falls for a waitress, and must overcome his natural
shyness in order to express his love for her. Unfortunately his brother
gets him involved in a gangland feud, which gives the story an
unnecessary (but welcomed) edge to the romance.There are some highly amusing scenes, such as when Charles and his
soon-to-be-girlfriend walk down a Paris sidewalk and he contemplates
what to say, do, and how to act, without offending her or making a fool
out of himself. We hear Charles' neurotic thoughts in voice-over – an
effect now overused in cinema but back in 1960, very new. It wasn't
until the intrusion of Woody Allen comedies such as Annie Hall that
sporadic first-person narratives became popular – in the noir movies of
the earlier decades voice-overs were sometimes used by narrators (such
as in the cult classic Detour) but never in such a way as Shoot the
Pianist's. It's one of the best scenes in the movie, and a great way of
expressing the inner-workings of Charles, the character.Shoot the Pianist's chaotic structure confused and overwhelmed many
audiences when the film was released in 1960. Its content (violence,
nudity, etc.) was not as welcomed by audiences as it is now, and as a
result the film was a financial and critical failure. The humor was not
appreciated, the insightful look at a French Everyman was not even
noticed – it was ruled out as a dud, and that's all that mattered to
anyone.Over the years it has picked up a rather small cult following and fans
of Truffaut's films have declared it to be one of his best pictures.
Looking back now in light of such recent gangster genre hybrids such as
Reservoir Dogs and Lock Stock &amp; Two Smoking Barrels, Truffaut's movie
not only seems more understandable but far ahead of its time. In
relation to Reservoir Dogs it contains the same sort of standard,
everyday nonchalance in accordance with gangsters – while it contains
the narrative flow of Guy Ritchie's British gangster cult hit.Regardless of how brilliant Shoot the Pianist seems forty years later,
Truffaut was scarred by the negative press surrounding his second
feature and never made another movie as daring (so to speak) or, more
likely, downright fun as Tirez sur le pianiste. It's a very amusing
movie, and it is one of the few 1960s films that doesn't seem dated
compared to the film-making standards of modern-day Hollywood. The
performances are flawless, the characters likable and realistic, the
movie overall highly enjoyable and worth seeing more than just once. It
is sadly one of Truffaut's most underrated movies, although hopefully
in another forty years it will only be all the more appreciated for its
qualities.5/5
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2248099/comments</url><from>from Beverley Hills, England</from><name>The_Void</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Shoot the Pianist is Francois Truffaut's attempt at mirroring the
greatness of the classic gangster films. And suffice to say; it is a
very nice attempt indeed. The film follows Charlie Kohler, a simple
bar-side piano player. Charlie's life takes a turn for the more
exciting one day when his brother turns up at the bar, telling his
brother that a couple of gangsters that he and his other brother
cheated out of their side of the loot from a job that the four did
together are after him. Charlie also has a secret admirer; Lena, a
barmaid at the bar he works in. Now this once simple piano player has
gone from a quiet life at a piano to having to deal with gangsters, his
brothers and a new love interest. But wait...there's more; is Charlie
all that he seems? Is he merely a simple piano player? That's what
makes this film great; it's never black and white (if you'll excuse the
pun), and it is always ready to throw in another plot turn to keep you
guessing.After the universally acclaimed "The 400 Blows", Francois Truffaut had
his work cut out for his next movie. Many will disagree, but I actually
think he surpassed it. The 400 Blows is undoubtedly a more important
work; but this film hits more of the right notes and is very much more
enjoyable. The cast is absolutely flawless throughout; Charles Aznavour
stars in the lead role. He gets his characterization spot on; his
melancholy comes naturally and is believable throughout. Marie Debois
and Nicole Berger star alongside Aznavour, and although they are more
in the background; they still manage to impress. There is also a role
here for Michèle Mercier, whom you may remember from the Mario Bava
masterpiece; Black Sabbath. Truffaut's cinematography is clean and
crisp and the film is an aesthetic treat throughout. Despite being
nearly 45 years old, the film also manages to retain a feeling of
freshness, and that's something that not all crime thrillers of today
can do after 4 years, let alone 45. Truffaut has also very obviously
got an astute sense of humour - there's one part of the film involving
one of the gangster's mother's dropping dead that made me laugh out
loud. Let it never be said that the French can't be funnyThe film features many anecdotes that ring true. My personal favourite
is when Lena says that what you do today becomes a part of you
tomorrow. It's simple, but very astute. Another good one is when one of
the gangsters talks about all the lovely gadgets he has, and after
listing them all he finishes with; "I'm bored". Truffaut obviously
knows that material goods aren't what make people happy, and this film
presents a rather amusing way of showing that. However, despite these
and several other anecdotes; the film doesn't appear to have a defining
point, which lessens its impact somewhat. Overall, however, Shoot the
Pianist is a lovely little film that shouldn't be missed by anyone that
professes to like gangster movies. It's amusing, has some points to
make and its flawlessly acted and directed. Highest recommendations for
this one.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1727211/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>kyle_c</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Truffaut's homage to the American gangster film stars Charles Aznavour as a
smalltime piano player in a bar who has a secret past that he keeps hidden. 
The film almost falls into the trap of not being an homage to the gangster
film, but rather being one itself.  What saves it is the film's unique wit
and charm - it's a blend of humor, romance, and gangster film.  The
gangsters themselves are quite funny, casually discussing everyday matters
in a way that certainly had to influence Quentin Tarantino when he was
writing Pulp Fiction.  Some of the jokes are funny just because they are so
silly (i.e., the gangster swearing his truth on his mother's grave).  It's
this sense of humor and the fact that the movie doesn't take itself
seriously that sets it apart from other gangster movies of the
day.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0355812/comments</url><from>from Cologne, Germany</from><name>Jules-96</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Masterful French director François Truffaut followed up his hard-hitting,
absorbing, highly acclaimed drama LES QUATRE CENTS COUPS (1959) with a
original film noir comedy, which is also considered one of his masterpieces
and one of the most important movies of the Nouvelle Vague. Based on the US
crime novel "Down There" by David Goods his visually fascinating,
humanistic, clever and inventive comedy drama uses the story of a lonely,
melancholic cafe piano man who through his criminal brothers gets into
trouble with some gangsters and at the same time falls in love with a
beautiful servant who discovers his past as a famous classic pianist only as
a frame to make his own statements about relationships between men and
women, success, glory, downfall and failure and at the same time paying a
affectionate and ironic homage to the clichéd, low-budget Hollywood gangster
films of the 40s and 50s. Though one could argue about the confuse
narrative, this is a unique film experience with a virtuous cinematic style
and many wonderful moments.Vanilla and Raspberry. One of the funniest, most memorable, though also
narrative-wise most unnecessary scenes has the real-life Parisian club
singer Boby Lapointe delivering a vulgar, fast-paced song named "Vanilla and
Raspberry" about the breasts of a woman. Add to this a handful of other
plot-ignoring sequences that are masterfully directed, outstandingly acted
and very well-written and you have seen the best parts of the movie. The
main plot only holds together what usually wouldn't click together. There's
a lot of comedy, a lot of melancholy, a lot of tragedy, a lot of pathos,
some funny songs, strange locations, interesting characters and so on. It's
really a work of a free-spirited artist trying everything to surprise his
audience instead of boring it with a conventional plot. That's why the
viewer is never sure what's going to happen next and so it's despite some
lengthy dialogue and calm scenes pretty suspenseful.
Another element that turns this patchwork into a near-masterpiece of
cinematic history is Truffaut's use of awesomely beautiful cinematography,
rough, unexpected cutting, unusual visuals composed in rhythm with the
excellent score by Georges Delerue and a scene-setting voice-over by the
hero. François plays with the visual concept of the story (it's a ironic
comedy about melancholia with optimistic views on life and love set in a
dark, nihilistic world!) and pretty much forgets about it in favour for
hilarious moments like when one of the characters swears to tell the truth
and if he doesn't his mother shall die immediately, Truffaut cuts to a old
woman falling down in her room and back. Or when the scene of the cafe owner
telling the bad guys where the piano player lives is split into three
singular takes sharing the screen. There are plenty of other memorable
moments like these and they're also magnificent.
The perfect cast also delivers the goods. The sad-faced, but ultimately
likeable Charles Aznavour, who was a popular singer in France, excels in the
lead combining the elegance of a shy artist playing the tunes of Chopin and
the coolness of a everyday piano player doing his job in a little cafe. The
supporting actors are also fine, especially Jacques Aslanian has some
scene-stealing moments as the bully and rude brother of Aznavour and the two
women (the magnificent Nicole Berger and the wonderful Marie Dubois) playing
the pianist's love interests are tremendously good.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5976235/comments</url><from>from Spain</from><name>wooodenelephant</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Francois Truffaut was a film critic for the magazine Cahiers du cinéma.
He was disenchanted with what he saw as a lack of originality and
honesty in contemporary cinema. He developed the theory of the auteur
in cinema - an idiosyncratic force such as his hero Hitchcock rather
than a 'civil servant of the cinema'.His motivation for entering the cinema was to make films which he, and
others like him, wanted to see and which then didn't exist. Cinema with
breadth and imagination, which took risks and broke rules. The zest and
vitality of his vision is still evident so many years on.After his impeccable full -length debut, Les Quatre Cents Coups (aka
The 400 Blows), which was a slice of life / coming of age tale,
Truffaut took a completely different subject matter for this second
feature. The source novel is 'Down There', typical US pulp fiction by
the little known David Goodis. Its a tale of crime set in seedy
locations with a graceless linear plot. Obviously its the way the
filmmakers use this source that makes Tirez Sur Le Pianiste the film it
is.Charles Aznavour, a mainstream celebrity in France, is the bizarre but
perfect choice for the lead role of Charlie Kohler. His passive,
indifferent demeanour makes him an anti-hero of a different kind to
Cagney or Brando - one who is ineffective in either solving or
preventing crime. This minor cinematic tradition I see as continuing
with John Klute in Klute (1971), Marlowe in The Long Goodbye (1973),
reaching its comical apex with The Dude in The Big Lebowski (1998).Not, in fact, that Charlie has to solve any crimes. He is simply out to
save his skin - and those of his brothers. His life is in danger
throughout the film yet he is more preoccupied with whether or not he
should take the arm of the attractive waitress Lena (Marie Dubois) from
the dive where he plays the piano, as he walks her home in a scene that
is a perfect marriage of its imagery and internal monologue. It is this
kind of juxtaposition of themes (threat to life and romantic shyness)
which makes this film such compelling and unpredictable viewing.The film opens with a charming conversation about the secrets of a
happy marriage, spoken by a character we never see again who simply
runs into Charlie's brother Chico (Albert Rémy) - who is the catalyst
for the 'plot'. The throwaway conversations are really more important
to the creative spirit of the film than any of the plot's major
concerns. This trend continues with the characters of Ernest and Momo,
the pursuing heavies. Though evidently dangerous men, they speak
tangentially on a range of subjects (mostly women, though) which cannot
help but remind a modern audience of Tarantino's hit men in Pulp
Fiction. Indeed much of what I said about Truffaut - how he was
compelled to make rule-changing cinema that he and others wanted to see
- could of course equally be applied to Tarantino.The centrepiece of the film goes back to Charlie' past where he was a
classical concert pianist. This beautiful vignette explains to us why
Charlie is in the pits now. Nicole Berger as Thérèse Saroyan, Charlie's
wife absolutely owns this part of the film. This section also features
the celebrated and beautiful sequence where the camera chooses to
follow a female violinist from the door of an apartment and out into
the courtyard. Why? Just for the sake of artistic freedom, it seems.As well as Aznavour and Berger, the casting is uniformly perfect.
Claude Mansard and Daniel Boulanger as the waffling heavies, Marie
Dubois as the sweet, maternal young waitress Léna, Michèle Mercier as a
tart with a heart with a body to die for (bringing the total of female
'leads' to three!), Serge Davri and Catherine Lutz as Charlie's
antagonistic and ultimately tragic employers. The obscure threesome
(the latter two brothers have their only major film roles here) of
Albert Rémy, Jean-Jacques Aslanian and the young Richard Kanayan are
brilliantly effective as Charlie's brothers, all of whom display
varying degrees of the criminal element - the 'curse' of Charlie and
his family. Early on in the film there is also a terrifically amusing
song (complete with karaoke-style lyrics) performed by Boby Lapointe, a
real-life Parisian entertainer.For all its wealth of ideas, though, this is generally not a pacey
movie. Its pace is as laidback as Charlie himself at times. But with
patience this will reward the audience with all kinds of unexpected
delights.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0156685/comments</url><from>from NYC</from><name>David Austin</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Sometimes you watch a classic for the first time and you don't understand
the hype. This time I was more than pleasantly surprised. Wonderful,
whimsical and sad little film noir. This movie completely plays with the
audience, but in a loving way. The actors and actresses are almost
uniformly
great. Some incredible faces. Aznavour in particular has an amazingly
distinctive look. Be warned, it takes about ten minutes to have an idea of
what is going on. Just hang in there and go with it. Highly
recommend.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0129130/comments</url><from>from New York, NY</from><name>3rdMan</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

With singer/actor Charles Aznavour in the lead (his expressive face is
priceless), "Shoot the Piano Player" is one of Truffaut's most charming
and
inventive works. Aznavour plays Charlie/Edouard -- a former concert
pianist
who becomes an anonymous piano player in a dive bar in order to escape his
past. After his brother (Remy, who Truffaut also used wonderfully in "The
400 Blows") gets in trouble with some borderline inept gangsters, chaos
ensues.Truffaut's winsome camera and editing techniques blend perfectly with
Aznavour's performance. A must for fans of the French New
Wave.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1745168/comments</url><from>from Edmonton, Canada</from><name>trixster7</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
It doesn't feel like a typical Truffaut film - though I've only seen
two others from his filmography - in that it's as stylish and
self-reflexive as a Godard film. I had got the sense that Truffaut was
more 'conventional' in his films, and this one certainly went against
it. Not that I'm complaining, though - it's probably the funniest New
Wave flick that I've seen. There are loads of little comic moments that
reminded me of the modern British comedies - stuff like Snatch and
Shaun of the Dead - that I love. But it's also got a dark edge, and not
in the black comedy sense. It's pretty depressing, and that's where it
fits in line with Truffaut's other films. It's not the relatively
light-hearted depression of Godard's films, it's full-fledged tragedy.
However, the combination of drama and comedy doesn't always mesh well,
as it rarely does for me, and the characters seem too short-changed to
justify such an ending. Still, it's very witty and fairly entertaining.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10601178/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>bob stafford</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The opening scene is of a man running in dark streets. We only hear his
steps and the menacing mechanical sound of traffic which we assume to
be made by the pursuer. He collides with a post and is stunned. A man
carrying a bouquet of flowers, helps him to his feet. As they walk, the
man is expansive and briefly describes the course of his relationship
with his wife, from simple selfish lust leading to marriage and only
later, leading to true love. The man excuses himself, turning towards
his home, and in an instant the original victim returns to his role as
prey to some all-pervasive, inhuman, pursuer.For me, this is Truffaut, the viewer identifying with the victim for a
few moments, being safe in the domestic harmony of the man, only to be
launched anew into the role of the hopeless quarry. The talkative man's
recognition of his dependence on his wife contrasts with a later scene,
in a car, where the two gangsters reveal highly cynical attitudes
towards women. The irony is that their cynicism is capped by Charlie
(Edward), who quotes his father as saying "when you've seen one woman,
you've seen them all". It is significant how timid and respectful he is
when daring to interrupt the macho diatribe of the two hoods. With this
one statement, we have the background to the whole story. Big brother, Chico, the "prey", needs help from Eddy, who is very
reluctant to be drawn in, but family ties prove too strong. We see
Chico as being a demanding,selfish, brute and can guess he takes after
his father. We also guess where Eddy's timidity originates. In the dialogue between Eddy and the brutish bar-owner, who is jealous
of Eddy's attractiveness to the waitress, Lena, Eddy even offers to
leave. When the bar-owner tells Eddy he is scared, Eddy repeats the
phrase, playing with it as if it were a new flavour. This seems to be
the ultimate in humility or humiliation, yet Eddy respectfully almost
accepts it as advice. This short conversation suggests a life of
victimisation, from father and big brother. Yet, most touching of all,
is that his submission does not mask underlying contempt; Eddy still
cares for the bar-owner as he does for his brother. Later, when the two
are collapsed in the alley after a struggle, Eddy tosses aside his
advantage of the knife and is then tricked by the bar-owner, who
appears to be offering to make peace with a manly hug, but then
attempts to strangle Eddy.In his relations with Lena, Therese and Clarisse we witness tenderness,
spontaneity, playfulness and trust. I don't know if it's my
imagination, but these scenes seem to have brighter lighting. With each
woman, there is a different mood. For instance, those involving Therese
are all flashbacks and seem to involve more classical, static
camera-work, lending an appropriate quality of distance. With Clarisse,
the prostitute, there is bawdy, but innocent humour and no physical
embarrassment, while with Lena there is adolescent awkwardness,
reminiscent of Woody Allen, followed by such delicate, romantic scenes
of physical discovery.There are unexpected cameos, such as Boby Lapointe, in the bar singing
"Framboises" and Fido, Eddy's kid brother being fascinated by the two
gangsters who have kidnapped him. The final moment of the film, ignores
the outcome of the feud between gangsters and brothers. We are only
concerned with Lena.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10601178/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>bob stafford</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
The opening scene is of a man running in dark streets. We only hear his
steps and the menacing mechanical sound of traffic which we assume to
be made by the pursuer. He collides with a post and is stunned. A man
carrying a bouquet of flowers, helps him to his feet. As they walk, the
man is expansive and briefly describes the course of his relationship
with his wife, from simple selfish lust leading to marriage and only
later, leading to true love. The man excuses himself, turning towards
his home, and in an instant the original victim returns to his role as
prey to some all-pervasive, inhuman, pursuer.For me, this is Truffaut, the viewer identifying with the victim for a
few moments, being safe in the domestic harmony of the man, only to be
launched anew into the role of the hopeless quarry. The talkative man's
recognition of his dependence on his wife contrasts with a later scene,
in a car, where the two gangsters reveal highly cynical attitudes
towards women. The irony is that their cynicism is capped by Charlie
(Edward), who quotes his father as saying "when you've seen one woman,
you've seen them all". It is significant how timid and respectful he is
when daring to interrupt the macho diatribe of the two hoods. With this
one statement, we have the background to the whole story. Big brother, Chico, the "prey", needs help from Eddy, who is very
reluctant to be drawn in, but family ties prove too strong. We see
Chico as being a demanding,selfish, brute and can guess he takes after
his father. We also guess where Eddy's timidity originates. In the dialogue between Eddy and the brutish bar-owner, who is jealous
of Eddy's attractiveness to the waitress, Lena, Eddy even offers to
leave. When the bar-owner tells Eddy he is scared, Eddy repeats the
phrase, playing with it as if it were a new flavour. This seems to be
the ultimate in humility or humiliation, yet Eddy respectfully almost
accepts it as advice. This short conversation suggests a life of
victimisation, from father and big brother. Yet, most touching of all,
is that his submission does not mask underlying contempt; Eddy still
cares for the bar-owner as he does for his brother. Later, when the two
are collapsed in the alley after a struggle, Eddy tosses aside his
advantage of the knife and is then tricked by the bar-owner, who
appears to be offering to make peace with a manly hug, but then
attempts to strangle Eddy.In his relations with Lena, Therese and Clarisse we witness tenderness,
spontaneity, playfulness and trust. I don't know if it's my
imagination, but these scenes seem to have brighter lighting. With each
woman, there is a different mood. For instance, those involving Therese
are all flashbacks and seem to involve more classical, static
camera-work, lending an appropriate quality of distance. With Clarisse,
the prostitute, there is bawdy, but innocent humour and no physical
embarrassment, while with Lena there is adolescent awkwardness,
reminiscent of Woody Allen, followed by such delicate, romantic scenes
of physical discovery.There are unexpected cameos, such as Boby Lapointe, in the bar singing
"Framboises" and Fido, Eddy's kid brother being fascinated by the two
gangsters who have kidnapped him. The final moment of the film, ignores
the outcome of the feud between gangsters and brothers. We are only
concerned with Lena.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10601178/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>bob stafford</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>