<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Barsaat Ki Raat</original_title><imdb_rating>7.0</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>India</country><director>P.L. Santoshi</director><producer>Shri Vishwabharthi Films</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Musical</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Amidst fierce Qawali competitions, a poor poet/singer, Aman Hyderabadi, falls in love with Shabnam, the daughter of Police Commissioner Khan Bahadur...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Madhubala</actor><actor>Bharat Bhushan</actor><actor>Shyama</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur22238372/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>jmathur_swayamprabha</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
If you are a young man (even when you are not so young) and in a rainy
night, you happen to see an extremely beautiful girl in a drenched
condition, what will be the reaction on you ? Quite naturally, you will
get romantic. And if you are an eligible bachelor, you may experience a
storm in your heart which is sure to be much bigger than the storm
being faced by you in the outer world that night.Barsaat Ki Raat (rainy night) is the story based upon such a rainy
night only in which the hero, Bharat Bhooshan happens to see the
heroine, Madhubala in a drenched state with her dress sticking to her
body. Madhubala was so beautiful that she used to be referred to as the
Venus of the Indian screen. Well, such an extra-ordinary beauty and
that too in the drenched state in the rainy night, needless to say that
heavens fell for the heart of our young hero. The story starts from this rainy stormy night of Hyderabad
(coincidentally I am also at Hyderabad and it's raining too) and moves
to Lucknow. The hero, Aman is a Qawwaal as well as a Shaayar (Urdu
poet) and as was natural in that time; young, charming and emotional
ladies used to fall for the touching poetry. So that sudden meeting
under a shed in that rainy night changed the life of both the young
Shaayar, Aman and the charming damsel, Shabnam who is the daughter of
the police commissioner (K.N. Singh). The hiatus in the statuses
becomes the insurmountable wall between the love-birds. Aman moves to
Lucknow and keeps on participating in the Mushaayaras (gatherings of
Urdu poets with the recitation of Urdu poetry). A lady Qawwaal, Shama
(Shyama) has already fallen for him. So there's a love-triangle in the
story. Finally, the story heads to Ajmer Shareef for its climax in
which Aman defeats a renowned Qawwaal in a Qawwaali contest
(Muqaabala-E-Qawwaali) and gets his sweetheart.This movie is based on the unique genre of music and poetry, Qawwaali
which is not an easy one to perform for even the seasoned and expert
singers. In this movie, the hero is not only an Urdu poet and singer,
he is portrayed as an expert in creating extempore poetry for his
Qawwaalis while the contest or the Muqaabla is in progress. The
lyricist of this movies' songs, the great Shaayar Sahir Ludhiyanvi and
the music director, Roshan both have done an outstanding job in
creating memorable Qawwaalis (and normal songs too) for the story of
the movie. Seasoned singers like Manna Dey, Rafi, Batish,
Shankar-Shambhu, Balbir, Lata, Asha, Suman Kalyanpur, Sudha Malhotra,
Kamal Barot have given their voices for the Qawwaalis and the songs. In
fact, it's the extra-ordinary music of this movie which has made it
immortal.All the songs are real gems. It boasts of classic Qawwaalis like Na To
Kaarvaan Ki Talash Hai (which includes Ye Ishq Ishq Hai Ishq Ishq), Jee
Chaahta Hai Choom Loon, Nigaah-E-Naaz Ke Maaron Ka Haal Kya Hoga etc.
In addition to them, memorable songs like - Zindagi Bhar Nahin Bhoolegi
Woh Barsaat Ki Raat, Garjat Barsat Saawan Aayo Re, Maine Shaayad Tumhen
Pehle Bhi Kahin Dekha Hai, Mujhe Mil Gaya Bahaana Teri Deed Ka, Maayus
To Hoon Vaade Se Tere etc. are all a grand treat for the genuine music
lovers. Listening to these songs take the music-lover to a different
enchanting world, where he / she loses the sense of the outer world and
just lost in the in the melody and the Shaayari drenched with
sentiments.The movie is otherwise also very interesting. Director P.L. Santoshi
has ably directed this unusual story. Curiosity has been maintained
well for the viewer. Art direction and cinematography are A class. The
Muslim environment in the cities of Hyderabad, Lucknow and Ajmer in the
fifties has been exasperated in an admirable manner. Production value
is high. Editing is also good.Performances are quite good. Bharat Bhoosan was a specialist in the
roles of artists (Shaayar, poet, singer, painter etc.) and he has done
well in this movie too. The Indian Venus, Madhubala is a treat to
watch. She has performed well too. K.N. Singh as the stern police
commissioner, Shyama as Shama, Ratna (playing her younger sister,
Shabaab) and all others have supported the main cast quite
proficiently. Ratna's performances as Shabaab deserves special mention.This black and white movie is an evergreen classic and the only movie
based on timeless Qawwaalis. Such movies are hard to find in today's
times. So watch it and get nostalgic once again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14606193/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>abhai pratap</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Last night i got a chance to watch this movie. The movie was one of the
biggest hits at the box-office in 1960. So i was expecting a lot. And
surely this movie has not disappointed me. The characters were good and
performance was so nice. Everybody was trying to outdo each other in
performance. There are at least two good reasons to watch this
under-appreciated gem of a film. Firstly it offers three notably strong
female characters, superbly played by talented actresses. Secondly it
has a memorable score, with lyrics by the great Sahir Ludhianvi (an
Urdu poet), sung by a stellar list of playback singers, and culminating
in a series of dazzling qawwali performances (of love-saturated and
Sufi-inflected couplets on the pleasures and pains of love) that are
among the best ever filmed. But you have to know Hindi and Urdu words
to appreciate the dialogues.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14606193/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>abhai pratap</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Last night i got a chance to watch this movie. The movie was one of the
biggest hits at the box-office in 1960. So i was expecting a lot. And
surely this movie has not disappointed me. The characters were good and
performance was so nice. Everybody was trying to outdo each other in
performance. There are at least two good reasons to watch this
under-appreciated gem of a film. Firstly it offers three notably strong
female characters, superbly played by talented actresses. Secondly it
has a memorable score, with lyrics by the great Sahir Ludhianvi (an
Urdu poet), sung by a stellar list of playback singers, and culminating
in a series of dazzling qawwali performances (of love-saturated and
Sufi-inflected couplets on the pleasures and pains of love) that are
among the best ever filmed. But you have to know Hindi and Urdu words
to appreciate the dialogues.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14606193/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>abhai pratap</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>