<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Once More, with Feeling!</original_title><alt_title>Chérie recommençons</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Stanley Donen</director><producer>Stanley Donen Films</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
Yul Brynner plays a musical genius whose eccentricities are kept in check by his wife, until she discovers him "auditioning" a sultry young pianist...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Yul Brynner</actor><actor>Kay Kendall</actor><actor>Geoffrey Toone</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0615110/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>delius1</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

It is a shame that this film has not been released on video.  It is a witty
observation of the classical music world with Yul Brynner playing the part
of a temperamental orchestra conductor.  It was also Kay Kendall's last
film
- she was fatally ill when she made it and died shortly after it was
finished.  She was a marvelous comedienne and was a great foil for Yul
Brynner.  Every classical music buff should see this film!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3794286/comments</url><from>from Arlington, Virgina</from><name>rich brown (drgafia@comcast.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This film is just plain funny. Yul Brenner is perfect as the fiery
uncompromising symphony conductor, Kaye Kendall likewise as his
companion of many years who has kept his orchestra afloat by her
unfailing ability to soothe the many feathers ruffled by the maestro --
until, that is, she returns one night to find him compromised with a
beautiful 21-year-old pianist. The first-rate performances here are not
limited to their acting alone; this is a fine piece of work and
everyone involved can be justifiably proud of their part in making it
so. The mystery, to me, is why this upbeat and thoroughly delightful
comedy is virtually unknown and why the only way in which viewers can
verify this is to catch it on its infrequent showings on late-night
television. This should really be available on VHS or DVD; my question
is, why isn't it?

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0997962/comments</url><from>from tyler, texas</from><name> (jay2@ballistic.com)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This is a latter-day example of the "screwball" comedies of the 1930s, and
has standout performances from Yul Brynner, Kay Kendall, and Gregory
Ratoff.
Beautifully filmed, gorgeous sets, great comic emsemble, and is LONG LONG
overdue for re-release on video.  Please!! I want to own a copy of this
film
for my library. This is one movie I could watch again every
week.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0836523/comments</url><from>from virginia</from><name>denscul</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Donen directs a film based on a familiar theme - the ugly side of of
genius that is hidden from the public, but all too familiar with valet,
wife or agent. Donen manages to make a comedy of it all, without
becoming a farce. That is probably due to the acting talents of Yul
Brynner, Kay Kendall and the over worked agent played by great
character actor Greg Ratoff. The plot may sound silly if one reads the
screen play, but as a finished film, it is a delight to watch as three
different personalities clash with each other, going in all directions
only to end up on the same page at the end. Donen manages to describe
genius, art, and a selfish ego and puts it into a package that will not
make you laugh, but smile through most of the film. If you like
classical music (and Sousa), you have an additional bonus. If you are a
musician or played in school, you will recognize some of the tantrums
of the conductor and the bulling of musicians who do not give the
conductor what he wants. And one final tribute to the film. Kay Kendall's acting is all the more
remarkable because she shows no signs of nearing the end of her life
and career. Once More With Feeling was her last film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1656564/comments</url><from/><name>Richard Ewing</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Sadly lost to viewers and DVD/VHS buyers in the United States, this is one
of the funniest films Kay Kendall made in her short life, and that is no
mean feat.  Yul Brenner also shines as one of the world's greatest
egomaniac
types--a symphony orchestra conductor.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Two of the stars who shot across public view in the 1950s were Yul
Brynner and Kay Kendall. Brynner's career included an Oscar winning
role in THE KING AND I, which became his career identifying part, and
Kendall became the most popular and promising female comedian from
Great Britain. But Kendall died prematurely, and Brynner (although he
remained a public favorite until his death in the 1980s) found greater
and greater difficulties in getting decent films and properties to
appear in. He kept returning so frequently to his role as the the King
of Siam that (with Rex Harrison's constant returns to playing Professor
Higgins in MY FAIR LADY) it was one of the two running jokes about
career parts. This 1960 film was Kendall's final film. Married to Harrison at the
time, she had been getting progressively weaker and weaker for the last
two years. In his autobiography REX, Harrison tells how the doctors
informed him that she had leukemia and would be dead within two years.
He proceeded to make the most intense use of the time as he could -
romancing her constantly and even co-starring with her in Vincente
Minelli's THE RELUCTANT DEBUTANTE. He was determined not to let her
know her life was going to end sooner than she would ever expect.**However, for a slightly less pleasant view of Harrison's feelings in
this tragic situation, read the memoirs of his ex-wife Lili Palmer,
CHANGE LOBSTERS AND DANCE.In ONCE MORE WITH FEELING, Brynner is (for a change) essaying his
comedy abilities. He could be funny (there are funny moments in THE
KING AND I), but usually is brooding and even tragic (as in what I
think is his best performance, the Russian officer in THE JOURNEY).
Here, as Victor Fabian he is the total egomaniac, who is determined
(whatever the cost) to make his orchestra the best in the world. But
his ego insists that everyone is secondary to that orchestra and
himself. As is pointed out in several of the reviews so far, Victor's
home and office are loaded with paintings and sculpture all of one
subject - the great him! The use of these pictures are clever, as there
are some attempts to copy technique and style of artists (one painting,
for example, looks like a Marc Chagall). He is extremely temperamental,
throwing tantrums, and getting very physical with his players (he
bashes one man with a violin and tears a shirt off another violinist).
But he has method to his madness: he hates complacency that is
developed by the orchestra liking the conductor - if it fears the
conductor it will be more alive to performing the pieces correctly.Victor has been engaged to Dolly (Kendall) for eight years, and she is
fed up with waiting. She has broken with Victor, and started dating a
Dr. Hilliard (Geoffrey Toone). Victor is not happy with this situation,
which is worsened by a threat to his beloved orchestra. He needs a
wealthy backer, and one elderly woman is quite willing to support his
orchestra for three years provided he adds one composer to his list of
Beethoven, Brahams, Berlioz, and other concert masters - the American
"March King" John Philip Sousa. Victor gags at that idea, but his agent
Max (Gregory Ratoff) tries to point out that an occasional playing of
"The Stars and Stripes Forever" would not be totally amiss. Then Victor
and Max learn that Dolly is friendly to the old lady, and realize they
need her to try to coax the old lady into supporting the orchestra with
or without Sousa.The film gives Brynner ample opportunities to use his domineering
master characterization for comic affect. Note a brief moment when
Hilliard has gotten into Victor's house and wants to see Dolly. Dolly
(earlier) flung a bottle of cold cream at Victor who shut the door in
time. When Hilliard shows up, Victor tells him Dolly is in the room
behind the closed door and is expecting him. "Don't bother to announce
yourself", says a slyly smiling Brynner, "Just go inside!" The next
moment we hear Hilliard getting hit by another bottle of cold cream
while Brynner looks beatific.Kendall shows her comic abilities very nicely movie - at one point
Dolly shows Hilliard she is prepared to protect herself with dueling
pistols if Victor tries anything on her. "I haven't watched all those
television westerns for nothing you know.", she explains to her
bewildered fiancé regarding her abilities as a shooter. When left
alone, she picks up one of the pistol, twirls it, and "fires" it with
loud verbal sound affects. Ratoff plays one of his sly, conniving types, who manages to mangle
English but get his ideas across. A veritable fictional version of Sam
Goldwyn in language malfeasance, he says things like, "If I'm not
telling the truth now, I'll never tell another lie again!" Even minor
characters have good moments. A misused violinist is being calmed down
by Kendall (the man wants to hurt Victor in retaliation). She explains
that Victor's actions are those of a brilliant man who is frequently
misunderstood by lesser people, "Just like the peasants who disliked
Galileo." The violinist says (without missing a beat) "Please, I don't
know all the Italian composers." The same violinist also notes with
approval all the autographed photos on Victor's piano. He sees Casals,
Heifitz, Van Cliburn, and then looks at a hidden photograph puzzled.
"Who is that?", he asks Ratoff. Ratoff looks and says, "It's President
Eisenhower." The photograph is then revealed of Ike. "And a very
distinguished looking man.", says our under informed violinist. It is a
very droll film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1901892/comments</url><from>from bahamas</from><name>manxman-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Delightful, enchanting, deliciously funny. Kay Kendall was all of these
things in her far too short life. Her last film, Once More With Feeling
is very rarely seen, more's the pity. As a companion piece to The
Reluctant Debutante this is a wonderful tribute to a dazzlingly
beautiful and talented young woman. The fireworks between Kendall and
Yul Brynner as her "apparent" husband (who really isn't) are a joy to
watch and give one a view of a masterfully comic actress whose talents
would have taken her way up into the stratosphere of cinema greats.
Great pacing and set pieces from director Stanley Donen. Yes, this
movie is a piece of fluff but the sheer professionalism of both leads
make it a must see. If you can get your hands on a copy then you're in
for a real treat. A beautiful looking production with top performances
all round. Would that the movies of today could be this enjoyable!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0453538/comments</url><from>from PALM BEACH, FLORIDA</from><name>CLAY  MARSTON (cmarston@interlog.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is the last film made by Kay Kendall, in which she really
excelled.....Possibly one of the two or three best films ever for Yul
Brynner.....and, a fine performance by one of filmdom's great character
actors, Gregory Ratoff.....The subject of this great unseen classic comedy
is the story of Victor Fabian (Brynner) as one of the world's greatest
conductors, whose townhouse is chock-a-block with hundreds of photos and
paintings of himself in ever room, throughout.This film should be considered a must-see.....Hardly ever seen on television
it has popped up in special showings with other top comedies such as " The
Trouble With Harry " 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7857489/comments</url><from>from Virginia, United States</from><name>vaggmk-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I finally found a copy of this which I had not seen since it came out.
I still found it wonderfully funny and vintage Kendall. Perhaps the
reason why this movie has not survived in the public arena is that it
deals with a couple "living in sin" who have to marry in order to
divorce after a 7 or 8-year liaison in order to satisfy public
morality. Seems unbelievable now, but can think of no other reason,
other than perhaps Kay Kendall's estate is difficult about her films.Another Kendall movie which seems to be unattainable is "Simon and
Laura" with Peter Finch. This film takes a rather cynical look at the
TV industry, viewer loyalty, and "soaps" and these aspects might be a
reason for its suppression. Since writing this, it has just been
released on DVD in the U.K.(March 2007)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Unlike Saratoga with Jean Harlow where you can easily tell that the
star was in some kind of distress while making the film, there is
absolutely no trace of any of ill health in Kay Kendall's sprightly and
last performance. A kind Providence left her just as I'm sure she would
want to have been remembered by her many fans in Once More With
Feeling.The film is adapted from the original play by Harry Kurnitz which ran
for 263 performances in the 1958-59 season on Broadway. Kurnitz was a
screenwriter of long standing with an impressive list of credits so I'm
sure he had no trouble getting this play sold to the screen and wisely
with the proviso he adapt it for film. The play was produced on
Broadway by Martin Gabel as a star vehicle for his wife Arlene Francis
in the part that Kendall had on screen. Her husband was Joseph Cotten
and the part of their manager was played by Walter Matthau.Cotten's role was taken by Yul Brynner as the egotistical symphony
conductor with his wife, talented harp prodigy Kendall. There's is a
stormy relationship and Brynner's got a roving eye. It roves to Shirley
Anne Field who turns out to be not a child prodigy of 12, but a shapely
young thing of 21. Too good to resist for Brynner, but the last straw
for Kendall.The problem is that in the world of classical music, she's the
attraction, him they put up with. Manager Gregory Ratoff finds that
Brynner's best solo offer is Fargo, North Dakota, quite a come down
from the London Symphony.After this the film and play start looking a whole lot like Twentieth
Century. That doesn't mean it isn't good, just not truly original.
Brynner and Kendall play well off each other. In the supporting cast I
like Mervyn Johns as the director of the Liverpool symphony with whom
Brynner is campaigning for a position with or without Kendall. In the
midst of the classical music, he who has the Liverpool Symphony deficit
as a tax write off for his canned goods firm demands The Stars and
Stripes Forever in all concerts and played with piccolo players
standing. Is there any other way? Will the Philistine get his way?Stanley Donen directed Once More With Feeling at a nice and bright clip
and he had his own little joke in the credits. Donen who directed
several MGM musicals both alone and in collaboration with Gene Kelly
had scores by Romberg, Gershwin, etc. Now of course he's dealing with
Wagner, Beethoven, Tschaikovsky, and of course John Philip Sousa.And this review is dedicated to Kay Kendall, who left a nice body of
work in her short life that ended at 33. And to my sister Nancy who
left us at 34. Both are sorely missed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Unlike Saratoga with Jean Harlow where you can easily tell that the
star was in some kind of distress while making the film, there is
absolutely no trace of any of ill health in Kay Kendall's sprightly and
last performance. A kind Providence left her just as I'm sure she would
want to have been remembered by her many fans in Once More With
Feeling.The film is adapted from the original play by Harry Kurnitz which ran
for 263 performances in the 1958-59 season on Broadway. Kurnitz was a
screenwriter of long standing with an impressive list of credits so I'm
sure he had no trouble getting this play sold to the screen and wisely
with the proviso he adapt it for film. The play was produced on
Broadway by Martin Gabel as a star vehicle for his wife Arlene Francis
in the part that Kendall had on screen. Her husband was Joseph Cotten
and the part of their manager was played by Walter Matthau.Cotten's role was taken by Yul Brynner as the egotistical symphony
conductor with his wife, talented harp prodigy Kendall. There's is a
stormy relationship and Brynner's got a roving eye. It roves to Shirley
Anne Field who turns out to be not a child prodigy of 12, but a shapely
young thing of 21. Too good to resist for Brynner, but the last straw
for Kendall.The problem is that in the world of classical music, she's the
attraction, him they put up with. Manager Gregory Ratoff finds that
Brynner's best solo offer is Fargo, North Dakota, quite a come down
from the London Symphony.After this the film and play start looking a whole lot like Twentieth
Century. That doesn't mean it isn't good, just not truly original.
Brynner and Kendall play well off each other. In the supporting cast I
like Mervyn Johns as the director of the Liverpool symphony with whom
Brynner is campaigning for a position with or without Kendall. In the
midst of the classical music, he who has the Liverpool Symphony deficit
as a tax write off for his canned goods firm demands The Stars and
Stripes Forever in all concerts and played with piccolo players
standing. Is there any other way? Will the Philistine get his way?Stanley Donen directed Once More With Feeling at a nice and bright clip
and he had his own little joke in the credits. Donen who directed
several MGM musicals both alone and in collaboration with Gene Kelly
had scores by Romberg, Gershwin, etc. Now of course he's dealing with
Wagner, Beethoven, Tschaikovsky, and of course John Philip Sousa.And this review is dedicated to Kay Kendall, who left a nice body of
work in her short life that ended at 33. And to my sister Nancy who
left us at 34. Both are sorely missed.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>