<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Guns of the Timberland</original_title><alt_title>Tonnerre sur Timberland</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Robert D. Webb</director><producer>Jaguar Productions</producer><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
Guns of the Timberland is a 1960 feature film starring Alan Ladd and Jeanne Crain. Alan Ladd plays Jim Hadley... See full synopsis »
</synopsis><actor>Alan Ladd</actor><actor>Jeanne Crain</actor><actor>Gilbert Roland</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Alan Ladd is cast as Jim Hadley, who, with his crew of lumberjacks, is
looking for a new forest to cut... But Hadley and crew soon find that
they will have to fight for their next load of wood...The residents of the valley town of Deep Wells, led by Laura Riley
(Jeanne Crain), realize that without the natural protection provided by
the surrounding woodlands, their ranches and homes would be buried by
mudslides during the first heavy rains...The interests of the inhabitants to drive out the intruders start with
their refusal to give horses or supplies of any kind, and increases to
blow out the logging road...Although the obligatory spark of romance lights up between Hadley and
Riley (as the lady rancher is called), the two remain at cross
purposes. The efforts of the townspeople to force the intruders to move
on begin with denials of horses and supplies and escalate to the
dynamiting of the logging road...Hadley, bracing himself for a fight, still insists on legal means to
reach the lumber. But his hotheaded partner, Monty (Gilber Roland)
favors a more direct approach...The fast friendship between the two loggers is strained to the breaking
point when Monty decides to open the road by the method that closed it:
dynamite... The film, set against some spectacular scenery, and climaxed by a
forest fire, remains a routine and simple outdoor melodrama... Frankie
Avalon's musical numbers are among the more ludicrous moments in an
already sorry film... As Avalon's love interest, Alana Ladd is cute but
makes no great impression as an actress...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Kirk Douglas said the worst film he ever did was The Big Trees, in fact
he did it for no salary in order to buy his way out of a Warner
Brothers contract. Like Guns Of The Timberland, it's a logging story
and was a bad step in the career of both stars.The problem with Alan Ladd, producer and star of Guns Of The Timberland
was that there weren't too many steps left for him. Douglas did his
timber disaster at the beginning of his career, Ladd towards the end.Ladd and Gilbert Roland are partners in a timber concern and they've
got a contract to cut logs in the territory of Jeanne Crain's ranch.
The problem for Jeanne and the rest of the valley is that it will leave
no watershed for flooding and as her foreman Lyle Bettger so aptly puts
it, her cattle will be eating mud next year.Of course the sight of Jeanne in a nice tight fitting cowgirl outfit
was enough to make Ladd only concerned about one log in his life. But
Roland wants to fight and therein lies the conflict.Like Douglas in The Big Trees, Ladd's conversion to the cause of
environmentalism is a bit too unconvincing. And Gilbert Roland going
berserk is not the Gilbert Roland I'm used to on the screen. I really
hated him in this and Gilbert Roland is one of my favorite players.Ladd produced as well as starred in Guns Of The Timberland and in order
to get a little box office from the young, he had current teen heart
throb Frankie Avalon make his screen debut opposite his own daughter
Alana. I don't think Frankie got any big hit records out of Guns Of The
Timberland, he did sing two forgettable songs here.But this was not the worst film Alan Ladd made. That would be next year
in Duel Of The Champions, but he was definitely tobogganing down career
wise in Guns Of The Timberland.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Physically ,Alan Ladd was becoming the ghost of himself:His puffed up
face had lost most of its charm;it was even worse in "duel of
champions" (aka "Horatio E Curazio"),his Italian sword and sandal,the
following year.In his final years ,only "the carpetbaggers"-in other
respects an average movie- gave him a prophetic role worthy of himself
,an aging actor down on his luck.This is a western which displays ecological concern : lumberjacks
versus farmers (the best scene shows Jeanne Crain taking Ladd to the
ghost town :"you would ruin our village too ").The cinematography is
fine ,with a good use of the wide screen which enhances the splendid
landscapes ,particularly in the scenes of the fire.But the characters
are cardboard .For those whose taste runs that way,Frankie Avalon sings
two songs ,the first one in a ball and the second after a quarrel with
his girlfriend.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Physically ,Alan Ladd was becoming the ghost of himself:His puffed up
face had lost most of its charm;it was even worse in "duel of
champions" (aka "Horatio E Curazio"),his Italian sword and sandal,the
following year.In his final years ,only "the carpetbaggers"-in other
respects an average movie- gave him a prophetic role worthy of himself
,an aging actor down on his luck.This is a western which displays ecological concern : lumberjacks
versus farmers (the best scene shows Jeanne Crain taking Ladd to the
ghost town :"you would ruin our village too ").The cinematography is
fine ,with a good use of the wide screen which enhances the splendid
landscapes ,particularly in the scenes of the fire.But the characters
are cardboard .For those whose taste runs that way,Frankie Avalon sings
two songs ,the first one in a ball and the second after a quarrel with
his girlfriend.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>