<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Wake Me When It's Over</original_title><alt_title>L'île des sans soucis</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Mervyn LeRoy</director><producer>Mervyn LeRoy Productions Inc.</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis/><actor>Ernie Kovacs</actor><actor>Dick Shawn</actor><actor>Margo Moore</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0277642/comments</url><from>from New York City</from><name>Karen Green (klg19)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I've not read the Howard Singer novel, but seeing this film is going to
send me straight to the library for it. I watched this on a whim,
because I wanted to see an Ernie Kovacs film performance different from
his turn in "Bell, Book, and Candle." The cast in this film--from
Kovacs, to newcomer Dick Shawn, to the marvelous Marvin Kaplan, to a
wonderfully subdued Jack Warden--is top-notch, and the writing is just
splendid. The film takes on military bureaucracy, sexual mores,
international relations, postwar backlash, and mixes it all up with the
sort of hijinks that Sergeant Bilko was best known for. It's sheer
delight.Shawn is the victim of a bureaucratic snafu: listed as dead after
having spent 2 years in a German P.O.W. camp, the Air Force decides to
issue him a new serial number instead of reinstating his old one, then
discharges him the next day. As a result, with only one day's service
on his record, Shawn is re-drafted 7 years after his official
discharge, and stationed on the remote Japanese island of Shima, where
the hostile inhabitants still have a shrine to a downed Japanese plane.The air base C.O. is a cavalier flyboy, played by Ernie Kovacs, with
the only other real authority being the doctor, played by Jack Warden.
The 100 men stationed there are bored out of their skulls (Don Knotts
has a nice turn as the activities counselor), and with Shawn's arrival
a plot is hatched to keep the men occupied, improve local relations,
and dispose of a great deal of G.I. surplus material.The movie is a little on the long side, and the subplot with the female
lieutenant seems a little forced, but the action and snappy dialogue
will keep you engrossed throughout.Sadly, this film is not available on VHS or DVD, which is a crying
shame. Watch for it on television; you won't regret it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0401063/comments</url><from>from Arlington Texas</from><name>bernie-50</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The film parallels the book with a few risqué exceptions. What is unique is
that even though major actors were picked for the movie they could not be
closer to the character description from the 1959 book of the same name by
Howard Singer.Russ is a schnook. Therefore if something can go wrong it will. His wife is
into insurance of all kinds. She wants him to get his GI insurance while he
can. After she forces him to apply (schnook), he must explain that he has
two serial numbers (schnook). When he was shot down over Germany he was
presumed dead and needed a second number to get discharged (schnook). So
naturally realizing that the (schnook) being in the service only one-day on
the second serial number, is called up to finish his time.He ends up on an island in the middle of the Sea of Japan. There he has a
revelation that saves his sanity and that of 400 other servicemen. A plan
so
brilliant that I am not about to tell you what it is or how it is executed.In the book the plan cured his shnookyness, in the movie it takes a trial.
The cast includes Dick Shawn as the schnook and Ernie Kovacs as his
commander and hotshot fighter pilot.I can relate to this as I also have two serial numbers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0401063/comments</url><from>from Arlington Texas</from><name>bernie-50</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The film parallels the book with a few risqué exceptions. What is unique is
that even though major actors were picked for the movie they could not be
closer to the character description from the 1959 book of the same name by
Howard Singer.Russ is a schnook. Therefore if something can go wrong it will. His wife is
into insurance of all kinds. She wants him to get his GI insurance while he
can. After she forces him to apply (schnook), he must explain that he has
two serial numbers (schnook). When he was shot down over Germany he was
presumed dead and needed a second number to get discharged (schnook). So
naturally realizing that the (schnook) being in the service only one-day on
the second serial number, is called up to finish his time.He ends up on an island in the middle of the Sea of Japan. There he has a
revelation that saves his sanity and that of 400 other servicemen. A plan
so
brilliant that I am not about to tell you what it is or how it is executed.In the book the plan cured his shnookyness, in the movie it takes a trial.
The cast includes Dick Shawn as the schnook and Ernie Kovacs as his
commander and hotshot fighter pilot.I can relate to this as I also have two serial numbers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0401063/comments</url><from>from Arlington Texas</from><name>bernie-50</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>