<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Can-Can</original_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Walter Lang</director><producer>Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation</producer><producer>Suffolk-Cummings Productions</producer><genre>Musical</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
1896, Montmartre: the Can-Can, the dance in which the women lift their skirts, is forbidden. Nevertheless Simone has it performed every day in her night club...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Frank Sinatra</actor><actor>Shirley MacLaine</actor><actor>Maurice Chevalier</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"Can-Can" is a feeble and obvious attempt to match the wit and high
professional gloss of "Gigi." The cast even included Maurice Chevalier,
still enjoying the quiet pleasures of old age as a tolerant judge named
Paul Barriere, and Louis Jourdan, cast here as an upright young judge
named Philippe Forrestier… After Judge Forrestier becomes amorously
involved with the café owner Simone Pistache (Shirley MacLaine), and
legally involved with her shifty lawyer boyfriend (Frank Sinatra), he
is no longer the same man… "Can-Can" is a musical film that virtually embodies the reasons for the
decline of the genre in the sixties… Except for its appropriately gaudy
costumes and for the exuberant performance by dancer Juliet Prowse as a
cancan girl, the musical is without joy or genuine style under Walter
Lang's unfocused direction…The Cole Porter score reveals the composer at his most ersatz Parisian…
The two of the central roles are grotesquely miscast: Sinatra, who
seems to have arrived to Paris by way of New Jersey, creates no
discernible or even vaguely likable character in François… MacLaine
does well in the musical portions, but her Pistache is simply shrill
and unappealing… Maurice Chevalier and Louis Jourdan work hard at
injecting some life into the dull proceedings… Chevalier with his
trademark shrugged-shoulders, laissez-faire attitude toward life and
love, expressed to such songs as "Live and Let Live" and "Just One of
Those Things," and Louis Jourdan with the French charm he displayed so
prominently in "Gigi." For all their efforts, however, Can-Can emerges as a flat soufflé…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Another Cole Porter Broadway show makes it Hollywood, but not intact.
Can Can retained most of its score, but 20th Century Fox added some
other Porter standards like Let's Do It. Just One of Those Things, You
Do Something To Me. And of course the book was sanitized by the
Hollywood censors.Briefly the plot is a girl who's a Can Can dancer played by Shirley
MacLaine has to choose between two men of the legal profession. Upright
judge, Louis Jourdan and less than scrupulous attorney, Frank Sinatra.
Maurice Chevalier is an older judge who knows all of them and presides
over the film like an avuncular grandfather.The performers all do justice to the Cole Porter score and the best
musical moment is Frank Sinatra's singing of It's All Right With Me.
He's singing it to Juliet Prowse who was his main squeeze at the time.
It's one of Sinatra's best musical moments on film, a perfect mating of
singer and song.I'm sure glad neither Sinatra or MacLaine attempted any kind of phony
French accent. Sinatra tried a Spanish one in The Pride and the Passion
and the results were hilarious.Shirley MacLaine before she came to Hollywood was in the chorus of
Can-Can on Broadway so she was a perfect fit for her part as Simone
Pistache the cabaret owner where the illegal Can-Can is performed.For reasons I don't understand a duet with Frank Sinatra and Maurice
Chevalier singing I Love Paris was cut, though it remained in the
original cast album. Blockheads at Fox, what were they thinking?It also would have been nice to have some Paris location shooting for
this film, it was all done at 20th Century's backlot where Nikita
Khruschev paid a historic visit and said this was an example of western
immorality and decadence. You couldn't buy that kind of publicity.Verdict on this film, well as Old Blue Eyes sang:RING-A-DING DING DING, C'est Magnifique.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I was all set to dislike "Can-Can" for a variety of reasons (not the
least of which is Frank Sinatra cast in a musical set in 1896
France...Frank Sinatra??), but the film is a lot of fun. Sinatra and
Shirley MacLaine are in good spirits throughout this pleasing
adaptation of the stage-success about a dance-hall proprietress who
defends her right to perform the scandalous title-named dance, deemed
lascivious in its day. It runs a little too long, and MacLaine is more
comfortable in her love scenes with Ol' Blue Eyes than with Louis
Jourdan (who doesn't match up well with Shirley at all--he looks puny
next to her), but otherwise it's surprisingly enjoyable and Juliet
Prowse gives her small part as a dancer a great deal of zest. **1/2
from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5258677/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>NF09</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
In 1960, when Can-Can was released, Frank Sinatra was at the top of his
game-most powerful performer in Hollywood, #1 box office draw, (with
Elizabeth Taylor) at the dawn of his Rat Pack Leadership, and he was
making the best and some of the most popular records around. Those were
truly Ring-a- Ding days, and Sinatra, as he stated in song, had the
world on a string. And it was then that Can-Can came along.When you take a huge star, hunt around for some little property that at
least loosely fit's his screen persona, put his name up in colored
lights, and try to make a lot of money by shouting '' Frankie's in
this!!!!'', you have made what is known as a VEHICLE.Like there are good and bad authors, insurance salesmen, and hula- hoop
instructors, there are both good and bad vehicles. This, I am very
happy to say, is NOT a good vehicle. It is a MAGNIFICENT vehicle.The reason for it's greatness does not lie in Shirley Maclaine, Louis
Jourdan, or even Maurice Chevalier, although they are all quite good
and entertaining.No. The real magic in Can-Can comes from what Frank Sinatra can do with
a Cole Porter song. Even though they stuck him in France in the 1800's,
he's still Sinatra, the incomparable ring-a- ding ding cool, the
essential charm and star quality, the cocky grin and blue eyes, and, of
course, that voice. THE Voice.Never would that voice be more perfect than in that scene in Can-Can
where he put away that lovable arrogance and gave one of the finest
performances of his career with the aching tenderness of '' It's All
Right with Me."It's no wonder Juliet Prowse, who he sang it to, proved it was
certainly all right with her as well. Although that little romance,
(like most of Sinatra's) was not long to last, the song's magic will
last forever.Over-all, if this film did not star Sinatra, it would still be fairly
good. Shirley would be as cute and nutty as ever, Louis Jourdan
elegant, though not amazing in either the vocal or ''cool''
departments, and Maurice would be Maurice- charming, talented,
timeless. Then, of course, there are the Can-Can numbers, fabulous Cole
Porter tunes, and an entertaining story.WITHOUT Sinatra I would probably rate this about 8 and a half. But with
the magic of IL' Blue Eyes making an unforgettable classic out of a
pretty good picture, Can-Can get's an easy 10... and then some. Highly
recommended.P.S- For those of you who believe it's impossible to find a Sinatra fan
under the age of forty, I have just turned fourteen, and have loved his
music, his movies,etc. for years. That's not surprising when you think
about it. Why settle for today's idiotic trash when you can have the
best? And that's all I've got to say.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0820162/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mdm-11</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Shirley MacLaine is a delight as the owner/operator of an 1895 Paris
Night Club. The problem: A new, "disgusting" dance craze called the
"Can Can" has swept Paris, and Shirley's night club seems to be the
only place that dares to perform it nightly. Money man Frank Sinatra,
who also is the on-again-off-again fiancé of the owner, attempts to
bribe the authorities to turn a blind eye to what's going on at the
club. Law man Louis Jourdan also falls for Shirley, while an ever-wise
Maurice Chevallier tries his best to play cupid.The musical numbers are wonderful, especially Shirley MacLaine's solo
"Come Along With Me", The MacLaine/Sinatra duet "Let's Do It" and the
grand finale "Can Can". -- This film cost 6 million dollars to produce,
which was a lot in 1960. I'm glad they went through with it, because
this is one of my favorite film musicals. They don't come much better
than this!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3139406/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, Ohio</from><name> (darkinvader45210@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Well, Can-Can is not a total loss, but it's not a 10-star gem of a movie
either, but - it IS entertaining, but the biggest problem that I see with
the film is that everyone looks like they're embarrassed to be in the movie
with each other because no one is actually looking at each other when
they're saying their lines.  Look at the scene where Shirley McClain is
making up the story as to how Louis Jourdan was trying to overcome her
sexually and the scene goes something like this:SHIRLEY:  And I fought him and fought him and stuggled, but what
could
a person do?
MAURICE:  [embarrassed to say] Uh - submit - of course!
SHIRLEY:  [slightly glances at thim and them says loudly]
SUBMIT?The film just kinda lays there and doesn't do anything.  Come on - it's not
Gigi!  It was really a re-uniting of Louie and Maurice because of their hit
movie Gigi and that's about where the uniting ends, but there are some
highlights to the film.  Shirley McClaine's apache dance with the guys while
Louis Jourdan looks on is a great number, and the Adam and Eve Ballet is
quite good and Shirley's line before the ballet is wonderful when she says
something like this:  "Be it known that sin may have been invented in the
Garden of Eden, but it was perfected in Monemart!"It just seems like all they're doing in the film is walking through their
dress rehearsal without putting any oomph into the acting, and at the same
time the some of the costumes are so tacky that they look like we did as
kids when we played dress-up as adults!  And, look at the scene before
Maurice and Louis sing "Live and Let Live".  It looks like it was inserted
on purpose so that they could have the opportunity to sing the song, and the
scene in which Maurice sings "It Was Just One of Those Things".  Even that
looks like it was inserted on purpose just to give him a chance to sing a
song, but the songs are great even though most of them were never in the
original broadway play such as "You Do Something To Me", "Let's Do It", and
"It Was Just One of Those Things", "It's Alright With Me" [which is slow and
a very boring rendition], and oddly enough "I Love Paris" a duet between
Frank Sinatra and Maurice Chevalier was deleted from the movie and only
heard in the the original soundtrack album, and the Oveture and beginning
Credits of the video, that is if you have the first video version of Can-Can
in which you get the Oveture, Intermission Music, and Exit Music with all
the musical numbers letter-boxed, and why they deleted "I Love Paris" from
the movie is beyond me since it was the hit of the show.  Again, Hollywood
has been known to do some dumb stuff!Juliet Prowse's big number "Maids From France" is quite good, but it's
obvious why she's in the scene with Frank Sinatra when he sings "It's
Alright With Me" because at that time they were having an affair, and I
guess if it was alright with them it should be alright with us, but later he
would marry Mia Farrow and since Frank was Italian it was only obvious that
his kids would call her "Uh-Mama Mia"!Anyway, I sure wish they would re-release the original video version of
"Can-Can" or a whole widescreen version on D.V.D..  Other songs from the
Broadway Show were deleted from the movie such as "Never Give Anything Away"
"Al-e-Vou-Zon" [which is only used in Shirley McClains apache dance as a
melody] "There Is No Trick To A Can Can" which is just used as a melody for
the Can-Can at the end of the movie, and again even though they deleted a
singing version of the hit of the play "I Love Paris", at least they use the
melody of it in the Adam and Eve Ballet, but Shirley McClains drunken
version of "Come Along With Me" is delightful, and here goes the insanity of
Hollywood again, at the end of the film when the Paddy-Wagon is pulling away
with Shirley and Frank in it - the chorus is singing the last lines of "I
Love Paris"!So - why didn't Louis get Shirley in the end?  Well, it's obvious that she
was in love with Frank Sinatra all the time, but more than  that; "Once a
Rat Packer; always a Rat Packer"!  

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This is another film which was often shown on TV (twice on the local
channel alone!) but I hadn’t bothered with until now; it’s recently
been released as a 2-Disc Set by Fox but, in view of its middling
reputation, opted to acquire the film by itself.To begin with, the DVD presentation had its good and bad points: the
film was made available in its “Roadshow Version” – running 142 minutes
against the “General Release Version” which eliminated 11 minutes of
extraneous music (Overture, Intermission, Entr’ Acte and Exit Music);
unfortunately, time seems to have taken its toll on the negative as
there were several instances of color fluctuation throughout! As can be
surmised, I decided to give the film a whirl as part of my ongoing
marathon to commemorate the 10th anniversary from the passing of its
male lead – Frank Sinatra; curiously enough, given his reputation as
one of the foremost American singers, he appeared in few vintage
musicals over the years…and it’s certainly a tribute to his acting
talent that his non-musical work (often in hard-hitting, even
groundbreaking films) has tended to overshadow this more familiar
aspect of his personality – at least on the silver screen! Anyway, to get back to the film proper: I found it quite engaging and
its considerable length not overly taxing – and this, to a large
degree, is thanks to the formidable star cast (which, apart from
Sinatra, included Shirley MacLaine, Maurice Chevalier and Louis
Jourdan). The first two had already appeared together – albeit in
dramatic roles – in SOME CAME RUNNING (1958), while the others had been
wonderfully teamed in the same genre and a similar ambiance in GIGI
(1958). Ironically, both these films were helmed by a master stylist –
Vincente Minnelli…so, perhaps, Fox should have struck a deal with MGM
to acquire his services for CAN-CAN – but, given director Lang’s
previous musical success with THE KING AND I (1956), they obviously
thought he could do no wrong. The fact is that his handling is sterile
and more accommodating to the Widescreen ratio than the necessities of
the plot and characters – filming events from a distance and rarely
cutting or even moving the camera; this lazy approach (which still
landed him a nomination from the Directors' Guild Of America!) is
doubly frustrating when viewed on a small screen!! Apparently, the production went through a lot of script changes
(Sinatra’s role, reportedly, wasn’t even in the stage original to begin
with!), songs were dropped and replaced by other Cole Porter standards
which don’t really fit in (such as Jourdan’s “You Do Something To Me”);
the rest of the soundtrack isn’t particularly outstanding (unlike that
of GIGI, for instance) but a number of tunes are cleverly reprised
(sometimes with variations and by different characters) during the
course of the film. It was nice, too, seeing two world-renowned singers
with such different styles as Sinatra and Chevalier come together (and
having fun with it); Chevalier and Jourdan’s roles, then, are virtual
carbon copies of their GIGI characterizations – but it’s a formula that
seems to work (even if it’s not as central to the main plot this time
around, Jourdan having been relegated to The Other Man type).MacLaine did few musicals as well but her vivaciousness (as a dancer
and owner of an establishment which finds itself frequently in trouble
with the law over the forbidden “Can-Can” dance, but who manages to
charm the stuffy judge at the trial) ensures that her numbers emerge as
the show’s highlights: the Apache Dance, the drunken recital of a
vulgar song at her engagement party to Jourdan (at the instigation of
lawyer Sinatra, who loves her but is unwilling to commit himself) and
the “Garden Of Eden” sequence (intended to demonstrate that “Sin wasn’t
invented in Montmartre – it was only perfected there”!). Two other
important figures (though both severely underwritten) are those played
by Juliet Prowse and Frenchman Marcel Dalio as the nervous but devoted
manager of the “Bal De Paradis” (the latter was a versatile actor in
his native land, but he was stuck with this kind of unrewarding role
during his long tenure in Hollywood!); the former appears as a leading
dancer at the club and MacLaine’s prospective rival – interestingly,
the two actresses’ physiognomies are strikingly similar – for Sinatra’s
attentions (a situation which is indirectly played upon during the
afore-mentioned “Garden Of Eden” number, apart from which they’re
teamed for the climactic Can-Can performance…to the predictable
enthusiasm of the formerly disapproving head of a female Legion Of
Decency-type group).In the end, while this film can’t be considered a classic musical as
such, it still seems to me to have been unfairly maligned – as some
fantastic talent has been assembled in the service of a charming
(albeit unsurprising) narrative to provide colorful (if uninspired)
entertainment which the genre was capable of during its studio-system
heyday…
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
After his greatest stage success (KISS ME KATE) Cole Porter entered the
last decade and a half of his life with a track record of hit and miss
musicals. It was not that he lost his abilities to compose great songs.
It was that not everything he touched turned to gold.The "gold" of this decade was his music for SILK STOCKINGS (his version
of NINOTCHKA) and his musical CAN-CAN. His misses included OUT OF THIS
WORLD, his attempt at a modern retelling of the Amphitryon myth from
Greece. OUT OF THIS WORLD has entered the history of Broadway as a
potentially great musical that was too advanced for its period.
Apparently much of the musical involved homosexual as well as
heterosexual sex (in keeping with ancient Greek culture both forms of
love were acceptable). Unfortunately they were not acceptable in 1950
New York City (and one may add in 2008 California and elsewhere). Only
one number from OUT OF THIS WORLD survived: FROM THIS MOMENT ON. It got
grafted into the film version of KISS ME KATE.It is a tradition that none of Porter's scores survived totally intact
in Hollywood. Songs were dropped from films or pushed into others. So
CAN-CAN has Let's Do It in the film score, although it was not in the
musical (it was over thirty years old by that time), and yet I LOVE
Paris, Porter's greatest anthem to the foreign city he adored above all
others, was dropped from the film. Still there is enough Porter in this
film to appreciate his best work. And as was said in another review,
Sinatra's singing "But It's All Right With Me" to Juliet Prowse happens
to be quite the best moment for old "Blue Eyes" in the film.The film tried to capitalize on the success (two years before) of GIGI,
by reuniting Maurice Chevalier and Louis Jourdan from that film with
Sinatra, and fellow rat-packers Shirley MacLaine and Prowse. Set again
in the France of the 1890s, here we are not watching a young girl
blossom into womanhood and win the man of her dreams, but we are
watching the sleazier theatrical world of the day in the Montmartre
District*. For MacLaine runs a dance hall/bar that has the town in a
tizzy due to the dancing of the "forbidden" can-can by the dance hall
girls. MacLaine's partner is her lawyer (and lover) Sinatra. When a
bunch of reformers cause a raid on the dance hall, they just miss
arresting Sinatra, MacLaine, and a corrupt (or friendly) jurist played
by Chevalier. MacLaine has to appear in court, and the judge there is
Jourdan, who is known to be incorruptible. He is, but he falls for
MacLaine. It enables Sinatra to beat the legal attack temporarily, but
it leaves MacLaine with a lovesick Jourdan to worry about.(*GIGI is not the only recent film that has an influence on CAN-CAN.
The Montmartre area is where Toulouse - Lautrec and other painters of
that period resided. The color of Huston's MOULIN ROUGE (1953) and the
background of the cabarets Toulouse - Lautrec went to is evident in the
film too. However, there even is a little joke (no pun intended). While
singing the opening song "Montmartre", Sinatra is in the street, and
passes Toulouse - Lautrec holding one of his canvasses. Toulouse -
Lautrec shows it to Sinatra, who looks at it, and says, "It'll never
sell!")The film follows MacLaine trying to get a commitment from Sinatra that
will make their sexual relationship permanent, but he is too
independent. So she is slowly finding the interest of Jourdan a kind of
refreshing alternative (although she does suspect it just cannot work).
Chevalier is pleased to see this troublesomely honest protégé of his
somewhat corrupted so that he won't interfere with the business at the
dance hall, but he realizes that Jourdan is serious enough to consider
marrying MacLaine, and ruining his career. Their duet ("Your Business
is Your Business, and My Business is Mine.") is not one of the best
recalled Porter tunes, but it is a bouncy enough one, and it certainly
illustrates Chevalier's realization that what was previously a useful
slip by Jourdan is now totally out of hand.The conclusion of the film is set in the dance hall, where the puritan
critics are given a demonstration of the sinful dance, and discover it
has a charm and excitement they had not expected. The dance sequence at the end was the only time that MacLaine (a pretty
affective dancer before she became an actress) shared film dance time
with Prowse. Juliet Prowse was a mediocre actress at best (see my
review of MONA MCCLUSKY, her attempt at a sit com), but she was a first
rate dancer, and the production number of her and MacLaine leading the
Can-Can is quite memorable. The number is a fine way to end the film,
and also for it to enter diplomatic history. As pointed out elsewhere
on this thread, Khrustchev was touring Hollywood when they were
shooting Can-Can, and watched the dance number being shot. He did
condemn the film as proof of the decadence of the west. However, that
did not prevent him from having his photo taken with Sinatra and
MacLaine. I guess there is decadence and there is decadence.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1560419/comments</url><from>from Kent &amp; Madrid</from><name>jogrant</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

**SPOILER**
This is a cute story that is well produced and acted.  There are some very
good numbers worth watching and the treatment of Paris by Americans is
always amusing.However, the ending is a huge disappointment as it doesn't follow from the
characters' evolution through the film; rather it falls back on the idea
that Mr. Sinatra had to be the one who got the girl.  Perhaps Frank was
just
tired of filming that day and wanted to wrap it up.  In any case, the
ending
reinforces an idea that even in the 60's was anachronistic (a girl from
the
slum will only be happy or comfortable with a guy from the slum) and which
today is certainly a big obstacle to enjoying the film
entirely.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0923630/comments</url><from>from xxxx</from><name>Marie-62</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

 I enjoyed the music, especially "It's All Right With Me" or "Do It - Let's
Fall in Love". I absolutely love this movie and wish amazon.com would sell
it again. I know that I would definitely buy it! Worth seeing if you like
Shirley MacLaine. Maurice Chevalier was absolutely awesome. I love this
movie and you probably will too. Extra comment below but don't read it if
you haven't seen it before!!SPOILER:
Why the heck didn't Louis Jordan get her at the end? Couldn't she see that
he truly did love her, and in return you could tell that she did love him,
and not the stooge that Sinatra played? Geez. The ending was
terrible.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0923630/comments</url><from>from xxxx</from><name>Marie-62</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

 I enjoyed the music, especially "It's All Right With Me" or "Do It - Let's
Fall in Love". I absolutely love this movie and wish amazon.com would sell
it again. I know that I would definitely buy it! Worth seeing if you like
Shirley MacLaine. Maurice Chevalier was absolutely awesome. I love this
movie and you probably will too. Extra comment below but don't read it if
you haven't seen it before!!SPOILER:
Why the heck didn't Louis Jordan get her at the end? Couldn't she see that
he truly did love her, and in return you could tell that she did love him,
and not the stooge that Sinatra played? Geez. The ending was
terrible.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/cancan.htm /m/cancan/comments.php?reviewid=1870221</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>A vulgar and lackluster version of Cole Porter's musical set in Gay Paree in 1896.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=15989 /m/cancan/comments.php?reviewid=1421389</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>Despite the star presence of Frank Sinatra and Shirley MacLaine, this is a second-rate musical due to Walter Lang's pedestrian direction but some of Cole Porter's songs are wonderful.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117789673.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/cancan/comments.php?reviewid=1806576</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/68776/can-can.html /m/cancan/comments.php?reviewid=1482015</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9F02E4DB1E38E333A25753C1A9659C946191D6CF&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/cancan/comments.php?reviewid=1389836</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=101750 /m/cancan/comments.php?reviewid=1147585</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>