<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Pollyanna</original_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>David Swift</director><producer>Walt Disney Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Family</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
A young girl comes to an embittered town and confronts its attitude with her determination to see the best in life.
</synopsis><actor>Jane Wyman</actor><actor>Hayley Mills</actor><actor>Richard Egan</actor><rt_rating>7.6/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>83</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2174206/comments</url><from>from Brentwood, CA</from><name>kimmie5</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

A period piece that boasts about "The Glad Game?"  Ready to tune out?  So
was I, until I got what was happening.  This movie is profound, not only
in
its execution of story, but in the relevant, lovely message it naturally
brings, as opposed to the message it sells.  I've viewed it 5 times and
each
time, I am newly informed as to how I can adjust my attitude for a better
way of life.  I come from a school of thought where sunny is ridiculed and
message movies are tedious, so the lead is an obvious target of disdain.
Stay with Pollyanna awhile and watch her reform all the bitter, crusty
malcontents on the planet into fans with a straightforward logic and
uncanny
point of view.  A true heroine.   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0337831/comments</url><from>from Baltimore, Maryland</from><name>Tommy-92</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

A vast improvement on the cutesy, blatantly unrealistic and cliched story
on
which it is based, the Disney film Pollyanna is a truly enjoyable,
BELIEVABLE film.  It has a very charming, nostalgic feel to it.  The
period
costumes and sets are very good, and the direction is good, too.  The best
thing about it, however, are the performances.  The talented cast really
makes you believe in them and forget they're all stereotypes.  Jane Wyman
is
quite good as Aunt Polly, as are Agnes Moorehead, Adolphe Menjou, and
espicially Karl Malden.  And Hayley Mills more than holds her own, giving
a
very good, subtle, believable performance.  This Pollyanna does not spend
all her time chatting her mouth off and misinterpreting every cold act of
her aunt's as an expression of love, which made her very annoying in the
book, but rather, she really gets to know people and very subtly brings
out
the best in them.  A truly good family film, much better than the book,
and
one really worth viewing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0102055/comments</url><from>from Chicago, Illonois</from><name>luke-31</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This is an absolutely remarkable film.It is uplifting,life-affirming,and
painfully truthful about human ways.Even though it is set in the early
1900's, its message is still very applicable in the modern world.I was
blown away by the genuine power of Hayley Mill's performance.The
supporting
cast is also excellent,especially Karl Malden and Agnes Moorehead.If you
want to see a nearly flawless and absolutely charming fim,than this is the
one to see.Far and away Hayley's best performance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3258885/comments</url><from>from Orlando, Florida</from><name>Greg  (gdisney99)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

SOME SPOILERSI wish that this movie could sink-in to some of the more cynical minds
that
walk the earth today.  It is a great story that is full of meaning and
nostalgia (which I love).Now before you sit down to watch this film, remember that the book,
"Pollyanna,' was a smash hit in the early 1900s.  Several books followed
the
original along with board games and other children's merchandise.  It is
also important to note that the Pollyanna character was much more "glad"
(more on that later) and overly talkative in the book than in Disney's
rendition.But Disney's telling of the story, choice in casting, and authentic 1900s
period recreation could not be any better.  The film is set in the
picturesque town of Harrington where all politics and decision-making are
controlled by the wealthiest resident, Polly Harrington (Pollyanna's
adopted
aunt).  Until being adopted, the little girl Pollyanna did not live a
silver-spoon lifestyle.  We soon find out that she was very poor while
living with her missionary parents before they died.  This somewhat
explained why she is overwhelmingly upbeat and "glad.'  She plays "The
Glad
Game" with her new friends and neighbors and gradually wins over the
entire
town with her optimism and love.  What was so moving about this story is
how
this little girl made grownups realize that they should be happy to be
healthy and alive.Director David Swift went through hundreds of girls to find the right
Pollyanna.  And thanks to Uncle Walt (Disney), he found a Special Academy
Award winner in Hayley Mills.  Other notable characters that I loved were
Jane Wyman as the prim and proper Aunt Polly, Karl Malden as the fire and
brimstone Minister, Adolphe Menjou as the town hermit Mr. Pendergast, Reta
Shaw as the cake-baking Mrs. Lagerlof and Agnes Moorehead as the
hypochondriacal Mrs. Snow.  All of these characters had great moments of
dialogue which made the story seem so real.The one thing I love about Walt-era Disney films is the
attention-to-detail.
And the detail in this film was incredible.  Costumes, buildings (Main
Street USA, anyone?), songs, automobiles and the town bazaar are just some
of the things that were authentic.  Even the preacher's (Karl Malden)
passionate flamed sermons were something not uncommon in this time
period.This film really showed Walt's sentimental side.  During the screening of
the film, Walt wiped tears from his eyes because it was so touching.  And
how could anyone not do the same?  I certainly do when I see the end.  A
perfect mix of cute moments for children and meaningful points for adults,
Pollyanna (like Mary Poppins) is also "practically perfect in every
way."
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Filling the tiny, but oh so impressive feet of Mary Pickford in one of
her most acclaimed silent screen classics was quite a chore for Walt
Disney. But in an impressive American screen debut, Hayley Mills
launched her career in a most impressive way as Pollyanna.Pollyanna, who is now an orphan, comes to live with her aunt Polly
played by Jane Wyman who is one reserved New Englander. She's the
richest woman in town and pretty much everyone kowtows to her. But when
the eternally optimistic Hayley Mills comes to live in that town, her
infectious spirit seems to effect everyone and everything around her.Pollyanna is one of Disney's best live action films, Mills and the rest
of the cast make it believable without being maudlin. Disney gave Mills
and Wyman an impressive roster of players in support that include,
Donald Crisp, Leora Dana, Karl Malden, Nancy Olson, James Drury, Reta
Shaw, Mary Grace Canfield, and Kevin Corcoran as Mills's partner in
juvenile hijinks.Two people deserve special mention. One is Adolphe Menjou because this
turned out to be his last film. He plays Mr. Prendergast the old miser
who lives alone and miserable, but who softens at the warmth Pollyanna
brings in his life. The second is my favorite here, Agnes Moorehead,
who plays crotchety old Ms. Snow, one of those old folks who seem to
enjoy being sick and miserable. Her scene at the end with Hayley Mills
is the most touching of all in the film.Pollyanna like George Bailey in It's A Wonderful Life both never
realizes all the good she's done in that town and like Jimmy Stewart's
character faces a crisis. But all her friends rally to her in an It's A
Wonderful Life type climax.Walt Disney does a wonderful job in recreating that era before World
War I in small town America, very much like The Music Man. Pollyanna is
what they mean by fine family entertainment, as good now as it was when
I first saw it in theaters in 1960.In fact it might just make one curious enough to check out the Mary
Pickford silent version.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0379447/comments</url><from>from Was UK Now US</from><name>bopdog</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

The DVD double-disk edition of this movie is a perfect example of just how
GREAT DVDs can be! Ostensibly a "big-kids' movie," "Pollyanna" is good
enough to appeal to adults as well. I saw it when I was 10 years old, and
fell in love with it then. I also had a crush on Haley Mills, as did most of
the other boys I knew. Coming back now and finding the movie on DVD to be a
treasure for myself--- nostalgia, childhood revisited, etc.--- came as no
surprise. However, finding the high quality of bonus materials and extras on
the two disks was amazing. Good for Disney Studios... Very well
done!Contrast "Pollyanna" DVD extras with those found on the new "Harry Potter"
DVD. "Harry," an excellent movie, nonetheless has DVD extras that are mostly
geared towards children. "Harry's" entire second DVD disk, the bonus disk,
has high production values (that is, it was obviously expensive to produce),
but most of it is so simplistic and slow that one can only imagine it was
designed for the 8- to 12-year old crowd. Which is fine (note, however, that
the "Interviews" selection on that disk is excellent and informative for
adults, too)."Pollyanna," however, gives us half a dozen bonus disk features that are ALL
aimed at adults (yet might also be appealing to older, brighter, more
inquisitive children). For example, Disney's film restorer guy gives a
behind the scenes explanation and multiple demonstrations of how and why
color film degrades, and how it can be brought back to life. "Where are they
now?" type things give us modern day glimpses of the surviving stars of the
movie. We get to hear them relate their experiences on the set, and
experiences vis-a-vis the movie since that time. We see archival TV footage
of Walt Disney commenting on the movie, what Haley Mills thought at the
time, what she went through, what her dad (famed actor Sir John Mills) said,
and what she thinks NOW, etc. The film's writer and director also makes
in-depth appearances in various features on the bonus disk, AND, he and
Haley Mills provide an interesting audio commentary as the feature itself is
viewed (I read that the director, whose name I cannot recall this instant,
died at the age of 80 or 81, just a few months ago. His death came just
after the DVD bonus materials were prepared). The whole thing was as meaty
and appropriate and entertaining as anything I've ever seen on The History
Channel, or A&amp;E or Bravo channels.Finally, the movie itself has been restored and lovingly presented (again,
optional director and star commentary is available). It is still a good and
solid entertainment! I gave this DVD edition of "Pollyanna" 10 out of 10.
Seriously, I hope the other studios and DVD makers will study this disk
religiously, and learn how it's done! I'd love to see ALL my DVDs prepared
with this degree of detail, care, and mastery.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0570008/comments</url><from>from New England</from><name>Son of Cathode</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

My parents told me this was the very first movie they took me to see, at a
drive-in yet! And what a flick to start with! This super-hit for Disney is
kind of like MAME for kids, and surprisingly enough it works, due to the
all-around charisma of the cast, and the wonderful
small town setting. Uncle Walt sure knew what he was doing when
he
snatched little Hayley Mills from father John and propped her up
in
the title role: walking around with her shiny pigtails and her
drippy
milk mustache, she simply shouts fertility, and the promise of the future.
Disney favorite Kevin Corcoran is fine as Polly's mischievous pal. Preacher
Karl Malden gives a creepy hellfire sermon, sure to scare the kids in the
audience, as well as the kids in the film. Then there's a creepy old
neighbor (Menjou) who supposedly keeps kids as slaves in
his rat-filled basement! Polly sets the guy straight, though; in fact,
precocious Polly has meaningful encounters with all the adult male authority
figures in town, and subsequently becomes fixated on the machinations of
prisms and politics. Then there's the
evocative night carnival, at which Polly sings "America,
the
Beautiful", wrapped up in the flag! There is of course, the
obligatory
traumatic near-death experience, but all ends well. This fun omnibus of a
film fully expresses Disney's interest with small-town America as cultural
and sociological experiment, a venture which began with Disneyland and
hasn't ended yet!

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0449150/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>ZoeBean</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Pollyanna is one of the sweetest movies I've ever seen.  So what if it's
cheesy at times?  Movies are still cheesy today, sometimes, but at least
Pollyanna is wholesome.  Now don't get me wrong, I'm not an advocate for
violence-free, nudity-free, perfectly goody-goody movies.  But I do think
this is a beautiful movie that just happens to be OK for everyone.  Young
children might be scared by the minister or by the ordeal Pollyanna faces,
but the fun and happy scenes in the movie (the carnival is my favorite) will
more than make up for the -- in the words of Pollyanna herself -- "gloomy"
ones.  Hayley Mills is terrific.  Watch Pollyanna's expressions.  You can
tell, at times, she thinks everyone in town is completely nuts, but she
never says it out loud.  Instead, she keeps a happy and hopeful demeanor
through most of the movie.  And while, at first, the townsfolk resent her
attitude and even insult her, she doesn't lose it, and she is rewarded for
it in the end.  This is a great message.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5158541/comments</url><from>from Poland</from><name>gusienka</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This movie ,,Pollyanna'' is quite fascinating especially the leading
actress makes a wonderful atmosphere while watching the actual film. A
good adaptation but it would have been nice if they'd show the ending
with Pollyanna on crutches. In some moments you could have seen a tear
in my eye, which proves the fact of the movie being sad and realistic.
Sweet Haylie Mills and the other actors make a great-standard
presentation of their talent.Unfortunately their seems to be something
missing and my vote goes for the ending. I also loved to see Agnes
Moorehead and the lovely cooks.If you liked this movie you'd probably
love ,,The parent trap'' with the same actress, or should I say
actresses taking the lead. A good film for the whole family.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1341122/comments</url><from>from Florida</from><name> (slduehring)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is a great family movie. I recommend this movie for children &amp;
their mothers. It might be a little cheesy for dads or men. It is very
idealistic - Good values - good plot. It is not for everyone -
especially if you are not "young &amp; pure at heart" (or at least long to
be). This Disney film is about a young girl and her joyous, Christian
outlook on life. Her view &amp; beliefs turn the town around. Hayley Mills
was a wonderful young actress who also starred in Parent Trap
(original), Summer Magic, That Darn Cat, etc. I have to make this
review at least 10 lines - so I'll just end by saying that I hope this
becomes a family favorite in your house, as it is in ours.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1341122/comments</url><from>from Florida</from><name> (slduehring)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

This is a great family movie. I recommend this movie for children &amp;
their mothers. It might be a little cheesy for dads or men. It is very
idealistic - Good values - good plot. It is not for everyone -
especially if you are not "young &amp; pure at heart" (or at least long to
be). This Disney film is about a young girl and her joyous, Christian
outlook on life. Her view &amp; beliefs turn the town around. Hayley Mills
was a wonderful young actress who also starred in Parent Trap
(original), Summer Magic, That Darn Cat, etc. I have to make this
review at least 10 lines - so I'll just end by saying that I hope this
becomes a family favorite in your house, as it is in ours.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1341122/comments</url><from>from Florida</from><name> (slduehring)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/pollyanna  /m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1949280</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>This is Disney at its finest.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,897497,00.html /m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1801248</url><from>TIME Magazine</from></reviewer><comment>Pollyanna emerges on the wide screen as the best live-actor movie Disney has ever made: a Niagara of drivel and a masterpiece of smarm.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/variety-staff/</url><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117794066.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1729433</url><name>Variety Staff</name><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment>Hayley Mills' work more than compensates for the film's lack of tautness and, at certain points, what seems to be an uncertain sense of direction.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/daniel-eagan/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1404255</url><name>Daniel Eagan</name><from>Film Journal International</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Heartwarming period coming-of-age tale with typical Disney gloss</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1327922</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>One of Disney's best 1960's films...and one of Hayley's best.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-null/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/Pollyanna /m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=311926</url><name>Christopher Null</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>It's so saccharine it's difficult to take seriously.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://movies.tvguide.com/pollyanna/review/109409 /m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1801247</url><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1402775</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/linda-cook/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1303046</url><name>Linda Cook</name><from>Quad City Times (Davenport, IA)</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ryan-cracknell/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=1291440</url><name>Ryan Cracknell</name><from>Movie Views</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=751864</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>/m/1016512-pollyanna/comments.php?reviewid=312801</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Movie Mom at Yahoo! Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>