<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Lost World</original_title><alt_title>Le monde perdu</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Irwin Allen</director><producer>Irwin Allen Productions</producer><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><genre>Sci-Fi</genre><synopsis>
Professor Challenger leads an expedition of scientists and adventurers to a remote plateau deep in the Amazonian jungle to verify his claim that dinosaurs still live there.
</synopsis><actor>Michael Rennie</actor><actor>Jill St. John</actor><actor>David Hedison</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2737479/comments</url><from/><name>phillindholm</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Producer/director Irwin Allen had big plans for this one. He also had
the big budget needed to craft a truly spectacular remake of the
original 1925 classic silent film. And, he rightly felt that a new
movie based on Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's science fiction masterpiece had
better be up to the task. Allen originally intended using the
"Stop-Motion animation" technique (made popular by Ray Harryhausen) to
bring his prehistoric monsters to life. But, just as production was
about to commence, Twentieth-Century Fox, who commissioned the film
(and were then experiencing severe monetary shortages, due to
production problems with their money guzzling "Cleopatra") slashed the
budgets of nearly every film currently being produced. "The Lost World"
was no exception, and Allen's dreams of a Sci-Fi Spectacular were
crushed. Being a resourceful film maker, though, he did the best he
could with what he had, and that turned out to be very good indeed.For his cast, he chose British character actor Claude ("The Invisible
Man") Rains to play the indomitable Professor Challenger, leader of the
expedition. As Playboy Johnny Roxton, he cast another British actor,
Michael Rennie. David Hedison played newsman Ed Malone, Jill St. John
played Jennifer Holmes, daughter of Malone's publisher and Fernando
Lamas was Gomez, the expedition's pilot. Supporting them were Jay
Novello, as a cowardly guide, and Vittina Marcus as a helpful island
native girl. Forced to forego his original Stop-Motion technique, Allen
had to make do with photographing lizards, alligators and such, adding
horns and gills when necessary. The result was pretty much the way it
sounds - the creatures this bunch discovered were a long way from
prehistoric beasts. Nevertheless, the movie entertains, with truly
beautiful wide screen photography, a fantastic collection of colors
which really bring the striking sets to eerie life. As for the performances, they are decent enough. Rains has gotten
plenty of criticism over the years for his bombastic Challenger, but
that's the way the character was written, and Rains is true to the
material, and highly enjoyable too. Michael Rennie is a bit colorless
in his big game hunter part, but he does have some good scenes as well.
David Hedison is OK as Malone, who falls for Jennifer (Roxton's
girlfriend) though their romance must have ended up heavily edited, as
there's little evidence of it here. Ms. St John and Ms. Marcus are
mainly eye candy, (this WAS the '60s after all) but act capably enough,
though for a woman described as "brave as a lioness". Jill certainly
does a lot of screaming while dressed in a very flattering, if
impractical wardrobe (which includes a Toy Poodle). Ray Stricklyn is
very persuasive as her rather immature but compassionate brother. Lamas
and Novello are the supposed villains of this piece, though Lamas has a
reason for his hostility. Allen's direction is good and the score by
Bert Shefter and Paul Sawtell adds immeasurably to the drama and
suspense. All in all, the picture is perfect Saturday Matinée fare, and
though the script is talky in places, it still delivers the goods at
the climax. The movie is a textbook example of a period when celluloid
escapism was all viewers demanded, and here, they got it In spades. Fox Home Video has just released "The Lost World" as a two-disc DVD
set, with special features (trailer, newsreels and galleries of
promotional material) from the film on disc one, and a restored version
(with a few outtakes!) of the 1925 original on disc two. Allen's film
looks wonderful in it's anamorphic CinemaScope transfer, and after
years of suffering through the faded pan-and-scanned prints used for TV
and video this is really a revelation. The new stereo soundtracks are
equally impressive and make this film, from a producer/director who
would one day be known as the "Master of Disaster', (thanks to such
fare as The Poseidon Adventure' and "The Towering Inferno") a must have
for collectors.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1229491/comments</url><from>from Fayetteville, GA</from><name>Bruce Cook (brucemcook@windstream.net)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Unlike `The Lost Continent' (1951), this 20th Century Fox Cinemascope
production had an ample budget -- but the money wasn't spent very well.  A
good cast (Michael Rennie, Claude Rains, Jill St. John, David Hedison, and
Fernando Lamas) are all part of an expedition that discovers a plateau in
South America where dinosaurs still thrive.Unfortunately producer Irwin Allen elected not to use stop motion
animation
to create the dinosaurs. Instead, the audience is treated to two hours of
disguised iguanas and enlarged baby alligators.  Irwin Allen also co-wrote
the script, which is burdened by an excess of soap opera melodrama. The
good
musical score, however, is by Paul Sawtell and Bert Shefter.Top quality production values and good photography make the film easy
enough
to watch, but there's a tragic story behind `The Lost World'.  Willis
O'Brien, creator of `King Kong', spent several years during the late 1950s
making preparations for a big-budget remake of his 1925 version of `The
Lost
World'.  He made his pitch to producer Irwin Allen and the big wheels at
20th Century Fox, showing them the hundreds of preproduction drawings and
paintings he had done.  He succeeded in persuading them to make the
film --
but Fox refused to let O'Brien do the film's special effects, substituting
the poorly embellished reptiles instead.From all reports, O'Brien's version would have been the greatest lost-land
adventure movie of all time.  Irwin Allen's lack of vision is puzzling in
view of the fact that in 1955 he produced `The Animal World' with animated
dinosaurs by Ray Harryhausen and Wills O'Brien!   See my comments on
`Animal
World' for more info.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1638404/comments</url><from>from Lancaster, Pennsylvania</from><name>William (onnanob66@gmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

You would expect much more from an Irwin Allen film than 1960's The Lost
World delivers. This film is high on silly-to-obnoxious characters, and
corniness. The first few scenes in the film are particularly loaded down by
corniness as we are introduced to the characters. There's eccentric
Professor Challenger (Claude Rains) with his silly facial expressions, and
boisterous but stuffy personality. There's Lord John Roxton (Michael Rennie)
with his selfish and uncharming personality. There's Jennifer Holmes (Jill
St. John) who starts out by trying to show the men a woman can also be
worthy to take along on an expedition, but then becomes a useless, timid
character who shows no strengths at all. The sexist remarks made by some
male characters in the beginning become even more obnoxious, because
Jennifer never comes through on showing strength, courage or ideas to help
her crew members. The only strength she really proves is that she can pick
out some elegant but inappropriate clothing to wear during the dangerous
expedition. Jennifer has also brought along her silly, little poodle named
Frosty. And then there's Costa (Jay Novello), a wimpy, greedy, seedy, little
man. Throw in Fernando Lamas as Manual Gomez, the hired helicopter pilot who
is also along for a side plot of personal revenge. He plots his
murder-revenge and strums his guitar along the way (the natives even let him
keep his guitar when the group is captured!) Not too many characters to
really care for, but there are a few to possibly like such as Jennifer's
brother, David (Ray Stricklyn.) David actually turns out to be more of a
help then originally believed. A captured native girl (Vitina Marcus) turns
out to be one of the better characters in the picture, but that is most
likely because she has none of the corny lines and characteristics the
expedition party's characters have. There's also corny drama from a love
triangle that forms along the way. We all know Claude Rains (Phantom Of The
Opera), Michael Rennie (The Day The Earth Stood Still) and others can do
fine acting jobs, and the acting in this movie is fine--It's just most of
the characters are so corny at times it should be embarrassing to the stars
of the picture. The action in the film does not really build to any exciting
levels as the crew is menaced by various creatures. The dinosaurs are
lizards and reptiles with fins and horns applied to their bodies, and the
giant spider is a rather lame effect (especially since it just hangs there,
and only moves its legs a bit.) There is an unpleasant scene in which a real
lizard fights a real reptile (portraying dinosaurs) that seems very
politically incorrect by today's standards (and should have been a no-no
even back in 1960.) Irwin Allen and 20th Century Fox could've done much
better than this, and it is not nearly as good of a film as Journey To The
Center Of The Earth (also from 20th Century Fox.) Still, The Lost World may
entertain on a Saturday afternoon matinee level, and it is one of those
movies collectors of horror and science fiction films will probably want to
add to their 1950's and 1960's collections.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2575838/comments</url><from>from sparks     nv</from><name>march9hare</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Irwin Allen puts a saddle on the Conan Doyle novel and digs in the spurs in
this silly adaptation of the eponymous book.  Loaded with action but not
much else, and well stocked with useless characters
such as Frosty the poodle.  SEE! Jill St.John, who starts off
feisty
but ends up as simpering baggage, explore the Amazon in pink
tights.
HEAR!! Michael Rennie murder the Spanish language.  FEEL!!! The sense of
loss as Fernando Lamas deadpans the line: "My helicopter".  In
an
interview years later, David Hedison admitted that he HATED this
movie,
and it's easy to see why.  With typical pre-release hype, Irwin Allen teased
the public with promises of unbelievably authentic-looking monsters("like
nothing you've ever seen before!").  Wrong: they were exactly like
everything we've seen before.  The actors, from Claude Rains to Fernando
Lamas, are all good to very good, but not in this 
clunker.  Their combined talents were wasted, as will be your money if you
buy or rent this film.  Get it ONLY if you feel compelled to complete a
collection of '50s and '60s B-movies, otherwise: don't
walk,
run!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532177/comments</url><from>from Isle Of Bute, Scotland</from><name>Theo Robertson</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This film was shown a couple of times in the " Saturday Night At The
Movies " slot on BBC 1 in the early 1970s and being a young child at
the time I enjoyed it immensely . Come on lads if you're six years old
any movie featuring dinosaurs in the present day is a movie highlightIt goes without saying that my enthusiasim for THE LOST WORLD has waned
in later life . It has a totally B movie quality to it and is rather
unsophisticated . There is still some amusement to be had at the
special effects . Nowadays thanks to the power of technology we can
watch convincing dinosaurs thudding around but in the 1960s we had to
put up with actors standing in front of some back projection pretending
they're frightened of a couple of giant lizards with massive fins stuck
on them . Oh well at least the cheese factor means it's more
entertaining than JURASSIC PARK: THE LOST WORLD
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1532079/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Chris Gaskin</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This was the first sound version of the Lost World and I think it is one of
the best.  The silent, 1925 movie is the best.  There have been several
remakes since this one.Professor Challenger takes a party to an uncharted plateau where dinosaurs
still roam.  They arrive there by helicopter, but not long after they get
there, this is destroyed by a dinosaur.  Despite this, they explore the land
and capture a native cave girl, who knows how to use a gun.  We learn that
Lord Roxton has been here on a previous expedition and he killed Gomez's
brother.  After a fight between two dinosaurs, the party are captured by
unfriendly natives, who are cannibals.  Luckily, the cave girl who the party
captured earlier helps them to escape and after meeting Burton White, the
blind surviver of an earlier expedition, make their way along a narrow ridge
where Challenger nearly meets his death.  The party collects some diamonds
and then Gomez holds everyone hostage as he wants Lord Roxton dead, but the
gun shot wakes the "fire monster" and it eats Costa.  Gomez then meets his
death by falling in the lava helping to open a rock door.  The plateau then
blows its top and everyone is safe.  But one last explosion causes the
dinosaur egg they found to fall on the floor and break, revealing a baby
T-Rex... The "dinosaurs" in this movie are enlarged lizards with fins and horns
attached to them and an enlarged crocodile.  This what director Irwin Allen
wanted unfortunately.  Pity he did not want stop-motion, despite Willis
O'Brien helping with the special effects.   We also see a giant spider and
man eating plants.The movie has a great cast: Claude Rains (The Invisible Man), Michael Rennie
(The Day the Earth Stood Still), David Hedison (The Fly, Voyage To The
Bottom Of The Sea) and Bond Girl Jill St John (Diamonds Are
Forever).I enjoyed this movie, despite the non stop-motion dinosaurs.Rating: 4 stars out of 5.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Irwin Allen's 1960 version of The Lost World may be shot in
CinemaScope, but stylistically it fits right in with his 60s sci-fi TV
shows (indeed, stock footage from the film found its way into his
Voyage to the Bottom of the Sea series, as did co-star David Hedison).
Originally intended to feature state-of-the-art stop-motion animation
from Willis O. Brien, the special effects genius behind the
groundbreaking 1925 version as well as King Kong, the ever-economical
producer opted instead for the tried and trusted and, most important of
all, much cheaper technique of supergluing fins and horns on real
lizards and having them double for dinosaurs despite looking like
nothing so much as lizards with fins and horns superglued on them.
However, even had he spent the extra time and money, this modernised
version was never going to be the definitive one: 'dinosaur' action is
fairly thin on the ground and the novel's finale that sees a
pterodactyl on the loose in London is unceremoniously dropped. Instead
there's a lot of wandering around the Fox ranch and backlot, cameo
appearances from the odd poisonous giant plant left over from Journey
to the Center of the Earth, a tribe of natives with a yen for human
sacrifice, a fortune in diamonds and the obligatory erupting volcano
finale, though it retains a certain nostalgic Saturday kids matinée
appeal even if most of today's kids wouldn't sit still for it. Claude
Rains gets to grandstand as Professor Challenger while Michael Rennie's
aristocratic big game hunter seems almost like a blueprint for George
Lazenby's take on James Bond, with Jill St. John tagging along for no
good reason other than Arthur Conan Doyle's thoughtless failure to
provide any female roles in the original novel.Fox's new DVD boasts a fine 2.35:1 widescreen transfer, but the stereo
tracks are reversed so that the left comes from the right speaker and
vice versa!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The Lost World might have been a better film if it had been set back in
the time when Sir Arthur Conan Doyle wrote the novel. Which would be in
the pre-World War I days of 1912. Back then such a plateau might have
escaped detection from modern man.In any event it's been updated to 1960 and I remember seeing it for the
first time at a downtown Rochester theater long since demolished and I
was with my grandmother. She took me when I was by myself visiting them
in Rochester. I remember the movie, but I also remember how slow she
was moving. What I didn't know was that she was in the first stages of
Parkinson's disease which would eventually kill her.Seen as an adult it's a film better left to the juvenile set. And it
could use a makeover now and replace those dinosaurs with the more
realistic ones of Jurassic Park.But I doubt we could get a cast as classic as the one I saw. Claude
Rains is in the lead as Conan Doyle's irascible Professor George
Challenger who was the protagonist in about five books. Not as many as
that much more known Conan Doyle hero Sherlock Holmes, but Challenger
has his following. In this film he's back from South America in the country roughly
between Venezuela and British Guiana at the time, deep in the interior
at some of the Amazon tributary headwaters. He claims he saw some
ancient dinosaurs alive on a plateau. True to his name Claude Rains invites company and financing on a new
expedition to prove him right. His rival Richard Haydn accepts as does
big game hunter Michael Rennie and David Hedison who is an American
newspaperman whose publisher promises financing for an exclusive.Of course it wouldn't be right in the day of woman's liberation if the
shapely Jill St. John, sportswoman and a crack shot doesn't come along
with her brother Ray Stricklyn. Guiding the expedition are South
Americans Fernando Lamas and Jay Novello who have an agenda all their
own involving at least one member of the party. Watching The Lost World again, I think of myself as a kid back in the
day and even with such a cast it really should stay in the juvenile
trade. And this review is dedicated to my grandmother Mrs. Sophie
Lucyshyn who took me to the movies that day back in 1960.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2020269/comments</url><from>from the Draconian Swamp of Unholy Souls</from><name>Coventry</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
It's such a damn shame that the youngest generation of cinema buffs
only knows about "Jurassic Park", because they have been making really
good dinosaur movies since the silent era already! Particularly Arthur
Conan Doyle's legendary novel has always been a very popular story that
received decent film versions in practically every decade. In case you
know nothing about the plot just yet: the obnoxious and self-centered
professor Challenger assembles a troop of unlikely adventurers to go on
an expedition deep in the Amazonian jungle, because there's supposed to
be a plateau where the dinosaurs never got extinct. The expedition sure
is no field trip, since the plateau also homes giant funky green
spiders and an aggressive tribe of aboriginals that don't really like
intruders. Unavoidably the group also falls apart due to personal
intrigues and two adventurers' mutual love-interest for the same girl.
"The Lost World" by Irwin Allen by no means is a good film, but it's
vastly entertaining, partly because the special effects and set pieces
are so incredibly crummy! The dinosaurs are just ordinary reptiles,
like lizards and even a crocodile, with fake horns glued onto them and
filmed with a fish-eye lens so that they appear to be gigantic. Well,
they obviously remain simple reptiles and totally don't evoke feelings
of fear or engagement. The decors are quite nice, though, and this film
definitely has the irresistible early 60's charm that never fails to
put a smile on your face. Claude Rains, here in the final stage of his
well-filled career, is excellent as the boisterous professor Challenge
and he obviously amused himself with yelling at people and hitting them
on their heads with an umbrella. The rest of the cast is rather
forgettable, expect from the stunningly beautiful Vitina Marcus who
plays the sexy native girl. Even though I only remember it vaguely, the
1925 version of the same story is a much better film, but this version
will definitely appeal more to larger audiences.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1100198/comments</url><from>from Kansas, U.S.A.</from><name>Doylenova (Doylenova@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I was six years old when this film came out, at which time my parents
took me to the theatre to see it, and I have not seen it since! So, any
comment I can make about this version of The Lost World will be from
the point of view of a six-year-old! Having clarified that, let me just
say this: It is one of only two or three films from my childhood that
left such a lasting impression on me. It started my interest in
dinosaurs, which continues to this day, and even now I can perfectly
visualize the baby dinosaur (okay, so it was only a lizard, I didn't
know back then!) hatching from its egg, and more than anything, wanting
it for a pet!!! From other people's comments that I have seen here,
perhaps, the special effects left something to be desired, and maybe,
as intimated here also, the makers of the movie had hired the best
special effects person and had hoped for more. Whatever the case, I was
impressed to the point of writing this review 40+ years later and maybe
all the special effects in the world couldn't have struck that same
chord with me &amp;/or many other children around the world? My husband,
who comes from England, remembers having had a similar effect when he
first saw the film! So, if making an impression counts, I'd say the
film was, after all, very successful indeed!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1100198/comments</url><from>from Kansas, U.S.A.</from><name>Doylenova (Doylenova@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I was six years old when this film came out, at which time my parents
took me to the theatre to see it, and I have not seen it since! So, any
comment I can make about this version of The Lost World will be from
the point of view of a six-year-old! Having clarified that, let me just
say this: It is one of only two or three films from my childhood that
left such a lasting impression on me. It started my interest in
dinosaurs, which continues to this day, and even now I can perfectly
visualize the baby dinosaur (okay, so it was only a lizard, I didn't
know back then!) hatching from its egg, and more than anything, wanting
it for a pet!!! From other people's comments that I have seen here,
perhaps, the special effects left something to be desired, and maybe,
as intimated here also, the makers of the movie had hired the best
special effects person and had hoped for more. Whatever the case, I was
impressed to the point of writing this review 40+ years later and maybe
all the special effects in the world couldn't have struck that same
chord with me &amp;/or many other children around the world? My husband,
who comes from England, remembers having had a similar effect when he
first saw the film! So, if making an impression counts, I'd say the
film was, after all, very successful indeed!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/lostworld1960.htm /m/lost_world/comments.php?reviewid=1826194</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C-
					</rating><comment>Incredibly stiff adaptation of a Sir Arthur Conan Doyle sci-fi story.</comment></review></movie>