<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Beat Girl</original_title><imdb_rating>5.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Edmond T. Gréville</director><producer>Willoughby Film Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
Paul, a divorced architect, marries Nichole, a woman from Paris. His teen daughter Jenny has fallen...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>David Farrar</actor><actor>Noëlle Adam</actor><actor>Christopher Lee</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1752296/comments</url><from>from UK</from><name>xmullet</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

This film is notable for two early appearances:  John Barry's
(James Bond) first film score and an early role for Oliver Reed as a
teenage reveller.  In some ways reminiscent of a pubescent La
Dolce Vita, the  film succeeds for one reason alone - Gillian Hills
makes a truly seductive and formidable she-devil in the form of
Jennifer.Yes, the film is dripping in kitsch value, but one can't help but be
absorbed the atmosphere, from the milk bar to the cave party,
where English Elvis wannabe Adam Faith curls his lip to the
drumming of an upturned guitar.  Although before my time, I'm
sure life in 1960 was never quite this with it, daddy-o.It's not the greatest film ever made, but the wonderfully sleazy
theme by Barry sets the tone nicely, and it rates as one of the best
teenage exploitation movies to come out of the UK.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0283144/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, BC</from><name>Vornoff-3</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Beat Girl goes where few American JD's films dare to go. It comments on
the nature of revolt, the need for revolt and the reasons for revolt. In
one
scene, when "the gang" are hanging out in a cave-like nightclub, the kids
begin to talk about their experiences during the Blitz, their disgust with
their middle-class conservative parents and their boredom with everyday
life. These are not the typical American "young thrill seekers" of the
50's
and 60's, moralistically raised by immoral parents. These are the burnt
out
products of modern society, angry at a world that offers them nothing of
any
meaning.
More shocking is the reaction the the Beat Girl's father to his new
wife's past life-he is horrified, and mad at having been deceived into
thinking he was marrying a "nice French girl". He has no sympathy or
imagination-if she was a stripper, she must have been a tramp. His
incapacity to love her unconditionally compares to the emotionless "love"
he
expresses for his daughter.
On the whole, this is social commentary of the first
degree.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1929687/comments</url><from>from Hollywood, CA</from><name>keithbrooks</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
First and foremost, who is Gillian Hills? And second, why didn't she
become a major star? After looking for this film for some time, I
finally got a chance to check it out the other night. As JD films go,
it wasn't a classic, yet it wasn't a clunker either. However, what
compelled me to write a review of the film was the sexy young star of
the film, Gillian Hills. Going by her bio, she was born in 1946, making
her all of fourteen when she made Beat Girl. Well, this has got to be
the sexiest fourteen year old ever! Brooke Shields, Jodie Foster, Sue
Lyons, even Tuesday Weld can't hold a candle to Ms. Hills. Her
performance is the glue which holds the bare thread plot together.
Gillian plays Jennifer Linden, spoiled, rich teenager who, along with
her beatnik friends, rebel against British society and it's rigid rules
and traditions. If one thinks that Jennifer is being led astray by her
friends, think again. If anything, it's Jennifer who is leading her
friends down the dark and tawdry path. Jennifer is no one's puppet, and
proves this in a game of "Chicken" on a railroad track. When her father
brings home a much younger Parisian wife Nicole (Noelle Adams),
Jennifer makes the woman's life a living hell. She tries to turn her
father against Nicole when she finds out that the woman once danced as
a stripper in Paris. Jennifer's scheme quickly turns against her and
soon she finds herself being manipulated and lusted after by the sleazy
strip club owner (played by the always villainous Christopher Lee). The
ending to the film was a disappointment, wrapped up rather conveniently
despite the fact a murder is committed. Still, Gillian Hills is a vamp
on par with some of the best the screen has ever offered. I would
assume that maybe it's her resemblance to Brigitte Bardot that may have
stymied her career. I would love to see a film of her as an adult, and
see if she still possessed that smoldering sexuality she displayed as a
teen.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0555856/comments</url><from>from Leicester, England</from><name>Ross-c</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I was a bit disappointed by this film. Some may see the
young
star as bravely standing up against the cruel older generation,
but personally I just found her annoying.One previous review talks about how her father was completely
unable to accept his wife having been a stripper. His initial
inability to accept this is only a brief passing stage,
and
he does accept his wife. After this scene they both worktogether to find his daughter, who is allowing herself
to
be seduced by a sleazy strip-joint owner (Christopher Lee
acting extremely well).My main disappointment with this film is that it isn't
as
laughable as the cover suggests. There is a small amount
of
risible dialog, but not enough.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This could easily beat out any of the weak JD b-flicks being produced
in the States at the time. While most of our juvenile delinquent
schlock was lame, polished, and not a very accurate portrait of the
youth, "Beat Girl" is sleazy, grimy, and all together tough as nails.
In other words, just the way I like my exploitation films. First off,
I'm shocked at why Gillian Hills didn't become a massive b-movie (if
not mainstream) star. She is charismatic and above all one of the
sexiest people to ever be caught on camera, its a shame she went on to
small roles (her only other really noteworthy part was in "A Clockwork
Orange"). Just watching this immediately adds her to my list of
greatest cult starlets. It also accurately captures the youth scene at
the time and avoids exploiting them.The greatest thing about this film however are the locations. Featuring
a glimpse into vintage Beat clubs and strip joints in the UK, I was
fascinated by such an alien culture. Plus, the theme song is memorable
and just flat out rocks. Not to mention Christopher Lee is in it! How
cool can this movie get? Sure its not a great piece of art, but as far
as cult cinema is concerned, it deserves more recognition and should be
placed in the echelon of "Plan 9 From Outer Space" or "Detour". On the
bad note, the commercial DVD from Mondo Crash is a piece of crap. The
image is horrible and there are scenes cut. You'd be much better off
grabbing this oldie from Kino Video. (7/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Architect Paul Linden has been travelling away in Europe for over three
months and returns with new, much younger French wife Nicole in tow.
Nicole's first challenge is Paul's sixteen year old daughter Jennifer,
who is going through a typically teenage difficult period of being
rebellious as she discovers her new sexuality and has places where her
and her friends can hang out away from adults and squares. When Nicole
starts trying to get to know her better, Jennifer reacts by digging for
dirt on her stepmother.This film got a rare screening on BBC4 recently so I watched it out of
retro-curiosity. For my money Beat Girl turned out to be a surprising
good film, partly because I was watching it on its own terms. What I
mean by this is that I quickly accepted that this was not going to be a
sharp examination of teenage alienation but rather a bit of an
exploitative b-movie of rebellion, beatniks, stripping and jive music.
In this area it works really well and is actually one of the better
"troubled youth" b-movies that I've seen. Sadly this is not because it
gets the adult characters right – because where it matters, it doesn't.
The parents are clunky authority figures and Nicole is little more than
a plot device.No, where Beat Girl works is in creating an enjoyable sense of grimy
rebellion and sass that is what these films is supposed to be all
about. The locations and music are a large part of this because it does
give the film an authentic feel to be in seedy strip-clubs and laidback
coffee houses, while the music is roundly cool and of the period. One
of the main things that the film is worth seeing for is a wonderful
turn from Gillian Hills in her debut film role. She is sexy with
genuine fire behind her eyes and a great attitude – I'm not really into
bad girls but I fell in love right here! Only marginally sexier is
dancer Pascaline who does a strip so hot that I had to check two
things: the first being that this was made in 1960, the second being my
watch, to confirm that, yes, BBC4 were screening it before the
watershed! Anyway, back on Hills, she is great and drives the film with
her harsh and convincing teenage girl. Alongside her Adam and Farrar
are a bit clunky while her various peers seem quite clichéd and dated
in a way that Hills' fire prevents. Lee has a real sleazy menace and
there are appearances from Reed and Faith to increase the "oh look its"
count. Overall Beat Girl is a dated and slightly trashy rebellious teen
b-movie. In terms of message and plot it is not great but it is worth a
look due to the cool points that the locations, direction, music and
very hot Hills give it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0293753/comments</url><from>from Essex County</from><name>cricket-14</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

Fun movie proves that even British film makers could do a trashy juvenile
delinquent film - with added bonus of cool, jazzy, rock'n'roll sound
track.Sixteen-year old beatnik art student rebels when her "square" middle-aged
dad brings home a "French poodle" 24-year-old stepmom. She and her beatnik
pals discover that her blonde bombshell step-mommy was once a Parisian
stipper!A few hysterical scenes later the girl realizes the error of her ways and
returns to her architect dad and step-mother.A must-see for any camp, bad movie film buffs!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0040533/comments</url><from>from Huntington Station NY</from><name>laura-6</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Once upon a time, Channel 9 in New York featured the Million
DollarMovie, which ran one movie all day long for a full day, a
programming technique that has been copied by modern cable and
satellite TV's in their endless repeats of movies and shows. But in the early 70's, before the invention of the VCR, Channel 9 was a
film student's dream in that he or she could watch a movie over and
over for one day and really study it. Beat Girl arrived on Channel 9, a few years after its run in British
and, presumably, American theaters. I watched about eight hours of Beat
Girl, in the generous, endless loop provided by Channel 9. This movie
fascinated the 13-yr.-old me who had never encountered such rebellion
and hostility on the part of a school-aged daughter towards her father,
who has returned from a trip with a step mother for whom the daughter
is unprepared.At 13, rebellious, unhappy, and edgy, I needed a "bad-girl" paradigm,
and this movie supplied me with her. I loved the heroine and despised
anyone who would stand in her way. She left such an impression on me
that I have been fascinated by "bad girls" ever since.However, the film is so bad -- or good, depending on your point of view
of gritty, early 60s "To Sir, With Love" England -- that you might want
to stick around to see what happens to this sullen chick who's
accompanied by some stoner boys to some bad jazz music. Or not: this is
one low budget film with fairly terrible acting but there is a gritty
earnestness to this film.Look for Oliver Reed, John McHenery, and Adam Faith in secondary roles.
As in all of 50/60 flicks. look for a moral -- but look for the moments
of rebellion, too. And dig that crazy music.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur18597851/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>johne23-1</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
What we've all been waiting for... Yes! It's another Christopher Lee
strip-club!Hooray!Hurrah! But there's much more here. We have a
(actually) 14 year-old Gillian Hills (later in Blow Up, when she'd
reached the ripe age of 21), Jon Barry (and his Seven) doing the music
and dreaming of James Bond, Adam Faith playing a beatnik-type-coffee
bar-teenage-dreamboat... Everyone goes around saying "Daddio" and "Go,
man, go" and "I'm real gone, man" and "Get out, you drivelling, jiving,
beatnik scum" (honestly!), and not much happens... ..so they all go and
play by having a drag race and then lying on a railway line and playing
chicken...And Then!Someone called Laya Raki does an unbelievable striptease that will make
your eyes water, (hers obviously did)...And Then!!Oliver Reed Starts Dancing!!...Sorry, I need to go and lie down for a bit...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5145895/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, Canada</from><name>David Ostrem (davost@telus.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I gave this a 10 because I only give two ratings, 10 or zero, pass or
no pass. Let's talk about Brit Rock. I was 15 and growing up in the US
when this movie came out and there was no such term as Brit Rock. When
the Beatles, Stones, and the others came out I completely disregarded
them. Who needs these guys doing Chuck Berry and Bo Diddley when we
have the real thing. Eventually I came to appreciate what they were
doing and soon developed a deep admiration for the British rock
movement going back to the 50's. This movie, though fraught with
awkwardness, has some very telling points. A very important point is
made when the kids were discussing the war scars. We Americans knew
nothing of that. To us rock was just a big jolly product. But these
kids had a way more emotional need for it and they took it more
seriously and they wound up exporting our own music right back to us
and basically saved Rock and Roll. Now the bad part of this film is the
pre posterous and thoroughly embarrassing "hip talk" although all the
American rock films of the time did pretty well the same thing. And the
plot is pretty tiresome but it still shows that basic need for rock,
the big thing about rock has always been that need. It's like in the
Lou Reed song, "her life was saved by rock and roll". Goofy as this
movie is, it does convey that message.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5145895/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, Canada</from><name>David Ostrem (davost@telus.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I gave this a 10 because I only give two ratings, 10 or zero, pass or
no pass. Let's talk about Brit Rock. I was 15 and growing up in the US
when this movie came out and there was no such term as Brit Rock. When
the Beatles, Stones, and the others came out I completely disregarded
them. Who needs these guys doing Chuck Berry and Bo Diddley when we
have the real thing. Eventually I came to appreciate what they were
doing and soon developed a deep admiration for the British rock
movement going back to the 50's. This movie, though fraught with
awkwardness, has some very telling points. A very important point is
made when the kids were discussing the war scars. We Americans knew
nothing of that. To us rock was just a big jolly product. But these
kids had a way more emotional need for it and they took it more
seriously and they wound up exporting our own music right back to us
and basically saved Rock and Roll. Now the bad part of this film is the
pre posterous and thoroughly embarrassing "hip talk" although all the
American rock films of the time did pretty well the same thing. And the
plot is pretty tiresome but it still shows that basic need for rock,
the big thing about rock has always been that need. It's like in the
Lou Reed song, "her life was saved by rock and roll". Goofy as this
movie is, it does convey that message.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5145895/comments</url><from>from Vancouver, Canada</from><name>David Ostrem (davost@telus.net)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>