<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Cimarron</original_title><alt_title>La ruée vers l'Ouest</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Anthony Mann</director><producer>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM)</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Western</genre><synopsis>
The epic saga of a frontier family, Cimarron starts with the Oklahoma Land Rush on 22 April 1889. The...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Glenn Ford</actor><actor>Maria Schell</actor><actor>Anne Baxter</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur10408116/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>jpdoherty</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
CIMARRON (1960) was MGM's big Cinemascope/colour remake of RKO's 1930
epic production of Edna Ferber's classic story of the same name. From a
screenplay by Arnold Schulman it was, I am loathe to say, unevenly
directed by Anthony Mann.I am quite astonished - even aghast - that some reviewers on these
pages elected to award this film a seven, eight, nine and in some cases
a ten star rating? Some even hinted that it is Mann's most underrated
western and could be his best work. "Cimarron" is nowhere near his best
work! His best work is "El Cid" (1961) and his best western is
"Winchester 73" with "The Naked Spur" coming a close second. "Cimarron
" isn't even a good western! Not in the normal sense of what is
regarded a good western like "Shane", "The Searchers" or "Last Train
From Gun Hill". Even Ford's "The Sheepman" is a superior western to
"Cimarron"! More lighthearted - sure but much more fun to watch!The first half of CIMARRON isn't at all bad and contains the best
staging of the 1889 Oklahoma land rush ever put on the screen and in
widescreen too (though in 1992 Ron Howard made a good fist of it in
"Far &amp; Away"). But let's face it the second half is relentlessly boring
and just drags and drags! Firstly Anne Baxter, who has third billing
after the leading lady Maria Schell, is written out of the film which I
suppose isn't very noticeable since she didn't have a very important
role in the picture anyway. But then Glenn Ford - the star of the movie
- is also written out of the picture and only makes a brief and
perfunctory reappearance just before the last reel. Then he's up and
gone again never to be seen in the movie any more. With its star gone
from the film the picture loses much of its balance and never regains
the stature it had in the first half. Of course the story is the old
chestnut of the mismatched couple who get hitched - she wants to play
house and raise a family - while he wants to be charging up San Juan
Hill, winning battles wherever they are and never seems to want to come
home to his lovely wife. Well, to my mind any man who could leave the
stunning Maria Schell - even for a long weekend - isn't playing with a
full deck! Hmmm!Nope I'm sorry but I really don't think that "Cimarron" is all that
great a movie! There are some great things in it! Besides the gorgeous
Miss Schell there is the fine Cinemascope/Colour cinematography of
Robert Surtees, the elaborate score by Franz Waxman (his Anthem like
choral Main Title and his recurring main theme throughout plus his
frenetic music for the land rush is outstanding) and the land rush
itself is wonderfully exciting to see but there is nothing in the
turgid second half that can persuade me to give this movie any more
than a three star rating. Pity!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4280907/comments</url><from>from London</from><name>Patricia Hammond</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I admit to not having read the book (but will now go to abe.com to find
it!) or seen the earlier film, but find it interesting to compare this
enjoyable movie with 'Giant'(Stevens, 1956), which incidentally also
had Mercedes McCambridge in it, also concerned an essentially
ill-matched couple, prejudice, mixed-race marriage, early oil-barons,
and also takes in a number of years in which we see the characters grow
older.Unlike the other reviewers here, I did NOT find Maria Schell's accent
annoying in the least. She makes a wonderfully believable pioneer
(note: the accent is genuine, which also sets her apart from many other
Hollywood 'foreigners') and she has a pleasingly natural acting style.
She shines beautifully when she is interacting with other women, be it
the wildcat and part-time prostitute Anne Baxter in one of the finest
scenes of the film (smouldering and feisty but underused I think) or
the earthy and magnificent McCambridge, whose subtle but hilarious
Southern accent is expertly modulated and a joy to the ear. So many
scenes between women in Westerns of this time are somewhat flat and
stagey, but I think they're superb here and set this film apart.Glenn Ford is good, and although the film rather tries to do too much
(as does Giant, in my opinion), it's really a fun way to spend a rainy
afternoon or even a hot afternoon. Plenty happens along the way and it
has something to say.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2206944/comments</url><from>from London, England</from><name>TrevorAclea</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
The last and least of Anthony Mann's Westerns, 1960's Cimarron was
originally intended by MGM as a Rock Hudson vehicle after the success
of Giant. It's at once a lavish film and an undernourished one, not
least because of the production problems that saw Mann's run of bad
luck with epics repeat itself: after being fired from Spartacus at the
start of shooting by Stanley Kubrick, on Cimarron he was replaced
towards the end of shooting by an uncredited Charles Walters. It's all
to easy to spot the join, with the many early exterior scenes that are
very obviously and artificially shot on interior sets at the studio
sticking out like a sore thumb with Mann's signature location filming.Though remembered today, if at all, as doorstop soap operas, in their
day Edna Ferner's novels were hugely controversial, and Cimarron was no
exception, dealing along the way with racism, anti-Semitism and Indian
land rights, though these are treated rather less boldly here than in
the 1930 version (especially in the general release and European
versions that trimmed a subplot with the leads' son marrying a Native
American girl, though these scenes are in the Region 1 DVD). What's
left is an ambitious saga, charting the changing face of the wilderness
from the Oklahoma Land Rush to the 'civilisation' that comes with the
discovery of oil and the big money to be made by a few, taking in the
winners and losers strewn along the path of progress along the way, all
nominally held together by the restless figure of Yancey Cravat (Glenn
Ford). A man who tries everything but can never stay the course before
chasing the next dream, he's held as the pioneer ideal, but it's clear
that his long-suffering wife (Maria Schell) is the saga's real hero,
setting roots and building a future. Structurally it's one of those
books better suited to a mini-series than a film, while the rootless
nature of its hero – who vanishes from the last third of the film
almost entirely – leaves it feeling very unsatisfying. It doesn't help
that the film's most spectacular scene, the truly epic land rush
sequence, happens so early in the film that everything that follows
seems an anticlimax.Unfortunately the casting doesn't help. While Ford isn't as
insufferably hammy as Richard Dix in the original, he never lives up to
the great claims made for his character, and he's not helped by a bad
haircut that makes him look like Oliver Hardy after a diet (it's no
surprise that this film and The Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse pretty
much ended his career as a top box-office attraction). And for all her
efforts, Schell isn't able to exert the kind of charisma or star power
that the problematic last third desperately needs. The supporting
performances are highly variable too. David Opatashu, Arthur O'Connell,
and Charles McGraw offer dependable turns but Russ Tamblyn is
shockingly bad.But ultimately the problem is that the film never seems to quite decide
what it wants to be or what parts of the story it wants to tell. It
just sprawls out in all directions, never building up much sense of
drive or purpose, and even Mann's visual imagination deserts him for
much of the film. Instead it's a film with a handful of memorable
moments – the land rush sequence, played more for chaos and carnage
than exhilaration, one terrific shooting after a lynching and an
excellent scene with Aline MacMahon at a makeshift grave – stranded in
a rather forgettable film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1778227/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>play78rpms</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Sorry but despite the fact that the 1931 version of this novel was the
only western film to win an Academy Award for Best Picture it does not
compare to the entertainment value of this version.
True this is perhaps not the best adaptation of Ms. Ferber's novel, but
then how many films are perfect adaptations of their source material. There
are wonderful scenes missing from this adaptation, but then there are
wonderful scenes missing from the adaptation of GWTW.  No, I am not
comparing this to a classic like GWTW.  But the '31 version is not in the
same class as GWTW either.  This film should be taken for what it actually
is, a good solid epic entertainment with spectacular scenes and good
performances.
Glenn Ford is perfect casting for Yancy. His performance is far superior
to
that of the overripe, stilted scenery chewing one delivered by Richard Dix
in the original. Ford's boyish manner easily captures the charming immature
nature of the character. Maria Schell is on a par with Irene Dunne.  It is
a
pity her character was rewritten from the novel to be weaker than Ferber
intended.  This was obviously done to make the film Ford's but she's still
gives a performance that is on the money.  As so do the myriad supporting
players in the film.
Back in 1960, MGM obviously needed a big movie to move into the theaters
that had been playing "Ben-Hur" for over a year.  So this production was
rushed to completion to fit the bill.  The fact that it was shot in
Cinemascope instead of a "Big" 70 mm process is evidence of this. It has
been written that the production was shut down before the scripted ending
could be filmed.  This explains the rather abrupt and somewhat awkward end
to the film.  Perhaps a regular non "Roadshow" release might have fared
better both with the critics and at the box-office.
It often seems that those who praise the older version over this film
have
seldom actually seen the former.  For many years the 1931 version was not
available for viewing.  During that period many film historians gushed in
their praise of it.  When it finally reappeared on screens most of them
found it very creaky and revised their opinions but the older opinions are
still in print, available and read.  True, they didn't change their opinion
of this version, but the older fell into proper perspective...Cinema
History
and rather dry history at that.  While this version is not a classic it
remains good entertainment.  Compare it to "How The West Was Won" made by
the same studio just a few years later.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7181287/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>donmage</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
To sum up a in a sentence, this movie is about what happens with a
couple in an early pioneer town of Oklahoma, where a man gets to do
what he wants and a woman must do what she must. This is one of those
movies that, unlike 90% of the "westerns" before the realist period
(1965-present), has a lot more realism than one would expect from one
produced in 1960. Not only does it depict violent racism, 19th century
views on women, wayward youth, etc., it also depicts the nuances
prevalent in a man desiring to give up, but incapable of burying, his
wanderlust ideals (men are just boys with bigger toys) for the sake of
his family. Just when one thinks the plot has died a death of boredom,
another wrinkle of interest pushes it's way to the viewing screen
provoking an astute viewer's enthusiasm for the story. Cimarron is one
of those movies with just enough realism that it is a welcoming bridge
from the 1950s 'cowboys &amp; Indians' saccharine period to the
ultra-realist, albeit minimalist, "spaghetti" westerns. If one doesn't
fall in love (not in an amorous way) with Maria Schell in this movie
then they haven't much of a heart anyway. This is a great western-genre
movie with lots of characters to care about lovingly or with disdain.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1826911/comments</url><from>from Yukon, OK</from><name>MisterMickey</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
CIMARRON didn't do well at the box-office, and what a pity. Then again,
it's the story of a man who was considered to be a failure in life by
those who knew him, yet, when you look at him, Yancey Cravat was the
most successful man around. It took me several viewings of the film to
recognize this, and for that, I'm ashamed of myself.The 1931 version is more faithful to Edna Ferber's novel. However, this
version, which contains one of Glenn Ford's best performances, is more
entertaining, and has an outstanding Franz Waxman score. It's the tale
of a man who lives by his own personal code, living by his conscience,
and suffers the consequences for it.CIMARRON is a film that cries to be seen in widescreen, and hopefully
gets such a release in DVD. Until then, TCM is the place to watch it.
Anthony Mann went from making westerns to epics, and with this film, he
was in the best of both worlds.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I've always liked the 1960 remake of the RKO classic Cimarron and have
never understood why it gets panned by so many people the way it does.
Director Anthony Mann who got fired towards the end of the film's
production did a very good job with both the cast and the spectacle.
The Oklahoma land rush scene was as thrillingly done as it was in the
1931 version.In fact truth be told, Glenn Ford did a better job as frontier
renaissance man Yancey Cravat. Richard Dix though nominated for Best
Actor in 1931 never did quite master the art of sound film and his star
progressively sank lower and lower in Hollywood. Glenn is a strong
heroic figure cursed with the fatal flaw of wanderlust.Truth also be told is that many different accents made up the western
pioneer population. Maria Schell's German accent is most assuredly not
out of place here and she holds her own with Irene Dunne's portrayal of
Sabra Cravat.All the characters present in Edna Ferber's saga of the transforming of
Oklahoma from territory to state made it from the first film. All of
them meet during the Oklahoma land rush and while Glenn and Maria are
the leads, the story of the film is what happens to all of them.One character is expanded considerably from the 1931 film. Edna May
Oliver was Mrs. Wyatt who was a pioneer woman whose husband we never
did meet. Here Mrs. Wyatt is played by Mercedes McCambridge who is
married to Arthur O'Connell who is very important to the story. They're
this hardscrabble share cropper family who get a real scrubby piece of
land at the beginning of the land rush, mainly because O'Connell falls
off the stagecoach right at the beginning of the land rush and Mercedes
runs across the starting line and she claims the land right at the
line.It turns out the land has oil and these people become the proverbial
beggars on horseback. McCambridge remains unchanged by their sudden
wealth, O'Connell is very much like that other nouveau rich oil
millionaire that Edna Ferber created, Jett Rink. From people who the
Cravats lent a hand to back in the day, O'Connell at least becomes an
opponent.One character that was eliminated thank the Deity was the black kid
Isiaih who hero worshiped Richard Dix in the 1931 version. In 1960 that
kind of racial stereotype would not have been tolerated.The cast includes also such fine people as Anne Baxter, Edgar Buchanan,
Russ Tamblyn, Vic Morrow, Aline McMahon, Robert Keith, Charles McGraw,
all ably filling out parts from the original version. The land rush
scene is every bit as good as the first time around.I'm at a loss as to why this film was panned the way it was. It's a
very good western and fans of the genre will appreciate it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3985319/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>lcallman (lcallman@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
I first saw this movie at ten years old and read the book shortly
thereafter. I now own a first edition. Coming from Oklahoma, this
beautiful "love story" made my young heart yearn. I imagine that this
is exactly what the Oklahoma Land Run looked and felt like. Please see,
if for no other reason than for how handsome Mr. Ford and Ms. Schell
are! Although there were many moments that took my breath away, prepare
yourself for an ending that you both do and do not expect. It will make
young women sigh and older women understand the meaning of true love.
"Cimarron" is larger than life - a spectacular movie that contains
history, action and heartbreak.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0218006/comments</url><from>from S. Paulo, Brazil</from><name>tmwest</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
The first time I saw Cimarron was at Radio City Music Hall, and I had
to leave halfway through the film because of an unbearable toothache. I
did not think much of what I saw, and did not bother to see the film
again. Not long ago I read an interview of Anthony Mann where he
complains that after twelve days of shooting, the Metro executives made
him take the whole company indoors. He ends up saying that because of
the panic of the executives that he would go over budget, he does not
consider Cimarron a film, but a disaster. I finally saw it on TCM a
couple of days ago, and the conclusion I got is that Mann was so upset
that he did not realize he made quite a good film. Unlike the first
version which was aiming at being an epic, this version follows the
conflict of two different points of view: Yankee Cravat (Ford) who will
always fight for hard to win causes and never, never, compromise and
Sabra (Maria Schell) who thinks he is selfish and does not try to give
material comfort for his family. This type of conflict is universal.
And so is the character of Tom Wyatt played by Arthur O'Connell, the
poor man who becomes a millionaire that makes shady deals.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5204799/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mikesheldon55-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I just caught this movie on TCM and, up front, I tend to hate these
kind of oats-sudsers. This movie had so much going on (plot,
characters, cameos, Western clichés) that it just screamed Cinerama
(Think 'How the West was Won') but it had one major aspect that took me
by surprise: a well-written and extremely well-acted characterization
by Maria Schell. She's actually the major star of this movie...Glenn
Ford disappearing entirely the last 1/4.....and she handles every bit
of it with humor, passion, and just the right amount of country ham.
She's never a perfect wife or mother, and doesn't just change to fit
the scene. I was just killing time watching this...and I honestly was
fascinated. I had no idea who it was until I looked it up here (I hate
that TCM often doesn't run credits) but now I want to see some other
performances by her to see if she was this good all the time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5204799/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mikesheldon55-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I just caught this movie on TCM and, up front, I tend to hate these
kind of oats-sudsers. This movie had so much going on (plot,
characters, cameos, Western clichés) that it just screamed Cinerama
(Think 'How the West was Won') but it had one major aspect that took me
by surprise: a well-written and extremely well-acted characterization
by Maria Schell. She's actually the major star of this movie...Glenn
Ford disappearing entirely the last 1/4.....and she handles every bit
of it with humor, passion, and just the right amount of country ham.
She's never a perfect wife or mother, and doesn't just change to fit
the scene. I was just killing time watching this...and I honestly was
fascinated. I had no idea who it was until I looked it up here (I hate
that TCM often doesn't run credits) but now I want to see some other
performances by her to see if she was this good all the time.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5204799/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mikesheldon55-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://emanuellevy.com/search/details.cfm?id=16161 /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1922037</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>A dull, inferior remake of the 1930 Oscar-winner Cimarron, this time starring Glenn Ford and Maria Schell.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/cimarron.htm /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1411193</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>Tedious remake of the 1931 Wesley Ruggles version of Edna Ferber's classic.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1414541</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/eric-lurio/</url><url>/m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1233064</url><name>Eric Lurio</name><from>Greenwich Village Gazette</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117789908.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1805376</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/69262/cimarron.html /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1480978</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9D03EEDC153DEE3ABC4F52DFB466838A679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1389319</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/matt-easterbrook/</url><url>/m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1176184</url><name>Matt Easterbrook</name><from>Matt's Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102071 /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=1148798</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/maryann-johanson/</url><url>http://www.flickfilosopher.com/oscars/bestpix/cimarron.shtml /m/1046579-cimarron/comments.php?reviewid=32479</url><name>MaryAnn Johanson</name><from>Flick Filosopher</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>