<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Cinderfella</original_title><alt_title>Cendrillon aux grands pieds</alt_title><imdb_rating>5.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Frank Tashlin</director><producer>Jerry Lewis Productions</producer><producer>Paramount Pictures</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Family</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis>
This was Jerry Lewis' answer to the classic Cinderella story. When his father dies, poor Fella is left at the mercy of his snobbish stepmother and her two no-good sons...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Jerry Lewis</actor><actor>Ed Wynn</actor><actor>Judith Anderson</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2737479/comments</url><from/><name>phillindholm</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
"Cinderfella" was Jerry Lewis' answer to the classic Cinderella story.
And he intended it to be a masterpiece. To say that it fell somewhat
short of it's goal is putting it mildly, but it's not bad. The plot is,
of course the familiar story, with a few (expected) variations. When
his father dies, poor Fella (Lewis) is left at the mercy of his
snobbish stepmother (Judith Anderson) and her two no-good sons,
Maximilian (Henry Silva) and Rupert (Robert Hutton). As he slaves away
for his nasty step-family, Maximilian and Rupert attempt to find a
treasure Fella's father has supposedly hidden on the estate. Meanwhile,
hoping to restore her dwindling fortunes, the stepmother plans a fancy
ball in honor of the visiting Princess Charmein (Anna Maria
Alberghetti) whom she hopes will marry Rupert. Eventually, Fella's
Fairy Godfather (Ed Wynn) shows up to convince him that he has a shot
at winning the Princess himself. Lewis had big plans for the film's
release. Although it was completed in January of 1960, he insisted it
make it's debut that Christmas, complete with a holiday campaign and
record album tie-in. In the meantime, he produced and starred in a low
budget item called "The Bellboy" in order for Paramount to have a Jerry
Lewis movie for summer release. "Cinderfella" was given a lavish
production and a formidable supporting cast was recruited to co star
with Lewis. He was indeed fortunate to obtain the services of Judith
Anderson, who, while not a performer one would expect in a Jerry Lewis
film, was nevertheless excellent as the stepmother, bringing just the
right touch of arrogance to the part. Ed Wynn is reliably daffy as the
Fairy Godfather,though, due to severe editing, he disappears before the
climax, and is not seen again. Silva and Hutton do what they can as the
stepbrothers, but the beautiful Alberghetti has nothing to do but fall
hopelessly in love with the hapless Fella. The pace of the film is
somewhat choppy, and several critics pointed out that the editing had
left voids in the plot. The film originally ran 99 minutes, it ended up
at 88. Sure enough, it was released at Christmastime, when it inspired
some of the most scathing critical comment ever bestowed on a Lewis
picture. Most of this was devoted to Lewis' own performance, and his
frequent mugging, mixed with his pathetic attempts to play for
sympathy. "Cinderfella" did just O.K. at the box office, and it ended
up well behind the modest "Bellboy" which was a box-office smash.
Thanks to handsome sets (with exteriors filmed at the "Beverly
Hillbillies" estate in Bel Air, CA), costumes and a pleasant (if
unmemorable) score, "Cinderfella" is entertaining enough to get by. But
you'd better be prepared for a lot of "singing/mugging" from the
Producer/Star, who fancied himself a brilliant vocalist. After all,
though, this is SUPPOSED to be a fairy tale!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0345741/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>Kim-89</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

I thought this was the cutest movie I've ever seen.  Jerry Lewis is
absolutely hilarious.  I was not a big Jerry Lewis fan when he worked with
Dean Martin.  I had a very hard time getting into his work.  However, when
he went out on his own, I really became interested in his work.  I would
like to make mention of some things I found very interesting and very
funny
in this movie.  For example, instead of a fairy God mother (like
Cinderella
had), he had a fairy God father.  He also read approx. 50 words when
reading
the inscription on the ring given to him by his deceased dad.  Like
Cinderella, Cinderfella was a loving, hard-working and honest person who
was
treated unfairly at first.  He waited on his step mother and step brothers
hand and foot.  I happily remember when he went to the kitchen to make
orange juice and proudly put his hand out the kitchen window, pulled in a
tree branch, took a knife and cut off several very large orange to use in
the juice.  I thought it was creative to have him listen to the radio and
act out playing the flute.  I loved it.  But, like Cinderella, Cinderfella
was rewarded in the end for all his hard work.  I waited with excitement
to
see how he would get to the ball and loved what the writers came up with..
And when he made his grand entrance into the ball, I couldn't help notice
what a smooth dancer Jerry Lewis really is. I thought the music was
beautiful.   After I saw this movie I had such a warm loving feeling in my
heart and I really thank God for this touching comedy.  Jerry Lewis is the
funniest actor in the world and his shoes (glass or leather that is) will
be
very hard to fill in the future.  Thank You.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1042377/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles, Californiai</from><name>gary brumburgh (gbrumburgh@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

Decades before there was a Jim Carrey, the movies unleashed another inspired
nut case – Jerry Lewis – whose 50s and 60s Paramount Studio vehicles tended
toward an oil-and-water mix of outrageous physical comedy and mawkish
sentimentalism.  1960's "Cinderfella" is a casualty of that uneasy
blend.Taking the classic fairy tale and tailoring it to fit his talents, the
stretch-faced, rubber-limbed comedian portrays "Fella," a poor, imbecilic,
ostracized stepson who lives only to serve his cruel, absurdly wealthy
stepmother (Judith Anderson) and her two greedy sons (Robert Hutton, Henry
Silva) in their palatial mansion.  The only reason they even allow Fella to
still "bunk" at the mans (his bedroom is more the size of a closet) is that
Fella's late father has hidden a vast fortune somewhere on the grounds of
the estate and the step-kin think the dolt may know where it might be
hidden.Jerry is priceless when it comes to engineering clever, complex, high-energy
sight gags.  A testament to his versatility here is his miming flutist scene
as he listens to a ditty on the radio in the kitchen (one of my all time
favorite Lewis routines).  The dinner scene where he caters to his family at
an absurdly long dining table is another ingenious moment.  Sprinkled
throughout too are numerous well-timed bits, like the reading of the
inscription off his father's ring, or (the frequently used) hair-combing
bit, etc.  But too much of the time, Jerry bogs the scenes down with cheap,
slick, sentimental mush.  He gets what I call "telethon tender" on us --
trying to work our heartstrings instead of our funnybones.I remember the Marx Brothers having the annoying habit of breaking up their
frantic comedy skits with "straight" musical numbers sung by some insipid
ingenues that always took away from the fun.  Same problem here...only
worse!  Lewis incorporates HIMSELF, a very mediocre singer, into these
cloying musical numbers, and ten times out of ten they don't work.  In
"Cinderfella," he allows himself no less than FOUR soporific songs to
indulge in, with one of those numbers, some silly nonsense about being a
"people" instead of a "person", just unbearable.  Jerry the Clown sells;
Jerry the Lounge Lizard doesn't.Judith Anderson is appropriately huffy and haughty and Henry Silva and
Robert Hutton make a fine pair of oily villains, while proving good sports,
too, as the unwitting victims of some of Jerry's mishaps.  But the late,
great Ed Wynn is wasted here as the "Fairy Godfather," mired in those gooey
scenes I was talking about before.  The demure, exceptionally lovely Anna
Maria Alberghetti, who complements the lavish surroundings, appears too late
in the proceedings to make any difference as the "Princess Charming"
character who, for whatever reason, is smitten by the ungainly Fella.  By
the time she arrives, the film has lost its charm and humor, and we have
lost our patience.  It's too bad she didn't get to sing instead of
Lewis.I know it sounds like I'm not a fan at all of Jerry's, but I am!  Like many
producer/director/stars of his calibre, their egos get the best of them. 
Like Elvis Presley, most of his vehicles were not up to snuff. And in the
case of "Cinderfella," Frank Tashlin may be credited with directing, but I
think we all know who the director REALLY was on this set.For those who appreciate Jerry as only the French can, I would suggest "The
Disorderly Orderly," "The Ladies Man" and his most popular, "The Nutty
Professor," to get a better feeling of this man's  genius.
 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5351586/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>soweird7</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
My mom told my sister and I she saw this movie when she was very young
and absolutely loved it. So, I did what my mom wanted me too, was to
Netflix it, and when it finally came, we all sat down to watch it.
And...it was so awesome! I love Jerry Lewis. I've never seen a movie by
him, and he was hilarious. I loved his singing too. He was amazingly
great. I wasn't expecting him to be terrible or anything, but you know.
I loved all the things he did. Just some simple things made it
hilarious. I loved it! I think any kid maybe about 4 or older will love
this. I am 14, and I enjoyed it so much. It's a movie I'll definitely
have my children watch! It's an amazing movie, that I think anyone will
love. This movie is definitely recommended.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0101706/comments</url><from>from Victoria, BC</from><name>Wizard-8</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I have nothing against Jerry Lewis - in fact, I've found several of his
other movies funny. CINDERFELLA, however, was quite painful to sit through.
The fault chiefly lies on Tashlin, who wrote and direct. He milks a gag
endlessly, and there aren't very many humorous things in the movie in the
first place. The music numbers consist of bad songs sung badly. Near the end
of the movie, the movie looks like it went through some major editing,
resulting in a number of things not explained or resolved. One good thing
about the movie is the sets - they look lavish!I hear they are planning to remake this movie. Though I usually balk at
remakes, at least here they are planning to remake a BAD movie - which means
there is plenty of room for improvement. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2158049/comments</url><from/><name>curtaincall9000</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

this is a sweet,warm and adorable film but i would feel better if jerry
wrote it. taken from the fairy tale, jerry does it again by being funny
and
throwing in some cute gags! ed wynn was great as the fairy godfather and
the
rest of the cast made this a great, heart warming movie. but, of course,
jerry really shined. as in the nutty professor, jerry belts out wonderful
songs with his swinging voice. the story was written and flowed nicely,
but
if the ending explained fella's and princess charming's relationship
together, it might of been for the better. wow! who knew jerry could dance
so well! the scene when jerry turned a swinging dancer was one of the best
scenes in the film! i recomend this movie for anyone looking for a cute
and
touching story with some jerry lewis charm! 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
This should've been foolproof: Jerry Lewis playing a male variant of
Cinderella, unloved and hoping to go to the ball. Talented
writer-director Frank Tashlin allows Lewis to run rampant with the
idea, which turns out to be a one-joke affair. Production is glossy,
but the execution is enervated, overlong and fairly unfunny from the
start. Jerry predictably mugs--he's never less than shameless--but with
such weak material (and too much incidental chatter), he simply becomes
a nuisance. His entrance in the ball sequence is, however, a wonderful
bit, but it can't save the movie from being a huge disappointment. *1/2
from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0820162/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mdm-11</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
One of Lewis's early non-Martin films. Superior production values and
charm throughout, this is a true Sunday afternoon family affair. Based
on the Brothers Grimm fairy tale "Cinderella", orphaned Lewis is
trapped in the situation of being royally taken advantage of by a
selfish, scheming step-mother and her two full-grown layabout,
playboy-wanna-be sons. The estate and a sizable fortune that went with
it was to go to Lewis, but his "family" cleverly swindled him, making
Lewis feel grateful to be "allowed to stay". Used and abused as
house-boy, Lewis attracts the attention of a love-interest, much to the
chagrin of the two rejected step-brothers. The rest is predictable.Not a huge box-office success, this piece of light Hollywood candy
nonetheless has found steady fans in the wonderful world of TV re-runs.
Like Annette &amp; Frankie and their beach outings, a steady supply of
1960s Jerry Lewis films have been shown and shown again on small
screens all over the world. To own this gem on VHS is a sound
investment in the comedy entertainment of any household. A big winner
in my book!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1644885/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name> (sleazerama@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Forget the age-old story... in the hands of Jerry Lewis, 'Cinderfella'
becomes something special. And in this case, there are some marvelous
set-pieces that are truly memorable.Most notable is Jerry's entrance to the grand ballroom. Standing at the
top of a staircase, snapping his fingers. Jerry moves beautifully
across the screen, utilizing all 63 steps -- all to the sound of a sexy
Count Basie number. His moves seem perfectly syncopated to the music.
It's a wonderful scene. And as Jerry has said, all done in one take -- which seems perfectly
believable when you then hear his voice crack slightly upon taking the
princesses hand ("Excuse me...").I do like watching Jerry squeeze the oranges in the kichen. An ordinary
task made funnier by his body language and goofy faces. And of course,
the long protracted dinner table scene -- switching jackets, running
back and forth, the salt in the soup -- great stuff.The rest of the cast are good too. Henry Silva is wonderfully slimy as
Jerry's conniving brother. And the beautiful Anna Maria Alberghetti is
perfectly cast as Princess Charming. Though I wish the big dance number
with Jerry had shown more of her.There are some very funny scenes and as sappy as the story gets, it's
rather sweet ("Keep breathing fish!). Considering that Jerry had
already been in his hugely successful act with Dean Martin (where most
performers would have retired), it was quite an accomplishment to have
started carving out a solo career.This man may have his flaws, but Jerry Lewis is priceless.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2542703/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edwagreen</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The old story told with a twist. The sexes are reversed in this one.This time it's Jerry Lewis victimized by a wicked stepmother and her 2
hoodlum sons. Who else but Ed Wynn could play a fairy godfather?Dame Judith Anderson, a veteran player of the wicked, is at it again
but how can we expect this great lady to add comedy to spice up her
performance. She needed to do her part with a comic twist as Jo Van
Fleet did in the television version of "Cinderella." Sadly, that's
missing. Playing the role straight is of no consequences in this farce.
The sons come off like underworld hoods. It's a little too heavy for
this film.Jerry is funny but his attempts at singing fall quite flat.Nice to show the kiddies that guys can be victimized too.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2542703/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edwagreen</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The old story told with a twist. The sexes are reversed in this one.This time it's Jerry Lewis victimized by a wicked stepmother and her 2
hoodlum sons. Who else but Ed Wynn could play a fairy godfather?Dame Judith Anderson, a veteran player of the wicked, is at it again
but how can we expect this great lady to add comedy to spice up her
performance. She needed to do her part with a comic twist as Jo Van
Fleet did in the television version of "Cinderella." Sadly, that's
missing. Playing the role straight is of no consequences in this farce.
The sons come off like underworld hoods. It's a little too heavy for
this film.Jerry is funny but his attempts at singing fall quite flat.Nice to show the kiddies that guys can be victimized too.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2542703/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>edwagreen</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/cinderfella.htm /m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1656976</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C-
					</rating><comment>It's a dreadful comedy that's only for diehard fans, critic apologists for such lame slapstick laced with sentimentality and the French.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1492342</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Video-Reviewmaster.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Fun Jerry Lewis vehicle, one of his best.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ken-hanke/</url><url>/m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1189167</url><name>Ken Hanke</name><from>Mountain Xpress (Asheville, NC)</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment>Interesting, uneven fantasy marred by Lewis' inability to edit himself.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1407073</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117789913.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1 /m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1806536</url><from>Variety</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/69268/cinderfella.html /m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1481983</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/howard-thompson/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9403E5DA103FE63ABC4F52DFB467838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1390536</url><name>Howard Thompson</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=102076 /m/cinderfella/comments.php?reviewid=1147513</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>