<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Young One</original_title><alt_title>La jeune fille</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Mexico</country><country>USA</country><director>Luis Buñuel</director><producer>Producciones Olmeca</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
An jazz musician seeks refuge from a lynch mob on a remote island, where he meets a hostile game warden and the young object of his attentions.
</synopsis><actor>Zachary Scott</actor><actor>Bernie Hamilton</actor><actor>Key Meersman</actor><rt_rating>8.3/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>100</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0655549/comments</url><from>from London, U.K.</from><name>Aw-komon</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Some of the above comments have mentioned pedophilia in connection with
this
film.  An important distinction has to be made here to prevent corruption
of
language.  What the Miller character (Zachary Scott) does is 'take
advantage
of an innocent' from his position of strength as an older man, but that is
not the same thing as pedophilia at all.  The girl in question is 13 years
old and sexually mature (an age at which it was FULLY LEGAL to get married
in some southern states, Jerry Lee Lewis anyone?).  This would make sexual
relations between her and a younger man closer to her age fully legal and
between her and the older man STATUTORY RAPE only if the laws in that
state
said so.  It is WRONG, in the sense that the girl is in a weak position
and
gets taken advantage of.  But that could happen at any age and age
interval
per se can never be the only measure of who took advantage of who (look at
all the women married to men 20 to 30 years their senior), although it is
a
pretty safe bet.  In fact towards the end of the movie, one of the likely
resolutions suggested by Miller to the priest as a way to redeem himself
is
"what would happen if I married her?"  And when Miller lets Bernie
Hamilton
leave the island he is doing this to redeem himself in his own eyes and
possibly marry the 13 year old girl later!That said, the main character is not the black fugitive (Bernie Hamilton)
but the young girl (Kay Meersman, a Liv Tyler lookalike in an amazing
performance).  She has lived on a remote island for most of her life and
knows very little about the racist realities of the American South (or
anything else.)  She is confronted with it head on, when a black
clarinet-player fugitive named Travers, unjustly accused of raping a white
woman escapes to her island to hide from a lynch mob.  She becomes
friendly
with him and likes him as a person and can't understand the irrational
animosity Miller (her temporary 'protector' whom she hates and who sleeps
with her against her will)has for this man.All this creates a whole bunch of complex tensions that Bunuel deals with
in
the most masterful way possible. You really believe in all these
characters,
they are multi-dimensional and historically and psychologically valid.
Bunuel has been called cynical and cruel.  That may be true but
nevertheless
quite a few of his films remain consummate works of art because they live
up
to Pascal's idea of showing man's 'greatness within wretchedness.' This is
one of them.  'The Young One' is a MUST SEE film, if there ever was one.
It
makes all other films about racism and the corruption of innocence look
like
amateur hour.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1790184/comments</url><from>from Los Angeles</from><name>FilmTx</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

I have been looking for this film for some time, and it's everything I've
waited for.  For 1960, this film has some rather advanced themes.  A
black
jazz musician named Traver winds up on an island used by a hunting
resort.
He has run away from a town after being accused of rape.  The resort is
kept
by a middle-aged man named Miller and an older man who has just died
leaving
his granddaughter Evalyn (no older than 14).  Traver finds the Miller's
shack and takes some items.  Miller wants to kill him, we assume for
racial
reasons.  Miller is also in love with Evalyn, now in his care, and wants
to
make her a woman.  This subplot is used through the eyes of two other
characters who learn about Miller's relationship with Evalyn.  You will
notice quickly that one man, Jackson, wants to shoot and kill Traver for
what others say he's done, and jokes with Miller about what he knows
Miller's done.  Statutory Rape is worse than rape, but to these people,
black crimes are worse than white ones.  Other reviewers seem not to pick
up
that Miller knows what he has done is wrong.  He knows he is a worser man
than Traver.  After he finds out Traver left money for the stuff he
stole,
Miller no longer wants to kill him.  Miller is not a racist man, any
hatred
for Traver that Miller has is spawned only from the fact that he's a
stranger.This film is the ultimate drifter film (under Tokyo Drifter)...like a
Spaghetti Western or a Samaurai movie, it starts as the man drifts into
this
new environment and follows him till he leaves this environment.  The
film
is book-ended with a great exterior scene with a compelling song playing
about running away.  Traver's name is short for Traveling Man, what
better
for a drifter?As one of Bunuel's two English films, I wish Anchor Bay would pick this
up
and put it on DVD, or whoever distributed it if they still exist.
Bunuel's
attention to detail helps mix in some hidden undertones of prejudices.  A
clarinet called a 'Licorice Stick'.  A priest offered a bed slept in by
Traver asks how long Traver slept in it.  "Only one night" the girl tells
him.  "It's okay, I'll just turn the mattress over."  I'm frightened to
even
think what the character would have asked if Traver has stayed a week.
Knowing Bunuel, the priest would probably say he'd just sleep on the
floor
after running to wash his hands.Bunuel is no stranger to prejudices, see Exterminating Angel.  As a
window
breaks, the host shrugs it off and says "probably a passing Jew".
Generally
he is so much harder on Catholics than anyone else, yet in this film, the
priest is the only character that wasn't flawed.  Obviously, I love this
film, if you can find it, you must see it.  The scenes between Traver and
Miller have such style in their words, you'll like them both.  Every
exchange they have is so smooth, I can't believe that Bunuel didn't make
more films in English.RENT THIS FILM!!!!!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0460714/comments</url><from>from Chicago</from><name>mgmax</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

To viewers in 1960 this mostly seemed a rather turgid and unappealing tale
of a bigot's reform, compromised by its trashy atmosphere.  The key to the
film, I believe, is Bunuel's admiration for the writing of the Marquis de
Sade.  The Zachary Scott character has a whole host of unexamined
prejudices, not merely a racial one-- and when that one tumbles, his mind
is
liberated in all directions.  The fact that this includes being "freed"
from
conventional sexual morality is the Sadean aspect of it-- as in A
Clockwork
Orange (but no other film that I can think of besides these two), true
freedom is by no means an entirely positive or benevolent
thing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0163275/comments</url><from>from View Park, California, USA</from><name>IboChild</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

THE YOUNG ONE may not be one of Luis Buñuel's finest films, but it is
certainly one of his most disturbing and provocative.  This picture
distinguishes itself from typical "race problem" movies in that Travers is
not the familiar "ebony saint" character popularized by the likes of
Sidney
Poitier.  Here Travers (played with intensity by Bernie Hamilton) does not
take any mess from the racist Miller -- and lives to tell about it.
Miller
on the other hand is one of the most vile and despicable characters ever
to
grace the silver screen.  Not only is Miller  a bigot, but a pedophile
too.
When Miller is not spewing racial slurs at Traver, he's trying to bed
Evalyn, the recently orphaned girl next door.  Daring for the time, THE
YOUNG ONE will provide Buñuel aficionados and those interested in the
portrayal of African American men in the early 1960's with much fuel for
discussion long after the films has been shown. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1219578/comments</url><from/><name>dbdumonteil</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
"Cela S'Appelle L'Aurore" (1955) :the priest ,in the luxury of the
bourgeois house ,can do nothing for the poor proletarian who has lost
house ,wife and job......"La Mort En Ce Jardin"(1956) :in the first part,the priests sing
"Alleluia" in their churches when the dictatorship kills
outside.....Later the heroes lost in the jungle will light a fire ,with
the pages of the Bible!But It was "Nazarin"(1958) which must be considered Bunuel 's greatest
achievement as far as this subject is concerned.The whole movie deals
with the life and times of a priest ,at odds with his hierarchy ,who
tries to live like a saint and who will only get a pineapple (sexual
symbol) at the end of his pitiful adventure."The Young One" continued in that vein.Although the priest is absent in
the first hour,it's him who finally invents right and wrong as a
doctrinaire religion imposes them on (more or less) innocent
characters. The scene when the girl wants to bury grandpa with a bottle
whiskey has something of all the old ancient pagan religions.Isn't it
better than a cross?My favorite scene remains that of the baptism,the girl's so-called
golden key.It's almost a comical scene as the priest washes the body in
the water and takes away the young one's sin.It' a golden key to a rotten world:the black man understood that a long
time ago ,he does not expect anything anymore from the white justice:
this is not the part of a black man you could see in Hollywoodian
flicks in 1960,no Uncle Tom and no Sidney Poitier style either.."The young one' is a good movie,but I would not rate it as high as
"Viridiana" or "Nazarin" the two greatest Bunuel achievements of the
1955-1965 era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5232724/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Polaris_DiB</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
A black jazz musician on the run from a lynch mob stumbles across the
game warder of a private island and the young, innocent girl the warder
guards over. Sweet and precocious Evy is almost completely unaware of
the world outside her isolated island and unable to defend against the
advances of her guardian, while also not comprehending the nature of
the problem with the musician's arrival.Bunuel's more well-known films are very impressive, but some of his
lesser-known films aren't given enough attention for what they are. "La
Joven" is a parable of innocence brought suddenly up against racism,
exploitation, and sex, and as a whole is a very morally ambiguous film.
Ultimately, the question must be asked: is one man's life being paid
for by the freedom of a young girl, or will she choose a different,
completely unfamiliar life full of its own trials? Those are the
questions left with the audience by the movie's conclusion.Bunuel's mastery is reinforced by how well he is able to get into the
regional dialect, settings, and character of this film. Here is a
director who has shot movies from all over the world and managed to
give a rather distinctive feel for each of the locations they've been
made in.--PolarisDiB
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Leonard Maltin's *1/2 review of this bafflingly overlooked Bunuel gem –
which, more by accident than design, has become one of my favorite
film-maker's most-watched efforts – seems, thankfully, to be a minority
opinion nowadays and, in fact, renowned critic Jonathan Rosenbaum
(albeit contending elsewhere that this was the Spaniard's biggest
critical and commercial disappointment) wrote about it in Steven Jay
Schneider's "1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die"…when Bunuel's
much more renowned THE EXTERMINATING ANGEL (1962) is conspicuous by its
absence therein! Incidentally, an almost equally obscure fate is shared
by the film's immediate predecessor, REPUBLIC OF SIN (1959; which is
still pretty hard to come by, though I did catch it once on late-night
Italian TV): perhaps, this is because both films were squeezed in
between two unexpectedly mature and highly personal works – NAZARIN
(1959) and VIRIDIANA (1961)...Anyway, THE YOUNG ONE is only the director's second English-language
film, after ROBINSON CRUSOE (1952), and it also proved to be his last.
Plot-wise, it's a hothouse melodrama (which has been considerably
altered from the original two-hander short story source) quite typical
of his low-budget Mexican output: a bigoted game warden (Zachary Scott)
lives on a remote stretch of land – the film was shot in Mexico but the
setting is clearly intended to be the American South – with his elderly
alcoholic assistant (who has just died when the story opens) and the
latter's sensual but naïve teenage grand-daughter (Key Meersman). This
situation seems to please Scott, as he suddenly realizes that the girl
is no longer a child – but their quiet life is unexpectedly turned
upside down with the arrival of a black musician from the mainland
(Bernie Hamilton), on the run after an older white woman accused him of
rape! Scott (whose character might very well represent the way his
beleaguered but optimistic farmer from Jean Renoir's THE SOUTHERNER
[1945] – which, incidentally had been adapted for the screen by the
blacklisted co-writer of both ROBINSON CRUSOE and THE YOUNG ONE, Hugo
Butler – would turn out under different circumstances!) is absent when
Hamilton lands on the island. The latter strikes up a friendship with
Meersman, while being embarrassed by her apparent lack of morals (which
stacks the sympathy cards in his favor...though, on butting heads with
Scott eventually, he loses no opportunity to address him as "white
trash")! A battle of wills between the two soon manifests itself: Scott
shoots holes in Hamilton's boat and then takes a pot shot at the man
himself; the latter turns up enraged at Scott's cabin and manages to
disarm him; the warden is thus forced to accept the black man into his
house, but still refuses to eat on the same table with him! Scott, meanwhile, continues to lust after Meersman – and, one night, he
forces himself upon her and they sleep together (a potentially
controversial sequence that the director handles in an admirably
sensitive manner); the very next day, a preacher (Bunuel regular
Claudio Brook) from the mainland comes to take the girl away even
though Scott had been making such arrangements himself. Meersman is so
innocent that she immediately confesses to the priest about her illicit
liaison, which obviously shocks him (though, in typical Bunuel fashion,
the latter Is himself a hypocrite who casually asks the girl to
overturn his mattress because the black man had previously slept on
it)! When Brook confronts Scott about the matter, the warden is willing
to marry the girl; the priest, however, has in mind another form of
compromise – knowing the malicious nature of the woman whom Hamilton is
supposed to have assaulted, he believes the musician to be innocent of
the crime. So, Brook asks Scott to let the black man go…though they
still have to contend with the bigoted boatman (the warden's contact
with the mainland) who will not think twice about executing Hamilton on
the spot! The intimate plot and swampy atmosphere are already compelling in
themselves – but the whole, then, is elevated by Bunuel's distinctive
handling (resulting in any number of irreverent touches along the way,
but also a few violent ones, that often have the additional effect of
enriching characterization). However, just as integral to the fabric of
the film, is the catchy traditional gospel tune "Sinner Man" – even if,
typically for Bunuel, it's only heard in the opening and closing
moments of the movie; for the record, the charismatic Hamilton also
indulges in a couple of jazz solos (to the girl's delight) during his
tenure on the island – one of which, however, is (in perhaps the film's
comic highlight) abruptly put to a literally explosive end by the
jealous Scott! Incidentally, THE YOUNG ONE proved to be the first of
just two films to feature the lovely Meersman and while I did get to
watch the other one – Damiano Damiani's ARTURO'S ISLAND (1962) – simply
because she was in it, the film itself was in no way as rewarding as
Bunuel's had been (and continues to be with each successive viewing).In fact, my previous three viewings of the film came via a slightly
fuzzy Italian TV screening in its original English language but
embedded with unremovable Italian subtitles. Therefore I'm thoroughly
grateful to Lionsgate for releasing THE YOUNG ONE on DVD as part of
their modest but very welcome 2-Disc "Luis Bunuel Collection" which
also incorporates arguably the director's most inconsequential (if
still not unentertaining) film, GRAN CASINO (1947). Incidentally, both
titles come accompanied by an Audio Commentary and the one for THE
YOUNG ONE is a joint and overly academic effort at analyzing the film's
themes and textures. But if this makes for a rather heavy-going
listening experience even for an avowed Bunuelian like myself, at least
one gets another opportunity to look at celebrated cinematographer
Gabriel Figueroa's sublime black-and-white images.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20089413/comments</url><from>from Netherlands</from><name>bennyraldak</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This truly is a masterpiece, lost in the wind of obscurity. As a big
Luis Bunuel fan I've seen almost all of his films - that is, except the
ones you just can't seem to find anywhere anymore. This is one of
those, and I finally found it. What a great and powerful picture. This
is Bunuel's second and last film in English; an American/Mexican
production mostly known as "The Young One".The entire film takes place on an almost deserted island; a place of
solitude that represents the deep south of America. A game warden named
'Miller' lives on this island with the teenage daughter of his recently
departed partner, a pretty girl named 'Evalyne'. Slowly 'Miller' is
starting to notice that young 'Evalyn' is not a child anymore, at least
in his mind. He finds himself very much attracted to her, and starts to
'act out' his forbidden but true desires. The plot thickens when a
black man - on the run for being accused of raping an older white woman
- enters the world of 'Miller' and 'Evalyn'. The old game warden turns
out to be a racist, and wants to kill 'Traver', the black man. However,
with young and innocent 'Evalyn' in the centre of the situation things
make a different turn, and 'Traver' starts to work for 'Miller', even
if he might still be a racist at heart. Then the plot thickens even
more when a preacher and another racist are joining in. The preacher
finds out there's sexual sin going on between 'Miller' and the young
innocent, and he decides to baptize her and confront 'Miller' with his
sins. Eventually he shows 'Miller' a way to redeem himself, by 'saving'
the girl and the black man.This film is as pure and human as they come. It takes us on a journey
to a place where we are confronted with themes like sin; sexual sin,
ethnic sin, and existential sin... religion, guilt, mercy, and
redemption. In short, all the famous Bunuel obsessions. Yet, this is
definitely not an average Bunuel piece. It's very realistic, pure and
extremely human. No impressive surrealistic cinematic tricks here. A
straight up story about the demons of everyday humanity in modern
times. And, I might add... one year prior to Kubrick's "Lolita", which
of course has obvious parallels.A forgotten masterpiece that's finally found and available again. A
cinefile's dream.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is a very daring film from famed director Luis Buñuel. While he's
famous for the films he made in Mexico and France, this is an
American-made film featuring American actors. Here he takes on two hot
topics for 1960--racism and pedophilia! While some films from Hollywood
were tackling racism, most were very sanitized and featured black
actors who were non-threatening--very well-spoken and easy to like.
Here, however, the black man is darn angry--something you just didn't
see back in films in 1960. As far as pedophilia goes, you never really
heard it discussed in films--and the movie was far ahead of its time.The film begins with a black guy (Bernie Hamilton) washing up on the
shore of an island in the American Southeast. Apparently he'd been
accused of raping a white woman and had escaped on the small boat to
avoid a lynch mob. It turns out the island is a private hunting
preserve and the white trash game warden (Zachary Scott) is off the
island on business. The only other resident is a young girl (about age
12) whose grandfather (and only guardian) just died--who exactly the
old man was and how they came to be there is never discussed but you
know that the girl has never been off the island and is ignorant of the
world. She finds the man and helps him--giving him food and treating
him with respect--presumably because she never learned to hate black
people.When Scott returns, he tries to kill Hamilton--and it's not even
because of the rumor that he raped a woman. He thinks Hamilton has
stolen some items...plus in Scott's mind, it's okay just to shoot any
old trespasser! But, it turns out Scott is much worse than this--as he
soon begins molesting the girl. As for her, she's so sheltered and
backward she doesn't quite understand what's happening.There is a lot more that happens after this--most of which is excellent
and very compelling. The only negative is the character of the
preacher, as Buñuel had a rather pathological hatred of religion. Even
though this minister is probably the most likable of any holy man in a
Luis Buñuel film, he is totally square and rigid in his
thinking--moralistic and a bit dumb. But, he still is basically a very
good man (a rarity in these films). His character was simply too
one-dimensional--as no preacher is THAT oblivious! Yes, we know the
director hated priests and the like, but this did appear to hinder the
film's believability--which is a shame, as it's a darn fine film and
very, very, very realistic otherwise. And, because it is so well-made
and daring, I still strongly recommend you see it, as it's not like
anything being made in this country at the time. While some felt this
was a lesser film by the director, I actually think it's among his most
powerful and best movies. I loved the raw language (back in 1960 and
even today it's really tough stuff) and parallel about the white man
who could easily excuse pedophilia but couldn't wait to kill the black
man!! Wow...gritty.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20117949/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>Ilpo Hirvonen</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Luis Buñuel who was born in Spain was very well known for his
surrealism, some have seen him as the father of it - An Andalusian Dog
(1929). He made few English language films and The Young One (White
Trash) is one of them. It was filmed in Mexico but takes place in the
southern states of the US. If one knows the main subjects of the film,
religion and racism, the idea of The Young One might not seem so
original. Its plot reminds me a little of Stanley Kramer's The Defiant
Ones (1958). But The Young One is a great example how Bunuel is able to
make something intense and personal from a conventional subject.The Young One starts when a black man, Traver, suspected from a rape,
escapes and runs into a young girl, Ewie (Evalyn). When Ewie takes
Traver back to the place she lives in, Traver meets Miller, a man Ewie
has been living with since her father died. Miller can't stand black
people and he wants to kill Traver for stealing his gun, which Traver
actually bought. When a priest comes to the place, Miller has to decide
whether to let Traver go or to give him to the mob. To look good or bad
in the girl's eyes. As the story goes on we start to see what is hidden
under Miller.The film is very enjoyable to watch, it is written very well and the
plot is interesting. Even in the beginning one will be hooked, because
of how intense it is. The hungry outlaw Traver runs to the lake - grabs
a lobster and eats it. The young Ewie stabs on a spider and collects
honey from bee hives. This strong sensuality tunes a certain intensity
for the film, which is reinforced by the absence of musical score.The Young One makes good observations on racism but basically brings
nothing new to one who has seen The Defiant Ones, but it not the
purpose of the film. Even that it's basic themes are racism and
religion, The Young One goes deeper on morality and youth. Luis
Bunuel's movie is a comical survey of these themes, racism and
religion, the coexistence of them. Ewie goes to the shower without
caring less about the fact that it might awake awkward urges in Traver.
Miller brings high heel shoes for Ewie from the town, in which Ewie
doesn't feel comfortable at all. Her first experiences of sexuality and
adulthood are clumsy. In the same way Bunuel describes Ewie's first
experience with religion. Usually films that "bash" religions, might go
over the top and showing how amazed people are when they hear of it.
But the baptism seems much more suspicious, in Bunuel's eyes, than the
act caused by Miller's urges.A fine film about racism, it also describes youth and religion in a
brilliant way. It's a poetic film, the girl and the obsessive
sensuality, the urge towards the woman. Bunuel leaves the end open,
will it be a tragedy or a comedy? The audience gets to decide that. The
Young One is a tragical, but also a comical survey of religion and
racism, it achieves a new level of cinematic poetry.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur20117949/comments</url><from>from Finland</from><name>Ilpo Hirvonen</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Luis Buñuel who was born in Spain was very well known for his
surrealism, some have seen him as the father of it - An Andalusian Dog
(1929). He made few English language films and The Young One (White
Trash) is one of them. It was filmed in Mexico but takes place in the
southern states of the US. If one knows the main subjects of the film,
religion and racism, the idea of The Young One might not seem so
original. Its plot reminds me a little of Stanley Kramer's The Defiant
Ones (1958). But The Young One is a great example how Bunuel is able to
make something intense and personal from a conventional subject.The Young One starts when a black man, Traver, suspected from a rape,
escapes and runs into a young girl, Ewie (Evalyn). When Ewie takes
Traver back to the place she lives in, Traver meets Miller, a man Ewie
has been living with since her father died. Miller can't stand black
people and he wants to kill Traver for stealing his gun, which Traver
actually bought. When a priest comes to the place, Miller has to decide
whether to let Traver go or to give him to the mob. To look good or bad
in the girl's eyes. As the story goes on we start to see what is hidden
under Miller.The film is very enjoyable to watch, it is written very well and the
plot is interesting. Even in the beginning one will be hooked, because
of how intense it is. The hungry outlaw Traver runs to the lake - grabs
a lobster and eats it. The young Ewie stabs on a spider and collects
honey from bee hives. This strong sensuality tunes a certain intensity
for the film, which is reinforced by the absence of musical score.The Young One makes good observations on racism but basically brings
nothing new to one who has seen The Defiant Ones, but it not the
purpose of the film. Even that it's basic themes are racism and
religion, The Young One goes deeper on morality and youth. Luis
Bunuel's movie is a comical survey of these themes, racism and
religion, the coexistence of them. Ewie goes to the shower without
caring less about the fact that it might awake awkward urges in Traver.
Miller brings high heel shoes for Ewie from the town, in which Ewie
doesn't feel comfortable at all. Her first experiences of sexuality and
adulthood are clumsy. In the same way Bunuel describes Ewie's first
experience with religion. Usually films that "bash" religions, might go
over the top and showing how amazed people are when they hear of it.
But the baptism seems much more suspicious, in Bunuel's eyes, than the
act caused by Miller's urges.A fine film about racism, it also describes youth and religion in a
brilliant way. It's a poetic film, the girl and the obsessive
sensuality, the urge towards the woman. Bunuel leaves the end open,
will it be a tragedy or a comedy? The audience gets to decide that. The
Young One is a tragical, but also a comical survey of religion and
racism, it achieves a new level of cinematic poetry.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/fernando-f-croce/</url><url>http://www.cinepassion.org/Reviews/y/YoungOne.html /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1887019</url><name>Fernando F. Croce</name><from>CinePassion</from></reviewer><comment>No other Buñuel picture boasts a more tangible, zestful feel for nature </comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/youngone.htm /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1672969</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>A rarely seen provocative racially and Lolita-like themed drama.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jeffrey-m-anderson/</url><url>http://www.combustiblecelluloid.com/classic/youngone.shtml /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1668711</url><name>Jeffrey M. Anderson</name><from>Combustible Celluloid</from></reviewer><comment>It gets under the skin of these characters, but offers little relief.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/michael-scheinfeld/</url><url>http://online.tvguide.com/newsearch/detail.aspx?tvobjectid=110171&amp;more=ucmoviereview /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1535682</url><name>Michael Scheinfeld</name><from>TV Guide's Movie Guide</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>Zachary Scott and Bernie Hamilton star as deadly adversaries on an island hell in Luis Bunuel's The Young One, a rarely shown English-language gem about racism and pedophilia.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/ed-gonzalez/</url><url>http://www.slantmagazine.com/film/film_review.asp?ID=1916 /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1452953</url><name>Ed Gonzalez</name><from>Slant Magazine</from></reviewer><rating>
4/4
					</rating><comment>Poets have said that eyes are the windows to the soul, but Luis Buñuel believed that our legs and feet revealed more about us than any other parts of our bodies.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-a-nesbit/</url><url>http://oldschoolreviews.com/rev_60/young_one.htm /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1235210</url><name>John A. Nesbit</name><from>Old School Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>provokes more discussions about life's existential problems than more conventionally moralistic filmmakers</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/jonathan-rosenbaum/</url><url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/capsules/9640_YOUNG_ONE.html /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=93845</url><name>Jonathan Rosenbaum</name><from>Chicago Reader</from></reviewer><comment>[The film] is full of poetic asides and unexpected developments, revealing Bunuel's dark, philosophical wit at its most personal.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>/m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1421362</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.channel4.com/film/reviews/film.jsp?id=110487 /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=1148065</url><from>Film4</from></reviewer><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/marjorie-baumgarten/</url><url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gbase/Guides/Film?Film=oid%3A139059 /m/young_one/comments.php?reviewid=850568</url><name>Marjorie Baumgarten</name><from>Austin Chronicle</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>