<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Le testament d'Orphée, ou ne me demandez pas pourquoi!</original_title><imdb_rating>7.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>France</country><director>Jean Cocteau</director><producer>Cinédis</producer><producer>Les Editions Cinégraphiques</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Fantasy</genre><synopsis>
The Poet looks back over his life and work, recalling his inspirations and obsessions.
</synopsis><actor>Jean Cocteau</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0257119/comments</url><from>from Sydney</from><name>Alph-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Jean Cocteau's final filmic flight of fantasy is very special indeed.Adopting the guise of a poet 'unstuck in time', Cocteau ranges over his life
in the world of poetry. It's a phantasmorgorical whirl of imagery, with plenty
of humour, pathos and an enormous, transcendent sense of wonder.  There's also
a trial sequence where the characters from his earlier success 'Orphee' try
him for bringing them into existence !Some of Cocteau famous friends feature in brief cameos. Look out for Picasso
and Bardot.You don't have to be a Cocteau fan to enjoy this movie. All you need is an
interest in the nature of creativity and an enjoyment of poetry, symbolic
art, and the wonderfully cinematic music of Georges Auric, who scored all
Cocteau's major films.   
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0524077/comments</url><from>from Aguascalientes, México</from><name>Alejandro Dávila (entreacto@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

Cocteau, as an authentic reinassance man, shown the world how poetry could
be inside everything. In this film, a real testament Cocteau delivers us
his
whole original world, that one that he constructed from life experiences.
His unique craft never needed big budgets, Cocteau creates the magic taking
a flower and primary cinema f/x. Thats all, what you see on the screen is
just poetry. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur13283282/comments</url><from>from Chinatown, California</from><name>Trent Bolden</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
French national treasure Jean Cocteau's last film is as personal and
private as it's title suggest. Le Testament d'Orphee is a fond farewell
to cinema with it's free-flowing, spirited collection of images and
scenes that includes characters from Cocteau's past films and personal
friends. One would hardly imagine a cinematic poet like Jean Cocteau
would be so crass as to make something like a mere sequel to his
acclaimed Orpheus/Orphee (1950). And instead what Cocteau does is to
give us perhaps cinema's first meta-film. The film itself is an
autobiographical fantasia of his whole life. Playing various versions
of himself, Cocteau glides through the film as a time traveler in
search of his place in the universe. He called it an active poem.The film was shot on location at Les Baux in the South of France, a
landscape whose rough limestone canyons appealed to Cocteau even more
than Greece. Francine Weinweller and the main crew put up at that
gourmet's mecca, the Hostellerie de la Baumaniere. Francine had a
costume part in the film as La Dame qui s'est trompe d'epoque. All the
icons out of Cocteau's past were woven into the visual testament -
mirrors, horses, flowers, tapestries, and many of his friends - Dermit,
Marais, Yul Brynner, Picasso and his wife, among others, appeared.Unfortunately for Cocteau, public and critics, weaned on the literature
of commitment popularized by Sartre and Camus, turned their backs on Le
Testament d'Orphee, finding it a self-serving celluloid relic, oddly
out of step with the times. One voice, however, and an important one,
praised the film. Young Francois Truffaut, winner of a large prize for
his film Les Quatre Cents Coups, had turned the money over to Cocteau
to help finance Le Testament. Truffaut liked the finished product,
which he considered a remake, thirty years later, of Le Sang d'un
Poete. Truffaut was not alone in seeing Cocteau, judged by his previous
films, as one of the main precursors of New Wave filmmakers.Le Testament d'Orphee is a misunderstood masterpiece. Brilliant!!!!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3013091/comments</url><from/><name>luminous_luciano</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
While clearly not the first in its eclectic genre, this classic is
definitely a great round-up of all that is surreal - all that the
''mechanics'' of both surrealism as those of dream can be deemed to be
all about... Said mechanics fascinated Cocteau, to the point that he
had to make this, his final film, a very original ''sequel'' of sorts
to his classic ORPHÉE. If only all sequels since had been so original!The cameos are indeed plentiful as also unexpected; many great stars of
1959 show up, from all fields as all continents! In this, the movie has
a time capsule quality that only adds to its surrealness...Most amazing though is the cameo that is not and could have been;
Chaplin, who admired Cocteau -and it was mutual- through the language
barrier and everything else that separated them... They had met on a
cruise and greeted each other as brothers, though unable to exchange a
single word almost... Surely he would have accepted to don the clothes
of the Tramp one more time for this unique film... What a surreal
addition to an already singular film it would have been! Although, on
that cruise, through interpreters, Chaplin had confided that he was sad
that he had become rich while playing a poor man... Cocteau admired him
all the more for that...Throughout "Le Testament d'Orphée", the film-goer has the impression of
walking through someone else's dream - the director's dream. It is the
goal of every film director to have his or her audience view things as
if through the director's own eyes - well, I don't think anyone has
ever succeeded quite like Cocteau did in this one, his cinematographic
swan song as it was as well...Le Testament d'Orphée is thus highly recommended for so many reasons;
Bergman fans as well as those left unimpressed somehow by "Un Chien
Andalou", because it was too short; those few will undoubtedly
appreciate the long treatment given to this by the master, Jean
Cocteau...!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"The Testament of Orpheus" is the last film by Jean Cocteau, and even
if it isn't as mind blowing as either "Orpheus" or "Beauty and the
Beast", its still a captivating and dreamlike work of art. Jean Cocteau
plays himself, "The Poet", who wanders into a bizarre landscape (not
unlike that in "Orpheus") inhabited by various creations of his who
blame him for their misfortunes. While if most other artists attempted
to make a film like this, it would come off as showy egotism, Cocteau
manages to make it feel as anything but. He raises some interesting
questions about the nature of art and the importance of the artist to
modern society. Also, the film is remarkably original, possibly the
first true "meta-movie" ever made.On a technical level, this is exquisite as well. Cocteau's direction is
wonderfully magical and surreal. His special effects and camera tricks
are always a highlight of his work. Hes obsessed with presenting many
simplistic tricks that are easy to figure out but carry a true sense of
otherworldly beauty. Even if one isn't interested in Cocteau's
intellectual quest, they'll be captivated by the visuals themselves.
The addition of several entertaining cameos (including Yul Brunner and
Pablo Picasso) is only the icing on the cake. Cocteau creates surreal
art films that are never boring, which is quite rare. (8/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1837276/comments</url><from>from India</from><name>Mukil Li</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Although the elements involved in the last part of the trilogy (of course
it's a trilogy!) are same, the movie is brilliant in the way it deal and
approaches with a poet's final years. I loved the self-reference to the
earlier versions and to Jean cocteau himself. The film touches A film inside
a film, a stage inside a stage, a life inside a life, a body inside a body
and ofcourse a world inside a world. This is a "timeless" classic. No pun
intended. This just my first viewing, I intend to see it again and again.
One interesting thing (a speculation) is the BULLET from the future world. I
wonder whether James cameroon got inspired from this idea to come up with
"The Terminator". Personally, I was always interested by the idea of NO TIME. This movie
touches the possible cyclic nature of the time and sometime it even goes
even further suggesting that -- ALL TIMES reside within ONE or NONE -- Well
we're not supposed to understand it :) I loved the dig at
intellectuals.I would recommend this movie to all surrealist and anybody who has the
eternal question -- WHY?! This movie is not an answer nor it asks question.
Just OBEY the natural laws and see the movie :)9/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0686544/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>mphilipm</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
While I had surely seen the second film in Cocteau's Orpheus trilogy if
not the first as well, I suspect I was in no position to appreciate any
of what Cocteau accomplished. Now I'm about the same age he was when he
did the Testament. I remember the time period for the second and third
pictures, having grown up in it. But how all three of these films
really transcend time as Cocteau is trying to show you works of art
should! I had to rely on the subtitles for the sense of the lines but
it was no matter. I don't remember anything else like these films. They
are political to the extent they lobby for the poet's point of view.
And in spite of the black and white and old prints their effect is most
striking. Orpheus Descending and Testament sometimes look like the
inspiration for Rebel Without a Cause. And Testament has some pithy
comments on modern technology and the short comings of air travel that
seem funnier and more relevant today. And toward the end of Testament,
having the red blood and the red hibiscus in this black and white
movie--how many times has that been imitated by computer technology?
But it is what the poet saw then, not what technology makes commonplace
and commercial today.On the discs for Blood of the Poet and Testament are two separate bonus
features, documentaries of Cocteau in fading Technicolor--but oh how
interesting they are as well. At some point Cocteau says it was Picasso
who taught them all to see. But what a treasure trove of talent Paris
produced in the first half of the twentieth century. I hope this kind
of sharing of artistic discovery can take place on the internet. Maybe
it is already happening and I just don't know it. But I do know people
who care for serious--but not heavy and sometimes witty--artistic
expression, let alone movies, should see all three of these movies and
the docs which accompany them.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15780544/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name> (richard@berrong.fr)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
When this movie starts out, you will find yourself - if you are old
enough - feeling that you have somehow been transported back in time to
the 1950s and some very serious coffee house (NOT Starbucks) where, on
Friday nights, they showed "experimental" films (not movies, of course,
but films). The surrealist tricks that had been innovative 30 years
before in "The Blood of the Poet" are still there, with the people and
objects that suddenly disappear or appear and the surreal movement.
There is still the clearly enunciated and theatrical speech. By the
1960s, this could be seen as kitsch.But there is still, fairly often, a certain imaginative touch that
comes off as real poetry. Not as much as in "Beauty and the Beast",
certainly, to which this is much inferior. But enough to justify giving
it a try.And then there is the cameo appearance by Yul Brenner, who actually
speaks very good French. Brenner was a big star at the time; how
Cocteau convinced him to appear in this I will never know.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16138948/comments</url><from>from France</from><name>depot-5</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This kind of movie is very difficult to rate. It can't compete with any
IMDb's top 250 movies. No Godfather, no Dark Vador, no Indiana Jones.
Not a feelgood movie, not a buddy movie... not any f... blockbuster
movie. Well. Let's face it : not anybody's movie. It's just a f... masterpiece
about Poetry. That's why it's not ranked, but still pretty well rated
for such an old movie. Films like this don't exist anymore. Maybe poets
like this don't exist anymore. Maybe Cocteau's Beauty and the Beast is
easier, and a better choice to start with Cocteau's Film works, but I
think this one is mesmerizing. Also, Cocteau's "Le Sang d'un Poete"
from 1930 is maybe a great movie for surrealist films fans. But Le
Testament dOrphee is Cocteau's last effort and for me it sums up and
benefits all. A testament and a masterpiece.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4061961/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>Eumenides_0</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Jean Cocteau's last movie is a lovely parade of fascinating images,
concepts and characters. Playing the The Poet, his alter ego, Cocteau
reflects about his work as a filmmaker, visual artist and poet. In a
self-reflexive move, he references his previous movie, Orpheus, and
openly addresses the creation of cinema. We're given a window into
which we can look at Cocteau's inspiration and creativity. The sets are
clearly sets and the characters are described as no more than
inventions by him. This is meta-cinema, before Dogville, Day for Night,
Persona and Otto e Mezzo.It's also a visual feast of fantasy. Cocteau had a surrealist streak
and fills this movie with images that could belong in anyone's dreams:
people dressed up as horses, which is not as silly as it sounds;
cadaverous masks; a clever use of reverse motion to show time running
backwards, which I presume is how the filmmaker shot the reconstruction
of a flower he had just torn to pieces.Almost fifty years old, The Testament of Orpheus still looks modern and
remains challenging. There are things in this movie that contemporary
cinema doesn't use anymore, which is a pity; for rather than being
old-fashioned, this movie still has a lot of teach to young filmmakers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4061961/comments</url><from>from Portugal</from><name>Eumenides_0</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Jean Cocteau's last movie is a lovely parade of fascinating images,
concepts and characters. Playing the The Poet, his alter ego, Cocteau
reflects about his work as a filmmaker, visual artist and poet. In a
self-reflexive move, he references his previous movie, Orpheus, and
openly addresses the creation of cinema. We're given a window into
which we can look at Cocteau's inspiration and creativity. The sets are
clearly sets and the characters are described as no more than
inventions by him. This is meta-cinema, before Dogville, Day for Night,
Persona and Otto e Mezzo.It's also a visual feast of fantasy. Cocteau had a surrealist streak
and fills this movie with images that could belong in anyone's dreams:
people dressed up as horses, which is not as silly as it sounds;
cadaverous masks; a clever use of reverse motion to show time running
backwards, which I presume is how the filmmaker shot the reconstruction
of a flower he had just torn to pieces.Almost fifty years old, The Testament of Orpheus still looks modern and
remains challenging. There are things in this movie that contemporary
cinema doesn't use anymore, which is a pity; for rather than being
old-fashioned, this movie still has a lot of teach to young filmmakers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>