<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Facts of Life</original_title><alt_title>Voulez-vous pêcher avec moi?</alt_title><imdb_rating>6.4</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Melvin Frank</director><producer>HLP</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
Two romantic couples are each married to different people! They really DO love each other. At the beginning Kitty thinks Larry is un-funny...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Bob Hope</actor><actor>Lucille Ball</actor><actor>Ruth Hussey</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1406078/comments</url><from>from New York</from><name>jotix100</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This surprising film was shown on TCM recently. Not having seen it, and
not having other choice, we decided to take a look, and quite frankly,
it was a surprise. The film, directed by Melvin Frank and co-written
with his partner, Norman Panama, shows two stars that endeared
themselves to the American public at their best.The story is just a pretext and a vehicle for the stars. The plot kept
reminding us of "A Guide for the Married Man", but that's all the
comparison, because one has nothing to do with the other. In fact, this
is a film made in 1960 when nothing too risky would be tackled for the
screen, yet, it presents two straying adults who suddenly find an
attraction where dislike existed before.Bob Hope was the surprise in the movie. He doesn't have a chance for
uttering his one liners, as the script doesn't allow it. It was one of
the best films in which he appeared, in our humble opinion. Lucille
Ball was an excellent comedienne, and she shows it on this film.The interesting supporting cast makes the best with the material they
were given to play. The excellent Ruth Hussey is seen as Bob Hope's
wife. Don DeFore, plays Lucille's husband. Louis Nye is also seen in
the film.The film is light and will charm anyone wanting to spend some time in
the company of some of America's best comic talent of the past.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2595862/comments</url><from>from Houston</from><name>LarryBrownHouston</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This movie surprised me. I really enjoyed it. Lucy is stunning as a
glamor star. She gets the soft focus and lighting, the glamor hair and
makeup, but the showstopper is the glamor wardrobe. I've never seen her
look more beautiful.I did not know that Lucy had made it so far in her movie career as to
be able to star as a glamor girl, opposite Bob Hope yet. Another notch
on the resume of this fascinating woman.My wife and I had just been discussing Lucy's talents as a straight
actress and by coincidence this movie came on the next day. I had the
opinion that Lucy was best in comedy and was not quite right in a
straight role. This movie proved me wrong on that! She is convincing
and when she kissed Bob I really believed it.Bob is also great. His comedy style here is more subtle than usual,
playing funny bits off in a straight style without the usual hamming.
The bit with the hankie made me belly laugh.The subject matter of this movie is similar to other movies of the
early 60s as the sexual revolution was just starting...all clean and
above board on the surface, yet doing their best to titillate us with
sexual situations and innuendo. As I said in my review of Bob's "I'll
Take Sweden," I find this juvenile and boring. There's no shock value
left by now, so it falls flat. However, this movie tackles more serious
subjects than simply titillating sex, namely the subjects of
infidelity, marriage, and marital boredom. That is more interesting and
even in 2005 I found the subject matter moving and thought-provoking.The script is tight and witty, with good dialog. The plot is also more
or less water tight with plausible motivations.Good stuff....worth watching.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1939043/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>oldmotem</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Lucy and Bob in a 1960 romantic, satiric comedy. What more could you
want?This is very aware for its time and has some wonderful period scenes.
Hope and Ball seem to have very complementary comedy styles which play
extremely well off each other.This movie came out way back in 1960, yet Bob Hope mentions problems
raising kids in the electronic age. How forward looking.The black and white format takes nothing away from this movie,
including the scenes of Acapulco when they're alone together. All in all, an extremely enjoyable movie. I like Lucy much better in
this style than her slapstick routine, although she's great in that
too. Give this one a look sometime, it's worth it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8042382/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>Isaac5855</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
One of their later screen teamings, THE FACTS OF LIFE was a 1960
comedy, rather adult for its time, where Bob and Lucy play two friends,
married to others, who usually participate in a group vacation together
and through some freak circumstances , end up on the vacation alone
this year and grow so close they actually drift into an affair and
consider leaving their spouses. I have to admit that this movie was
surprising to me when I first saw it a few months ago, so I'm sure it
raised a few eyebrows in the 1960's...infidelity was most likely a bold
subject for a movie comedy and I doubt if it was something Bob or Lucy
had done prior to this. but for this day and age, this was a very adult
movie comedy that probably didn't do the business it deserved in 1960
because of its "contorversial" storyline. Though it would hardly be
considered controversial today, this film was probably quite the
departure for its stars and as a curio of cinema history, it is
definitely worth a look.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1728252/comments</url><from>from Chicago, IL</from><name>Fad King</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Bob Hope and Lucille Ball team up very nicely here as each steps away from
their well-known screen personas to play a suburban everyman and everywoman
who unexpectedly fall for each other, despite the complication of being
married to other people. The comedy includes some surprisingly tart satire
on the claustrophobic lifestyles of the 50's suburban/country club/den
mother families that we all know so well from "Leave it to Beaver," etc.
But
the big laughs come as the two sneak around town to try to be alone
together. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3280905/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>theowinthrop</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
After Bob Hope made THAT CERTAIN FEELING the general trend of his films
as far as being worthy of the talent he had and of the best of his work
was gone. In the future would be films like CANCEL MY RESERVATION.
There was one more film with Bing and Dorothy Lamour, THE ROAD TO HONG
KONG, but even that film was below par for the series (one wonders what
the proposed final "Road" film - THE ROAD TO TOMORROW - would have been
like). There was, however, this film...again not quite the film with
Hope that one expected, but sturdy because of the support he shared
with his leading lady, Lucille Ball.THE FACTS OF LIFE is the story of two people who share a midlife
crisis. Hope is married to Ruth Hussey and Ball is married to Don
DeFore. Both have children, and both seem reasonably well settled in
their marriages (Ball's sole reason for complaining about DeFore is his
gambling habits). Both couples are in the upper middle class of 1960
suburban America, belonging to the local country club, and going on
shared vacations with their best friends. A trip is planned to Acupulco
but Hussey stays home to take care of her ailing son, and DeFore is
forced by his boss to take over operations of the San Francisco office
after the person there is injured in a car accident. So Hope and Ball
travel with Philip Ober and his wife to Mexico. But the latter two get
what appears to be Montezuma's Revenge, and Hope and Ball are thrown
together to try to salvage the vacation. Although they have
occasionally been caustic about each other, they find they really get
along quite nicely. In fact, after Ball lands a huge Marlin fish with
Hope's assistance, and go touring the town, they find they really like
each other. And a small affair begins.What follows is Hope and Ball trying to keep their raging/aging
hormones in check, and yet still occasionally get together. This
includes two funny sequences at a drive-in theater, and later Hope
desperately trying to remember which roadside motel he left Ball in
after a dinner dance. Finally they decide to take advantage of the
Christmas holidays to make some plans. Will Ball leave DeFore for Hope,
or will they find they can't shake responsibilities that come from
being middle aged?Hope is not totally subdued in this film. At the start he actually is
playing a scene in a familiar role: he is the master of ceremonies at a
country club dinner. His comments regarding winning sportsman Louis Nye
are sharp ones. So are his attempts to speed a cub scout meeting he has
to chair (he wants to get together with Ball) but he is forced to
listen to one of the scouts read a long, dull report about smoke
signals. Ball is also good, particularly towards the end when she
starts lecturing Hope about how much better DeFore is as a mechanic.
The rest of the cast is good, DeFore dismissing his gambling habit (he
plays craps downstairs during the opening awards dinner, and thinks
nothing about losing $200.00). Nye is fun as a philandering husband
with a trusting, nitwit wife. On the whole the film is quite adult in
its point of view, and may be the last really good film that Hope made
in his career in movies.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0999827/comments</url><from>from Salinas, Ca</from><name>doghouse-8</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>

I watched this movie primarily because it was nominated for Best
Screenplay,
and in that regard, I was not disappointed.  There are several funny scenes
and some pretty witty dialogue, but overall this movie rates about 6/10.
It's a little too long and some of the plot points are pretty contrived,
but
Bob and Lucy have good chemistry, which makes up for the few weak points in
this film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1464358/comments</url><from>from NY, NY</from><name>David (Handlinghandel)</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
In some ways, this is like an "I Love Lucy" show with cursing, lots of
drinking, and centering on adultery. Ball and Hope work well together.The plot begins inauspiciously: We see Hope doing a comedy gig as MC at
a local event. We hear Ball's thoughts about how crass and unfunny he
is. (And he -- this character, not Hope himself -- is.) Because of
circumstances that throw them together, however, they are very soon
sexually and romantically involved with each other.If one can get past this, which I could, the movie is sophisticated
(well, for its time) and often funny. It was probably a courageous move
for both of them to step into such a risqué plot.The supporting cast is good. Ruth Hussey plays Hope's wife. As always,
she is good. But seeing her is sad: Though she looks fine, her voice
had aged badly. Irene Dunne's did too. Though I am crazy about Dunne,
her last couple movies are painful for this reason. Hussey sounds like
an elderly woman, which she really was not. Ball's voice had gone the
opposite direction: She speaks almost in the basso profondo of her
later television series.If this turns up, give it a try. It's surpassingly good.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11706796/comments</url><from>from Texas, United States</from><name>charlotte34-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
This is a pretty good movie, as far as situation comedies go. Very
typical of the movies Hope was making at that time. Pepole who have
only seen the Hope and Crosby Road shows think Hops did only one-liner
jokes, actually more of his movies were in the vein of this one. I
watched all these movies when they came out in the theaters. I started
watching Ball and Hope in movies when I was 8 years old, and they were
young people. Mostly, I get a kick out of reading the reader comments.
Mature for it's time, Advanced for movies made in that era etc. This
was NOT considered a racy movie for the times. There were many with a
much more " like today's movies" story line and script. The bedroom
farce movies were being made and shown to general public audiences i
the 40, and take a look at some of the movies made in the late 20s and
30s, before censorship stepped in. They didn't use swear words and the
language they use today in movies in the 30s, but those people made
some really "broad minded?" movies then. This was just a run of the
mill, cutest movie of the times. If you liked Hope in this, you will
also like, That Certain Feeling-- 1956-- Bob Hope and Eva Maire Saint
The Iron Pettycoat---- 1956-- Bob Hope and Katherine Hepburn I'll Take
Sweden------ 1965-- Bob Hope, Dina merrill You don't want to over look
Bob Hope in Beau James--- 1957. Tis is the story of the flamboyant
mayor of New York City.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3837125/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn, NY</from><name>pvbklyn</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I was surprised by this film and the quality of work by its two stars.
We always think of Lucy as goofy or screwy and Hope either swinging a
golf club or playing wingman for Bing Crosby. Billed as a romantic
comedy, Hope and Ball aim for the funny bone. But there are some
serious adult issues raised. This tasty confection, made in 1960, I
think is a lot of fun (though it could have been better paced and the
contrivances are a bit much) and it has two terrific old pros at work
in roles that you just wouldn't expect them to be in. Lucy looked
pretty good when she got all dolled up. And Hope is ageless as ever. I
thought they had some chemistry between them. Also includes Ruth
Hussey, Louie Nye and Dom DeFore (Ozzie and Harriet's neighbor).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3837125/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn, NY</from><name>pvbklyn</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I was surprised by this film and the quality of work by its two stars.
We always think of Lucy as goofy or screwy and Hope either swinging a
golf club or playing wingman for Bing Crosby. Billed as a romantic
comedy, Hope and Ball aim for the funny bone. But there are some
serious adult issues raised. This tasty confection, made in 1960, I
think is a lot of fun (though it could have been better paced and the
contrivances are a bit much) and it has two terrific old pros at work
in roles that you just wouldn't expect them to be in. Lucy looked
pretty good when she got all dolled up. And Hope is ageless as ever. I
thought they had some chemistry between them. Also includes Ruth
Hussey, Louie Nye and Dom DeFore (Ozzie and Harriet's neighbor).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3837125/comments</url><from>from Brooklyn, NY</from><name>pvbklyn</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/factsoflife.htm /m/facts_of_life/comments.php?reviewid=1855914</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B-
					</rating><comment>A mild satire on an adulterous affair between bored suburbanites.</comment></review></movie>