<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Beatniks</original_title><imdb_rating>1.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Paul Frees</director><producer>Glenville</producer><genre>Crime</genre><synopsis>
A young singer's chance at fame is threatened by his hoodlum pals.
</synopsis><actor>Tony Travis</actor><actor>Karen Kadler</actor><actor>Peter Breck</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3100038/comments</url><from>from Chambana</from><name>kilgore2345 (kilgore2345@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
This is my largest complaint; no Beatnik culture, no snapping fingers
and performance poetry, marijuana, not even the stereotypical black
clothes and sunglasses -- how can you get that part wrong? Instead the
"Beatniks" are mostly your typical 50s squares and range to a
geek-greaser (Mooney) and the lone woman in the group, think of a
"Grease" Frenchy-Rizzo mix.Since, the majority of the plot of this movie revolves around Eddie's
musical ability the audience gets plenty of solo performances. The
music is fine for a low budget movie like "Beatniks", nothing you will
remember past the end credits. Again, even when Eddie was a "Beatnik"
he wasn't singing Beatnik music, more like Mel Torme-like crooning.Other glaring mistakes in this movie is the continuity (see the GOOFS
section) and the character of Moon is just ridiculous, with a catch
phrase that will live on forever (I'm gonna MOON ya'!). The Eddie
character is a little annoying in his inconsistency -- is he a goon
with a heart of gold or just a jerk? All in all this is a very, very
bad movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Filmed for $2.67, this routine, rather predictable film is only good
for a few unintentional laughs. Among the least of its many problems is
that nothing whatsoever having to do with beatniks ever appears in the
movie! The story concerns a group of troublemakers who don masks and
rob the same store over and over in order to gain spending money. They
then head to the coffee shop run by one of their girlfriend's mother
and dance to the tunes on the juke box. One day, Travis is singing
along with an instrumental number and is discovered by record producer
Delaney who is trapped at the coffee shop with car trouble and is
hanging on the pay phone, waiting for help. Instantaneously, Travis
zips to the big city where he appears on a TV show, then, after making
a huge splash, is set up the next evening to record his first album!
Unfortunately, he's dragged along his entourage of Breck, Edwards,
Wells and Kadler who proceed to trash his hotel room, coerce him into
staying out late and generally wreck his chances at success. More drama
unfolds as Travis attempts to rectify his and his gang's wrongdoings
and make a go of his potential new life as a singing star. Travis is an
attractive young man and ought to have had a slightly better career
than he wound up with. His lip-synching to the songs is abominable,
though. He obviously has no idea what he's doing. (The vocals he's
singing to, though, are surprisingly good!) Kadler plays his girlfriend
and is a dead-ringer for Ava Gardner, though lacking Gardner's charisma
and talent as a performer. Edwards (who was in his mid-forties at the
time of filming!) and Wells don't have a lot to do, but do try to come
up with ways to pass the time (check out Wells attempting to recreate,
in the mirror, a hairstyle on a magazine cover he's holding!) Delaney
is all right at times, but doesn't appear to be well and, in fact, died
before the film's release! Playing his secretary and the woman who
steals Travis' heart is Terry. She gives a reasonable performance, but
has distracting blew eyes. That is to say that one blew one way and one
blew another! Careening though the film in a reprehensibly bad
performance of hellacious ham is Breck. It's amazing that he ever
worked again after this unbelievably rotten piece of indulgent,
unappealing "acting". (Amazingly, he went on to craft the highly
likable character of Nick on "The Big Valley" a few years after this.)
One major supporting role (unbilled) is the boom mike, which looms into
view with regularity. It's shabbily directed by voice-over artist Frees
and he cast the film with virtually all fellow voice-over performers.
It's clear why most of them stayed off-camera through the bulk of their
careers! The camera-work is often pitiful with uncomfortable framing
and close-ups which almost get the actors' entire faces in the frame.
It's got a stale story, a bad script, mediocre acting and uncreative
direction. The only thing it's really good for is as a curio to poke
fun at, which the MST3K guys did gleefully. Viewers may be quite
surprised to find out that Edwards supplied the voice of Thumper in
Walt Disney's "Bambi" (not to mention that Wentworth, playing Kadler's
mom, was Madam Mim in "The Sword in the Stone".)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0398094/comments</url><from>from Edmonton, Ab.</from><name>mark czuba (gspotbuy@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Maybe for the time is might have been, especially with a tag-line like that.
This pretty obscure film is about Bad singers, Sleazy Talent scouts, teen
gangs, robbery and general pandemonium. No Beatniks here, really. Ginsberg
and Kerouac probably couldn't believe what they had wrought-this certainly
was not it.If you want to see a better example of one of the so called "beatnik" films
that were created around 1959 to 1961, (where Exploitation Producers latched
onto popular media phrases like "Beatnik"), check out The Beat Generation
starring Mamie Van Doren, or Beat Girl starring a then unknown Oliver Reed.
Although these were not about 'niks they had a somewhat inkling to what a
"beatnik" was.As with all exploitation films very few of the catch phrases and trends used
in marketing the films were used very accurately, nevertheless the films did
make obscene amounts of money because they were presented to the public
within a few months of a trend that was in high gear.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0861465/comments</url><from>from Queens, NY</from><name>InzyWimzy</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>

That is one song that never fails to crack me up.Beatniks anyone?  See any?  There are none to be found here.  Tony Travis
plays Eddy Crane; rebel and small-time hood, but also sings like a pansy
femme??  This definitely ruins any credibility since you really can't
straddle the fence.  Either tell Iris to shut up, or sing "With a Look"; you
can't do BOTH!  That audition scene is hilarious getting to see hardcore,
tough Eddy crooning sentimentality. HA HA HA HA!!!Who else shamed themselves?  Peter Breck as Mooney.  Ham anyone?  He takes
the manic psycho character to probably the only entertainment in this flop. 
It's tough to be scared of someone who threatens you with "I'm gonna MOON
you!!".  His soliloquy regarding the barkeep is also priceless scene
followed by on odd whiny fit.  Then there's annoying broad Iris who's
dancing can scar even those unprepared for random corkscrew gyrations.  Mr.
Morrissey taught me that to succeed as a talent agent, get in an auto
accident, call for a tow, and listen to the guy near the jukebox!!  Then
there's a dive called Charlie's run by a guy named Gus(?). Despite this corny premise, maybe the makers of Beatniks were trying to make
a statement about life; it's not all wavy gravy and the man always square
forcing the minds of our best generation to conform to antiquated norms
while suppressing self expression.  Rail against the establishment!! 
Whoops, slipped into Beatnik mode there.  Well, someone had to because this
film sure doesn't!!"I KILLED THAT FAT BARKEEP!"It's true...it's not what you say, but how you say it.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>1/10</rating><comment>
If there's anyone out there expecting to see a film about the Fifties
counterculture prototypes, skip this one by. Skip it by for that reason
and on general principles.The Beatniks is about a gang of punks who bully and rob people for
kicks and one of them, Tony Travis is discovered in true Hollywood
tradition in a roadside dive by an agent. He's got a decent singing
voice and the agent promises to make him the next Elvis.But our lug-nut of a hero instead of saying goodbye Daddy-O in true
beatnik fashion, doesn't want to lose the old gang. And the old gang
don't want to let him go. Especially Peter Breck, a twisted psycho with
some gay leanings who's crushing out on Travis big time.Despite this film where he gives an over the top performance like Jack
Palance on amphetamines, Peter Breck was the only one in this no name
cast to have anything resembling a career.The Beatniks is a film without a lot going for it. This was one of
those drive-in flicks which one could get down to serious business at
the drive-in without missing anything of importance.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4997726/comments</url><from>from Wavy Wheat, Nebraska</from><name>lemon_magic</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Well, actually that line is from another movie altogether ("The
Oscar",featuring Tony Curtis), but MST3K used it to hilarious effect in
one of their skits lampooning "The Beatniks" during their treatment of
the movie. OK, so what do we have here? Um, let's see...no beatniks, that's for
sure, just some well dressed Juvenile Deliquents hanging out and
causing trouble. Our hero, he's a Troubled Soul With A Heart Of Gold,
and he gets his Big Break when he's discovered singing along to a song
on the Jukebox, but he's held back (and held down) by his old gang. His
old gang buddy becomes jealous of his success and tries to cause
trouble with the hero's agent/producer. Hilarity Ensues. (And by
"hilarity", I mean some of the goofiest fist fights ever staged in the
history of black-and-white cinema.) While this movie is strictly "By The Numbers", it isn't all that bad.
Yes, the acting is barely there, but it's good enough for the material
and the script (with the exception of Peter Breck, who chews the
scenery with admirable energy and verve). Tony Travis, who plays the
lead, is a handsome fellow who can at least play himself on camera, and
while he has nothing new to offer in the Teen Dream department, he's at
least as good as the lout who plays "Daddy-O" in the film of that name.
But based on what we see in the movie, the only reason he becomes a
public sensation is because the plot requires it - 3rd rate Fabians and
4th rate Sinatras were a dime a dozen back then, and this poor guy is
so wooden and limited in dramatic range that you could replace him with
a life sized Ken doll and no one would probably notice, as long as a
stage hand moved the Ken Doll's arms once in a while. If you feel the need to spend time watching "Public Service
Announcement/Moral Drama Films" about Our Troubled Youth, lots of other
films do this kind of thing better. "Untamed Youth" and "Girls' Town"
have better music and feature Mamie Van Doren, and "Daddy-O" has a
mystery/caper aspect that drives a much more intriguing plot. But
compared to a snooze-fest like "I Accuse My Parents", this is pure
gold. Make your choices accordingly, and don't complain that I never
warned you.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2956897/comments</url><from/><name>Angel Meiru</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This has to be one of my favorite MST3K episodes of all time. And a reason
why Paul Frees has stuck to animation and cartoon voice overs, since this
was his first and last live action feature film he has ever
done.Though the movie is suppose to be a serious musical/crime drama, I sure
laughed my head off over it, especially with Joel and the bots there to save
it. It deals with an Elvis clone named Eddy Crane whom hits the top when a
music agent and a sexy blond woman discovers his so-called "talents".
However, his so-called "beatnik" friends want him to come back to him and
stop singing, especially a nutcase named Mooney, whoms immortal lines were
"One word outta you and I am gonna moon ya!" "MOON, YOU!". That part right
there cracks me up.And another thing, why did Paul Frees decided to call this movie "Beatniks"?
It is a gang of juvenile deliquents (perhaps special ed rejects?) whom like
to get into trouble. What was Paul Frees on when doing
this?Oh well, at least Frees learned his lesson here, while there are some much
worse so-called "talents" whom have not.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3109237/comments</url><from>from Tennessee</from><name>bensonmum2</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
After knocking over a market, Eddy Crane (Tony Travis) and the rest of
his gang stop at a diner for a bite to eat. Quite unexpectedly (at
least I didn't see it coming), Eddy begins singing to a little jazzy
number playing on the jukebox. He's overheard by a talent agent who
thinks he can make Eddy a star. Before you can say "Daddy-O", Eddy's on
TV and has a recording contract lined up. But Eddy can't escape his
past. While celebrating his good fortune, one of his friends, Mooney
(Peter Breck), kills a bartender. Eddy's agent asks the gang to leave
Eddy alone and gets stabbed for his efforts. The gang drags Eddy back
down at every opportunity. Eddy's must ultimately fight for his
freedom.I wonder if Paul Frees and the rest of those behind this bad idea of a
movie had any concept of just what a "beatnik" was. It doesn't appear
so. Calling this gang of self-centered, unintelligent, small-time hoods
with a Pat Boone style crooner as its leader "beatniks" would have
Maynard G. Krebs spinning in his grave. These aren't "beatniks" in the
traditional sense of the word. These are not the philosophical
counter-cultural bongo beaters Kerouac wrote about. If everyone
involved wasn't in their 30s, I'd call them juvenile delinquents.
Beatniks? I don't think so.But beyond the misuse of "beatniks", the movie has very little to
offer. Some moments in The Beatniks might be appealing in that
bizarrely entertaining sort of way, but not in any traditional sense.
The plot it bad, the acting is horrible, and the cinematography is as
lazy as I've seen recently. In short, The Beatniks isn't a very good
movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4276975/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>catherine yronwode</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
No Beatniks appear in this film, the acting by the young leads is
execrable, the song lyrics are both insane and badly lip-synched, and
the plot is dumb. As others have commented, radio and voice actor Paul
Frees assembled quite a nice cast of fellow radio and voice actors to
play the "normal" people in this tale of troubled youth, but he
neglected to cast credible actors as the over-the-hill "teens" who hang
around engaging in delinquent acts of senseless violence. I was quite
pleased to see radio and voice actor Stanley Farrar on screen, and,
like other comment writers i wonder whose rather nice voice actually
sang the lame songs that the character Eddie was inexpertly mouthing
along to, but all in all, this one is a loser. Having read all the
reviews here, some folks will no doubt seek it out for its sheer
badness. To them i say, "Come back later and tell us if it was really
worth it!"
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4482580/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>paultrefzger-1</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This movie, that was part of the Mystery Science Theatre 3K batch of
"so bad, they're good" flicks. The film's worst offense is its title.
There are no beatniks in the movie, but rather, juvenile delinquents
(all over 2o, at least). By all Hollywood standards, this is a B movie,
but I find it more entertaining than some movies that are nominated for
an Oscar. Good looking lead Tony Travis is also a good actor, as is
Peter Breck as a wise-cracking gang member who is supposedly psychotic
but in the overall scheme of things comes across as funnier than
menacing. Karen Kadler is fun too as Mr. Travis' gang girl-friend.
Travis plays Eddie Crane, who in the course of the movie sings 4 times
and sings well, from Sinatra-like ballads to early rock 'n' roll. There
is a plot that involves shootings, and a jazz/ big band score...and a
weak attempt at artsy filming but what we care about most is whether or
not Eddie will side with the upright show biz people and leave his
gang. Don't get serious about this film, just enjoy it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4482580/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>paultrefzger-1</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
This movie, that was part of the Mystery Science Theatre 3K batch of
"so bad, they're good" flicks. The film's worst offense is its title.
There are no beatniks in the movie, but rather, juvenile delinquents
(all over 2o, at least). By all Hollywood standards, this is a B movie,
but I find it more entertaining than some movies that are nominated for
an Oscar. Good looking lead Tony Travis is also a good actor, as is
Peter Breck as a wise-cracking gang member who is supposedly psychotic
but in the overall scheme of things comes across as funnier than
menacing. Karen Kadler is fun too as Mr. Travis' gang girl-friend.
Travis plays Eddie Crane, who in the course of the movie sings 4 times
and sings well, from Sinatra-like ballads to early rock 'n' roll. There
is a plot that involves shootings, and a jazz/ big band score...and a
weak attempt at artsy filming but what we care about most is whether or
not Eddie will side with the upright show biz people and leave his
gang. Don't get serious about this film, just enjoy it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4482580/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>paultrefzger-1</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/beatniks.htm /m/beatniks/comments.php?reviewid=1775580</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>A shrill take on small-time thugs here mistakenly called beatniks.</comment></review></movie>