<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Tutti a casa</original_title><alt_title>La grande pagaille</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Italy</country><country>France</country><director>Luigi Comencini</director><producer>Dino de Laurentiis Cinematografica</producer><producer>Orsay Films</producer><genre>War</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis/><actor>Alberto Sordi</actor><actor>Eduardo De Filippo</actor><actor>Serge Reggiani</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is possibly Comencini's finest work (which I watched in tribute to
his recent passing), one of several contemporaneous Italian war-themed
films - Mario Monicelli's LA GRANDE GUERRA (1959), Gillo Pontecorvo's
KAPO' (1959), Roberto Rossellini's IL GENERALE DELLA ROVERE (1959) and
ERA NOTTE A ROMA (1960), Florestano Vancini's LA LUNGA NOTTE DEL '43
(1960), Vittorio De Sica's LA CIOCIARA (1961), Luciano Salce's IL
FEDERALE (1961), Nanni Loy's LE QUATTRO GIORNATE DI NAPOLI (1962), etc.
Still, despite being awarded the David Di Donatello for best film (and
other international prizes), it's not very well-known outside Italy!The international cast assembled for the film is comprised of Italians
(Alberto Sordi, Nino Castelnuovo, Edoardo De Filippo, Carla Gravina),
French (Serge Reggiani) and Americans (Martin Balsam, Alex Nicol); Nino
Manfredi was originally intended for the role eventually played by
Reggiani - but Sordi apparently objected to the idea of having two
comic stars in the film! Still, in spite of Sordi's reputation, it's
not an out-and-out comedy but rather a tragi-comedy about the chaos
which pervaded Italy in the final days of WWII - with most of the
soldiers eager to go back home by every possible means, regardless of
the risk of their being arrested for desertion! The scene in which Sordi's father (celebrated playwright De Filippo)
contrives to have his war-weary son join the resurging Fascist Army as
soon as he arrives home is a moving depiction of the elders' illusion
of their country's glory and, at the same time, the children's
disenchantment with their own parents. Despite their inherent
self-preservation and egotism (exemplified by Sordi's escapade with a
lusty merchant), the soldiers are bound together by solidarity - and,
eventually joining the partisans, he gets to indulge in some
machine-gun action at the very end.A wonderful dramatic sequence involves Jewish Gravina being hounded by
the Germans: with the help of Sordi and his company, she flees their
pursuit on various means of transportation - but this actually leads to
Castelnuovo's demise. Similarly poignant is the night-time conversation
between U.S. refugee Nicol and Sordi at Balsam's house - which is
interrupted by the arrival of the Fascists, who promptly arrest the two
American actors (though Balsam is actually playing an Italian, as is
Reggiani).The film's comic highlight, then, sees the boys pilfering Reggiani's
precious food parcel while he's asleep and substituting it with rocks
(an incident which has a tragic outcome later on). Another episode
which mixes farce with suspense is the one where Sordi and other
escaping prisoners take refuge inside a church (the star hides in a
confessional and, mistaken for the parish priest by an old lady, she
starts relating her sins to him!).Unfortunately, the print I watched of this gem was rather soft and hazy
- and I'm wondering what the quality of the bare-bones Italian DVD is
like...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0359770/comments</url><from>from Rome, Italy</from><name>kristen skullerud (kskuller@tiscalinet.it)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

A historical premises....
After the armistice of the 8 th September 1943, Italys
defeated
army literally collapsed.Italy effectively had switched sides
in
the world war alliances,allied with USA against Nazi Germany,leaving many
Italian army units in the lurch....and the
Nazi German army invasion a few weeks later!
Some units joined the the Anglo-Americans and valiantly fought with them,a
few more joined the Fachist militias of the Salò regime in Northern Italy
sustained by Nazi troops which together perpetuated massacres of
civilians.
However a large number of Italian army units,just melted like snow in a
sunny spring day,disappearing or rather deserting in mass,prefering like
the
title of the film "..to return home".
The films spirit is basically about a strong desire of war weary soldiers
to
return back home to their families.
Something which apparently would seem an easy task....but
not
in this film!!This film retaining a deep tragic undertone has also some hilarious scenes
of the more tragi-comical style,which was typical of the post
neo-realistic
film scripts of Italian cinema in the 1950's and 1960's,(The best period
of
Italian cinema).An absolute "must see film" for Italo-philes and fans of
Italian cinema.Strangely enough,this film has never been much appreciated
in
Italy,and it is hard to find as video-cassette both for renting or
buying.My
vote 9.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0359770/comments</url><from>from Rome, Italy</from><name>kristen skullerud (kskuller@tiscalinet.it)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

A historical premises....
After the armistice of the 8 th September 1943, Italys
defeated
army literally collapsed.Italy effectively had switched sides
in
the world war alliances,allied with USA against Nazi Germany,leaving many
Italian army units in the lurch....and the
Nazi German army invasion a few weeks later!
Some units joined the the Anglo-Americans and valiantly fought with them,a
few more joined the Fachist militias of the Salò regime in Northern Italy
sustained by Nazi troops which together perpetuated massacres of
civilians.
However a large number of Italian army units,just melted like snow in a
sunny spring day,disappearing or rather deserting in mass,prefering like
the
title of the film "..to return home".
The films spirit is basically about a strong desire of war weary soldiers
to
return back home to their families.
Something which apparently would seem an easy task....but
not
in this film!!This film retaining a deep tragic undertone has also some hilarious scenes
of the more tragi-comical style,which was typical of the post
neo-realistic
film scripts of Italian cinema in the 1950's and 1960's,(The best period
of
Italian cinema).An absolute "must see film" for Italo-philes and fans of
Italian cinema.Strangely enough,this film has never been much appreciated
in
Italy,and it is hard to find as video-cassette both for renting or
buying.My
vote 9.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0359770/comments</url><from>from Rome, Italy</from><name>kristen skullerud (kskuller@tiscalinet.it)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>