<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Magnificent Seven</original_title><alt_title>Les sept mercenaires</alt_title><imdb_rating>7.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>John Sturges</director><producer>Mirisch Company, The</producer><producer>Alpha Productions</producer><genre>Western</genre><genre>Adventure</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
An oppressed Mexican peasant village assembles seven gunfighters to help defend their homes.
</synopsis><actor>Yul Brynner</actor><actor>Steve McQueen</actor><actor>Charles Bronson</actor><rt_rating>7.9/10</rt_rating><rt_meter>93</rt_meter><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2059044/comments</url><from>from Washington, DC</from><name>byght</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I recently subjected "The Magnificent Seven" to just about the toughest
test imaginable--I watched it just a few days after "Seven Samurai."
And while I'm not going to pretend it's on par with Kurosawa's
astounding masterpiece, I have to tip my hat to Hollywood on this one:
it's good, DAMN good, among the best American Westerns.The focus of the screenplay is more on post-Bogart-pre-Eastwood cool
banter than the gradual, taciturn character development of "Seven
Samurai," but that doesn't mean that the film doesn't have a heart.
Considering it clocks in at barely over two hours (compared to the
marathonic three and a half of "Samurai"), it actually does a fantastic
and very economical job of fleshing out its memorable cast of
characters.One particularly wonderful scene that stuck in my memory from the first
time I saw the film ten years ago is the one where Lee (Robert Vaughn),
drunk in the middle of the night, confesses his frailties and fear to
two of the farmers. The scene (along with the general story of these
down-and-out heroes) was groundbreaking in that it began the
deconstruction and deromanticization of the Western hero which would be
brought to fruition in Sergio Leone's unparalleled spaghetti Westerns.The star-studded cast wouldn't hold up doing Shakespeare, but they're
ideal in this gunslinging, cool-talking tough-guy adventure. As if a
lineup of heroes that included Yul Brynner, Steve McQueen, Charles
Bronson, and James Coburn wasn't enough, Eli Wallach steals the show as
the Mexican bandit chief, a worthy precursor to his classic role "The
Good, the Bad, and the Ugly." If the screenplay has a major flaw, it's
that his character isn't featured more.The score is, of course, one of the all-time classics. And while not as
alive visually as the Japanese film that inspired it or the Italian
Westerns it influenced, it's still mighty fine to look at, and the
gunfights don't disappoint.The pieces add up to one of the great entertaining films of all time,
which still manages to be moving and morally aware despite its
Hollywoodization of Kurosawa's vision.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0176092/comments</url><from>from Mexico</from><name>ironside (robertfrangie@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
John Sturges acquires a reputation as a solid director of superior
Westerns filled with tense action scenes such as: "Escape From Fort
Bravo," "Bad Day at Black Rock," "Backlash," "Gunfight At The O.K.
Corral," "The Law and Jack Wade," "The Last Train From Gun Hill,"
"Sergeant Three," "The Hallelujah Trail," and one of the best of all
Wyatt Earp movies, "Hour of the Gun." He succeeds in one of the most exhilarating opening sequences of all
Western movies, when he had McQueen and Brynner riding a hearse up
legendary Boot Hill creating a mood and peril that never allow the
slightest degree of viewer confusion or ennui... For Sturges, the West
is a man's world, and his cool, hard, detached style, emphasizing
action, excitement and the rugged environment of the frontier, endorses
the point..."The Magnificent Seven" is derived from Kurosawa's superb "The Seven
Samurai," a compelling tale of intimidated and impoverished medieval
villagers hiring mercenary warriors to repel bandit ravages... The
villagers in this case are Mexicans, plagued beyond all bearing by the
activities of bandit Calavera, who always leaves them on tortillas and
few beans... Three of them cross the border to offer meager pay and
sustenance for any professionally skilled fighting men who will aid
them...Yul Brynner is the man, dressed in black, with the luminous dome and
the hypnotic Mongolian eyes who portrays the distinctive Chris Adams
leader of the seven hired gunmen hired to chase some 'flies from a
little Mexican village.' Eli Wallach is memorable as Calvera, chief of the ruthless outlaws...
He is greedy and merciless terrorizing without pity the poor
peasants...Steve McQueen gives a standout performance as the sardonic gunman ('We
deal in lead, friend'), carrying appealing ease and sense of humor to
his role as Vin, Brynner's first recruit and second-in-command...Charles Bronson portrays Bernardo O'Reilly, who explains his curious
name to Chris, with 'Mexican on one side, Irish on the other—and me in
the middle!' Bronson, the strongest face in Western, and with a bit of
Mexican in him—cunning face, steady eyes, revealing voice—the character
of Bernardo O'Reilly suits him perfectly... This half-breed gunfighter
becomes the conscience of the team... Because of his tender paternal
instincts, he is adopted by three children who promise him, in case he
falls, to bring him, every day, fresh flowers...Robert Vaughn—who was to do nicely on TV in "The Man from Uncle" spy
spoof— plays Lee, the 'good gun' with black gloves and nightmares,
living in style with no enemies alive...Brad Dexter plays Harry Luck, Brynner's happy friend who returns to
join the team convinced of the existence of a large amount of hidden
gold...James Coburn makes a big impression as Britt, the expert gunman who can
out-draw a gun with his knife-throwing... His looks and vague figure of
violence are quite a response for his few talks...Horst Bucholz represents youth, eagerness, and the urge to be proved
and sorted out from the boys... He was caught on the road by Rosenda
Monteros...Robert J. Wilke is Britt's insisting challenger who swells the ranks of
the villains in many Westerns like "High Noon," "The Far Country," and
"Man of the West." The Magnificent Seven's success spawned three sequels: "Return of the
Seven" (again starring Yul Brynner), "Guns of the Magnificent Seven"
and, last and least of all, "The Magnificent Seven Ride." With a terrific Oscar-Nominated Musical Score by Elmer Bernstein, "The
Magnificent Seven" remains a richly enjoyable Western, shot on location
in Morelos state, Mexico...
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193491/comments</url><from>from Cincinnati, OH</from><name>Poseidon-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

What could have been a fairly routine western is lifted into the realm of
classic thanks to some smart casting, sturdy direction and a rousing music
score.  A reworking of Akira Kurosawa's "Seven Samurai", the story concerns
a Mexican village which is constantly pillaged by bandit Wallach and his
small army of followers.  Three of the villagers hire a mix of gunslingers
to come back to protect and defend the town and rid it of the oppressors. 
Brynner leads the group (seven in total, hence the title) as they teach the
farmers how to use a gun and prepare the town for the eventual onslaught
from Wallach.  The already tough odds are lengthened when some of the
villagers begin to lose faith in the power of the seven.  Brynner is solid
in the lead role (though, unfortunately, his later role in "Westworld" adds
an odd shading to his character here.)  He, McQueen and Coburn define the
word cool as they go about their various exploits before and after they join
forces.  McQueen and Coburn are men of few words, but of fierce actions when
necessary.  Bronson (rather young and handsome, though still a little craggy
looking) does his best with a pretty mushy storyline involving the youth of
the village.  Buchholz overacts feverishly as a determined, but
inexperienced youth.  Vaughn seems a tad out of place and has one major ham
moment during a nightmare.  Dexter (easily the most often forgotten member
of the group) has a few moments, but his character is not particularly
defined.  Wallach excels in the showy role of the chief bandit.  His brash
performance is a great counterpoint to the more steely and solemn title
gunmen.  The villagers come off as hapless and pitiful, for the most part. 
Along the way, there are several memorable vignettes that showcase the charm
of the actors involved.  The casting director did an almost miraculous job
of using known stars and picking supporting actors who would soon be just as
big so that the film now has virtually an all-star cast.  The biggest shot
in the arm of all is the monumental score by Elmer Bernstein.  The instantly
recognizable title music is just one of the many great pieces he created for
the film.  The sometimes laconic story is carried a long way by his score. 
The concept of disparate characters being brought together for a common
cause has been done many times, but rarely with this level of quality.  It's
sometimes hard to believe that the film was made in 1960 as its look,
content and cast make it seem like a later film.  It was definitely a
touchstone in the development of the western film.  
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0821456/comments</url><from>from Southern Hemisphere</from><name>mentalcritic</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Based somewhat faithfully on the Akira Kurosawa classic Shichinin no
samurai, The Magnificent Seven could be mistaken for just another of
the many Westerns that were turned out in Hollywood during this era.
But there is a certain something that keeps The Magnificent Seven
unique. Part of it is the concept borrowed from the earlier Japanese
film, but some of it lies in the attitude of the seven mercenaries
referred to in the title.Much is made here of the difference between fighting for money,
fighting for justice, or fighting for a future. While this version of
Kurosawa's epic contains all the philosophical leanings of the
original, it isn't nearly as long-winded or languid. The downside to
this is that it isn't nearly as moody or powerful. In fact, one can
easily see the difference between American and foreign cinema simply by
comparing Shichinin no samurai with The Magnificent Seven. One is
incredibly dark and downbeat most of the time. The other mostly has a
score that is so major it wouldn't sound out of place in Seven Brides
For Seven Brothers.Differences in feeling aside, the ultimate question is whether this
version of the story manages to entertain. The hardest challenge any
film faces is keeping the audience amused while all the exposition is
laid out. Here, the exposition is kept to a minimum while carefully
inserted between some fast-paced, albeit very mild action sequences.Sometimes, the dialogue ("We deal in lead, friend.") gets incredibly
stilted. Sometimes, it seems incredibly wise. Well, since we have
examples of films where it's all stilted, all the time, we can forgive
this one. The film also includes several textbook examples of how to
include a sudden plot element without seeming contrived. When we learn
why Calvera's men just won't go away, it needs no setup simply because
it is consistent with their behaviour throughout the rest of the film.In the end, The Magnificent Seven comes off as an excellent remake of a
masterpiece. There are better Westerns out there, and there are better
action films, but there aren't many. I gave it a nine out of ten. Go in
expecting to be entertained, but little more, and you cannot go wrong.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4445210/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>ccthemovieman-1</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
This is considered one of the all-time great westerns: a real classic,
and I can't argue. I've seen a number of faster-moving and better
westerns but few with a cast this good that's still entertaining. I
never get tired of seeing the stars in this movie. How often are actors
like Yul Brynner, Steve McQueen, Charles Bronson, James Coburn and Eli
Wallach boring.....or all in the same movie? Not too often. Throw in
Robert Vaughn and Horst Buchholz and you have a memorable cast.As "cool" as McQueen was in his day, in this film Brynner was the
"coolest" guy. Just the intense look on his face with those piercing
eyes and deep voice command attention whenever he's on screen.
Meanwhile, nobody but nobody played a Mexican villain better than
Wallach.The "good guys" in this classic movie are all professional killers and
show their human side by admitting their weaknesses and the emptiness
of their profession. No one says it better here than Bronson, who gives
a couple of very powerful "sermons" to some young boys.A solid western and a pretty famous theme song, too! It's also another
good example of showing some real tough guys who can be convincing
without profanity. Can you imagine the dialog if this film was re-made
today?!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0443768/comments</url><from>from Colorado</from><name>Sleepy-17</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I've seen both the American and Japanese versions many times, and while
everyone agrees about which one is better, the American version has some
virtues:
1) Our heroes are selected by the farmers when they defend a dead Indian's
right to be buried in the same place as white people; therefore they are
seen as champions of social and racial equality by the
farmers.
2) A magnificent villain played by Eli Wallach.
3) Charlie Bronson's relationship with the village boys.
And some tremendous faults:
1) Combining the Young Student and Crazy Fool characters; some of the most
poignant scenes in the Japanese version involved the interaction between
these two.
2) Not filming the final battle in the rain.
And of course many more of each. It's an interesting discussion.
Both are great movies that shouldn't be missed.
Remember that Kurosawa gave John Sturges a sword in appreciation after
seeing his film.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0270791/comments</url><from>from Edinburgh, Scotland</from><name>Richard Brunton (imdb-update@brunton.org.uk)</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

A wonderful classic beautifully scored and shot.There are so many moody looks between characters, and little movements or
idiosyncrasies that just make each of the gunmen seem so real. Apparently,
there were big egos behind the camera that caused these acts of showmanship,
but unlike most films where the egos clash, here they just build the
characters up without harming them.Yul Brynner and Steve McQueen are just wonderful, and James Coburn and
Charles Bronson both put in equal performances. There's just nothing about
this film that you can fault, the script is kept light when required and the
stunning score lifts up and the acting is huge but never too much. This is a
must see…again and again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1128258/comments</url><from>from Mayfield Heights, OH, U.S.A.</from><name>AbeStreet (AbeStreet@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I first saw this film about 20 years ago as a teenager and I still find it
as enjoyable now as I did then.  It is the tale of seven gunfighters who are
hired by a poor Mexican farming community to help drive off the bandits who
periodically show up and steal the communities food and goods.  Of the
Magnificent Seven most of the screen time is given to Chris (Brynner), Vin
(McQueen) and Chico (Bucholz).  While no details are given about the
individual pasts of the Magnificent Seven it is fairly clear what there
pasts may have been.1. Chris:  A leader, perhaps a former soldier, who has encountered danger
before and gained a degree of mastery over his emotions in dangerous
situation.2. Vin:  A capable man with a gun, perhaps a one time cowboy. He seems to be
comfortable working as a loner but clearly would like to one day settle
down.3. Chico:  The youngest of the Seven and most inexperienced.  He wants to
shed his farming past and attempts through acts of bravado to persuade
others and himself that he is a gunfighter at heart.4.  Bernardo (Bronson):  A strong solitary man that in many ways resembles
Chris although not displaying the desire to lead.  In many ways he is the
most interesting character.  He has made quite a bit of money in the past
even though he is now broke.  The attention he gives to the local village
children and the gift he gives a village girl hint at the idea that while he
is good at gunfighting he knows that it is a good family life that is
important.5. Lee (Vaughn):  The most difficult character to relate to.  He appears to
be a gunman who in the past was cocky, arrogant and self assured but now
after experiencing life on the run now doubts himself.  He wants to do the
right thing but finds it difficult to step up to the plate when it's his
turn.6.  Britt (Coburn):  A loner who is unequaled in a gun or knife fight.  A
man whose motives remain his own.7.  Harry (Dexter):  A good man to have in a fight but one who lets greed
cloud his every decision.  It would seem that Harry is one of those
individuals who is always one step away from gaining riches but somehow
never gains them.The leader of the bandits is Calvera (Walsh) who is not an unlikeable
fellow.  He appears to believe that it is his job to steal so that he can
support himself and his men.  For him it is only a job, not unlike the
farmers who work the land to provide for their families.  He has what can
almost be describes as a code of ethics for those who make their living with
guns.  This code of ethics is evident in the way he treats the Magnificent
Seven towards the end of the film.  However, given the films ending, this
code does not seem to be shared by the Magnificent SevenLastly, while many people may view this film as a western action film I
think there is quite a bit of underlying humanity and character depth woven
into the story. It is these underlying characteristics that distinguish it
from the average western action flick and have helped to make this film as
popular as it is.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0123856/comments</url><from>from Sydney, Australia</from><name>Philby-3</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Re-make are seldom as good as the original, but here Hollywood or
rather John Sturges managed to capture some of the spirit of Kurosawa's
'Seven Samurai' which itself owes something to the 'Three Musketeers'
and which Sturges duly acknowledged in the credits. Partly this is due
to some inspired casting. With the exception of Yul Brynner, none of
the actors was particularly well known at the time. Steve McQueen,
Charles Bronson, James Coburn, Robert Vaughn, Eli Wallach and Horst
Buchholz (an unlikely Mexican) all went on to successful acting
careers. The format of this film was replicated in many later films. The plot couldn't be simpler. Desperate Mexican villagers, bled white
by local bandits, retain a group of almost equally desperate
gunslingers from the other side of the Rio Grand to deal with the
bandits. A lot of the fun arises early on as leader Cajun Chris seeks
out half a dozen suitably deranged but deadly types for the job.
Ostensibly they are doing it for the money but it becomes apparent
early on that they are really on the team just for the hell of it. Once
they are together things don't quite go to plan, but the camaraderie
holds up, and their mission is accomplished, though at considerable
cost.Despite all the action it is a character-driven piece in some ways. Eli
Wallach's Calvera the bandit leader is more than a cardboard cut-out
villain and Yul Brynner's enigmatic Chris keeps us guessing. The
villagers, despite their matching white smocks, are not all lily-white
and each of the Seven has at least one interesting weakness.A strong feature of the film is the music, penned by the ubiquitous
Elmer Bernstein, and entirely appropriate, with a main theme which
seems to be permanently welded into my brain.'The Magnificent Seven' was made at a time when the appetite for
westerns was going into decline. Whereas westerns were staple film and
TV fare in the 50's, the sixties saw a sharp decline, as spy dramas and
sex farces burgeoned. One interesting theory I've heard about this is
that it's not so much that the audience tired of westerns, but that TV
executives discovered that they were being watched by the people too
poor to buy their sponsor's fine products. Anyway this film holds up
very well after 45 years, a true classic and satisfying to watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0408793/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Ontario, Canada</from><name>Rob Deschenes</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

SEVEN is one of the better Westerns to come out for the aging genre. Also,
for any genre, it has much better characterization; from the cowboys, to the
farmers, and even the outlaws themselves, everyone gets their own fair share
of camera time to make MAGNIFICENT SEVEN a classic in its own right.Outlaws steal from a small Mexican farming town every once in awhile. Since
the authorities do nothing, the farmers enlist the aid of seven gunmen to
solve their problem.Compared to THE SEVEN SAMURAI, I would have to say MAGNIFICENT is less dark
and reflective. An outlaw such as Calvera is hard to hate seeing him as a
character on screen. Also, a better motive to explain why the outlaws
continue their attack on the village is shown here, as opposed to Kurosawa's
classic, where the raiders relentlessly never gave up, not once thinking (or
admitting) the village is well fortified and they were not going to win. The
scene and spirit of the old west, combined with the philosophies of the far
east, have made a fine movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0408793/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Ontario, Canada</from><name>Rob Deschenes</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

SEVEN is one of the better Westerns to come out for the aging genre. Also,
for any genre, it has much better characterization; from the cowboys, to the
farmers, and even the outlaws themselves, everyone gets their own fair share
of camera time to make MAGNIFICENT SEVEN a classic in its own right.Outlaws steal from a small Mexican farming town every once in awhile. Since
the authorities do nothing, the farmers enlist the aid of seven gunmen to
solve their problem.Compared to THE SEVEN SAMURAI, I would have to say MAGNIFICENT is less dark
and reflective. An outlaw such as Calvera is hard to hate seeing him as a
character on screen. Also, a better motive to explain why the outlaws
continue their attack on the village is shown here, as opposed to Kurosawa's
classic, where the raiders relentlessly never gave up, not once thinking (or
admitting) the village is well fortified and they were not going to win. The
scene and spirit of the old west, combined with the philosophies of the far
east, have made a fine movie.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0408793/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Ontario, Canada</from><name>Rob Deschenes</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/emanuel-levy/</url><url>http://www.emanuellevy.com/review/magnificent-seven-the-1960/ /m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=2002260</url><name>Emanuel Levy</name><from>EmanuelLevy.Com</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>John Sturges remake of Kurosawa's masterpiece, Seven Samurai, is enjoyable on its own terms due to the stellar cast, not to mention Elmer Bernstein's score, but it helps to know the Japansese classic.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carly-kocurek/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/Magnificent-Seven.html  /m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1950313</url><name>Carly Kocurek</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Classic shoot-'em-up not for young viewers.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/christopher-smith/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1478473</url><name>Christopher Smith</name><from>Bangor Daily News (Maine)</from></reviewer><rating>
A-
					</rating><comment>Overly celebrated, but the gun fights are among the best ever in a Western.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/magnificentseven.htm /m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1462944</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>An inferior remake of Akira Kurosawa's 1954 action classic The Seven Samurai, though worth seeing because of the star performances.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/chuck-oleary/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1453962</url><name>Chuck O'Leary</name><from>Fantastica Daily</from></reviewer><rating>
2/5
					</rating><comment>A classic that's never been one of my favorite Westerns.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pete-vonder-haar/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1444912</url><name>Pete Vonder Haar</name><from>Film Threat</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>If you're going to rip someone off, may as well rip off the best</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/pete-croatto/</url><url>http://www.filmcritic.com/misc/emporium.nsf/reviews/The-Magnificent-Seven /m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1381217</url><name>Pete Croatto</name><from>Filmcritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>Get the Pringles ready.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/steve-crum/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1349916</url><name>Steve Crum</name><from>Kansas City Kansan</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>A classic western, a stellar cast.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/larry-carroll/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=787965</url><name>Larry Carroll</name><from>Countingdown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>If it's not the greatest Western ever made, it's certainly in the top three. This is the movie that made Steve McQueen a star.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/scott-weinberg/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=745991</url><name>Scott Weinberg</name><from>eFilmCritic.com</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment>Simply one of the most entertaining Westerns ever made.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-kendrick/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=221503</url><name>James Kendrick</name><from>Q Network Film Desk</from></reviewer><rating>
3.5/4
					</rating><comment>a rousing adventure story that not only includes a brilliant cast, but explores some of the deeper contradictions of the mythic noble outlaw</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/john-j-puccio/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=218584</url><name>John J. Puccio</name><from>DVDTown.com</from></reviewer><rating>
7/10
					</rating><comment>...holds up as a rousing adventure and as a fascinating turning point in the history of movies about the Old West.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/david-forsmark/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/articles/218324/one_of_the_most_popular_westerns_of_all_time_the_heroic_story_of_the_magnificent_seven_has_influenced_countless_other_movies_in_nearly_every_genre/ /m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=218324</url><name>David Forsmark</name><from>Credo</from></reviewer><comment>One of the most popular Westerns of all time, the heroic story of The Magnificent Seven has influenced countless other movies in nearly every genre.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/cole-smithey/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1550524</url><name>Cole Smithey</name><from>ColeSmithey.com</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/joseph-proimakis/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1533227</url><name>Joseph Proimakis</name><from>Movies for the Masses</from></reviewer><rating>
5/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/lori-hoffman/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1499528</url><name>Lori Hoffman</name><from>Atlantic City Weekly</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/frank-swietek/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1265234</url><name>Frank Swietek</name><from>One Guy's Opinion</from></reviewer><rating>
3/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/spence-d/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1243582</url><name>Spence D.</name><from>IGN Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/carol-cling/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1216563</url><name>Carol Cling</name><from>Las Vegas Review-Journal</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/james-oehley/</url><url>/m/1013077-magnificent_seven/comments.php?reviewid=1210936</url><name>James O'Ehley</name><from>Sci-Fi Movie Page</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review></movie>