<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Kyonetsu no kisetsu</original_title><imdb_rating>7.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Koreyoshi Kurahara</director><producer>Nikkatsu</producer><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>They Do Every-thing!</synopsis><actor>Tamio Kawaji</actor><actor>Eiji Gô</actor><actor>Noriko Matsumoto</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0570008/comments</url><from>from New England</from><name>Son of Cathode</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Two teenage convicts and a young prostitute wreak havoc in Tokyo. Wow.
Imagine John Cassavettes remaking REBEL WITHOUT A CAUSE in Japan, and
throwing in some raw sex scenes, and you get an idea of this wild and edgy
Asian treat, brought to our shores by sexfilm wunderkind Radley Metzger.
Dynamic photography and a cool jazz score augment the air of pure anarchy
as
our three anti-heroes plow through society, p***ing off as many people as
possible. Some breathtaking location scenery of urban Japan, and stark
illustrations of sociopathic nihilism make this a real eye-opener, and a
fascinating look at early 60s Japan youth culture.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Great looking, but ultimately rambling story of two thugs and a
prostitute who get out of prison an continue their wanton ways, while
taking revenge on, and repeatedly crossing paths with, the people who
put them there.Playing like a Japanese Breathless or Rebel Without a Cause, this is
wonderful looking movie. The film was clearly shot on real locations so
it has a sense of place that few films I've seen can match. Luscious
black and white photography is arresting to see. I'm guessing the
cities and country sides never looked this good.The cast is very good and keep you watching even when the plot seems to
be going nowhere for a good chunk of the first half.Thats the rub, the plot. This hip and happening tale of young Japan
rambles around for a good chunk of it going nowhere. Its not that its
bad, its just it took a long time to get where it was going, or at
least feel like it was heading somewhere. The point of the film is to
contrast the three antiheroes with the pair who sent them away, and who
are seen, in the end to be just as awful as those they despise. Once
that happens the first time we're only left with a repetition of the
point the two or three more times it happens. Sprinkled with profanity,
rape, robbery and abortion this would have gotten banned in many
communities had it showed up in the US at the time of release in Japan.
Even today its more than likely liable to get a rise out of most
audience. Its a walk on a dark side that rattles you with its matter of
factness.Is it worth seeing? On most levels yes. Its a wonderful antidote for
what was being done elsewhere in the world at the same time (its also
more real than many similar Hollywood films). The music is great and
the hip, often nihilistic attitude almost saves it all. On the other
hand odds are that this is probably not going to be a film you watch a
second time, there's nothing wrong with it, its just not as meaty as it
thinks it is or we hoped it would be. Ultimately its a movie I admire
more than I like.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3699259/comments</url><from>from Miami</from><name>Elliot James</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Tamio Kawaji gives a an incredible, repugnant, unbelievable performance
as a mentally and emotionally disturbed criminal in a film that is
STILL ahead of its time 51 years later. He's a hyperkinetic, twitching
deviate, a human Road Runner causing trouble wherever he's dashing
around, usually shirtless and sweating; eating and drinking in fast
motion; stealing; moving like a speed freak; sexually assaulting,
attacking. Eio Go is his more standardized criminal buddy who thinks
his ticket to life's best is to join a Yakuza gang. The two live with a
beautiful young prostitute and wreak havoc everywhere they go,
destroying the lives of a middle-class couple engaged to be married.
The radical, frantic cinematography is brilliant and the jazz score is
integral to the story. I've never seen a film like this before or
since. The running time is short which is just as well because it's an
exhausting experience. Now just released by Criterion in a beautiful
print in Japanese with English sub-titles; Something Weird Video
originally released it. Radley Metzger brought the part street-punk,
part sexploitation film to the States for a theatrical release as The
Weird Lovemakers.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0668676/comments</url><from>from amsterdam, the netherlands</from><name>hulstra (hulstra@xs4all.nl)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This film should be well-known, but isn't. It is in many ways the typical
sixties Japanese pop-film, combining the best of nouvelle vague (hand held
camera, cool-jazz score, moody, young characters) and the Japanese
exploitation cinema (lots of violence, sex and rape). It is unknown,
probably because of it's raw content. The main line - girl falls in love
with the small time criminal who raped her - isn't to the taste of the
western public, but is actually handled in a subtle matter.
I've
seen this one on Something weird video.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0668676/comments</url><from>from amsterdam, the netherlands</from><name>hulstra (hulstra@xs4all.nl)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This film should be well-known, but isn't. It is in many ways the typical
sixties Japanese pop-film, combining the best of nouvelle vague (hand held
camera, cool-jazz score, moody, young characters) and the Japanese
exploitation cinema (lots of violence, sex and rape). It is unknown,
probably because of it's raw content. The main line - girl falls in love
with the small time criminal who raped her - isn't to the taste of the
western public, but is actually handled in a subtle matter.
I've
seen this one on Something weird video.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0668676/comments</url><from>from amsterdam, the netherlands</from><name>hulstra (hulstra@xs4all.nl)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>