<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Sunrise at Campobello</original_title><imdb_rating>7.1</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Vincent J. Donehue</director><producer>Schary Productions</producer><producer>Warner Bros. Pictures</producer><genre>Biography</genre><genre>Drama</genre><synopsis>
The story of Franklin Roosevelt's bout with polio at age 40 in 1921 and how his family (and especially wife Eleanor) cope with his illness...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Ralph Bellamy</actor><actor>Greer Garson</actor><actor>Hume Cronyn</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2483625/comments</url><from>from Buffalo, New York</from><name>bkoganbing</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Before Franklin D. Roosevelt could lead the nation in overcoming
economic depression and fascist aggression, he had to overcome one of
the greatest of personal challenges any would be president ever had to
overcome. The years 1921 to 1924 in his life are the subject of Dore
Schary's play Sunrise At Campobello which won a Tony Award for Best
Play and for Ralph Bellamy as FDR.Bellamy and Alan Bunce as Alfred E. Smith are the only ones who
repeated their stage roles in this film. Bellamy, a most respected
player was certainly not a leading man in a traditional sense nor any
kind of box office. Mary Fickett who played Eleanor Roosevelt on stage
was replaced by Greer Garson. I'm not sure why Henry Jones who also won
a Tony for playing Louis McHenry Howe was replaced, but Hume Cronyn
certainly did an admirable job as the asthmatic, cigar smoking former
reporter who became FDR's devoted acolyte and one of the very few whom
he vested 100% trust in during his life.You can read the various biographies of Roosevelt by James McGregor
Burns, Frank Freidel, Emil Ludwig and a host of others and most
recently by British author Conrad Black and you'll find that Schary
sticks very closely to what exactly happened in those four years. For
people who grew up in the Roosevelt era like Schary, like my parents,
Roosevelt approached almost deification in their minds. I would have
expected nothing less than that from Dore Schary, a certified New Deal
liberal in his politics.One summer after spending a day swimming in the Bay of Fundy on
Campbello Island where the Roosevelts had a summer home, Roosevelt was
taken down with chills which quickly developed into paralysis,
infantile paralysis, a dread scourge back in those days.Roosevelt's career was thought to be over. At the time the disease
struck him he was contemplating his next move after having run for Vice
President with James M. Cox in 1920 on the Democratic ticket. It was
thought he was finished then, he would retire to his estate at Hyde
Park with people occasionally remembering what might have been. That
was certainly what mother Sara, played by Ann Shoemaker wanted.It's not what Eleanor wanted and definitely not what Louis Howe wanted
who gave him the spark to overcome the limitations the disease put on
him, if not the disease himself. That's the story of Sunrise At
Campobello.Sunrise at Campobello got four Oscar nominations, Best costume design,
best art&amp;set direction, best sound and for Greer Garson, best actress.
Greer unfortunately was up against a sentimental vote for Elizabeth
Taylor who had battled back from disease herself that year for
Butterfield 8.However the film is best remembered for Ralph Bellamy as FDR. He became
the actor most identified with the role even though many like Dan
O'Herlihy and Arthur Hill have played FDR in other venues. Bellamy got
to repeat his portrayal of FDR in the acclaimed mini-series The Winds
Of War. It's certainly something better to remember him by than what he
had done before in films, usually the earnest goof who loses the
leading lady in the end.I highly recommend this film, especially for younger viewers who want
to get a glimpse of incipient presidential greatness. It holds up well
and will continue to for centuries.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0239428/comments</url><from>from Cleveland, Ohio</from><name>harry-76</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

"Sunrise at Campobello" enacts early events in the personal life of Franklin
Delano Roosevelt with fine production values, including solid
performances.Certainly both Ralph Bellamy and Greer Garson had their work cut out
playing, respectively, Franklin and Eleanor.  They got their
characterizations down pat, and their work is of a high calibre.The talented supporting cast is headed by Hume Cronyn as Franklin's best
friend and Ann Shoemaker as his doting mother. Jean Hagen is seen as a
good-natured secretary.It may be that Dore Schary's script from his play was too lengthy, or that
Vincent J. Donahue's direction was too slow.  Whatever the case, running at
144 minutes this seems a pretty long haul for the average viewer. Bellamy's work is consistently exectued, with all of the famous FDR
mannerisms--it is also slowly-paced.  Garson's Eleanor captures her
distinctivly slow, deliberate speech cadence.  Likewise, both principals'
makeups are subtely effective.The script begins in 1921 when Franklin was 40 and wisely ends just three
years later with his politically important nominating speech for Al Smith. 
While there may be some dramatic modifications of factual material, the
basic flavor of the period and characters are well handled.Fraklin's overcoming of physical adversity to become a four term US
president is a story of great interest, from both a human and professional
perspective.  "Sunrise at Campolbello" skillfully presents this inspired
period of American history.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1048771/comments</url><from>from U.S.A.</from><name>Neil Doyle</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
For anyone remotely interested in the history of U.S. presidents,
SUNRISE AT CAMPOBELLO does an outstanding job of recreating the period
of time during which Franklin Deleano Roosevelt coped with his victory
over suffering polio in his forties, just as his political ambitions
were taking shape.RALPH BELLAMY repeats his stage role and makes you forget that all he
ever played in his earlier movies were the hapless saps who lost the
girl in the last reel. He gives a full-bodied portrait of the man and
is ably assisted by an actress who seemed a most unlikely choice for
her role--GREER GARSON as Eleanor Roosevelt.With a striking supporting cast headed by HUME CRONYN as Roosevelt's
closest friend and adviser, the only weak point of the whole enterprise
is the length of time it takes to tell the story. 144 minutes is a long
time to sit through a tale such as this, crammed as it is with some
static scenes and full of dialog exchanges that go on for some length
of time.But all in all, it's a fascinating history lesson in that all of the
events unfold using a lot of historical background as to the politics
of the time. Oddly enough, Bellamy himself did not win an Oscar
nomination but Greer Garson did. She also won awards from The National
Board of Review and the Golden Globes as Best Actress.Well worth seeing, although it seems to wear out its welcome during the
last twenty-five minutes or so.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0053000/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>RodReels-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Ralph Bellamy gives perhaps his best performance as a very credible FDR.
Greer Garson and Hume Cronyn give their usual solid efforts, and the
supporting cast is all great.  The atmosphere is right.  The script is
surprisingly crisp, but the length of the piece weighs it down.  When it
reaches the two-hour mark, the whole movie starts to creak.  So if you
have
an interest in history and politics, it's great.  If not, it's tough
sledding up this long, steep hill.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur7722322/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>robert-891 (robert@campobello.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Sunrise at Campobello portrays the absolute in getting away from it
all.Campobello is famous for it's sunsets of which one of the trivia
questions asks of the two places with the most beautiful sunsets. One
of these places is Campobello Island. Although it is not meant to be a
spoiler, during the shooting of the movie the weather would not
cooperate to deliver the spectacular sunrise that was wanted. Instead
they filmed a sunset and ran it backwards. This can be varified by
noticing that the land in the background is Eastport Maine to the west,
when in fact a sunrise on Campobello shows no land to the east. I guess
if you have watched the movie it just proves a point. The sunsets here
on Campobello rate right up there with the sunrises. Being a long time
resident here on Campobello affords me many of both.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
In 1921, while summering at his Campobello estate, future U.S.
president Franklin D. Roosevelt (Ralph Bellamy) is stricken with
"infantile paralysis" (also known as polio). Though the use of his legs
is permanently lost, Mr. Roosevelt perseveres, combining inner strength
with the support of wife Eleanor (Greer Garson) and political pal Louis
Howe (Hume Cronyn). Ex-MGM production chief Dore Schary's "Sunrise at
Campobello" began its life as a Broadway hit, and is a little too
lengthy and theatrical as a motion picture. Still, it's an important
story, about what may well wind up being the most important world
leader of the twentieth century.The film also features what has become regarded, in many circles, as a
legendary portrayal of FDR by Mr. Bellamy, reprised in Dan Curtis'
mammoth mini-series "The Winds of War" (1983) and follow-up "War and
Remembrance" (1989). Bellamy's FDR won a "Tony" award, but was oddly
overlooked for an "Oscar" (the five nominees as "Best Actor" were also
deserving, however).Ms. Garson did receive an "Academy Award" nomination as "Best Actress"
for her portrayal of Eleanor; at the time, the role was considered a
stretch, which Garson pulled off. Her vocal work often sounds too
affected; but, so was the real Mrs. Roosevelt's voice, many would
argue. Garson outright won the dramatic actress award from both the
"Golden Globe" and the "National Board of Review" groups. Other
organizations noted Mr. Schary's film was one of the year's best, with
Vincent Donohue (Director), Bellamy, Garson, and Mr. Cronyn (Supporting
Actor) among the honorably mentioned. The real Mrs. Roosevelt seems to
have agreed.******* Sunrise at Campobello (9/28/60) Dore Schary : Vincent J.
Donehue ~ Ralph Bellamy, Greer Garson, Hume Cronyn, Tim Considine
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
In 1921, while summering at his Campobello estate, future U.S.
president Franklin D. Roosevelt (Ralph Bellamy) is stricken with
"infantile paralysis" (also known as polio). Though the use of his legs
is permanently lost, Mr. Roosevelt perseveres, combining inner strength
with the support of wife Eleanor (Greer Garson) and political pal Louis
Howe (Hume Cronyn). Ex-MGM production chief Dore Schary's "Sunrise at
Campobello" began its life as a Broadway hit, and is a little too
lengthy and theatrical as a motion picture. Still, it's an important
story, about what may well wind up being the most important world
leader of the twentieth century.The film also features what has become regarded, in many circles, as a
legendary portrayal of FDR by Mr. Bellamy, reprised in Dan Curtis'
mammoth mini-series "The Winds of War" (1983) and follow-up "War and
Remembrance" (1989). Bellamy's FDR won a "Tony" award, but was oddly
overlooked for an "Oscar" (the five nominees as "Best Actor" were also
deserving, however).Ms. Garson did receive an "Academy Award" nomination as "Best Actress"
for her portrayal of Eleanor; at the time, the role was considered a
stretch, which Garson pulled off. Her vocal work often sounds too
affected; but, so was the real Mrs. Roosevelt's voice, many would
argue. Garson outright won the dramatic actress award from both the
"Golden Globe" and the "National Board of Review" groups. Other
organizations noted Mr. Schary's film was one of the year's best, with
Vincent Donohue (Director), Bellamy, Garson, and Mr. Cronyn (Supporting
Actor) among the honorably mentioned. The real Mrs. Roosevelt seems to
have agreed.******* Sunrise at Campobello (9/28/60) Dore Schary : Vincent J.
Donehue ~ Ralph Bellamy, Greer Garson, Hume Cronyn, Tim Considine
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15896852/comments</url><from>from Earth</from><name>wes-connors</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/sunriseatcampobello.htm /m/sunrise_at_campobello/comments.php?reviewid=2025107</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
B
					</rating><comment>Inspirational biopic on the only American president to be elected for four terms.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>http://www.commonsensemedia.org/movie-reviews/sunrise-campobello  /m/sunrise_at_campobello/comments.php?reviewid=1949488</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Common Sense Media</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment>This is an exceptional and inspiring true story.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/nell-minow/</url><url>/m/sunrise_at_campobello/comments.php?reviewid=313131</url><name>Nell Minow</name><from>Movie Mom at Yahoo! Movies</from></reviewer><rating>
4/5
					</rating><comment/></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/bosley-crowther/</url><url>http://movies.nytimes.com/movie/review?res=9405E4DA1330EF3ABC4151DFBF66838B679EDE&amp;partner=Rotten Tomatoes /m/sunrise_at_campobello/comments.php?reviewid=1389039</url><name>Bosley Crowther</name><from>New York Times</from></reviewer><comment/></review></movie>