<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Tall Story</original_title><imdb_rating>6.2</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Joshua Logan</director><producer>Mansfield Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><genre>Sport</genre><synopsis>
Love puts a college basketball star into a tailspin.</synopsis><actor>Anthony Perkins</actor><actor>Jane Fonda</actor><actor>Ray Walston</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8585901/comments</url><from>from Seattle</from><name>okgal-1</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I love this film. Jane Fonda is darling and irresistible and Tony
Perkins is adorable. It is so blatantly 50's style sexist but great
fun. Great supporting cast including "My Favorite Martian" guy and
"Billy Jack". I just love Jane Fonda in this as well as in "Cat
Ballou". She is sexy and oh so American girl cute. Unfortunately, it is
not out on DVD yet, just VHS so I can't get it from netflix. I'm a
sucker for Doris Day/ Rock Hudson movies and this is in that genre. In
this movie, living in a trailer is celebrated and marriage is the goal
for every girl, just like in a Jane Austen story. Warning: extremely
sexy shower scene :), a far cry from the one in Psycho!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0249396/comments</url><from>from Marietta, GA, USA</from><name>Hermit C-2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

There was life before 'Psycho' for Anthony Perkins. I'm not so sure how
much
there was afterward. Prior to that movie's 1960 release (the same year as
'Tall Story') he could get roles in light comedies like this one, and
other
kinds of work, too. The Hitchcock picture identified him forever with one
character, and though he achieved fame, his options as an actor were
severely limited.That's a shame, because he's very good in this pleasant story of a college
basketball star being pursued by a single-mined husband-hunter. There are
some funny lines and moments, especially in the latter third of the
film.This was Jane Fonda's first starring role and she is already fully formed
as
an actress. With all due respect to Henry and Peter, even early on in her
career it's evident who was the standout talent in the Fonda family. She
must shake her head sometimes about the role she played here. Near the
film's start her character tells two professors she came to this college
because she was tall. They look puzzled, so she explains she will have a
better chance of snaring a husband at this school, with its outstanding
basketball program. This role might embarrass her more than
Barbarella.There's a fine supporting cast of old pros on hand including Ray Walston,
Marc Connelly, Anne Jackson and Murray Hamilton. Look closely and you'll
see
Gary Lockwood ('2001...') as one of the basketball players. But even if
you
are a fan of the 'Billy Jack' movies, you might not recognize Tom Laughlin
as a married friend of the young couple. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0253660/comments</url><from>from Memphis, TN</from><name>Lisa Kelly Sneed</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Perhaps most notable as Jane Fonda's screen debut, "Tall Story" is also
remarkable for what it didn't do for Anthony Perkins: define his acting
career. Released the same year as Hitchcock's classic thriller "Psycho,"
"Tall Story" shows the charming, naive and humorous side of Perkins. He
stars as Ray Blent, Custer's star basketball player and star student who
finds himself caught in an ethical nightmare just before the biggest game of
his life against the Russian Sputniks. Fonda is adorable as a cunning co-ed
whose one aim in college is to snare the unwitting Ray. Unfortunately, we
didn't see more Perkins characters like this one because the actor was
typecast as a psychotic madman following his admittedly excellent portrayal
of Norman Bates in "Psycho." This movie shows the virtuosity of a great
actor who regretfully didn't get the chance to demonstrate his full range of
acting skills more often. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16454388/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>  (my_wife_smells@yahoo.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I was pleasantly surprised to find this playing one morning on TCM. I
didn't know anything about the film before, so I was completely
unprepared for what turned out to be a truly delightful comedy. At
first I thought the movie was serious, then it started turning sillier
and sillier. Anthony Perkins and Jane Fonda do a great job. This was a
perfect vehicle for Fonda to launch her acting career. And I must admit
I agree with her - she does have quite beautiful legs, and I feel
fortunate that we are treated to seeing them in her cute little
cheerleader outfit.This movie is entertaining and I recommend viewing it on a lazy
afternoon one day, it is much better than watching re-runs of Gilligans
Island.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0989035/comments</url><from>from redlands, ca</from><name>moonspinner55</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
Jane Fonda before "Barbarella", Anthony Perkins the same year as
"Psycho", Tom Laughlin before "Billy Jack", Ray Walston doing the same
professor bit he utilized in "Fast Times At Ridgemont High", and still
the flick's a dud! Set on some mythical college campus with
well-scrubbed students who look as if they're about to burst into song
a la "Good News", it's a forced-friendly atmosphere that does little
for wispy story of a basketball player targeted by a pretty co-ed who
really wants A MAN! Fonda is alternately coy and coquettish--not a
credible mix--but does look cute in her chemistry glasses. Perkins
fares far worse, with a voice that sounds dubbed by a 12-year-old boy
on the verge of puberty. It's not a complete loss(the director is Josh
Logan, who knows how to put a picture together), but the results are
still awfully sticky. *1/2 from ****
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0171859/comments</url><from>from marion, oh</from><name>steve alden (littleton.24@eudoramail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Anthony Perkins shines as a small town basketball star
who
finds more than sports success at Custer College.  Jane
Fonda is wonderful in this morally simplistic depiction ofsmall town life.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4821881/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>stepale-1</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Tony Perkins wasn't type-cast after "Psycho." Not at first. For the
next six years, he went on to act in seven or eight other movies, most
of which were shot in Europe by some of the world's best directors
including Orson Welles, Claude Chabrol, Jules Dassin and Anatol Litvak
and none of the roles were similar to Norman Bates. In fact, Perkins
went on to be a bigger star in Europe than he ever had been in America
after starring in "Goodbye Again" in 1961, for which he won he Best
Actor Award at the Cannes Film Festival. "Pretty Poison," released in
1968, was the first movie in which he played a similar character to
Norman Bates, and only after that film did the "type-casting" begin.
But it was really all of the "Pyscho" sequels that did him in, so to
speak. Perkins had a wider range as an actor than producers, directors
(and casting directors) had given him credit. Too bad he did not have a
more "creative" agent for the second half of his career. (Ironically,
he was represented by CMA also known as "Creative Management
Associates.")
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4457450/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>fernanb</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
I am only commenting on this now, but I've thought about it for some
time. Tony Perkins is, without question, the most physically inept
actor ever to play an athlete on film. Ever see his portrayal of Jimmy
Piersall of the Boston Red Sox in "Fear Strikes Out"? This guy could
not walk and chew bubble gum at the same time. In "Tall Story," he
plays a college basketball star. Every time he goes to shoot the ball,
the next shot is a tight close-up of the ball going through the hoop.
What that should tell anyone is that the movie would have gone over
budget if they needed 500 takes before he could make an actual shot.
Really, no one should ever make a sports movie with a lead actor who is
so uncoordinated and klutzy. As far as being typecast after "Psycho,"
hey, Perkins was excellent as a crazy person, which is why "Fear
Strikes Out" wasn't a total bomb. Also excellent as disturbed persons
(it should be a separate genre) are Bruce Dern and Dennis Hopper,
except that both are better actors than Mr. Perkins was.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4457450/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>fernanb</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>
I am only commenting on this now, but I've thought about it for some
time. Tony Perkins is, without question, the most physically inept
actor ever to play an athlete on film. Ever see his portrayal of Jimmy
Piersall of the Boston Red Sox in "Fear Strikes Out"? This guy could
not walk and chew bubble gum at the same time. In "Tall Story," he
plays a college basketball star. Every time he goes to shoot the ball,
the next shot is a tight close-up of the ball going through the hoop.
What that should tell anyone is that the movie would have gone over
budget if they needed 500 takes before he could make an actual shot.
Really, no one should ever make a sports movie with a lead actor who is
so uncoordinated and klutzy. As far as being typecast after "Psycho,"
hey, Perkins was excellent as a crazy person, which is why "Fear
Strikes Out" wasn't a total bomb. Also excellent as disturbed persons
(it should be a separate genre) are Bruce Dern and Dennis Hopper,
except that both are better actors than Mr. Perkins was.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4457450/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>fernanb</name></reviewer><rating>3/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>