<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>The Bulldog Breed</original_title><imdb_rating>5.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>UK</country><director>Robert Asher</director><producer>Rank Organisation, The</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>
When he is crossed in love, grocers assistant Norman Puckle joins the Navy, where he is recruited to man the first British rocket.
</synopsis><actor>Norman Wisdom</actor><actor>Ian Hunter</actor><actor>David Lodge</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0695689/comments</url><from>from Derby, England</from><name>Davo123</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

'The Bulldog Breed' is one of my favourite Norman Wisdom films, but not one
of his best.It is interesting because of the space flight angle, and the
film certainly captures the mood of the era.In many respects this is a sad film; Puckle is portrayed as a rather tragic
character, who never really finds his niche.The whole films carries a
slight
air of depression about it, which is not helped by the melancholy music
score.There are several funny scenes, notably the 'man overboard' scene, the
diving lesson, and the mountain climbing episode. In all of these though,
the comedy is diluted by the overall gloom of the film.A hidden gem in the film are the brief, uncredited, appearances of Michael
Caine and Oliver Reed in the cinema foyer scene.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0156363/comments</url><from>from Bradford, England</from><name>Jim Cross (iamacamera@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

Norman Wisdom is- in all of his films- very human. The puppy-dog eagerness,
willingness to do anything set before him, ability to make a mistake and
then go on to make it worse- are, of course, the very stuff of the comic
character that he sets up for us to laugh at. But his genius lies in the
ability to make us identify with him, to 'live the life' with him, even as
we guffaw.In the Bulldog Breed there are stock characters aplenty, and the players act
their roles accordingly, but Wisdom- like a wicked imp- seems to dodge and
dart round the convention &amp; hierarchy that still- in 1960- characterized
much of the English way of doing things. He is like the benign counterpart
of a poltergeist: causing disruption, certainly, but not as an alien or
supernatural incursion, rather a human intervention into a stiff and inhuman
environment. The sequence in which he gets a whole ship's crew into the
water is an excellent example of this.One thing that often goes unremarked in Wisdom's films is the sexual
presence there. There is almost always some lubricious lovely in the line-up
and, in this case, Wisdom (after some other amorous adventures) ends up on
the beach with a girl in a grass skirt, being told to 'carry on'. By
contemporary standards what is there is so laughably little that it seems
distinctly odd to regard it as 'sex interest' but, in historical context, it
is definitely that, and as much a part of the humour as 'dirty postcards'
were a part of the English seaside holiday of the time.Bear in mind, by the way, that in the years running up to the first
moon-landing, this film is also a comment on Britain's presence in
space!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6694944/comments</url><from>from Archangel, Russia</from><name>Andrei Pavlov</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Well, kind of, because it's freaking funny. Why? It's about the first
man in space. "The Russians?" Even worse. The laughable disaster of
"Pitkin" kind.Again I'm writing a few words about a Norman Wisdom movie. And again
I've got nothing bad to say. A great comedy from the good old
black-and-white era. Finally in my DVD collection. I especially like
the way this movie jumps from one subject to another (while some other
reviewers are tend to consider it a drawback). Delivery service -
suicide topic - Royal Navy - space travelling. And Mr Norman Wisdom
delivers. He delivers his top-notch performance from the beginning of
this picture till the very end adding ridiculous "Aye aye, sir" to his
character's incompetent actions. And I was thoroughly surprised by the
ladies' actions. The scene where some hot chick lures Norman into
love-making is dynamite. How daring for 1960.Congratulations, Mr Norman Wisdom. You've made me laugh again. And not
just once or twice during the movie but continuously. The fabulous
highlights of the film for me are: Norman's collision with the local
band, the three ways of "doing oneself in", the famous "man overboard"
scene (I especially like the gun play here), the three ways of Norman's
"trials" (gymnastics, diving-costume, mountains), the ridiculous
"Attention!" boxing scene and a bit further - a reprise of it, and
space travel with Norman pushing every button to get any result. The
movie has also a very neat bunch of puns (look up the reference of this
comment – it is a brilliant example).And don't tell me the movie's rating is lower than 7 out of 10. It must
rub shoulders with Mr Charlie Chaplin's films on the top list. That's
what I think.10 out of 10 (yes, I know it is too subjective, so what?). Thanks for
attention.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14245978/comments</url><from>from Thailand</from><name>corrdepot</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I think the talent of Norman Wisdom has it's own unique quality.There is only one Norman Wisdom and that is what some believe is a
disadvantage because he seems to play the same character in all his
films, to others this is good and of great entertainment.Have been watching his films since I was a child up to present day,
they never fail to make me laugh, no matter how many times I see them.There seems to be a split amongst some about the talents &amp; films of
Norman Wisdom, they either hate him or love him. Personally I love him.Our Norman is in his 90s now. I wish him continued long life and long
may be reign.FromChiang Mai, Thailand
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0193118/comments</url><from>from England</from><name>Welly-2</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

As time passes, the warmth and innocence of Norman Wisdom films becomes a
rarer and rarer treat. This is one of his best and includes all of the
trade-mark ingredients. The scene where Norman throws the whole crew of a
Navy frigate overboard is priceless and the reaction of the supporting cast
to Norman throughout the film is as worth watching as the man himself. If
you like the predictable, honest and gentle humour of the black and white
Ealing era then this is one of the best. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16161013/comments</url><from>from United Kingdom</from><name>JohnRouseMerriottChard</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
The Bulldog Breed is a Norman Wisdom vehicle that's directed by Robert
Asher &amp; co-written by Wisdom with Henry Blyth &amp; Jack Davies. Plot sees
Wisdom as Norman Puckle, a hapless grocer's assistant who is hopelessly
in love with Marlene (Penny Morell). When she spurns his offer of
marriage he attempts to commit suicide, but he proves to be inept at
that as well. Finally settling on jumping off of "Lover's Leap" as a
sure fire way to die, he is saved at the last minute by a Naval Officer
who seduces him with talk of life as a sailor, where the girls are
plenty and life is totally great. Buying into it Norman enrols, but he
quickly finds that it's a tough life, that he is hopeless as a sailor
and that the commander wants to fly him off into outer space!.The Bulldog Breed comes at a time when Wisdom was most prolific on the
big screen, in a 17 year period from 1953 to 1969 Wisdom was the lead
star in 15 movies. While during this time he was lending support to a
number of ensemble and TV pictures too. It's inevitable that during a
busy period such as this that the quality of entertainment will vary,
this effort falls some where in the middle on the list of Wisdom's best
movies. The formula remains the same as Wisdom plays plays a bumbling
but lovable dope who creates carnage where ever he goes. The comedy set
pieces are many, with a "man overboard" sequence of events the
particular highlight. While it also serves as an interesting snap shot
of the times. Where The Bulldog Breed differs from many of Wisdom's
most fondly thought of film's is with its darker tones of suicide and
sexual suggestion (the latter beautifully brought to life by the sultry
Liz Fraser). It's an odd mix of a film, and one that has proved to
divide Wisdom purists. Newcomers to his work are most likely better off
choosing something else as a starting point to his movie output. 6/10Footnote: The film marks early appearances of Michael Caine and Oliver
Reed who share a scene together with Wisdom. While fans of British soap
Coronation Street will find value in seeing actors Johnny Briggs and
William Roache also appearing in the piece.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17284158/comments</url><from/><name>Aaron Hassard</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
In the bulldog breed, Norman is tricked into the navy, after many
attempts at committing suicide (which were quite funny!) but as soon as
he joins, the navy isn't all gorgeous girls as he was tricked into
thinking..... .....instead it's a hard life where Norman gets into all
sorts of trouble, getting is fellow Naval men three weeks leave for his
hilarious mistakes but they get the three weeks deducted off later
on.... ....he has been chosen to be the first man to enter space, but,
has to go through some rigorous training, which he fails miserably!
Which means that someone else had to be chosen for the expedition....
...but Norman finds his way onto the Space Craft after chasing a dog
and a rabbit onto the rocket (the dog and rabbit escape unharmed) but
Norman is left to man a space craft and successfully makes it back to
earth, crashing near an island which has a very beautiful girl on it,
Norman had to stay on the island for a fews hours, i'm sure he didn't
mind!So overall i'd give this film a 6/10 because it didn't have as many
laugh out loud moments as any other Norman Wisdom film i've watched,
but still very good
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
Entertaining but disjointed star farce in which Norman joins the Navy
after being jilted by the girl of his dreams; in fact, the plot takes
in all of the following and more: a scuffle outside a cinema (one of
the bullies who beat up Wisdom is none other than Oliver Reed!),
several hilarious attempts at suicide (by far the best scenes in the
film), the star doing conjuring tricks, some rather silly shipboard
shenanigans (as when Norman throws the entire crew overboard), an
amusing court-martial sequence (featuring John Le Mesurier as the
Prosecutor), a lengthy mountain-climbing episode and even a climax
which sends the star into outer space! The film's trick effects utilize
some crudely effective animation, and a reliable supporting cast
highlights Ian Hunter (as the ship's Admiral), David Lodge (usually the
brunt of Wisdom's antics), Edward Chapman (as the inventor of the
rocket) and Liz Fraser (from the delightful Peter Sellers vehicles I'M
ALL RIGHT, JACK! [1959] and TWO WAY STRETCH [1960]).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1256155/comments</url><from>from Northern Territory, Australia</from><name>club44</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Being a night baker by profession, I couldn't sleep on one of my nights
off.
Switching on the television I found myself intrigued by this '60's black
and white film.
This is a fun comedy based around a hapless lad "Puckle" who longs to
find a
place in the world around him and a lady to love.
Unfortunately for Puckle, he has somewhat of a reverse Midas-touch and
everything he sets his mind(?) to, comes undone.
At times you can sympathize, at others you can only laugh.
In my opinion this movie is a fun way to spend 90 odd minutes.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Grocer delivery boy Norman Puckle is frustrated in his attempts to et a
local girl and tries to kill himself.  However he is saved at the last
minute and told that to join the navy is to get all the girls he'll ever
want.  However Norman is not a sea-faring man by trade and struggles with
the disciplined lifestyle required.  Things are made worse when The Admiral
selects him for an experimental rocket as proof that any sailor could
operate it given the proper training.  He hadn't planned on
Norman.Wisdom is very much an acquired taste.  I'm not an Albanian but I do still
enjoy most of his films.  Here the plot sees him as, wait for it, a lowly
worker who makes good, gets the girl and shows up the toffs at the same
time!  So not a mile (or a yard) away from the usual fare then.  But that's
fine, the usual stuff is actually OK.  Here his usual routines are mostly OK
but some are just average.  If you usually get a laugh from it then this
will just about suffice.Wisdom is good and has a strong support cast.  However the problem is that
it feels too heavily on his shoulders and the rest aren't used well enough
to share the load.  When you've got actors like Hunter, Chapman, Jones,
Alexander and the ever great Le Mesurier then you need to use them.  Most
have the odd good line or two but I wanted more from all of
them.The comedy is basic and times and you know where it's heading from minute
number 1! I'm a fan and found this to be amusing but not Wisdom's best by
any means.  If this is your first meeting with Wisdom then you may be
disappointed, fans will enjoy it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

Grocer delivery boy Norman Puckle is frustrated in his attempts to et a
local girl and tries to kill himself.  However he is saved at the last
minute and told that to join the navy is to get all the girls he'll ever
want.  However Norman is not a sea-faring man by trade and struggles with
the disciplined lifestyle required.  Things are made worse when The Admiral
selects him for an experimental rocket as proof that any sailor could
operate it given the proper training.  He hadn't planned on
Norman.Wisdom is very much an acquired taste.  I'm not an Albanian but I do still
enjoy most of his films.  Here the plot sees him as, wait for it, a lowly
worker who makes good, gets the girl and shows up the toffs at the same
time!  So not a mile (or a yard) away from the usual fare then.  But that's
fine, the usual stuff is actually OK.  Here his usual routines are mostly OK
but some are just average.  If you usually get a laugh from it then this
will just about suffice.Wisdom is good and has a strong support cast.  However the problem is that
it feels too heavily on his shoulders and the rest aren't used well enough
to share the load.  When you've got actors like Hunter, Chapman, Jones,
Alexander and the ever great Le Mesurier then you need to use them.  Most
have the odd good line or two but I wanted more from all of
them.The comedy is basic and times and you know where it's heading from minute
number 1! I'm a fan and found this to be amusing but not Wisdom's best by
any means.  If this is your first meeting with Wisdom then you may be
disappointed, fans will enjoy it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1002035/comments</url><from>from Birmingham, UK</from><name>bob the moo</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>