<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Battle of Blood Island</original_title><imdb_rating>4.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Joel Rapp</director><producer>Bickman/Rapp Productions</producer><producer>San Juan Productions</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>War</genre><synopsis>
Two American GIs are the only survivors of a unit wiped out in a battle with Japanese troops on an isolated island. The two, who don't like each other, find try to put aside their differences in order to evade the Japanese and survive.
</synopsis><actor>Richard Devon</actor><actor>Ron Gans</actor><rt_rating/><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4214225/comments</url><from>from minneapolis, minnesota, on the planet Earth</from><name>cutterccbaxter</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A couple of soldiers are stranded on an island in the Pacific during WW
II. Richard Devon plays Moe, who in civilian life is a happily married
accountant. Ron Kennedy plays Ken who is a pitching prospect for the
Yankees in civilian life. At first Moe and Ken must survive hiding in a
cave as the island is occupied by the Japanese. They periodically kill
off a Japanese soldier here and there, and eventually the Japanese
soldiers figure there is no way to get out of the movie other than to
kill themselves. Moe and Ken then have the island and the movie
entirely to themselves. Ken is kind of a whiner (like most Yankee
players and fans) and he gets on Moe's nerves. At one point Moe says to
Ken, "Why you, I oughta..." For a low budget "war film" the movie is
actually more thoughtful than action oriented. I'm guessing this stems
from the Philip Roth story on which it is based. The fighting sequences
aren't staged particularly well, but I did find myself engrossed in the
plight of the two main characters.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6652148/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>asinyne</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
I definitely liked this film more than the other reviewers. Yeah, the
battle at the beginning was badly staged and kind of goofy. If the
marines fought anything like those guys we would have never won any war
period. Afterwards though I really enjoyed what essentially became a
tale of survival on a deserted island. Think Castaway here. One of the
soldiers is badly injured and depends on the other for almost every
single thing he needs. This puts a lot of stress on Moe who is pretty
darn high strung anyhow. Basically you have one physically incomplete
person and one mentally incomplete person somehow struggling through
all their issues while wondering if they're ever gonna see civilization
again or simply die in the middle of nowhere.This is more of a psychological film as opposed to the typical war
film. Yeah, there is lots of fighting and killing but what happens
internally to the two stranded GIs is what the movie is all about. I
found that it kept my interest very well indeed and wish I could have
given it a 7 and a half. The actor playing Moe was really good and his
face is pretty recognizable. He played lots of heavies and gangsters
back in the sixties.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
This film and "Shell Shock" have been packaged together by Something
Weird Video. Both are ultra-low budget WWII films that were made during
the post-war period. However, unlike the wretched and extremely boring
"Shell Shock", "Battle of Blood Island" manages to be entertaining
despite its many shortcomings.The biggest problem with the film is probably the title. There really
isn't any battle--at least not that you'll see in this action-less
action picture. When the story begins, a small group of US Marines have
already been killed as they were trying to take this small Pacific
island (though the film was actually made in Puerto Rico). Two manage
to survive...but one just barely. The healthy guy saves the wounded one
and they hide from the tiny occupying Japanese force through the first
half of the film. Then, a very odd thing happens. When the two soldiers
have mustered up the nerve to attack the dozen or so occupants, just
before they do so, the Japanese soldiers obligingly kill
themselves--apparently they just found out they lost the war and
decided to commit mass suicide. Now the two men realize that although
they will indeed survive, perhaps no one will ever come to rescue
them--after all, the island is small and the Americans probably assumed
the entire unit was wiped out in the earlier attack. This is a pretty
novel idea and without a working radio, I am sure there must been a few
cases like this at the end of the war.The relationship between the two men makes up an interesting second
half of the film. I especially was intrigued by what I thought was a
gay subtext late in the film when the one healthy guy did NOT try to
communicate with the American ships passing by--making you wonder if he
really liked the idea of spending the rest of his life with the other
man! But, sadly, the film didn't really follow up on this....making you
wonder WHY the healthy guy didn't try to signal the ship. A gay love
interest seems to be the only answer. But, despite this, the film still
is different and pretty well acted.By the way, the ending was only okay. I predicted that the island would
be Bikiki or some other island used for nuclear testing because goats
and other livestock were released on the islands to see the effects of
the bomb on them (that's kind of sad, huh?). But, I think they missed
their chance for a great twist ending. When the healthy guy was finally
discovered by the soldiers who were rounding up the goats and pigs,
wouldn't have been wild if at that point it turned out there really WAS
only one survivor on the island and the sick guy had died long before
and was only now a figment of the other man's imagination? This
"Twilight Zone" ending would have improved the film
considerably--especially since the ending otherwise didn't make
complete sense. Still, it's well worth a look.By the way, the film really blew it with the toucan. This bird lives
ONLY around the Caribbean as well as Central and South America--not the
Pacific. And, for that matter, they cannot talk like a parrot of mynha
bird. Oops.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6070953/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>jt_3d</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Poor combat scenes, a platoon of guys attacking an entire island,
defended by less than 20 guys, in rubber boats (the attacking guys, not
the defending guys). Actually they apparently only had one rubber boat.
You never see two at the same time but at least they saved like ten
bucks. At first the Japs are behind rocks, then after the battle we
find that it was actually an open beach. Americans shot down while
running back and forth in front of Japanese, like ducks in a shooting
gallery. One survivor was supposed to have caught a mortar frag in the
back but there wasn't a single explosion. Some of the Japs have M-1s
(incorrect) some have bolt action rifles (correct). Some have bolt
action rifles that fire multiple times without being cycled
(incorrect).But enough about the first two minutes of this movie. The movie itself
was actually not too bad as a tale of survival. Follow the antics of
the two survivors of a failed attack on a small Pacific island as they
try to survive on a slightly enemy held island. They have to off the
occasional Jap but it's mostly about rounding up something to eat and
keeping the whiny guy quiet. Soon enough our intrepid heroes decide the
island is too crowded and want to create some Lebensraum by doing unto
the enemy before the enemy can do unto them, with a bunch of grenades.
Alas, before any excitement can break out or anything can explode the
Japanese guys kill themselves.Now there's even less excitement left in this movie and we settle into
a dull grind of listening to the whiny guy say "Moe" over and over and
trying to figure out what's in that delicious soup Moe makes.Now as soon as I saw a goat had mysteriously appeared on the island I
had the ending written and there was going be one explosion in this
movie, even if it was stock footage. But no, they went with the least
interesting ending they could have used. Oh well.4/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4120034/comments</url><from>from Ireland</from><name>peapulation (peapulation@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>
Hello. - MOE! - I thought I would review this film, I don't usually,
but I feel inspred. - MOE! - The film is quite simple. Two men are the
only survivors of a disastrous attack on a Japanese island in WWII. -
MOE! -The two men are incompatible yet, they must stick together
because they only have each other.The more I think about it, the more is just wrong about the film. -
MOE! - One, 10,000 men were sent to the island and only two survive? It
looks like there is about twenty Japanese soldiers fighting them off.
And anyways, isn't 10,000 men too many for an island so small and
insignificant? - MOE - - MOE! - Most of it is just talking, and while
the soundtrack makes it sound like a B-horror movie by Ed Wood, and the
war suit will neither make it appealing to fans of war movies or talkie
dramas, the atmosphere is intense (or mind numbing, you decide). - MOE!
- Bottom line is that you will either hate this film or love it.P.S. Could Ken have said MOE! any more than he did in this film? :)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>
Two soldiers are stranded on a pacific island with the Japanese all
around them.Talky war film will either strike you as great drama or bore you to
tears. I kind of like it but I also can find it s a chore to get
through. I have this as a double feature tape from Sinister Cinema
where its paired with Ski Troop Attack. Depending on my mood after the
first film the lack of activity in this film has been known to put me
to sleep. Other times I'm fine. I know that's not a sterling
recommendation but it's the best I can do.Your mileage will probably vary as well.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6822728/comments</url><from>from Fahaheel, Kuwait</from><name>verbusen</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Before you balk at a 7 of 10 rating I'm giving this, it is in
proportion to the films budget which is mid 60's drive in movie, indi
production, very low money. It is on the 50 Movie Pack Combat Classics
collection through Amazon, I highly recommend it for the price of what
one or two movies alone go for. If your a Roger Corman fan you will
enjoy this movie. I'm not a big fan of Corman's stuff but I keep
watching it. I like hopeless situation movies usually post atomic war
stuff, and this has a bit of that taste. I found it at first fun to
watch seeing the dramatized invasion (you have to use suspension of
belief in this movie which I did), but then the situation of two GI's
(one wounded and para-pelagic) on an island abandoned with a squad of
Japanese was something I never saw before so I got into it. It then
turned into a drama of men going insane and of course what would a war
movie be without a little racial bigotry thrown in for even more easy
drama. I was hoping the ending would turn out different in a bad way,
it would have been a very Cormanesque twist like he did in that cave
man movie I think titled teenage caveman. Anyway for a really low
budget forgotten drive in war flick it's a good one to catch, 7 of 10.
It does seem a lot longer then 68 minutes though. Corman is uncredited
as a soldier in this one as well so you see some versions packaged with
his face on the cover but as far as I can tell on IMDb he is an
uncredited actor only, maybe he made this under a different name?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur6822728/comments</url><from>from Fahaheel, Kuwait</from><name>verbusen</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Before you balk at a 7 of 10 rating I'm giving this, it is in
proportion to the films budget which is mid 60's drive in movie, indi
production, very low money. It is on the 50 Movie Pack Combat Classics
collection through Amazon, I highly recommend it for the price of what
one or two movies alone go for. If your a Roger Corman fan you will
enjoy this movie. I'm not a big fan of Corman's stuff but I keep
watching it. I like hopeless situation movies usually post atomic war
stuff, and this has a bit of that taste. I found it at first fun to
watch seeing the dramatized invasion (you have to use suspension of
belief in this movie which I did), but then the situation of two GI's
(one wounded and para-pelagic) on an island abandoned with a squad of
Japanese was something I never saw before so I got into it. It then
turned into a drama of men going insane and of course what would a war
movie be without a little racial bigotry thrown in for even more easy
drama. I was hoping the ending would turn out different in a bad way,
it would have been a very Cormanesque twist like he did in that cave
man movie I think titled teenage caveman. Anyway for a really low
budget forgotten drive in war flick it's a good one to catch, 7 of 10.
It does seem a lot longer then 68 minutes though. Corman is uncredited
as a soldier in this one as well so you see some versions packaged with
his face on the cover but as far as I can tell on IMDb he is an
uncredited actor only, maybe he made this under a different name?
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>