<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Hanyo</original_title><imdb_rating>7.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>South Korea</country><director>Ki-young Kim</director><producer>Kuk Dong</producer><producer>Seki Trading Co.</producer><genre>Crime</genre><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
The hero, a composer, has an immoral relation to a maid. The maid is jealous of his wife and gives vent to her bad temper to him. When the hero rebukes her, she asks him for dying together for love.
</synopsis><actor>Eun-shim Lee</actor><actor>Jeung-nyeo Ju</actor><actor>Jin Kyu Kim</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4009887/comments</url><from>from NYC</from><name>Lina  (backfisch)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Allow me to add to the hype: this film is as delirious as they come.
Starting out as a typical realist glance into 1960's South Korea as
centered on a upwardly-mobile family, after the plot gets settled,
becomes a hysterical and expressionistic tale of corrosive sin and
deception. The transformation of one night's flirtation into a
grandiose moral eradication is the one of the most stunning turns of
atmosphere I've ever seen in a film. Also amazing is how your view of
the characters changes dramatically as they are faced with this living
hell. While researching about the director, I found out that the
actress who played the housemaid, Eun-shim Lee, fulfilled the part so
well that she couldn't find work after this movie. Audience members
were literally screaming for her death at the original showings! See
this film just for her, you won't regret it! I can't say enough great
things about the director Kim Ki-young, too bad most of his films
aren't available in English!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0456282/comments</url><from>from San Francisco</from><name>poikkeus</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Sometimes, it's too easy to give abnormally high ratings to films may
not necessarily deserve the honor. The good news is that Hanyo (The
Housemaid) is the real thing - the kind of rarity that fills the viewer
with such astonishment that you talk about it years later. Kim Ki-young's 1960 masterpiece must be seen at the first possible
opportunity -- if you have the luck. This black and white morality tale
is pure black comedy, the almost-campy tale of a respectable music
teacher whose life is soon complicated with a passion for one of his
students. The tone is not unlike a deliciously lurid pre-Code drama
about the withering power of vice, but The Housemaid almost takes
pleasure at showing the incremental erosion of morality and the
corrosiveness of sin. The strange subtitles, some handwritten, only add
to the atmosphere. And if you're blown away by the deadpan comedy,
prepare yourself for an ending that will leave you slack-jawed for
days. The movie's a miracle.Hanyo's construction is inventive and completely unpredictable - a
fascinating case-study on Confucian ethics. It's so good that Martin Scorsese and other sponsors funded a complete
restoration of the old print, which includes painstakingly subtitle
tracks. They did an outstanding job restoring a problematic print that
was at the same time extremely rare.You should be able to catch a free
streaming video that's fully authorized.
(http://www.theauteurs.com/films/2039)Or better yet, the DVD has just been released, and contains additional
material about its restoration
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0094793/comments</url><from>from W. Hollywood, CA</from><name>NeelyO</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>

Suicides, attempted suicides, blackmail, murder, attempted murder,
adultery,
paranoia -- the goings-on in this bizarre and fascinating melodrama put
even
MANJI to shame.No wonder one critic calls director Kim "Douglas Sirk on acid" -- while
Western audiences may laugh at some of the overheated melodrama, this
potboiler nonetheless is pretty wild for 1960, and manages to be both lurid
and unforgettable. (It's also got one of the great death scenes *ever* --
see for yourself!)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0891256/comments</url><from>from Minneapolis</from><name>mlovmo-2</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

I bought this film on NTSC-VHS format from an online Korean business
called koreapop.com.  The copy evidently had been put together from two or
three diffrent copies of the film, since some parts of the film looked
like
they were in better shape than others, and also there were English
subtitles
in some parts, but not most others.  (Note that I bought this film knowing
that it would be in Korean, with no subtitles).This movie features what is probably the first scene in cinematic
history where a woman rapes a man- a whole 25 years before Isabella
Rosellini raped Kyle McCallahan in "Blue Velvet"!  As a Korean movie, it's
story challenges traditional Korean propriety.  The housemaid character is
a
castrating hose-beast: Not exactly the kind of Korean woman portrayed in
most Korean movies made then or now.  Director Kim Kiyoung tends to turn
the
conventional Korean-movie plotline on its head in this movie, since there
is
no real "happy-ending", in fact, things just seem to get worse and worse.
The only other Korean movie similar to it in this sense, is the recently
released "Kilimanjaro" (also an EXCELLENT film).  This movie is indeed a
Korean-movie classic.  It's just too bad that the remaining copies of such
classic Korean films are not given the best of care, since many, like this
one, are in fairly rough shape.  I hope that the Koreans will take more
pride in their cinematic history and prepare for better archival storage
and
restoration of their nation's film legacy.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0812631/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>refresh daemon</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I remember the first time I ever watched The Housemaid, during a Korean
cinema series hosted by Harvard and it left quite the impression on me.
I knew that a lot of older Korean films suffered the ravages of time
and the lack of proper care, so the picture and the sound were both at
times abysmal, but recently, the World Cinema Foundation assisted the
Korean Film Archive in restoring this film and I was quite curious how
it turned out. I also wanted to own what is assuredly a classic of
Korean-- nay--world cinema and was hopeful to get my hands on this long
awaited DVD release, but I waited too long on its initial pressing and
it went out of print. But, with the theatrical re-release in Korea this
past June, I guessed correctly that another printing of this film would
be made and this time I didn't let it slip through my fingers.The Housemaid follows in a long tradition of Korean domestic
melodramas, but happens to also be directed by the subversive Kim
Kiyoung, whose films gained popularity with female audiences. In The
Housemaid, an upwardly mobile music teacher, Dongshik (Kim Jingyu) who
holds a cushy job teaching music to women factory workers is pushed by
his wife (Joo Jeungnyuh) to build a larger house to accommodate their
growing family. To this end he takes on a private student among the
many students, although a scandal involving an infatuated student
results in some tumult. Also, due to the greater responsibilities of
managing the larger house on a pregnant wife, they hire a coworker of
their student's as the titular housemaid (Lee Eunshim in the only role
she would ever have as an actress due to the notoriety of her
performance). However, the somewhat strange young woman that comes to
work as their maid would destabilize the house, with lust, greed and
betrayal colliding in a maelstrom of domestic destruction.I absolutely love the progression of the story from happy and stable to
absolute domestic tumult and the corruption of the seemingly good
family, even the little cracks, resulting in its fall with the
housemaid as a catalyst. This is, for the wife, a tale of hubris, for
the husband, a tale of his ultimate ineffectiveness and for the
housemaid, a story about ambition and I like how all three of these
principal characters all have independent motivations that result in
these schisms in the household. Most interestingly, although the
housemaid is certainly a domestic villain, she isn't painted as a
complete monster either, but is actually drawn with a measure of
sympathy, even as she uses it to attempt to get what she wants. Also
very interesting, but expounded upon better in many academic papers, is
the subtle and even subversive commentary on domestic and social
structures in the post-war era Korea. Yet, the film clearly follows the
ethical codes of the times, allowing it to be excepted by viewers at
large.Kim is clearly aware of expressive directorial techniques and can
certainly draw parallels to Alfred Hitchcock himself in terms of the
visual dynamism in his framing and mis-en-scene, despite that the space
he's using in the Housemaid is largely limited to a small handful of
indoor locations. And, perhaps in concession to the fact that audiences
were likely to react strongly to the film's bleak depiction of domestic
downfall, he actually builds in a fourth wall breaking moment that hits
another level of the surreal in the film. Credit also goes to the
actors for their performances, which, while not natural per the
conventions of modern cinema, expressively capture the progression of
the story in their bodies as the acting morphs to match the
increasingly distraught tone in the story. Lee Eunshim, in particular,
does a great job of physically embodying the kind of strange
instability with a glint of crazy in her eye that eventually infects
the other characters.The Housemaid is considered a classic and with good reason. Kim would
make many other challenging-while-entertaining films in his career, but
Housemaid captures so many elements at once, with inspired filmmaking
and strong performances tied into an almost surreal-but-conceivable
story and striking presentation. The new restoration takes the whole
thing to another level with many of the scenes being stunningly clean
and clear, with so many of the specks and scratches cleaned out and
even the previously burned in subtitles removed (leaving a few
shimmering artifacts here and there). It's still clear that there are
frames that weren't able to be saved and other scenes clearly use an
inferior quality print, but I really never thought I'd see an old
Korean film like this looking as good as the Housemaid does. I can't
recommend the Housemaid to everyone quite simply because it's a product
of another era, but for cinephiles, I think it's a fascinating and
compelling watch. 8/10.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur5580339/comments</url><from>from Singapore</from><name>Eternality</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
It was only in the last two decades that Korean cinema had slowly
become a force to be reckoned with. Today, Korean films set the
standard for Asian cinema, and are only occasionally bettered by films
from Japan, China, Taiwan, and Hong Kong. Some of Korea's top
filmmakers, such as Park Chan-wook, Kim Ki-duk, and Bong Joon-ho, to a
name a few, are now rubbing shoulders with the great directors of
Europe, frequently taking part and winning awards in film festivals
like Cannes and Venice.The renaissance (if that is the correct word) of contemporary Korean
cinema owes a debt to Kim Ki-young's The Housemaid, one of only a few
great films to emerge post-war from the country. The Housemaid is about
a happy family who are torn apart by a maid hired by the husband to
help with daily chores. The maid seduces the husband and tries to wield
control over his materialistic wife who is pregnant. The maid also has
tensions with their children – a crippled daughter and a mischievous
boy.The Housemaid starts out like an Ozu-esquire drama where life couldn't
be more ordinary, with Kim taking his time to flesh out the film's
major characters. The first scene immediately foreshadows what is to
come later: The husband, who is reading the paper, is aghast at a
report of a man who committed adultery with his maid. His wife reacts
by replying, "Men are hopeless, taking interest in a maid." Their maid
unsurprisingly appears in the second-quarter of the film, bringing an
ominous development to the proceedings. The performance by the actress
(I can't quite figure out her name) who plays the maid is tremendous,
providing Korean cinema with one if its vilest villains. She hides her
"sexual predator" self under her shy demeanor, only exposing her true
colors when she finds herself alone with her master.Kim also sets up the mood of the film to work out like a "haunted
house" picture. Many of the external shots are that of lashing rain and
blinding lightning, giving the film a sinister edge. His direction is
assured, and slowly but surely, he navigates his film into horror
territory. The second hour of The Housemaid is unpredictable. The
situation that unfolds border on disturbing material, with Kim
exploring the worst of human nature.The climax is frightening not because it is horrific, but because it is
tragic. Kim also adds a layer of dark humor into the dialogue, which
coupled with some over-the-top acting, helps to make the film less
grim. Nevertheless, The Housemaid remains as a stinging social
commentary and a powerful tale of lust, greed, and revenge. In the
final scene that breaks the "fourth wall', men are mocked for their
ease of succumbing to temptations of flesh, like tiger to fresh meat.
But really, is it fair to put the blame on one half of the human race?SCORE: 8/10 (www.filmnomenon.blogspot.com) All rights reserved!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1416505/comments</url><from>from Groningen, The Netherlands</from><name>Boba_Fett1138</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This movie was a real surprise. I knew nothing about this director, or
'old' Korean cinema, so I had no idea what to expect from this movie. I
was really surprised at how incredibly well and professionally it got
directed and the story got written, as if it all got done by some big
Hollywood names involved, with years of experience in the business
under their belt.Everything about this movie got basically done extremely well. Asian
cinema is not often known to feature the fastest pace but this movie
has a very pleasant quick pace to it and still manages to build up its
characters and drama as powerful and effective as any other old and
much slower Asian genre attempt. This is of course for most part due to
the directing approach of Ki-young Kim, that is nothing short of
brilliant to be honest. There are some amazingly well set up moments in
the movie, that get brought beautifully and at times even artistically
to the screen.But it's also due to the fine written story, by Ki-young Kim as well,
that makes this movie such an extremely good one. It's a quite simple
movie, in terms of that it doesn't feature that many characters in it
and it is being set for most part at only two different locations; an
house and a factory. What I foremost liked about the story was that all
of the characters within it interact differently with each other and
each of them have a different feeling and opinion about the other. It
lets the story and all of its emotions and tension work out so very
well. And this is all despite the fact that the movie just doesn't
really have the most likely and convincing story in it. Or perhaps this
is more due to the fact that's its about an entirely different culture,
so all of the character motivations and their actions often seem like
odd ones, through modern Western eyes.The movie is being a (melo)drama but with definitely a thriller
overtone to it. The movie features some classic, effective genre
elements, such as a great sense of claustrophobia, a constant sense of
danger and unpredictability to it all, overall desperateness and even a
femme fatale.It's also being a very well cast movie. Not only do all of the actors
really let their characters work out well but they also all seem to
have the right looks for their part. They are also all very distinctive
looking, so you never have to worry about mixing one or two different
South-Koreans up with each other, like perhaps sometimes is the case in
other black &amp; white Asian movies, in which all of the characters look
alike with the same costumes and hairstyles.One surprisingly great movie, that got beautifully and fully restored
by Martin Scorsese's World Cinema Foundation.9/10http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur17699578/comments</url><from>from Greece</from><name>chaos-rampant</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
I haven't seen before melodrama as stunning, shocking, utterly
ridiculous and in full knowledge of it, Korea's cautionary tale answer
on marital infidelity to Reefer Madness if it weren't at the same time
as cinematically vibrant and obstinate as the best works of Sam Fuller,
driven by suspenseful will and heavy with undertones of something at
once sinister and horrifying to make you think parts of it were
destined at some point for Les Diaboliques or Whatever Happened to Baby
Jane, as Ki-young Kim's The Housemaid; for all intents and purposes,
this is melodrama a-go-go, not in the cosmopolitan sense of the term,
but ironic and campy, a dazzling movie steeped in artifice and insanely
interesting human behaviour that sets out to provoke and push common
sense to a limit.A well to do couple hires a maid to help out the wife with the chores
around the house, but no sooner has she gone into the kitchen to get a
glass of water than the entire household threatens to collapse in ruins
of rat poison and unwanted pregnancies, illicit thrysts and alliances
striken casually and alternatively between the wife and the maid who is
now a mistress, the wife and the husband against the maid who they need
to get rid of before she speaks to anyone about her love affair with
the husband, the maid and the husband against their own selves.The other movie I've seen by Ki-young Kim, Iodo, a Korean version of
The Wicker Man that takes place in a remote island populated
exclusively by fisherwomen, was also utterly bonkers and made up of the
most outrageous plotting imaginable this side of Italian exploitation,
but it lacked the ability to see that in itself, to recognize the
madness and defy it. The Housemaid at first seems like the product of
Ed Wood incompetence. Some of the dialogue and character behavior had
me in stitches. But it soon reveals that to be a facade which the movie
can lift and put back in place at whim, so that it can be all things to
all people not because of any particular notion of ambiguity shared by
Ki-young Kim because the movie is blunt like a hammer in the face, but
because it doesn't abide by any notion of common sense or realism
unless it wants to. The movie behaves with the same audacity of its
maid protagonist. It sets up an image of a socially upwards mobile
household where a couple can afford to buy a television even if it
means hours of slaving away on a sewing machine to get it, and then
affronts it violently, perversely toys with it and corrupts it to the
heart.In the end, if any more clue was required, we get fourth walls broken
and a man winking straight at us. This is Le Théâtre de l'Absurde at
its best where life is revealed to be inherently meaningless, with the
avantgarde tropes replaced by soap opera clichés.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0112151/comments</url><from>from Hong Kong</from><name>kam-wing pang (kamwingpang@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

When I first watched this I thought 'what is this film'? I mean, all the
characters are over the top, the emotions were so unreal, the situations so
stupid (and often hilarious when it was intended to be to serious) that I
didn't know what to feel. I was in serious doubt that this film could have
been a Korean classic! Then the last 5 minutes changed everything you felt
about the film and it all made sense! The film is indeed a classic and worth
watching!It's about a man and how one mistake in his life caused so much death and
sadness in his family. It goes through various surreal situations which made
me laugh. There seemed to be some frustration that I felt since the actors
were like in a comic book yet portrayed a serious topic which shouldn't have
been funny at all, yet you laugh anyway... 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16146381/comments</url><from>from Japan</from><name>Drago_Head_Tilt</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A piano and music teacher (Kim Jin-Kyu) and his seamstress wife (Ju
Jeung-Ryu) are busy being middle-class and upwardly mobile, renovating
a second home and buying all the new material goods (including a TV
set). Enter into this already somewhat dysfunctional setting a
simple-minded housemaid (Lee Eun-Shim) with her eyes on him. One act of
infidelity and a myriad stupid reactions to it fueled by desperate,
stifling adherence to social conventions results in a bizarre,
absurdist psychodrama that must have packed quite a punch at the time.
Thanks to a restored DVD print remastered by the World Cinema
Foundation (thanks Martin Scorsese), modern audiences can now enjoy
this unique cult gem (and do double-takes at the fourth-wall-breaking
coda). With Um Aing-Ran and Seong Ei-Ahn (later a very famous actor) as
the young boy. The great b/w photography is by Kim Deok-Jin. Director
Kim (apparently quite the auteur, and here's hoping for more of his
works are re-released soon) more-or-less remade the same story twice
(in 1970 and 1982), and 2010 saw an official remake.Movie reviews at: spinegrinderweb.com
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur16146381/comments</url><from>from Japan</from><name>Drago_Head_Tilt</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
A piano and music teacher (Kim Jin-Kyu) and his seamstress wife (Ju
Jeung-Ryu) are busy being middle-class and upwardly mobile, renovating
a second home and buying all the new material goods (including a TV
set). Enter into this already somewhat dysfunctional setting a
simple-minded housemaid (Lee Eun-Shim) with her eyes on him. One act of
infidelity and a myriad stupid reactions to it fueled by desperate,
stifling adherence to social conventions results in a bizarre,
absurdist psychodrama that must have packed quite a punch at the time.
Thanks to a restored DVD print remastered by the World Cinema
Foundation (thanks Martin Scorsese), modern audiences can now enjoy
this unique cult gem (and do double-takes at the fourth-wall-breaking
coda). With Um Aing-Ran and Seong Ei-Ahn (later a very famous actor) as
the young boy. The great b/w photography is by Kim Deok-Jin. Director
Kim (apparently quite the auteur, and here's hoping for more of his
works are re-released soon) more-or-less remade the same story twice
(in 1970 and 1982), and 2010 saw an official remake.Movie reviews at: spinegrinderweb.com
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>