<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ren hai gu hong</original_title><imdb_rating>5.6</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Hong Kong</country><director>Sun-fung Lee</director><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Family</genre><synopsis/><actor>Cho-fan Ng</actor><actor>Yin Pak</actor><actor>Bruce Lee</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317399/comments</url><from>from Singapore</from><name>DICK STEEL</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
As a fan of Bruce Lee, I've seen his landmark movies countless of
times, from The Big Boss right up until Game of Death. However, he's
appeared in non martial arts roles before, and I wouldn't have missed
the festival's screening of The Orphan for the world, being projected
in 35mm glory from the Hong Kong Film Archives, though with some colour
correction irregularities that had the film sitting in a lab for 30
years. But that's another story altogether.The first few minutes already got my interest piqued, not because my
idol had appeared, but for its documentary value in seeing Hong Kong in
the 60s, fronted by an almost unrecognizable harbour front. Outdoor
shots though were few and far between throughout the movie, and for a
60s movie like the locally made Lion City, one chief reason besides
nostalgia, is to gawk at how advanced a city has progressed through the
lens of a movie camera. I thought something of value here, which I
wasn't aware, was how even Dragon Dance has evolved – it wasn't as if
the entire dragon piece was stitched together in one seamless fabric,
but was rather quite fragmented, with sections of the head to the body
connected by rope, looking as if it was a really nasty and mean looking
creature with protruding skeletal structure. Interesting.The story wasn't something to shout about, largely centered upon a
director of an orphanage school, Ho Si-Kei (played by Ng Cho-fan, who
also wrote the story), who had lost his family during the war, where
the daughter and wife perished from a collapsing wall, and the son and
nanny disappeared, whereabouts unknown. While he may have lost his
family, in return he got a new one through his care of the many orphans
in the school.It's not that difficult to see that the film was intended to address
some of society's ills and indifference, especially to youth and youth
crimes. There was lengthy discourse between characters about what
affluent society should do to attempt to arrest the root of juvenile
delinquency, and of society at large shirking responsibility in the
pursuit of wealth. The wealthy, though stereotyped, get to be put on
the spot, and probably reflected what the working class's perception of
their unwillingness to lend a hand. In fact, they don't really redeem
themselves even in the end, probably largely reflecting on their
reliance on the good Samaritans to do what is right, and to combat
juvenile crime single handedly.That got personified through Ho Si-Kei, and at times you can feel his
loneliness at such an uphill battle. He got brushed aside by wealthy
families who probably alluded his presence to asking for donations, he
has difficulty in trying to attract and retain teaching staff – it
isn't easy trying to teach and inspire wayward youths – and actually
becomes the sole decision maker in the running of the school, as if
lacking administrators. In all, a one man show, and for someone who
prides himself at teaching and obtaining results, the last act has him
in shock when a surprising discovery turns out to be sort of a slap in
the face for all he stood for.Besides a short sub-plot about possible romance between him and a
fellow teacher, the star of the show is undoubtedly Bruce Lee as Ah
Sam, a petty thief fashioned after Oliver Twist, whose inclination for
thievery stemmed from a need to belong to a larger family, where he's
doing not so bad in terms of hierarchy (No 3 in the gang). And you'd
have a chance to discover that he's quite the dancer too with his mean
cha-cha moves, linked to delinquent lifestyles to be frowned upon at
that era.While he's usually stoic and a man of few words in his more renowned
movies, here he's got plenty to talk about in presenting himself as a
street corner gangster, and it's really rare to see him being really
loose with his mouth where swear words fly, and I don't really recall
his lighting up of cigarettes in those movies too. There were two sides
of his character here, the filial one in front of his nanny, and the
real, confused him when out there in the real world.Given storytelling techniques of the past not being too refined or
subtle (the music usually lets the cat out of the bag), you would just
know the big important secret when both Ah Sam and Director Ho cross
paths. Although the final act might seem a little messy and hastily
reconciled, the fun factor in the movie still belongs to Bruce Lee in a
role that is not often seen by contemporary fans of his, and for that,
like the other movies in his filmography, should be seen more widely
when opportunity presents itself again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317399/comments</url><from>from Singapore</from><name>DICK STEEL</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
As a fan of Bruce Lee, I've seen his landmark movies countless of
times, from The Big Boss right up until Game of Death. However, he's
appeared in non martial arts roles before, and I wouldn't have missed
the festival's screening of The Orphan for the world, being projected
in 35mm glory from the Hong Kong Film Archives, though with some colour
correction irregularities that had the film sitting in a lab for 30
years. But that's another story altogether.The first few minutes already got my interest piqued, not because my
idol had appeared, but for its documentary value in seeing Hong Kong in
the 60s, fronted by an almost unrecognizable harbour front. Outdoor
shots though were few and far between throughout the movie, and for a
60s movie like the locally made Lion City, one chief reason besides
nostalgia, is to gawk at how advanced a city has progressed through the
lens of a movie camera. I thought something of value here, which I
wasn't aware, was how even Dragon Dance has evolved – it wasn't as if
the entire dragon piece was stitched together in one seamless fabric,
but was rather quite fragmented, with sections of the head to the body
connected by rope, looking as if it was a really nasty and mean looking
creature with protruding skeletal structure. Interesting.The story wasn't something to shout about, largely centered upon a
director of an orphanage school, Ho Si-Kei (played by Ng Cho-fan, who
also wrote the story), who had lost his family during the war, where
the daughter and wife perished from a collapsing wall, and the son and
nanny disappeared, whereabouts unknown. While he may have lost his
family, in return he got a new one through his care of the many orphans
in the school.It's not that difficult to see that the film was intended to address
some of society's ills and indifference, especially to youth and youth
crimes. There was lengthy discourse between characters about what
affluent society should do to attempt to arrest the root of juvenile
delinquency, and of society at large shirking responsibility in the
pursuit of wealth. The wealthy, though stereotyped, get to be put on
the spot, and probably reflected what the working class's perception of
their unwillingness to lend a hand. In fact, they don't really redeem
themselves even in the end, probably largely reflecting on their
reliance on the good Samaritans to do what is right, and to combat
juvenile crime single handedly.That got personified through Ho Si-Kei, and at times you can feel his
loneliness at such an uphill battle. He got brushed aside by wealthy
families who probably alluded his presence to asking for donations, he
has difficulty in trying to attract and retain teaching staff – it
isn't easy trying to teach and inspire wayward youths – and actually
becomes the sole decision maker in the running of the school, as if
lacking administrators. In all, a one man show, and for someone who
prides himself at teaching and obtaining results, the last act has him
in shock when a surprising discovery turns out to be sort of a slap in
the face for all he stood for.Besides a short sub-plot about possible romance between him and a
fellow teacher, the star of the show is undoubtedly Bruce Lee as Ah
Sam, a petty thief fashioned after Oliver Twist, whose inclination for
thievery stemmed from a need to belong to a larger family, where he's
doing not so bad in terms of hierarchy (No 3 in the gang). And you'd
have a chance to discover that he's quite the dancer too with his mean
cha-cha moves, linked to delinquent lifestyles to be frowned upon at
that era.While he's usually stoic and a man of few words in his more renowned
movies, here he's got plenty to talk about in presenting himself as a
street corner gangster, and it's really rare to see him being really
loose with his mouth where swear words fly, and I don't really recall
his lighting up of cigarettes in those movies too. There were two sides
of his character here, the filial one in front of his nanny, and the
real, confused him when out there in the real world.Given storytelling techniques of the past not being too refined or
subtle (the music usually lets the cat out of the bag), you would just
know the big important secret when both Ah Sam and Director Ho cross
paths. Although the final act might seem a little messy and hastily
reconciled, the fun factor in the movie still belongs to Bruce Lee in a
role that is not often seen by contemporary fans of his, and for that,
like the other movies in his filmography, should be seen more widely
when opportunity presents itself again.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0317399/comments</url><from>from Singapore</from><name>DICK STEEL</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>