<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Stop! Look! and Laugh!</original_title><imdb_rating>5.5</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>USA</country><director>Don Appell</director><producer>Harry Romm Productions</producer><genre>Comedy</genre><synopsis>More fun than a barrel of Monkeys! (original one-sheet poster)</synopsis><actor>Moe Howard</actor><actor>Larry Fine</actor><actor>Curly Howard</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1335437/comments</url><from/><name>crusefamily</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

STOP! LOOK! AND LAUGH! was a compilation film linking ten of their shorts
together. The film is okay, but The Three Stooges aren't shown enough. And
the background music added into the film is not even funny, it's more
serious. This is the basic plot. At the beginning, Paul Winchell tells his dummy,
Jerry Mahoney, how the world began (features a clip of the stooges as
monkeys) and he talks about how water came, the the stooges are shown
floating down the river in footage from HOW HIGH IS UP? From here, we get
the whole construction worker scenes. Then he tells Jerry the story of three gas station worker, and we see them
in footage from VIOLENT IS THE WORD FOR CURLY, the only stooge short to have
a stooge name in it. We do new footage after the stooges fall in the lake.Then Paul Winchell talks about Jerry as a baby, and then hears a real one
crying, in footage from SOCK-A-BYE BABY. Then we get a basically complete
version of that short. Paul checks on his car, and we see garage footage from HIGHER THAN A KITE.
They do new footage after the parts fall out of the car. After that, Paul
tells Jerry about Mexico (footage from WHAT'S THE MATADOR?).Then he calls the hospital after Jerry fakes getting sick, and we see all
the footage from CALLING ALL CURS. Then Jerry watches a western TV show, and
we see chase scenes from GOOFS AND SADDLES. Then Paul calls the plumbers to fix the sink, and we see parts of
MICRO-PHONIES and A-PLUMBING WE WILL GO. And then we see a terribly long
scene with Paul telling Jerry the story of Cinderella, acted by chimps.The film ends with scenes of HALF-WITS HOLIDAY and Paul trying to end the
party. Most of the film was good. Without the music, the Cinderella scenes,
and cut-down sequences with Paul and Jerry,  this would be a major hit! *** out of 4 stars. 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1112373/comments</url><from>from Queens, New York</from><name>Bill Treadway (treads22@hotmail.com)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

"Stop! Look! and Laugh!" is basically nothing more than a compilation film
designed only to make a quick buck from the millions of Stooge fans.
Apparently Moe Howard thought the same thing, because he sued Columbia to
prevent the film from being released. Eventually, he relented after
Columbia
offered to finance and distribute all Stooges features thereafter. If
anything, "Stop! Look! and Laugh" made the Three Stooges even more popular
and at least washed the awful taste of "Snow White and the Three Stooges"
away.Basically, producer/director Jules White (who directed most of the shorts
clips were taken from)edited the best moments from such classic shorts as
"Micro-Phonies", "A Plumbing We Will Go", "Calling All Curs","How High Is
Up" among others and shot new footage with Paul Winchell and his dummies,
Jerry Mahoney and Knucklehead Smiff. This made sense, since the Stooges
shorts were packaged into a half hour show and shown along side "The
Winchell/Mahoney Show" on regular TV. This way both shows get
exposure.Unfortunately, fans looking for a full fledged Stooges feature will be
disappointed. But take solace in the fact that this so called "compromise"
film was actually much better than most of the New Three Stooges features
that followed.  We get to see the original Stooges team in top form, great
gags with Winchell and Mahoney and many memorable moments. The editing is
excellent; much of it is seamlessly handled by a team of skilled editors;
it
should have garnered an Oscar nomination.The only thing that sort of slows this film down is the Marquis Chimps
sequence, which I could have done without, but if seeing animals acting
silly is your thing, fine, enjoy it. But it doesn't take away from the
previous 60 minutes of hilarity.**** out of 4 stars 
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0429405/comments</url><from>from Midnight Movie Land</from><name>Schlockmeister</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

This film was made to be a B picture, meaning it opened for the main movie.
As a B picture, it is sufficient, it does it's job, holds the attention,
provides Stooge and Paul Winchell fans with some laughs. This film was never
meant to satisfy an audience would would come 40 years later, spoiled by
pristine remastered complete prints available with the click of a DVD
player.No, this was for the kids who wanted a quick laugh, familiar gags they had
probably seen a hundred times (by 1960 the Three Stooges as well as the
Little Rascals were syndicated on many kiddie TV shows), so this movie
fulfills it's requirement of keeping audiences happy till the main feature
came up.So, if you want to see this, watch it in that spirit, get up one Saturday
morning, pop some popcorn and get some soda pop put this tape in , watch a
few cartoons after it's over and then you will be warmed up for something
like a film from the Sinbad series, early Jerry Lewis or something else you
might enjoy from the period.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1679475/comments</url><from>from Van Buren, Arkansas</from><name>krorie</name></reviewer><rating>6/10</rating><comment>
I saw "Stop!Look!and Laugh!" as part of a double bill when I was a
teenager and found it amusing, but strictly for the small fry. Whether
the viewer enjoys this picture or not depends greatly on being a fan of
the Three Stooges and Paul Winchell and Jerry Mahoney. Even Three
Stooges addicts will be disappointed with the disjointed nature of the
editing culled from some of the Stooges best film shorts.Paul Winchell and Jerry Mahoney became TV's answer to the extremely
popular Edgar Bergen/Charlie McCarthy radio program. Though Winchell
was a much better ventriloquist than Bergen, his humor basically was
for the kids whereas Bergen appealed to a much wider audience, pleasing
adults as well as children. So in this movie, Mahoney is presented as
Winchell's little boy who hates school and uses all types of stratagems
to stay home.The film has a major problem in making transitions from Winchell and
Mahoney's comic routines to the archival footage featuring the Three
Stooges. The transitions are at best forced and at times complete
failures. The archival footage of the Stooges presents the goofy trio
in much edited versions, sort of like a celluloid Reader's Digest.
Still, the slapstick humor of the Stooges often rises above the sloppy
editing to make the audience laugh.Never serious competition for Laurel and Hardy or the Marx Brothers,
The Three Stooges could deliver the belly laughs at times, especially
the original Moe, Larry, and Curly, with Curly turning out to be one of
the best visual comedians of his day. Many of the scripts were
well-written and the early shorts well directed. Unfortunately Curly's
humor suffered in later years as a result of poor health. So rather
than wasting your time on "Stop!Look! and Laugh!," rent "Disorder in
Court," the Clark Gable parody, "Men in Black," or "A Plumbing We Will
Go" to see the Stooges at their very best. If you're a fan of old-time
slapstick you will certainly enjoy the Classic Stooges but may find
"Stop!Look!and Laugh!" a bit disappointing.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0966066/comments</url><from>from Mamaroneck, New York</from><name>stanbabe143</name></reviewer><rating>4/10</rating><comment>

When this film was first publicized by Columbia Pictures and The film's
producer:Harry Rome in l960.They promised that "The Three Stooges"(Who at
that time were:Moe Howard,Larry Fine &amp; Curly Joe DeRita)would appear in
the
film with Ventrilloquist/Entertainer:Paul Winchell and with NYC based kids
tv host/performer:"Officer Joe"Bolton.But when audiences did see:"Stop
Look
&amp; Laugh!"? "The Three Stooges"(Moe,Larry and Curly Howard.Who died during
the winter of l952)only appear in stock footage from the l930's and
40's.Hence! "The Three Stooges"never really appeared in this film.Thus
depriving the audiences of seeing their favorite comedy trio in action.The
film does feaure some witty banter and slapstick from Mr.Winchell and his
puppet pals:"Jerry Mahoney"and"Knucklehead Smiff"and a wonderful cameo
from"Officer Joe"Bolton.(At that time Mr.Bolton was still hosting reruns
of
"The Three Stooges"Films from the l930's and 40's on WPIX TV Ch.ll
NYC's:"Three Stooges Funhouse!")but the Stock footage with the boys is
brief
and forgetable.When shown with horrible music and graiting sound
effects.And
"The Marquis Chimps"parody of the Fairy Tale "Cinderella"(Which also using
the charming voice over talents of Ms.June Foray.Best remembered as the
voices of "Rocky Squerill and Natasha Fatale')is nothing more than cheap
timefiller for the more memorable comedy squences featuring Mr.Winchell
and
his puppets.Hence! This film should not tell you to"Stop Look &amp;
Laugh!".But
to"Stay away from this Three Stooges RippOFFF!".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15700100/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>A_Forest_Lady</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I saw this when I was a kid. I remember it being advertised as "See the
original Three Stooges in Stop, Look and Laugh!". I was disappointed
and I was a kid easily entertained. I didn't think it was close to
being worth the 35 cents admission. That was one week's allowance
money, after all. I could have seen the horror flick The City of the
Dead or better yet, I could have used the 35 cents and purchased seven
Milky Way candy bars and eaten them in the basement on Saturday morning
while watching an episode of Fury on television. The problem with Stop,
Look and Laugh was that the Stooges comedy wasn't made for feature
length film. And that fact gets compounded when it's a film made of old
Stooges clips spliced together. I did pay $10 to get into a Stooges 24
hour marathon a few years ago and it was worth the money. I made it
through 2 1/2 to 3 hours worth of Stooges or about six shorts, with one
being a mediocre "Shemp".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15700100/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>A_Forest_Lady</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
I saw this when I was a kid. I remember it being advertised as "See the
original Three Stooges in Stop, Look and Laugh!". I was disappointed
and I was a kid easily entertained. I didn't think it was close to
being worth the 35 cents admission. That was one week's allowance
money, after all. I could have seen the horror flick The City of the
Dead or better yet, I could have used the 35 cents and purchased seven
Milky Way candy bars and eaten them in the basement on Saturday morning
while watching an episode of Fury on television. The problem with Stop,
Look and Laugh was that the Stooges comedy wasn't made for feature
length film. And that fact gets compounded when it's a film made of old
Stooges clips spliced together. I did pay $10 to get into a Stooges 24
hour marathon a few years ago and it was worth the money. I made it
through 2 1/2 to 3 hours worth of Stooges or about six shorts, with one
being a mediocre "Shemp".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur15700100/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>A_Forest_Lady</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/stoplookandlaugh.htm /m/three_stooges_stop_look_and_laugh/comments.php?reviewid=1571218</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
C
					</rating><comment>The film is fit for the kiddies, who are more apt than adults to take to the Stooges' silly slapstick routines.</comment></review></movie>