<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Ljubav i moda</original_title><imdb_rating>6.9</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Yugoslavia</country><director>Ljubomir Radicevic</director><producer>Avala Film</producer><synopsis/><actor>Beba Loncar</actor><actor>Dusan Bulajic</actor><actor>Miodrag 'Ckalja' Petrovic</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2100347/comments</url><from>from Stockholm</from><name>Sanda</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>

Yugoshic, clothes company is about to have a catwalk for the coming
season.
Concurrents, Yugofashion, is also about to have a catwalk. Competition is
tough. Suddendly, CEO of Yugochic changes plans and decides to have their
catwalk one day before Yugofasion (which is in 2 weeks) and for that he
flies off to Rome to fetch models. It's crisis because the main designer
has
no - inspiraion!In the meantime, a local aero-club finds out they have no money for
collective summer vacation and decides, i  order to raise funds, fix a
party...CEO is lost in Rome, models are missing, and chef designer ends up at Aero
party. Love and fasion :)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2062380/comments</url><from>from Belgrade, SRB</from><name> (v_tadic)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
When I first saw this movie, I was instantly madly in love with
beautiful 18 yrs old actress Beba Loncar. Naturally, I was not alone.
The entire Yugoslav male population of the early sixties was also
enchanted by her. The film was full of good music, mostly composed by
famous composer Darko Kraljic and performed by excellent actor/singer
Djuza Stojiljkovic and some contemporary very popular singers, such as
Ivo Robic, Lola Novakovic, Gaby Novak and the world class vocal jazz
quartet of the trumpet player Predrag Ivanovic. Western flavor was
skillfully intermixed with Serbian humor, and the film was completely
devoid of any politics. In 2010 the film, digitally remastered, was
shown at the Sopot Film Festival and the guest of honor was Beba
Loncar, looking stunning even in her late sixties.The film has kept its freshness and is popular even in younger
generations. It is always a pleasure to watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2062380/comments</url><from>from Belgrade, SRB</from><name> (v_tadic)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
When I first saw this movie, I was instantly madly in love with
beautiful 18 yrs old actress Beba Loncar. Naturally, I was not alone.
The entire Yugoslav male population of the early sixties was also
enchanted by her. The film was full of good music, mostly composed by
famous composer Darko Kraljic and performed by excellent actor/singer
Djuza Stojiljkovic and some contemporary very popular singers, such as
Ivo Robic, Lola Novakovic, Gaby Novak and the world class vocal jazz
quartet of the trumpet player Predrag Ivanovic. Western flavor was
skillfully intermixed with Serbian humor, and the film was completely
devoid of any politics. In 2010 the film, digitally remastered, was
shown at the Sopot Film Festival and the guest of honor was Beba
Loncar, looking stunning even in her late sixties.The film has kept its freshness and is popular even in younger
generations. It is always a pleasure to watch.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2062380/comments</url><from>from Belgrade, SRB</from><name> (v_tadic)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>