<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Jigoku</original_title><imdb_rating>6.8</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Japan</country><director>Nobuo Nakagawa</director><producer>Shintoho Film Distribution Committee</producer><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Horror</genre><synopsis>
A graduate-school student has a friend who is pure evil. His friend and he are out driving one night when they hit a drunkard and the friend leaves the accident victim to die...
See full summary »
</synopsis><actor>Shigeru Amachi</actor><actor>Utako Mitsuya</actor><actor>Yôichi Numata</actor><rt_rating>N/A</rt_rating><rt_meter/><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0462268/comments</url><from>from Toronto, Canada</from><name>Roger Keightley (rkeightley@sympatico.ca)</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>

This is the granddaddy of all the extreme Japanese horror movies that have
emerged and gained cult status recently. Not only is it amazing that this
film was made more than 40 years ago, but, more surprising still, it was
conceived, written, part-financed and directed by one of the most
classically-inclined of Japan's genre filmmakers. For some reason, Nobuo
Nakagawa decided to suddenly turn his back on the period ghost stories
which
established his reputation, and create a contemporary exercise in Grand
Guignol that was so far ahead of its time, his career never fully
recovered.Most reviews of this remarkable movie understandably focus on its last 40
minutes, which constitute the most bizarre, gruesome and sadistic scenes
in
any country's studio-produced feature films up to that time. The picture's
first hour is usually unmentioned, yet in some ways it's even more daring.
Within a naturalistic framework, we're introduced to apparently normal
main
characters with faults not very different from our own. After a couple of
accidental deaths, the characters migrate to a hell-on-earth masquerading
as
a nursing home. The story becomes a wild mixture of pathos and black
comedy,
with satiric attacks on the supposed sanctity of parents, the aged, the
media, the police and authority figures in general. The earthbound part of
the film climaxes with the mass deaths of the nursing home's patients,
staff
and visitors.Jigoku is certainly not for all tastes, but viewing it is essential to an
understanding of the modern Japanese horror film.

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0630665/comments</url><from>from Worcester, MA</from><name>TimothyFarrell</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
"Jigoku" is an utterly amazing Horror film, possibly the best one to
come from Japan. The film has gained infamy for being the first all out
gore flick. To be honest, its a bit less bloody than I expected. I
really don't care about how graphic or not a film is however and I was
completely impressed with this one. Even though I'm an agnostic, I've
always found the concept of Hell to be horrifying (maybe its my
Christian upbringing). Because of this, "Jigoku" was quite an unnerving
experience. Its an incredibly surreal film, one of the few horror films
I've seen with absolutely no standing in reality. The film's first half
has been called slow-moving, but I feel its an interesting meditation
on life and death. The second half is when it truly comes to life with
the most memorable depiction of hell ever in the movies.Part of the reason why the film works so well is the art direction and
cinematography. "Jigoku" looks absolutely fantastic and is constantly
dreamlike throughout. The direction by Nobuo Nakagawa is great also, as
he knows the right moments to use a quick or slow pace. The screenplay
is a bit ridiculous (why is it that the only two good and honest people
in the film are the ones punished the most), but as with all nightmares
it only seems illogical on reflection. The acting is campy to be sure
but never distracting. "Jigoku" remains one of the greatest cult
classics and a truly unique viewing experience. Kudos to Criterion for
releasing another overlooked classic. (8/10)
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur8242258/comments</url><from>from United States</from><name>irearly</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
I read about this movie when I was a kid. Never thought that much about
it since I would probably never see it. Recently rented it off Netflix
and WOW! Nakagawa's message comes through loud and clear across 46
years and the even wider cultural gap between US and Japan. Unusual
stylization (truly hope to see this on a theater screen someday) is
incredibly effective as a purely aesthetic experience (meaning you
could turn off the subtitles and still be enthralled by the visuals and
the music) AND as an elegy for the Japanese traditions of beauty and
honor. You can read the various summaries in other posts. Suffice it to
say this movie qualifies as a masterpiece if you don't go into it with
"horror movie" expectations. See it!
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2586592/comments</url><from>from Turku, Finland</from><name>paha_kuukkeli</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

I usually find it positive if I can't categorize a movie and Jigoku
surely gets the point from that. It's somewhat bizarre combination of
drama, horror, film noir and art house where happy moments are more
rare than good movies in Hollywood.While the hell sequences of Jigoku seem to gather most of the attention
I think that the story as a whole is what makes this movie good. It
proceeds fluently from disaster to another and while some events lead
to unexpected results the script never leaves a viewer with a feeling
that the twist was added just for the twist's sake (as is the case with
many new movies).Technically the movie is awesome; good acting, great score (especially
the haunting vocals) and beautiful cinematography. From modern
perspective some of the hell sequences are way outdated (mainly the
demons) while some look brilliant even today (settings like the river
bank and some of the gore effects like the guy who gets flayed).I doubt that Jigoku pleases everyone but if you're into bleak and
uncompromising movies this is almost a must see. 8/10

</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0493442/comments</url><from>from Hollywood, ca</from><name>rlcsljo</name></reviewer><rating>5/10</rating><comment>

This movie spends half of its time in the real world and half in the
afterlife.  During the first half you ask "where the hell is hell
anyway?".
After it goes to the "real" hell, you realize that hell is all the things
that went undone in the mortal coil.You realize that if you don't want to live in hell later, don't live in
"hell" now.A great psychedelic trip without psychedelic trappings.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3079504/comments</url><from>from Glen Cove, New York</from><name>dbborroughs</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>

I had read about and seen stills from this movie for years. I had heard how
freaky and bloody and scary this movie's vision of hell was, but I never got
a chance to actually see it. Finally I was able to secure a copy and I sat
down to watch the horror.For the first hour of this film we watch as our hero lives a life that is
more or less a living hell. More horrible, terrible things befall him and
those around him than anyone outside of a soap opera has a right to expect.
Very act is bound to damn someone to hell and it isn't long before our guilt
ridden hero crosses over and experiences what true torment is. Its enough to
make you want to laugh were it not played so painfully
straight.What we see once we get to  Hell itself looks great. Even some 40 years
after it first marched across theater some of the shots of flayed flesh and
disemboweled intestines are still shocking. The cramped and dark vistas are
something out of a nightmare. Many tormented images you'd almost be proud to
have on your walls.Is it scary a bit but its not the be all and end all that some had made it
out to be.  Then again the films images have been raided by others so it
less shocking. I also find that some of the pacing is off and what may have
once worked now borders on tedious.The film seems to be saying that all life, here or in the next world is
miserable hellish  and that no matter what we do we're doomed simply to
suffer. A happy little film if there ever was one.I like the film but far from love it. The first part is very soapy and over
blown, while the second is almost a catalog of horrors. I give it points for
trying but I don't think it completely works.Should you see it?A coin toss. It really depends on what you're looking for. If you're
looking, for gore and guts, its here but not enough to make you walk away
happy. Are you looking for a meditation on sin, guilt and existence, you may
like it, especially if you can get past the soap. If you want to see a
technically well made film that doesn't quite work but influenced later
films and which will provide some discussion over dinner, then try
it.I give it 7 out of 10 for the parts more than the whole.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur0150803/comments</url><from>from Huntington, NY</from><name>Glenn Andreiev (gandreiev@aol.com)</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>

The Japanese word JIGOKU translates to English as HELL.  During the first
half of this 1960 epic shocker, we follow some students take on a rather
evil mentor.  Most of the students are killed during various fits of rage.
The second half follows these students in Hell.  Though this film was made
40 years ago, the Hell scenes could still garnish an NC-17 if shown in a
modern multiplex.  Sinners are sawed in half, slammed in the jaw with
spikes, limbs are torn.   It's brutally frightening!  Masterfully
photographed and acted.    
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur1399158/comments</url><from>from Naxxar, Malta</from><name>MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)</name></reviewer><rating>7/10</rating><comment>
Words can't aptly describe the assault on the senses that is JIGOKU but
I'll try anyway: over-used phrases like fascinating, surreal,
disturbing and unique instantly come to mind - but the film is all of
these and more. By now, I have a fair number of strange Japanese films
under my belt - but this one's something else entirely!From the stylized approach (shooting from odd angles and the occasional
adoption of a greenish hue) to its plethora of arresting imagery
(especially the gruesome body piercing - sword through neck,
eye-gouging, feet stamping on huge needles, torso sawed in half, etc.),
director/co-writer Nakagawa's vision of Hell is surely among the most
visceral ever depicted on the screen. While its concept of establishing
sections (or circles) of punishment for specific crimes goes all the
way back to Dante Alighieri - though, as mentioned in the film itself,
Buddhism has its own take on the subject - cinematically it anticipates
the one seen in the Coffin Joe outing THIS NIGHT I'LL POSSESS YOUR
CORPSE (1966). Still, with respect to both the microcosmic viewpoint of
the plot and the film's vivid color scheme, it also reminded me of GOKE
- BODY SNATCHER FROM HELL (1968), while its essential nihilism (I
literally lost count of the number of people killed off during the
first hour!) looks forward to BLIND BEAST (1969).The doppelganger element - in the DVD's main supplement, a 39-minute
featurette, it's mentioned that the script was partly inspired by the
Faust legend - heightens the film's already disquieting aura: Yoichi
Numata as an emissary of Hell in human form (though he's not spared the
painful retribution for his sins once the scene shifts to the
netherworld) is especially effective; interestingly, the actor was
disappointed by his own performance and admits now that he couldn't
understand the role! However, I need to point out that - much like I
had written of Ingmar Bergman's THE RITE (1969) - the plot reaches a
level of implausible melodrama as to feel almost like a parody (even
more so when considering the various characters' penchant for bursting
into sentimental songs a' la the work of John Ford!).Anyway, while I found the DVD transfer somewhat dark, I'm glad to say
that the copy I own is the 'Second Pressing' - this means that the
problem concerning a 2-minute sequence, which previously got skipped
when watching the disc on a DVD player, has now been fixed. Originally
intended for Eclipse, Criterion's sub-label - back when it was supposed
to release little-known genre/exploitation titles - I feel that the
film is important enough to warrant its place in the official
Collection.The bits from GHOST STORY OF YOTSUYA (1959) shown in the featurette
were very intriguing and, hopefully, won't be too long in coming;
still, I was equally itching to learn more about the various 'B' horror
films by Nakagawa and production company Shintoho (which had actually
started out by making such masterworks of World Cinema as Akira
Kurosawa's STRAY DOG [1949] and Kenji Mizoguchi's THE LIFE OF OHARU
[1952]!) whose posters form the extensive still gallery... Although I have to admit that I'd never heard of the film prior to
Criterion's DVD announcement, Chuck Stephens - in his rather
pretentious essay in the accompanying booklet (though he perceptively
suggests that the pairing of the dead yakuza's mother and girlfriend
may well have anticipated the deadly female relatives of ONIBABA
[1964]) - believes that JIGOKU ought to be thought of in the same terms
as such horror landmarks as EYES WITHOUT A FACE (1959), BLACK Sunday
(1960), PEEPING TOM (1960) and PSYCHO (1960), films which collectively
brought an unprecedented maturity to the genre. Needless to say, the
film's greatest influence can be seen in the gore-drenched Asian
exploitation cinema which survives to this day (interestingly enough,
JIGOKU was itself remade twice over the years - in 1979 and 1999!).
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2951437/comments</url><from>from Mountains of Madness</from><name>fertilecelluloid</name></reviewer><rating>8/10</rating><comment>
Nobuo Nakagawa directed a handful of horror/ghost pictures, but this is
the most interesting of them all. A young man (Shigeru Amachi),
indirectly responsible for a number of deaths, is sent to Hell for
punishment. The Hell depicted here is the Buddhist version crossed with
the Catholic version. Pools of fire. Torture. Lost souls doomed to walk
in endless circles. Bodies flayed. Dismemberment. Flesh ripped from
bones. The whole nine yards. The last half hour possesses an authentic
level of hysteria as our "hero" attempts to extricate himself from the
madness. Like "Kaidan" and even the "Female Convict - Scorpion" pics,
this has a strong theatrical feel and is lit like an avant garde stage
play. That this was made in 1960 is quite extraordinary for it
foreshadows the extremes of cinema to come such as Japan's own "Guinea
Pig" as well as 1964's "At Midnight I'll Take Your Soul" (from Brazil)
and 1967's "Tonight I'll Possess Your Corpse" (also from Brazil). A
groundbreaking, genre-creating masterpiece that is definitely a product
of a more naive but less conservative era.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3987336/comments</url><from>from Tokyo, Japan</from><name>haildevilman</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Could this be the first gore film? WWII flashbacks, yakuza violence,
families falling apart, stereotypes, depressing sequences...this has it
ALL.The first gore scene? When the man sliced in half sees his guts hit the
floor.The producers of this were going for it. They made it work with the
great cinematography and the well developed characters.It's not so much a religious question as just a speculation. If all
religions had hell, would it look like...what? My wife liked this film
and she hates horror. She was glad when I got the DVD. Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur3987336/comments</url><from>from Tokyo, Japan</from><name>haildevilman</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
Could this be the first gore film? WWII flashbacks, yakuza violence,
families falling apart, stereotypes, depressing sequences...this has it
ALL.The first gore scene? When the man sliced in half sees his guts hit the
floor.The producers of this were going for it. They made it work with the
great cinematography and the well developed characters.It's not so much a religious question as just a speculation. If all
religions had hell, would it look like...what? My wife liked this film
and she hates horror. She was glad when I got the DVD. Don't miss it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/anton-bitel/</url><url>http://www.eyeforfilm.co.uk/reviews.php?film_id=11934 /m/jigoku/comments.php?reviewid=1650799</url><name>Anton Bitel</name><from>Eye for Film</from></reviewer><comment>the film's bleak portrayal of sin and (maybe) redemption is easily adapted to any time, even if Nakagawa's particular version is unimaginable in any decade but the Sixties.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>http://www.timeout.com/film/reviews/71898/hell.html /m/jigoku/comments.php?reviewid=1557885</url><from>Time Out</from></reviewer><comment>Shot mostly on bare studio sets with a lighting style even more theatrical than the acting, it feels like a weird piece of fringe theatre in three acts.</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
				http://rottentomatoes.com/critic/dennis-schwartz/</url><url>http://www.sover.net/~ozus/jigoku.htm /m/jigoku/comments.php?reviewid=1557024</url><name>Dennis Schwartz</name><from>Ozus' World Movie Reviews</from></reviewer><rating>
A
					</rating><comment>[Director Nobou] Nakagawa dazzles with his stunningly erotic-grotesque visualization of his interpretation of the lower depths.</comment></review></movie>