<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><movie><original_title>Doa al karawan</original_title><imdb_rating>7.3</imdb_rating><year>1960</year><country>Egypt</country><director>Henry Barakat</director><genre>Drama</genre><genre>Romance</genre><synopsis>
This compelling tale of love and betrayal, set in the upper Egyptian countryside, follows the story of Amna as she plots her revenge on the engineer who destroyed her family's honor.
</synopsis><actor>Faten Hamama</actor><actor>Ahmed Mazhar</actor><actor>Amina Rizk</actor><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur4793386/comments</url><from>from USA</from><name>ramy-10</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
For over an hour and half of enjoyment watching this magnificent story
and special movie you will ask your self this question, which is more
powerful?Amna (played by the Legendary Faten Hamama) is a young sister that
watches the death of her older sister by her Uncle, the guy that
abandoned her family and left them with no support. She hears from her
mother that her sister was killed because she dishonors the family and
based on their culture, she deserve to die. Amna doesn't think so; she
believes that her uncle was the one to blame for what they are
suffering from. She switches her focus and revenge to the engineer who
fooled her sister and lied to her (role played by Ahmed Mazhar) and was
a direct cause for her death. Amna moves to his house to work as maid
and tried to poison him many times, but her plans always fails. She
discovers after a while that she can't kill, she doesn't have the power
to kill. This engineer keep playing with her try to have fun, but she
kept resist him. The more she resisted, the more he was attracted to
her and finally he loved her. The poor girl thought that by making him
falling in love with her would destroy his life. What she didn't count
for was her heart started to click signals for that guy. Her plan was
to dig a hole for him and through him in it, but she fell in the hole
with him.She faced him with the truth, and who she is. She decided to leave him
and get away from him. She knows that her plan was failed and she needs
to get away. It was about time for her uncle (the guy who killed her
sister) to find where she is and was after her death to keep his family
pride and honor shinning!!!!!!!!!!!In her way out of the house, she sees him and she knows that he has bad
intention, but the engineer sees him too, and takes the bullet in his
back to protect her and save her life. It's a sad ending that you will never forget. There are no enough words to describe how this picture is great. A
story by Taha Hussein (the Dean of the Arabic Literature), Faten Hamama
(The lady of the Arabic Screen), Ahmed Mazhar, Amina Rizk, Zahrat
El-Olla and running this show by someone like Henry Barakat is
something deserves great appreciation after watching it.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur11842025/comments</url><from>from prejudicemadeplausible.wordpress.com</from><name>ametaphysicalshark</name></reviewer><rating/><comment>
Although he is not as frequently discussed as Youssef Chahine, Salah
Abou-Seif, or even contemporary directors like Yousy Nasrallah, Henry
Barakat was one of the most successful and popular studio directors in
the classic era of Egyptian cinema, of which few films are currently
available to Western audiences on home video, one of them being the
recent DVD release of this classic, massively acclaimed masterwork.
Henry Barakat cared little about careful compositions and stylization,
focusing heavily on fast and economical storytelling with fleeting
moments of poetic imagery in most of his dramatic films, while his
comic efforts showed an immense talent for staging sight gags and
getting good comic performances out of classically trained dramatic
actors.There is little comedy in "Doa al karawan", also known as "The
Nightingale's Prayer", and it comes almost solely in the first half
hour or so of the film, along with the film's only moments of comfort
and joy. This is among the most depressing films ever made, a classical
tragic melodrama, certainly, but one far more poetic, intelligent, and
understanding of human emotions and relationships than most. That is
not all that surprising either, as the film is closely based on the
prose masterpiece by famed literary master Taha Hussein. The film
touches on all the bases when it comes to tragedy: lust, revenge,
murder, repression, love, betrayal, and death, but does so through a
story that rarely feels contrived and which is always effective and
intelligent, never dumbed down for the masses in spite of this being a
popular and relatively mainstream film, albeit one that was heavily
censored at the time (an attempted rape scene was cut, I believe, but
is restored on home video). Starring Egyptian superstar and terrific actress Faten Hamama (Omar
Sharif's wife for many years), the film follows the story of Hamama's
character Amna as she, her mother, and her sister are forced to leave
their village to preserve the family's honor by Amna's viciously
patriarchal and hypocritical uncle following the murder of her father
after he was caught committing adultery. Amna and her sister move to
the city, naive village girls as they are, shocked and appalled at the
simple sight of a train and awed by things like pianos and gramophones,
and doubtlessly scandalized by the heavy drinking and fornication that
was fairly common in Egyptian city life at the time, and find jobs
working as maids. Soon Amna's sister is seduced by her employer, which
leads to her uncle finding out and killing her, leading Amna to plot
revenge against her sister's previous employer, an alcoholic
businessman who soon falls in love with Amna. The film twists and turns, but never feels contrived, and is always
literate and well-written, although the English subtitles unfortunately
cannot translate certain poetic passages well, which come off as
decidedly corny or lose their power once translated. The film is very
much in the spirit of Taha Hussein's writings, and is probably among my
favorite literary adaptations overall in terms of how good the film is
and also how well it brings the novel to the screen. The ending is
devastating, the characters are well-developed, the tragedy feels real,
the melodramatic air of the film fits well, the story is immensely
well-told on a visual level, the orchestral score is excellent (but,
unfortunately, very poorly-recorded), and every performance is
excellent. In addition there is some excellent cinematography, although
the transfer on the DVD is unfortunately not very good.Audiences which strongly dislike classic American or British melodramas
may not take to Henry Barakat's "The Nightingale's Prayer", but I think
it is one of the very best of its sort (possibly the best, period) and
is stylistically in tune with the nature of the tale as an adaptation
of something akin to an Arabic prose version of a Shakespearian
tragedy. With the film now available on DVD in North America, I
sincerely hope it will be seen by more people outside Egypt, where it
is widely considered a classic. Regardless of the criticism it may face
from some, "The Nightingale's Prayer" is a film I have seen many times
since my childhood, and one which has never lessened in power or
resonance, and is still very much relevant to the world today.10/10
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur2467618/comments</url><from>from Bradenton, Florida</from><name>planktonrules</name></reviewer><rating>9/10</rating><comment>
This is a wonderful Egyptian film that the average Western audience
never gets an opportunity to see. It's really a shame as the movie
gives so much insight into the culture and the story, though very
"foreign" features some characters you can easily relate to an care
for.The film is a great film that shows the clash between very conservative
Islamic values and traditions and those of a more modern Moslem world.
This clash is extremely poignant and seems to illustrate that the
spirit of the law and tradition is much more important that the
traditions themselves.The film begins with a woman and her two adult daughters finding out
that the father is murdered. It seems that this man was committing
adultery and someone took it upon themselves to punish him. However,
instead of just punishing him and being done with it, the family
Patriarch (the uncle) tells the women they must leave the village and
fend for themselves! It ISN'T because they did anything wrong, but that
they would be a reminder of the man's infidelity. So, in his twisted
thinking, he cast these women out with no regard to their future just
so the family APPEARS good and just to outsiders!! The ladies appear
fortunate when they arrive at a far-off town because the two youngest
are able to get jobs as maids. However, the oldest daughter is
eventually seduced (or possibly raped) by her employer and the family.
The mother is extremely upset by this and contacts the patriarch to ask
for his assistance. The "kindly" uncle agrees to take them back to the
original village, but on the way, he murders the "fallen sister"! The
inequity of her death and the employer never being punished is a major
theme of the film. While some in the male-dominated society might
approve of this, the unjustness of the murder is definitely called into
question. And, since no one seems to care, the youngest daughter, Amna,
decides to run from her Uncle's home and find the older sister's
ex-employer and exact justice! All this occurs just in the first half
of the movie! The rest is the slowly unfolding of Amna's revenge and
the unexpected twists and turns the plot takes along the way. And,
fortunately, this is NOT a by-the-numbers movie--it is definitely NOT
predictable or written for a dumb audience! This is an exceptionally
well written, acted and directed film. In addition, the cinematography
is exquisite. The only down side, and this is a very minor quibble, is
that the music is a bit "tinny".
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14023070/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>natalieb-3</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Amna, Hanadi, and their mother are village women who are forced into
city life when their cruel Uncle Gaber casts them out of the village.
The characters they encounter in the city are a revealing mix of urban
professionals and seedier individuals. The professionals (the chief of
police, the engineer) represent the new technocratic upper class of
Egypt, responsible for modernization, urban planning, and
bureaucratization. In the chief of police's home, Amna transforms from
an illiterate village girl in hijab to a literate young woman in
Western dress. In the end, the oppressive, misogynistic Uncle Gaber is
arrested in the city, proof that his village code of honour does not
apply in the modern urban context.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com/user/ur14023070/comments</url><from>from Canada</from><name>natalieb-3</name></reviewer><rating>10/10</rating><comment>
Amna, Hanadi, and their mother are village women who are forced into
city life when their cruel Uncle Gaber casts them out of the village.
The characters they encounter in the city are a revealing mix of urban
professionals and seedier individuals. The professionals (the chief of
police, the engineer) represent the new technocratic upper class of
Egypt, responsible for modernization, urban planning, and
bureaucratization. In the chief of police's home, Amna transforms from
an illiterate village girl in hijab to a literate young woman in
Western dress. In the end, the oppressive, misogynistic Uncle Gaber is
arrested in the city, proof that his village code of honour does not
apply in the modern urban context.
</comment></review><review><reviewer><url>
					 			http://imdb.com</url><from/><name/></reviewer><rating/><comment>Add another review</comment></review></movie>